<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-113991" number="33861" version="227">
			<HEADING>Chapter 2: Medical Examiner</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6751" name="T17C002"/>Chapter 2: Medical Examiner</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-28163" number="33862" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 17-201 Report of deaths; removal of body.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6753" name="17-201"/>§ 17-201 Report of deaths; removal of body.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28164" number="33863" version="680">
											<PARA>It shall be the duty of any citizen who becomes aware of the death of any person, occurring under the circumstances described in paragraph one of subdivision (f) of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="557" destination-id="0-0-0-0">five hundred fifty-seven</LINK> of the charter, to report such death forthwith to the office of the chief medical examiner, and to a police officer who shall forthwith notify the officer in charge of the station-house in the police precinct in which such person died. Any person who shall wilfully neglect or refuse to report such death or who without written order from a medical examiner shall wilfully touch, remove or disturb the body of any such person, or wilfully touch, remove or disturb the clothing or any article upon or near such body, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-28165" number="33864" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 17-202 Procedure in deaths reportable to the office of chief medical examiner.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6755" name="17-202"/>§ 17-202 Procedure in deaths reportable to the office of chief medical examiner.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28166" number="33865" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon any such death, the officer in charge of the station-house in the police precinct in which such person died shall immediately notify the office of chief medical examiner of the known facts concerning the time, place, manner and circumstances of such death. Immediately upon receipt of such notification the chief medical examiner, or a deputy chief medical examiner, or a medical examiner, or a medical investigator, or a lay medical investigator shall go to and take charge of the dead body. Such medical examiner, medical investigator or lay medical investigator shall fully investigate the essential facts concerning the circumstances of the death, taking the names and addresses of as many witnesses thereto as it may be practicable to obtain, and shall record all such facts and file the same in the office of chief medical examiner. Such medical examiner, medical investigator or lay medical investigator shall take possession of any portable objects which, in his or her opinion, may be useful in establishing the cause of death, and except as provided in subdivision c hereof, shall deliver them to the police department.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28167" number="33866" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The police officer detailed in such cases shall, in the absence of next of kin of the deceased person, take possession of all property of value found on such person, make an exact inventory thereof on his or her report, and deliver such property to the police department, which shall surrender the same to the person entitled to its custody or possession.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28168" number="33867" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivisions a and b of this section, any suicide note or other written evidence of suicide found on such deceased person shall be delivered to the chief medical examiner and shall be retained by said medical examiner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28169" number="33868" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing in this section contained shall affect the powers and duties of a public administrator.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-28170" number="33869" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 17-203 Autopsies; findings.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6757" name="17-203"/>§ 17-203 Autopsies; findings.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28171" number="33870" version="3">
											<PARA>If it may be concluded with reasonable certainty that death occurred from natural causes or obvious traumatic injury, and there are no other circumstances which would appear to require an autopsy, the chief medical examiner, deputy chief medical examiner or medical examiner or medical investigator in charge shall certify the cause of death and file a report of his or her findings in the office of chief medical examiner. If, however, in the opinion of a medical examiner, an autopsy is necessary, the same shall be performed by a medical examiner. Where indicated, the autopsy shall include toxicologic, histologic, microbiologic and serologic examinations. A detailed description of the findings of all autopsies shall be written or dictated. The findings of the investigation at the scene of death, the autopsy and any toxicologic, histologic, serologic and microbiologic examinations, and the conclusions drawn therefrom shall be filed in the office of chief medical examiner. Such findings and conclusions shall be signed by the medical examiner performing the autopsy.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-28172" number="33871" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 17-204 Cremation.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6759" name="17-204"/>§ 17-204 Cremation.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28173" number="33872" version="3">
											<PARA>Whenever an application is made pursuant to law for a permit to cremate the body of any person, the department, board or office in which such application is filed shall forward such application to the chief medical examiner who shall thereupon cause an investigation and report to be made thereon. In the event that the chief medical examiner, or a deputy chief medical examiner, or a medical examiner shall, in the course of such investigation, determine that reasonable grounds exist therefor, an autopsy shall be performed upon such body by a medical examiner. Where indicated, the autopsy shall include toxicologic, histologic, microbiologic and serologic examinations. A detailed description of the findings of all autopsies shall be written or dictated. The findings of the investigation, the autopsy and any toxicologic, histologic, serologic and microbiologic examinations, and the conclusions drawn therefrom shall be filed in the office of chief medical examiner. Such findings and conclusions shall be signed by the medical examiners performing the autopsy.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-28174" number="33873" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 17-205 Records.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6761" name="17-205"/>§ 17-205 Records.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28175" number="33874" version="680">
											<PARA>Records shall be kept in the office of the chief medical examiner, properly indexed, stating the name, if known, of every person dying under the circumstances described in paragraph one of subdivision (f) of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="557" destination-id="0-0-0-0">five hundred fifty-seven</LINK> of the charter, the place where the body was found and the date of death. To the record of each case shall be attached the original report of the medical examiner and the detailed findings of the autopsy, if any. The appropriate district attorney and the police commissioner of the city may require from the chief medical examiner such further records, and such daily information, as they may deem necessary.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-28176" number="33875" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 17-206 Fees for copies of records.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6763" name="17-206"/>§ 17-206 Fees for copies of records.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28177" number="33876" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever the chief medical examiner shall furnish to any private individual a copy or transcript of any record or any photograph or photostat of such record, such chief medical examiner shall and is hereby authorized to charge as follows: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28178" number="33877" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TABLE>
													<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2" left-border-space="0" left-border-width="30" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="0" right-border-width="30" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="0" top-border-width="30" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="30" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="0" horizontal-border-width="15" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="0" vertical-border-width="15" vertical-border-color="#000000">
														<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="25" percentage="yes"/>
														<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
													</TABLEFORMAT>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>1. For each copy or photostat of medical examiner&apos;s report on cause of death</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>five dollars per page</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>2. For each copy or photostat of hospital report </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>five dollars per page</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>3. For each copy or photostat of autopsy report </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>five dollars per page</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>4. For each copy or photostat of toxicological chemical laboratory report </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>five dollars per page</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>5. For each copy or photostat of identification form </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>five dollars per page</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>6. For each copy or photostat of serological and/or bacteriological report </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>five dollars per page</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>7. For each copy or photostat of notice of death slip </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>five dollars per page</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
												</TABLE>
											</PARA>
											<PARA>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28179" number="33878" version="3">
											<PARA>It is provided that the charge for any single request for documents of a single case shall not exceed fifty dollars.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28180" number="33879" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The chief medical examiner shall waive such fee or any portion thereof when furnishing such copies to indigent next of kin.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28181" number="33880" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The chief medical examiner, in his or her discretion, shall have the power to waive such fee or any portion thereof when furnishing such copies to those engaged in scientific or other research.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-28182" number="33881" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 17-207 Root cause analysis, office of chief medical examiner.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6765" name="17-207"/>§ 17-207 Root cause analysis, office of chief medical examiner.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28183" number="33882" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of this subdivision, the following terms shall have the following meanings:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28184" number="33883" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Designated root cause analysis officer&quot; shall mean an employee of the office of chief medical examiner who is responsible for determining whether a significant event has occurred within the office of chief medical examiner and, if such significant event has occurred, for convening the root cause analysis committee.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28185" number="33884" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Root cause analysis&quot; shall mean a process for investigating the causal factors of a significant event that shall focus primarily on systems and processes, not on individual performance or human error, and shall identify appropriate corrective action, including strategies to prevent the reoccurrence of a significant event or potential improvements in systems or processes that will decrease the likelihood of a significant event occurring in the future.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28186" number="33885" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Root cause analysis committee&quot; shall mean a committee composed of representatives of certain divisions of the office of chief medical examiner appointed by the designated root cause analysis officer and assembled in response to a significant event in order to conduct a root cause analysis and to produce a root cause analysis committee report pursuant to this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28187" number="33886" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Root cause analysis committee report&quot; shall mean a final report issued by the root cause analysis committee that shall include the findings of the root cause analysis committee, including, but not limited to, the identification of the root cause or causes of the significant event and a corrective action plan.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28188" number="33887" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Significant event&quot; shall mean an occurrence in the office of chief medical examiner involving a significant likelihood of an act, error or omission that affects the accuracy, reliability or integrity of the reported results of evidence examination or reported results of analysis. Such act, error or omission shall include, but not be limited to, any (i) act or acts by an employee of the office of chief medical examiner involving intentional fabrication of work product, evidence examination, analysis or test results; (ii) significant error or errors by an employee of the office of chief medical examiner, or deficiency in a system or procedure used by such office, that may have affected the accuracy of reported results of evidence examination or the accuracy of the reported results of analysis in one or more cases; (iii) failure by an employee of the office of chief medical examiner to follow such office&apos;s protocol that may have affected the accuracy of reported results of evidence examination or the accuracy of the reported results of analysis in one or more cases; or (iv) statement in the course of testimony by an employee of the office of chief medical examiner that significantly misrepresents or misstates her or his education, experience, training or qualifications, or the reported results of any evidence examination or analysis.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28189" number="33888" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The office of chief medical examiner shall appoint an employee of the office of chief medical examiner who shall serve as the designated root cause analysis officer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28190" number="33889" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The office of chief medical examiner shall develop and post on its website root cause analysis guidelines to assist in the implementation of this section. Such guidelines shall provide guidance for:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28191" number="33890" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>determining whether a significant event has occurred, consistent with this section;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28192" number="33891" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>reporting a significant event;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28193" number="33892" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>creating a root cause analysis committee upon a determination of the root cause analysis officer that a significant event has occurred;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28194" number="33893" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>selecting individuals who shall serve as members of a root cause analysis committee;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28195" number="33894" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>determining the roles and responsibilities of members of a root cause analysis committee;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28196" number="33895" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>determining when and how frequently a root cause analysis committee shall meet once a committee has been assembled in response to a significant event;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28197" number="33896" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>producing a root cause analysis committee report in a timely manner;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28198" number="33897" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>identifying causal factors of a significant event;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28199" number="33898" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>identifying corrective action to be taken as a result of the root cause analysis; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28200" number="33899" version="1778">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>10.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>recusing the designated root cause analysis officer in the event that the occurrence at issue is likely to involve acts or omissions by such officer, either acting in the capacity of the designated root cause analysis officer or any other capacity within the office of chief medical examiner, or in any other appropriate instance as specified in the guidelines;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-223970" number="33900" version="1778">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>appointing an employee of the office of chief medical examiner to serve as the acting designated root cause analysis officer in the event of such recusal to fulfill the duties of the designated root cause analysis officer pursuant to subdivisions d, e and f of this section, provided that the occurrence at issue is not likely to involve acts or omissions by such individual appointed to serve as acting designated root cause analysis officer; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-223971" number="33901" version="1778">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>requiring a decision not to recuse the designated root cause analysis officer to be reviewed by the executive management of the office of chief medical examiner, such as a director or deputy commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28201" number="33902" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within ten days of the discovery of an occurrence in the office of chief medical examiner involving the substantial likelihood of an act, error or omission that affects the accuracy, reliability and integrity of the reported results of evidence examination or reported results of analysis, or receipt of a report that a significant event has occurred in the office of chief medical examiner, the designated root cause analysis officer shall make a formal determination whether a significant event has occurred. In the event that the designated root cause analysis officer makes a determination that a significant event has not occurred, such officer shall provide written explanation to the chief medical examiner explaining why such occurrence does not constitute a significant event.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28202" number="33903" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within five business days of a formal determination by the designated root cause analysis officer that a significant event has occurred within the office of chief medical examiner as provided in subdivision d of this section, such officer shall appoint a root cause analysis committee for the purpose of conducting a root cause analysis and producing a root cause analysis committee report. Such committee shall include at least six members, provided that:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28203" number="33904" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>one member is the designated root cause analysis officer;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28204" number="33905" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>at least one member is knowledgeable in the subject area relating to the significant event and is a lab worker or other employee who performs scientific or technical services and works in a non-managerial capacity;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28205" number="33906" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>one member serves in the executive management of the office of chief medical examiner, such as a director or deputy commissioner;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28206" number="33907" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>two members are from divisions, departments or laboratories of the office of chief medical examiner that are not implicated by the significant event, and at least one of the two members works in a non-managerial capacity; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28207" number="33908" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>one member is an external expert who works in a medical or scientific research field. Such member may serve without compensation. For the purpose of executing paragraph 5 of this subdivision, the office of chief medical examiner shall develop and maintain a list of external experts who may serve as an external expert on a root cause analysis committee if called upon to serve in such capacity.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28208" number="33909" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within thirty days of a determination of the designated root cause analysis officer that a significant event has occurred within the office of chief medical examiner, the office of chief medical examiner shall report the occurrence of such significant event to the mayor and the council of the city of New York, and to any district attorney and defense counsel of record that can be identified and who has a case or client that can reasonably be found to be affected by the significant event. In the event that the defense counsel of record works in the office of an institutional defender, notice shall also be given to the head of such office. In the event that defense counsel of record is assigned from the 18b panel of either the first or second department in the city of New York, notice shall also be given to the administrator of the 18b panel of the assigning department.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28209" number="33910" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The root cause analysis committee shall submit a root cause analysis committee report no later than ninety days following the appointment of such committee, provided, however, that should it not be practicable to complete such report within ninety days, the committee shall report in writing to the mayor and council of the city of New York on the progress of the committee&apos;s findings and set forth a statement why such report is not yet completed and when completion is anticipated.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28210" number="33911" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within seven days of submission of a root cause analysis report to the mayor and council of the city of New York, the office of chief medical examiner shall send a copy of the root cause analysis report at a minimum to (i) the New York state commission on forensic science and any entity responsible for the accreditation of the department of forensic biology of the office of chief medical examiner, provided that the significant event that is the subject of such report is relevant to the department of forensic biology of the office of chief medical examiner, and (ii) to district attorney and defense counsel of record that can be identified and who has a case or client that can reasonably be found to be affected by the significant event. In the event that the defense counsel of record works in the office of an institutional defender, notice shall also be given to the head of such office. In the event that defense counsel of record is assigned from the 18b panel of either the first or second department in the city of New York, notice shall also be given to the administrator of the 18b panel of the assigning department.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28211" number="33912" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The root cause analysis report produced pursuant to subdivision f of this section shall not include the names of, or otherwise identify:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28212" number="33913" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>any employee of the office of chief medical examiner;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28213" number="33914" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>any complainant, victim or decedent; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28214" number="33915" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>any other individual who is the subject of investigations associated with forensic casework performed by the office of chief medical examiner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28215" number="33916" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section shall not be construed to create a private right of action to enforce any of its provisions.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-28216" number="33917" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 17-208 Transparency, office of chief medical examiner.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6767" name="17-208"/>§ 17-208 Transparency, office of chief medical examiner.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28217" number="33918" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the purpose of this section, the following terms shall have the following meanings:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28218" number="33919" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Forensic DNA laboratory&quot; shall have the same meaning as set forth in subdivision two of section nine hundred ninety-five of article forty-nine-b of the New York state executive law, or any successor provision thereto.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28219" number="33920" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Proficiency test&quot; shall mean such testing as is required by the New York state commission on forensic science and the New York state subcommittee on forensic DNA laboratories and forensic DNA testing pursuant to paragraph b of subdivision three of section nine hundred ninety-five-b of article forty-nine-b of the New York state executive law, or any successor provision thereto.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28220" number="33921" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Proficiency testing report&quot; shall mean an annual report produced by the office of chief medical examiner which reports the number of employees working in the department of forensic biology of the office of chief medical examiner who have taken a proficiency test that year, and the percentage and number of those employees who passed such proficiency test.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28221" number="33922" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The office of chief medical examiner shall annually prepare a proficiency testing report and shall include comparison data for each of the previous five years as available. The proficiency testing report shall not include the names of, or otherwise identify, any employee of the department of forensic biology of the office of chief medical examiner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28222" number="33923" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To the extent the office of chief medical examiner is authorized to publish such materials, the office of chief medical examiner shall post prominently and maintain on its website the following concerning the department of forensic biology of the office of chief medical examiner:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28223" number="33924" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>current copies, and copies used within the preceding two years, of all manuals, guidelines, or other documents relating to scientific procedures or protocols, quality assurance and quality control procedures or protocols, materials used for the training of lab workers, and evidence and case management procedures, including, but not limited to, accreditation standards and accreditation audit reports;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28224" number="33925" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>the most recent annual proficiency testing report; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28225" number="33926" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>current copies of all certificates of accreditation issued to the department of forensic biology of the office of chief medical examiner, whether by a governmental entity or a non-governmental entity responsible for the accreditation of the department of forensic biology of the office of chief medical examiner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28226" number="33927" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Historic copies of any manual, guidelines, or other document identified in paragraph one of subdivision c of this section used on or after January first, two thousand and not fully available on the website of the office of chief medical examiner shall be made available to any person upon request, and a notice describing such availability and how to make such a request shall be posted on the office&apos;s website.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-28227" number="33928" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section shall not be construed to create a private right of action to enforce any of its provisions.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>