<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-128138" number="31555" version="1020">
			<HEADING>Chapter 4: Single-Use Items</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6257" name="T16C004"/>Chapter 4: Single-Use Items</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-26800" number="31556" version="1464">
				<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
					<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> This chapter was repealed and replaced by L.L. 2021/064, 6/12/2021, eff. 11/1/2021. This chapter formerly pertained to the New York City rechargeable battery law. For related unconsolidated provisions of the former chapter, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2005/097" destination-id="0-0-0-25148">L.L. 2005/097</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-209290" number="31557" version="1464">
										<HEADING>§ 16-401 Restrictions on providing single-use plastic beverage straws, beverage stirrers and beverage splash sticks.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6321" name="16-401"/>§ 16-401 Restrictions on providing single-use plastic beverage straws, beverage stirrers and beverage splash sticks<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">.</CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26801" number="31558" version="1020">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions</CHARFORMAT>. As used in this section, the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135139" number="31559" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Beverage splash stick.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;beverage splash stick&quot; means a device primarily intended to be used to keep heat and liquid from escaping a lidded cup. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135138" number="31560" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Beverage stirrer.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;beverage stirrer&quot; means a device primarily intended to be used by a person for the purpose of stirring beverages. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135137" number="31561" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Beverage straw.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;beverage straw&quot; means a tube primarily intended to be used for transferring a beverage from its container to the mouth of a person. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135136" number="31562" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Compostable.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;compostable&quot; means: (i) capable of undergoing biological breakdown in an industrial composting process, (ii) degradable into biomass that results in a material that is safe and desirable as a soil amendment and (iii) where applicable, as set forth in rules of the department: (A) compliant with ASTM D 6400, ASTM D 6868 or successor standards or other applicable standards developed by ASTM or other international standards organizations that specify criteria relating to the degradation of manufactured items into safe and environmentally beneficial material and (B) approved by a third-party field testing organization that has tested the item at issue to ensure that it is degradable into biomass that results in a material that is safe and desirable as a soil amendment. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135135" number="31563" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Food service establishment.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;food service establishment&quot; means a premises or part of a premises where food is provided directly to a person, whether such food is provided free of charge or sold, and whether consumption occurs on or off the premises or is provided from a pushcart, stand or vehicle. Food service establishment shall include, but not be limited to, full-service restaurants, fast food restaurants, cafes, delicatessens, coffee shops, bars, nightclubs, grocery stores, vending trucks or carts and cafeterias. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135134" number="31564" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Plastic.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;plastic&quot; means a synthetic material made from organic polymers, including, but not limited to, polypropylene and polystyrene, that can be molded into shape while soft, and then set into a rigid or slightly elastic form. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135133" number="31565" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Self-serve station.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;self-serve station&quot; means a designated area or mechanical dispenser in a food service establishment where consumers may help themselves to eating or drinking utensils such as napkins, cups, knives, forks, straws, stirrers or splash sticks. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135132" number="31566" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Single-use.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;single-use&quot; means designed and intended to be used only once for drinking, eating or to serve a food or beverage. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135131" number="31567" version="1020">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No food service establishment in the city shall provide to any person any single-use beverage stirrer or single-use beverage splash stick made of plastic. Nothing in this chapter shall preclude food service establishments from providing compostable beverage stirrers or compostable beverage splash sticks that are not made from plastic. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135130" number="31568" version="1020">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No food service establishment in the city shall provide to any person a single-use plastic beverage straw that is not compostable except upon request. Nothing in this chapter shall preclude food service establishments from providing compostable beverage straws that are not made from plastic. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135129" number="31569" version="1020">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All food service establishments shall maintain a sufficient supply of single-use plastic beverage straws that are not compostable. If a person specifically requests a plastic beverage straw, such food service establishment shall provide a single-use plastic beverage straw that is not compostable free of charge and shall make no inquiry into the reason for such request. A violation of this paragraph may also violate the reasonable accommodation provisions of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T08" destination-id="0-0-0-2039">title 8</LINK> of this code and be subject to enforcement by the city commission on human rights. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135128" number="31570" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All food service establishments that have one or more self-serve stations shall display a sign at each such station that states: &quot;Plastic straws available upon request.&quot; Such signs shall be unobstructed in their entirety. Such signs must be at least two inches by seven inches, in no less than 20 point font. A sample sign that satisfies the requirements of this paragraph shall be made available in a downloadable format on the department&apos;s website. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135127" number="31571" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding subdivision c of this section, food service establishments may provide compostable beverage straws that are made from plastic upon request only if such straws are used by persons on such food service establishments&apos; premises and such food service establishments dispose of all such straws through a commercial composting provider or in accordance with paragraph 1 of subdivision c of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-306.1" destination-id="0-0-0-6273">16-306.1</LINK> if such establishments are covered establishments pursuant to such section. Food service establishments that are not covered under section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-306.1" destination-id="0-0-0-6273">16-306.1</LINK> that provide compostable beverage straws that are made of plastic pursuant to this subdivision shall maintain distinct and clearly labeled bins indicating where such compostable beverage straws that are made from plastic are to be separated for purposes of disposal. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135126" number="31572" version="1020">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section does not apply to single-use beverage straws, beverage stirrers or beverage splash sticks that are packaged in bulk by a manufacturer and offered for retail sale. This section does not apply to pre-packaged beverage straws attached to individual beverage boxes, including but not limited to juice boxes, by the beverage manufacturer. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135125" number="31573" version="1020">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In consultation with other city agencies, the department shall conduct outreach and education about the requirements of this section. Such outreach and education shall be offered in multiple languages and shall employ best practices for accessibility for people with disabilities. Additionally, the department shall provide information about available compostable single-use beverage splash sticks, beverage stirrers and beverage straws on its website. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135124" number="31574" version="1020">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department, the department of health and mental hygiene and the department of consumer and worker protection shall have the authority to enforce the provisions of this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135123" number="31575" version="1020">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who violates this section or any rule promulgated pursuant thereto shall be liable for a civil penalty recoverable in a civil action brought in the name of the commissioner, the commissioner of health and mental hygiene or the commissioner of consumer and worker protection, or in a proceeding before the office of administrative trials and hearings, pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="1049-a" destination-id="0-0-0-0">1049-a</LINK> of the charter, or in the case of a food service establishment within the jurisdiction of the commissioner of health and mental hygiene or the commissioner of consumer and worker protection, in a proceeding before the office of administrative trials and hearings pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="1048" destination-id="0-0-0-0">1048</LINK> of the charter. Such penalties shall be in the amount of one hundred dollars for the first violation, two hundred dollars for the second violation committed on a different day within a period of twelve months, and four hundred dollars for the third and each subsequent violation committed on different days within a period of twelve months, except that such departments shall not issue a notice of violation, but shall issue a warning for any first violation that occurs before November 1, 2022. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135115" number="31576" version="1020">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2021/064, 6/12/2021, eff. 11/1/2021) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26802" number="31577" version="1464">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> Former § 16-402 was repealed by L.L. 2021/064, 6/12/2021, eff. 11/1/2021. For related unconsolidated provisions of the former section, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2005/097" destination-id="0-0-0-25148">L.L. 2005/097</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-209296" number="31578" version="1464">
										<HEADING>§ 16-402 Restrictions on providing eating utensils, condiment packets, napkins and extra eating containers.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6323" name="16-402"/>§ 16-402 Restrictions on providing eating utensils, condiment packets, napkins and extra eating containers<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">.</CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26804" number="31579" version="1321">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> For purposes of this section: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202989" number="31580" version="1321">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Condiment packet.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;condiment packet&quot; means an individual single-service container, sealed by the manufacturer, containing a sauce or other substance used to enhance the flavor of food, which may include, but need not be limited to, mustard, ketchup, mayonnaise, soy sauce, hot sauce or salad dressing. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202988" number="31581" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eating container.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;eating container&quot; means a tool used for holding food or beverage, including but not limited to, a plate, bowl, cup, or lid, but does not include a beverage splash stick as defined in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-401" destination-id="0-0-0-6321">16-401</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202987" number="31582" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eating utensil.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;eating utensil&quot; means a tool used for eating and drinking, including, but not limited to, a knife, fork, spoon, or chopsticks, but does not include a beverage stirrer or beverage straw as defined in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-401" destination-id="0-0-0-6321">16-401</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202986" number="31583" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Extra eating container.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;extra eating container&quot; means an empty eating container that is not used to hold a customer&apos;s food or beverage. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202985" number="31584" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Food service establishment.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;food service establishment&quot; has the same meaning as set forth in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-401" destination-id="0-0-0-6321">16-401</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202984" number="31585" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Napkin.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;napkin&quot; means a piece of cloth or paper used to wipe a person&apos;s hands or face or protect garments while eating. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202983" number="31586" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Take-away.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;take-away&quot; means food or beverage provided by a food service establishment to be consumed off the premises of such food service establishment. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202982" number="31587" version="1321">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Third-party courier service.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;third-party courier service&quot; means a service that: (i) facilitates the same-day delivery or same-day pickup of food, beverages, or other goods from a food service establishment on behalf of such food service establishment or a third-party food delivery service; (ii) is owned and operated by a person other than the person who owns such food service establishment, and (iii) is not a third-party food delivery service. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202981" number="31588" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Third-party food delivery service.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;third-party food delivery service&quot; means any website, mobile application or other internet service that: (i) offers or arranges for the sale of food and beverages prepared by, and the same-day delivery or same-day pickup of food and beverages from, a food service establishment; and (ii) that is owned and operated by a person other than the person who owns such food service establishment. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202980" number="31589" version="1321">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No food service establishment shall provide eating utensils, condiment packets, napkins, or extra eating containers to a take-away customer, whether directly to such customer or through a third-party courier service or third-party food delivery service, unless such customer requests eating utensils, condiment packets, napkins, or extra eating containers. A food service establishment maintaining a self-service station at which such items are offered shall not be a violation of this subdivision. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202979" number="31590" version="1321">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Third-party food delivery services shall provide options to allow a customer to request eating utensils, condiment packets, napkins, and extra eating containers upon submission of an order, if such items are offered by the food service establishment fulfilling such order. Such options shall be prominently and conspicuously provided for all methods of ordering, including but not limited to phone, internet, or mobile phone application orders. The default selected option shall be that no eating utensils, condiment packets, napkins, or extra eating containers are requested. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202978" number="31591" version="1321">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No third-party courier service or third-party food delivery service shall provide eating utensils, condiment packets, napkins, or extra eating containers to a customer, unless such eating utensils, condiment packets, napkins, or extra eating containers are requested by such customer, or such eating utensils, condiment packets, napkins or extra eating containers are in the food or beverage packaged by the food service establishment for delivery when such third-party courier service or third-party food delivery service picks up such food or beverage. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202977" number="31592" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If a food service establishment fills an order placed through a third-party food delivery service, such food service establishment may rely on the information provided by such third-party food delivery service regarding whether the customer has requested eating utensils, condiment packets, napkins, or extra eating containers pursuant to paragraph 1 of this subdivision. In a proceeding to collect a civil penalty pursuant to subdivision f of this section, it shall be a complete defense for a respondent food service establishment to establish that such food service establishment relied on the information provided to it by the third-party food delivery service regarding the customer&apos;s choice pursuant to paragraph 1 of this subdivision. A copy or screenshot of a communication by the third-party food delivery service to the food service establishment regarding the customer&apos;s choice pursuant to paragraph 1 of this subdivision shall constitute prima facie evidence that the food service establishment relied on the information provided to it by the third-party food delivery service. Each third-party food delivery service shall provide such communication in writing to a food service establishment within 72 hours of such food service establishment&apos;s request for such communication. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202976" number="31593" version="1321">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department and the department of consumer and worker protection shall have the authority to enforce the provisions of this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202975" number="31594" version="1321">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In consultation with other city agencies, the department shall conduct outreach and education about the requirements of this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202974" number="31595" version="1321">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any food service establishment, third-party food delivery service, or third-party courier service that violates this section or any rule promulgated pursuant thereto shall be liable for a civil penalty recoverable in a civil action brought in the name of the commissioner or the commissioner of consumer and worker protection, or in a proceeding before the office of administrative trials and hearings pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="1049-a" destination-id="0-0-0-0">1049-a</LINK> of the charter, or in the case of a food service establishment within the jurisdiction of the commissioner of consumer and worker protection, in a proceeding before the office of administrative trials and hearings pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="1048" destination-id="0-0-0-0">1048</LINK> of the charter. Such penalties shall be in the amount of $50 for the first violation, $150 for the second violation committed on a different day within a period of 12 months, and $250 for the third and each subsequent violation committed on different days within a period of 12 months, except that any agency enforcing the provisions of this section shall not issue a notice of violation, but shall issue a warning and provide information on the provisions of this section, for any violation that occurs before July 1, 2024. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202973" number="31596" version="1321">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department, as part of the waste characterization study required pursuant to subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-316.1" destination-id="0-0-0-6291">16-316.1</LINK>, shall, where practicable, assess the amount of single-use items in the waste stream and the change in such amount from any previous studies. The department shall include such information in such study submitted to the council and the mayor. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202971" number="31597" version="1321">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2023/017, 2/1/2023, eff. 7/31/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-202970" number="31598" version="1464">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> Former § 16-402 was repealed by L.L. 2021/064, 6/12/2021, eff. 11/1/2021. For related unconsolidated provisions of the former section, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2005/097" destination-id="0-0-0-25148">L.L. 2005/097</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-135117" number="31599" version="2000">
										<HEADING>§ 16-403 Reusable beverage containers in sports venues.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6325" name="16-403"/>§ 16-403 Reusable beverage containers in sports venues<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">.</CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26812" number="31600" version="2000">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> For purposes of this section, the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227039" number="31601" version="2000">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Reusable beverage container.</CHARFORMAT> The term “reusable beverage container” means a drinking vessel that is composed primarily of aluminum or stainless steel, and is designed and manufactured to be capable of multiple reuses, including a bottle or cup. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227038" number="31602" version="2000">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Sports venue.</CHARFORMAT> The term “sports venue” means a building, structure, or place in which professional or collegiate sporting competitions are held. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227037" number="31603" version="2000">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A sports venue shall not prohibit an individual attending any professional or collegiate sporting competition in such sports venue from bringing a reusable beverage container into the sports venue, except as provided in this subdivision. A sports venue may require that reusable beverage containers be empty upon entering the sports venue. A sports venue may restrict reusable beverage containers capable of holding more than 24 fluid ounces. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227036" number="31604" version="2000">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any sports venue that violates this section or any rule promulgated pursuant thereto shall be liable for a civil penalty recoverable in a civil action brought in the name of the commissioner or in a proceeding before the office of administrative trials and hearings pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="1049-a" destination-id="0-0-0-0">1049-a</LINK> of the charter. Such penalties shall be in the amount of $500 for the first violation, $750 for the second violation committed on a different day within a period of 12 months, and $1,000 for the third and each subsequent violation committed on different days within a period of 12 months. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227034" number="31605" version="2000">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2024/035, 1/20/2024, eff. 5/19/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135118" number="31606" version="2000">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> Former § 16-403 was repealed by L.L. 2021/064, 6/12/2021, eff. 11/1/2021. For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2005/097" destination-id="0-0-0-25148">L.L. 2005/097</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-209292" number="31607" version="1464">
										<HEADING>§ 16-404 Rechargeable battery disposal ban. [Repealed]</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6327" name="16-404"/>§ 16-404 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rechargeable battery disposal ban. [Repealed]</CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26814" number="31608" version="1020">
											<PARA>(Repealed L.L. 2021/064, 6/12/2021, eff. 11/1/2021) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135119" number="31609" version="1464">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2005/097" destination-id="0-0-0-25148">L.L. 2005/097</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-209293" number="31610" version="1464">
										<HEADING>§ 16-405 Rechargeable battery recycling program. [Repealed]</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6329" name="16-405"/>§ 16-405 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rechargeable battery recycling program. [Repealed]</CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26826" number="31611" version="1020">
											<PARA>(Repealed L.L. 2021/064, 6/12/2021, eff. 11/1/2021) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135120" number="31612" version="1464">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2005/097" destination-id="0-0-0-25148">L.L. 2005/097</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-209294" number="31613" version="1464">
										<HEADING>§ 16-406 Penalties. [Repealed]</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6331" name="16-406"/>§ 16-406 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Penalties. [Repealed]</CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26830" number="31614" version="1020">
											<PARA>(Repealed L.L. 2021/064, 6/12/2021, eff. 11/1/2021) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135121" number="31615" version="1464">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2005/097" destination-id="0-0-0-25148">L.L. 2005/097</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>