<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-209295" number="31616" version="1464">
			<HEADING>Chapter 4-A: Electronic Equipment Collection, Recycling and Reuse</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6333" name="T16C004-A"/>Chapter 4-A: Electronic Equipment Collection, Recycling and Reuse</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-26831" number="31617" version="1429">
				<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
					<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
						<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/013" destination-id="0-0-0-24998">L.L. 2008/013</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-207387" number="31618" version="1429">
										<HEADING>§ 16-420 [Short title.] </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6335" name="16-420"/>§ 16-420 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">[Short title.] </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26832" number="31619" version="3">
											<PARA>This local law shall be known and may be cited as the &quot;Electronic Equipment Collection, Recycling and Reuse Act&quot;.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26833" number="31620" version="1429">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/013" destination-id="0-0-0-24998">L.L. 2008/013</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-207388" number="31621" version="1429">
										<HEADING>§ 16-421 Definitions. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6337" name="16-421"/>§ 16-421 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26834" number="31622" version="3">
											<PARA>As used in this chapter: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26835" number="31623" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Brand name&quot; means a manufacturer&apos;s name, brand designation, make or model name or number, or other nomenclature by which covered electronic equipment is offered for sale by a manufacturer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26836" number="31624" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Cathode ray tube&quot; means a vacuum tube or picture tube used to convert an electronic signal into a visual image.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26837" number="31625" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Computer&quot; means an electronic, magnetic, optical, electrochemical or other high-speed data processing device performing a logical, arithmetic or storage function, and may include both a computer central processing unit and a monitor; but such term shall not include an automated typewriter or typesetter, a portable hand-held calculator, a portable digital assistant, or other similar device.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26838" number="31626" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Covered electronic equipment&quot; means any computer central processing unit; cathode ray tube; cathode ray tube device; keyboard; electronic mouse or similar pointing device; television; printer; computer monitor, including but not limited to a liquid crystal display and plasma screens, or similar video display device that includes a screen that is greater than four inches measured diagonally and one or more circuit boards; a laptop or other portable computer; or a portable digital music player that has memory capability and is battery-powered. &quot;Covered electronic equipment&quot; does not include any automobile; mobile phone; household appliances such as clothes washers, clothes dryers, refrigerators, freezers, microwave ovens, ovens, ranges or dishwashers; equipment that is functionally or physically part of a larger piece of equipment intended for use in an industrial, research and development or commercial setting; security, anti-terrorism or medical equipment that utilizes a cathode ray tube, a cathode ray tube device or a flat panel display or similar video display device that is not separate from the larger piece of equipment; or any other device, as that term is defined in 21 U.S.C. § 321.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26839" number="31627" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Electronic recycler&quot; means a person who 1. refurbishes or otherwise processes covered electronic equipment for reuse or resale; or 2. removes, segregates or otherwise extracts components or commodities from covered electronic equipment, either by manual or mechanical separation or by changing such equipment&apos;s physical or chemical composition, for the purpose of reusing or recycling such components or commodities.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26840" number="31628" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Label&quot; means information, as required by this chapter, on the surface of covered electronic equipment, which must be permanently attached to, printed or engraved on or incorporated in any other permanent manner on such equipment, and obvious and visible to users of such equipment.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26841" number="31629" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Manufacturer&quot; means a person who: 1. assembles or substantially assembles, or has assembled or substantially assembled, covered electronic equipment for sale in the city; 2. manufactures or has manufactured covered electronic equipment under its own brand name or under any other brand name for sale in the city; 3. sells or has sold, under its own brand name, covered electronic equipment produced by another person for sale in the city; 4. owns a brand name that it licenses or has licensed to another person for use on covered electronic equipment sold in the city; 5. imports or has imported covered electronic equipment for sale in the city; or 6. manufactures or has manufactured covered electronic equipment for sale in the city without affixing a brand name.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26842" number="31630" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Monitor&quot; means a separate visual display component of a computer, whether sold separately or with a central processing unit and includes the cathode ray tube, liquid crystal display, or other image projection technology, and its case, interior wires and circuitry, all exterior and interior cables, and power cord.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26843" number="31631" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Orphan waste&quot; means covered electronic equipment, the manufacturer of which cannot be identified or is no longer in business and for which no successor-in-interest has been identified.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26844" number="31632" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>j.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Person&quot; means any individual, business entity, partnership, company, corporation, not-for-profit corporation, association, governmental entity, public benefit corporation, public authority, or firm.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26845" number="31633" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>k.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Recycle&quot; means to use the materials contained in covered electronic equipment or components thereof as raw materials for new products or components, but not for energy recovery or energy generation by means of combustion, gasification, pyrolysis or other means.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26846" number="31634" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>l.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Reuse&quot; means any operation by which covered electronic equipment or components thereof are used for the same purpose for which they were conceived.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26847" number="31635" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>m.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Sell&quot; or &quot;sale&quot; means any transfer for consideration, by lease or sales contract of title to or the right to use covered electronic equipment from a manufacturer or retailer to any person, including, but not limited to, transactions conducted through retail sales outlets, catalogs, or the internet; &quot;sell&quot; or &quot;sale&quot; includes transfer of new, used or refurbished covered electronic equipment, but does not include transfers between end users of such equipment.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26848" number="31636" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>n.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Television&quot; means a display system containing a cathode ray tube or any other type of display primarily intended to receive broadcast video programming, having a viewable area greater than four inches when measured diagonally.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26849" number="31637" version="1429">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/013" destination-id="0-0-0-24998">L.L. 2008/013</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-207389" number="31638" version="1429">
										<HEADING>§ 16-422 Responsibility of manufacturer collection. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6339" name="16-422"/>§ 16-422 Responsibility of manufacturer collection<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26850" number="31639" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning July first, two thousand nine or one hundred eighty days after a manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan is approved by the department, whichever date is later, such manufacturer must accept for collection, handling and recycling or reuse covered electronic equipment that is offered for return by any person in the city, and has been assembled, manufactured, or imported by such manufacturer, or has been sold under such manufacturer&apos;s brand name.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26851" number="31640" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning July first, two thousand nine or one hundred eighty days after a manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan is approved by the department, whichever date is later, such manufacturer must accept for collection, handling and recycling or reuse on a one-to-one basis with the purchase of the same type of covered electronic equipment other than orphan waste that is offered for return by any person in the city, and has been assembled, manufactured or imported by persons other than such manufacturer, or has been sold under the brand name of a person other than such manufacturer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26852" number="31641" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning July first, two thousand nine or one hundred eighty days after a manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan is approved by the department, whichever date is later, and ending on June thirtieth, two thousand eleven, such manufacturer must accept for collection, handling, and recycling or reuse orphan waste that is offered for return by any person in the city on a one-to-one basis with the purchase of the same type of product by such person.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26853" number="31642" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning July first, two thousand eleven, each manufacturer must accept for collection, handling, and recycling or reuse orphan waste of the same type sold by such manufacturer in the city that is offered for return by any person in the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26854" number="31643" version="1429">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/013" destination-id="0-0-0-24998">L.L. 2008/013</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-207390" number="31644" version="1429">
										<HEADING>§ 16-423 Manufacturer electronic waste management plan. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6341" name="16-423"/>§ 16-423 Manufacturer electronic waste management plan<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26855" number="31645" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than September first, two thousand eight, a manufacturer shall submit to the department an electronic waste management plan for the collection, handling, and recycling or reuse of covered electronic equipment and orphan waste. Any person who becomes a manufacturer on or after September first, two thousand eight shall submit to the department an electronic waste management plan for the collection, handling, and recycling or reuse of covered electronic equipment and orphan waste prior to selling any covered electronic equipment in the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26856" number="31646" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A manufacturer&apos;s submission of an electronic waste management plan pursuant to subdivision a of this section shall be accompanied by a fee of one thousand five hundred dollars. A manufacturer&apos;s submission of an annual report pursuant to subdivision a of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-428" destination-id="0-0-0-6343">16-428</LINK> of this chapter shall be accompanied by a fee of one thousand two hundred fifty dollars. Any manufacturer who submits such plan or report without the requisite fee shall be deemed not to have submitted such plan or report and shall be subject to the penalties set forth in paragraph one of subdivision d of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-427" destination-id="0-0-0-6345">16-427</LINK> of this chapter for failure to submit such plan or report.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26857" number="31647" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The manufacturer shall not impose a fee or other charge on any person for the collection, handling, and recycling or reuse of covered electronic equipment or orphan waste, except that a fee or other charge may be imposed by contractual agreement between a manufacturer and a business entity, partnership, company, corporation or firm having more than fifty full time employees other than a not-for-profit corporation as defined in subparagraph five or seven of subdivision a of section one hundred two of the New York not-for-profit corporation law, association, governmental entity, public benefit corporation or public authority.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26858" number="31648" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>An electronic waste management plan shall include, at a minimum:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26859" number="31649" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>details for the collection, handling, and recycling or reuse of covered electronic equipment and orphan waste as required by this chapter, including but not limited to the methods by which a person can return to the manufacturer such covered electronic equipment and orphan waste. Such methods shall be convenient for residents of the city;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26860" number="31650" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>how the manufacturer will inform residents and businesses of the city about the manufacturer&apos;s plan for the collection, handling, and recycling or reuse of covered electronic equipment and orphan waste, which shall include an internet website and a toll-free telephone number;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26861" number="31651" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>information on the manufacturer&apos;s plan for the disposition of covered electronic equipment and orphan waste, including any plan for the recycling or reuse of such covered electronic equipment and orphan waste. If the manufacturer provides a plan for the recycling or reuse of covered electronic equipment and orphan waste, the manufacturer shall include details about anticipated end markets and electronic recyclers expected to be utilized by the manufacturer, including but not limited to details on the methods of collection, handling and recycling or reuse of covered electronic equipment used by such electronic recyclers, details on any disassembly or physical recovery operation to be used by such electronic recyclers, the locations of any such operations, and details on the manufacturer&apos;s compliance with applicable laws and regulations relating to the disposition, recycling or reuse of covered electronic equipment;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26862" number="31652" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>a description of how the manufacturer will plan to attain the performance standards established in paragraph a of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-424" destination-id="0-0-0-6347">16-424</LINK> of this chapter;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26863" number="31653" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>annual city sales data of the manufacturer&apos;s covered electronic equipment for the previous three calendar years;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26864" number="31654" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>the method to be used to destroy all data in any covered electronic equipment and orphan waste collected, either through physical destruction of the data storage components thereof or through data wiping meeting or exceeding United States Department of Defense standard 5220.22M;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26865" number="31655" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>a list of the manufacturer&apos;s brand names, including: (i) any brand name under which the manufacturer assembles or substantially assembles, or has assembled or substantially assembled covered electronic equipment; (ii) any brand name under which the manufacturer manufactures and sells, or has manufactured and sold, covered electronic equipment; (iii) any brand name under which the manufacturer sells or has sold covered electronic equipment produced by another person under such manufacturer&apos;s own brand; (iv) any brand name that the manufacturer owns and licenses or has licensed to another person for use on covered electronic equipment; (v) any brand name under which the manufacturer imports or has imported covered electronic equipment for sale in the city; and (vi) any brand name of covered electronic equipment of which the manufacturer has become the successor-in-interest;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26866" number="31656" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>a certification that the manufacturer&apos;s collection, handling, and recycling or reuse of covered electronic equipment complies with all local, state, federal and international laws and regulations; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26867" number="31657" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>any other information as may be required by department rules.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26868" number="31658" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall approve or disapprove a proposed electronic waste management plan submitted by a manufacturer within one hundred eighty days of its submission. The department may approve a submitted electronic waste management plan that does not conform with every one of the requirements of this chapter upon application and a showing of good cause by such manufacturer. If the department approves an electronic waste management plan, it shall expeditiously notify the manufacturer of the approval in writing. If the department disapproves an electronic waste management plan, it shall expeditiously notify the manufacturer in writing of the disapproval and specify the reasons for such disapproval. The manufacturer shall have thirty days to resubmit a revised electronic waste management plan after the department notifies the manufacturer of its disapproval. The department shall approve or disapprove a resubmitted electronic waste management plan within ninety days of resubmission.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26869" number="31659" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning on July first, two thousand nine, or one hundred eighty days after an electronic waste management plan is approved by the department, whichever date is later, a manufacturer of covered electronic equipment shall implement its approved plan for the collection, handling and recycling or reuse of covered electronic equipment and orphan waste.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26870" number="31660" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>An electronic waste management plan may provide for the sharing of resources by one or more manufacturers, provided that such plan meets the requirements of this section. Any electronic waste management plan providing for the sharing of resources must include a list of manufacturers participating in such plan.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26871" number="31661" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Proposed modifications to a previously approved manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan shall be submitted to the department which shall approve or disapprove such modification within sixty days and expeditiously notify the manufacturer of its determination in writing. If the department disapproves such modification, it shall specify the reasons for such disapproval in writing and the manufacturer shall have thirty days to submit a revised modification to the department.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26872" number="31662" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>At any time, the department may require submission of a proposed modification where it determines that the manufacturer is not in compliance with the collection standards as set forth in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-424" destination-id="0-0-0-6347">16-424</LINK> of this chapter. The department shall approve or disapprove such modification in accordance with paragraph one of this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26873" number="31663" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the provisions of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-423" destination-id="0-0-0-6341">16-423</LINK> of this chapter, any person who becomes a manufacturer of covered electronic equipment subsequent to the effective date of this section may include within a submitted electronic waste management plan a proposed schedule for compliance with the minimum collection standards set forth in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-424" destination-id="0-0-0-6347">16-424</LINK> beyond the respective compliance dates set forth in such section. The commissioner may approve such proposed schedule or may approve a modification to such proposed schedule that provides for a reasonable compliance time beyond that provided for in such section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26874" number="31664" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>j.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All decisions of the department pursuant to this section shall be made public.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26875" number="31665" version="1429">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/013" destination-id="0-0-0-24998">L.L. 2008/013</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/021" destination-id="0-0-0-24992">L.L. 2008/021</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-207341" number="31666" version="1428">
										<HEADING>§ 16-424 Performance standards. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6347" name="16-424"/>§ 16-424 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Performance standards. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26876" number="31667" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A manufacturer shall demonstrate whether, pursuant to its electronic waste management plan, it is collecting for recycling or reuse at least its share of covered electronic equipment. Such manufacturer&apos;s share of covered electronic equipment is determined by applying the following minimum collection standard percentage by the average annual sales of the manufacturer&apos;s covered electronic equipment in the city, reported by weight, during the previous three calendar years; by July 1, 2012, the minimum collection standard is twenty-five percent; by July 1, 2015, the minimum collection standard is forty-five percent; by July 1, 2018, the minimum collection standard is sixty-five percent.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26877" number="31668" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of calculating achievement of the minimum collection standard specified in paragraph a of this subdivision, a manufacturer may count the collection of a single item of covered electronic equipment as twice its weight when that item is donated free of charge for reuse to the New York city department of education, or to any not-for-profit corporation, as defined in subparagraphs five or seven of subdivision a of section one hundred two of the New York not-for-profit corporation law, a principal mission of which is to assist low-income children or families living in city. To qualify for the donation reuse credit under this subdivision, the covered electronic equipment must be: (a) no older than three years old, (b) in full working condition, and (c) accepted as a donation by the recipient in writing.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26878" number="31669" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner may grant an annual waiver, in whole or in part, from the minimum collection standards set forth in subdivision a of this section where a manufacturer who has an approved electronic waste management plan has demonstrated to the commissioner&apos;s satisfaction that such minimum collection standards could not be met despite the best efforts of the manufacturer because the manufacturer has substantially increased the amount of covered electronic equipment sold within the city over the three-year period during which compliance with subdivision a of this section is to be measured and it was not practicable to meet the applicable minimum collection standard.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26879" number="31670" version="1429">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/013" destination-id="0-0-0-24998">L.L. 2008/013</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/021" destination-id="0-0-0-24992">L.L. 2008/021</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-207339" number="31671" version="1428">
										<HEADING>§ 16-425 Labeling. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6349" name="16-425"/>§ 16-425 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Labeling. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26880" number="31672" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning July first, two thousand nine or one hundred eighty days after a manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan is approved by the department, whichever date is later, such manufacturer may not sell or otherwise distribute for sale in the city covered electronic equipment unless such equipment has a label that identifies such manufacturer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26881" number="31673" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning July first, two thousand nine or one hundred eighty days after a manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan is approved by the department, whichever date is later, such manufacturer shall provide at the point of sale information on how a person can return covered electronic equipment pursuant to such manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan. Such information shall include a toll-free telephone number or internet website address describing how covered electronic equipment can be returned pursuant to the manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26882" number="31674" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning July first, two thousand nine, the department shall post on its web site all information provided to it from manufacturers describing how covered electronic equipment can be returned pursuant to a specific manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26883" number="31675" version="1429">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/013" destination-id="0-0-0-24998">L.L. 2008/013</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-207391" number="31676" version="1429">
										<HEADING>§ 16-426 Disposal ban. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6351" name="16-426"/>§ 16-426 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Disposal ban. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26884" number="31677" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning July first, two thousand ten, no person shall dispose of covered electronic equipment as solid waste in the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26885" number="31678" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning July first, two thousand nine, no manufacturer shall dispose of covered electronic equipment as solid waste in the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26886" number="31679" version="1429">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/013" destination-id="0-0-0-24998">L.L. 2008/013</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-207392" number="31680" version="1429">
										<HEADING>§ 16-427 Enforcement. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6345" name="16-427"/>§ 16-427 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Enforcement. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26887" number="31681" version="414">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department and the department of consumer and worker protection shall have the authority to enforce the provisions of this chapter. Any notice of violation charging a violation of any provision of this chapter shall be returnable to the environmental control board, which shall have the power to impose civil penalties as provided herein. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-052]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26888" number="31682" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who violates the provisions of subdivision a of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-426" destination-id="0-0-0-6351">16-426</LINK> of this chapter shall be liable for a civil penalty of one hundred dollars for each violation.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26889" number="31683" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any manufacturer who violates the provisions of subdivision b of section of 16-426 of this chapter shall be liable for a civil penalty of one thousand dollars for each violation.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26890" number="31684" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning September first, two thousand eight, a manufacturer who fails to submit an electronic waste management plan or an annual report as required by this chapter shall be liable for a civil penalty of one thousand dollars per day for each day that an electronic waste management plan or an annual report is not submitted.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26891" number="31685" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning September first, two thousand eight, a manufacturer who submits an electronic waste management plan that has been disapproved by the department more than two times shall be liable for a civil penalty of one thousand dollars per day for each day that an electronic waste management plan is not submitted and approved by the department following the date of such second disapproval.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26892" number="31686" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning July first, two thousand nine, a manufacturer who knowingly submits an annual report as required by this chapter that contains a false or misleading statement as to a material fact or omits to state any material fact necessary in order to make a statement therein not false or misleading shall be liable for a civil penalty of ten thousand dollars.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26893" number="31687" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning July first, two thousand nine, or one hundred eighty days after a manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan is approved by the department, whichever date is later, a manufacturer who fails to accept covered electronic equipment or orphan waste offered for return by any person in the city pursuant to such manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan shall be liable for a civil penalty of two thousand dollars for each piece of covered electronic equipment or orphan waste not accepted.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26894" number="31688" version="414">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning July first, two thousand twelve, a manufacturer who has not met the performance standards set forth in subdivision a of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-424" destination-id="0-0-0-6347">16-424</LINK> of this chapter shall be liable for a civil penalty of fifty thousand dollars for each percentage point that said manufacturer falls below the performance standards, and shall also submit a modified electronic waste management plan to the department with details explaining how said manufacturer intends to comply with the performance standards. The department shall review such modified electronic waste management plan as provided in subdivision h of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-423" destination-id="0-0-0-6341">16-423</LINK> of this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-124457" number="31689" version="706">
											<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2020/080, 8/28/2020, eff. 8/28/2020) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-052]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26895" number="31690" version="2278">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/013" destination-id="0-0-0-24998">L.L. 2008/013</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/021" destination-id="0-0-0-24992">L.L. 2008/021</LINK>, and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2020/080" destination-id="0-0-0-20343">L.L. 2020/080</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-128139" number="31691" version="805">
										<HEADING>§ 16-428 Reporting requirements. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6343" name="16-428"/>§ 16-428 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Reporting requirements. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-222907" number="31692" version="1869">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>On or before July first, two thousand nine, and annually on or before July first thereafter, a manufacturer that offers any covered electronic equipment for sale in the city shall submit an annual report to the department that includes the following information for the prior calendar year: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26897" number="31693" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>any approved modification to the manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26898" number="31694" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>sales data for the manufacturer&apos;s covered electronic equipment sold in the city; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26899" number="31695" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>the quantity of covered electronic equipment collected for recycling or reuse in this city, expressed both in terms of the total weight of such covered electronic equipment and as a percentage of the average annual sales of the manufacturer&apos;s covered electronic equipment in the city, reported by weight, during the previous three calendar years, and categorized by the type of covered electronic equipment collected pursuant to such manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan, and further categorized, to the extent possible, by the quantity of such covered electronic equipment collected from individuals and government entities; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26900" number="31696" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>the weight of orphan waste collected, categorized by the type of covered electronic equipment collected, pursuant to such manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26901" number="31697" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>information on the manufacturer&apos;s compliance with the performance standards established in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-424" destination-id="0-0-0-6347">16-424</LINK> of this chapter; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26902" number="31698" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>information on the end markets and electronic recyclers utilized by the manufacturer, including details on the methods of collection, handling and recycling or reuse of covered electronic equipment used by electronic recyclers, details on any disassembly or physical recovery operation to be used, the locations of any such operations, and details on the manufacturer&apos;s compliance with applicable laws and regulations relating to the disposition, recycling and reuse of covered electronic equipment and orphan waste; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26903" number="31699" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>examples of how the manufacturer has informed residents and businesses of the city about the manufacturer&apos;s plan for the collection, handling and recycling or reuse of covered electronic equipment and orphan waste; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26904" number="31700" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of visits to the internet website and calls to the toll-free telephone numbers established by the manufacturer&apos;s electronic waste management plan; and </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26905" number="31701" version="1871">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>any other information required by department rules. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-086]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26907" number="31702" version="1869">
											<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2023/069, 5/29/2023, eff. 6/28/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-086]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-224846" number="31703" version="1869">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/013" destination-id="0-0-0-24998">L.L. 2008/013</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/021" destination-id="0-0-0-24992">L.L. 2008/021</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-207340" number="31704" version="1428">
										<HEADING>§ 16-429 Confidential information and trade secrets. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6353" name="16-429"/>§ 16-429 Confidential information and trade secrets<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26908" number="31705" version="3">
											<PARA>Information relating to covered electronic equipment submitted to the department pursuant to this chapter may be designated by the department as confidential upon a showing of good cause by the person submitting it. Except as otherwise provided by or pursuant to law or court order, such information may be used only by the department, its agents and employees, other city agencies, and as authorized by the mayor, employees of the United States Environmental Protection Agency or the attorney general of the state of New York.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26909" number="31706" version="1429">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/013" destination-id="0-0-0-24998">L.L. 2008/013</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-207393" number="31707" version="1429">
										<HEADING>§ 16-430 Application by the department of collected covered electronic equipment toward recycling goals. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6355" name="16-430"/>§ 16-430 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application by the department of collected covered electronic equipment toward recycling goals. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26910" number="31708" version="3">
											<PARA>The department shall be allowed to apply the amount of covered electronic equipment and orphan waste collected by manufacturers pursuant to this chapter towards achieving its recycling goals.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26911" number="31709" version="1429">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/013" destination-id="0-0-0-24998">L.L. 2008/013</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-207394" number="31710" version="1429">
										<HEADING>§ 16-431 Severability. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6357" name="16-431"/>§ 16-431 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Severability. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26912" number="31711" version="3">
											<PARA>The provisions of this chapter shall be severable, and if any provision of this chapter is declared to be void or invalid by a court of competent jurisdiction, the remaining provisions shall not be affected, and shall remain in full force and effect.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26913" number="31712" version="1429">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/013" destination-id="0-0-0-24998">L.L. 2008/013</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-207395" number="31713" version="1429">
										<HEADING>§ 16-432 Rulemaking authority. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6359" name="16-432"/>§ 16-432 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rulemaking authority. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26914" number="31714" version="3">
											<PARA>The department shall be authorized to promulgate rules as necessary to implement the provisions of this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-26915" number="31715" version="1429">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/013" destination-id="0-0-0-24998">L.L. 2008/013</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>