<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-130900" number="2314" version="803">
			<HEADING>Chapter 8: Transition and Inaugural Donations and Expenditures</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1133" name="T03C008"/>Chapter 8: Transition and Inaugural Donations and Expenditures</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-1608" number="2315" version="1540">
				<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
					<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1998/039" destination-id="0-0-0-25800">L.L. 1998/039</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-214610" number="2316" version="1540">
										<HEADING>§ 3-801 Transition and inauguration donations and expenses. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1155" name="3-801"/>§ 3-801 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Transition and inauguration donations and expenses. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1609" number="2317" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Candidates elected to the office of mayor, public advocate, comptroller, borough president, or member of the city council may authorize one or more entities, other than a political committee, for the purpose of accepting donations and loans, and for making expenditures, for transition or inauguration into office. Such donations and loans may not be accepted and such expenditures may not be made on behalf of the candidate prior to the registration with the campaign finance board of each such entity. The campaign finance board shall promulgate rules to establish the time and manner for such registration. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1610" number="2318" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Candidates elected to the office of mayor, public advocate, comptroller, borough president, or member of the city council, and the entities they authorize pursuant to subdivision one of this section, shall:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1611" number="2319" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>not use funds accepted by a political committee authorized by the candidate for any election to make expenditures for transition or inauguration into office, and shall not transfer funds from a political committee to an entity the candidate is required to register pursuant to subdivision one of this section;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1612" number="2320" version="146">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>not accept any donation or donations of money, goods, or services from any individual other than the candidate, political committee, employee organization, or entity which in the aggregate exceeds the limit for a non-participating candidate for the applicable office contained in paragraph (f) of subdivision one of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="3-703" destination-id="0-0-0-1107">3-703</LINK>, as adjusted pursuant to subdivision seven of such section as applicable. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-039]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1613" number="2321" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>not incur any liabilities after January thirty-first in the year following the election, nor accept any donations after all liabilities are paid; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1614" number="2322" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>not accept any donation or donations of money, goods, or services from any corporation, limited liability company, limited liability partnership or partnership not permitted to contribute pursuant to paragraph (l) of subdivision 1 of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="3-703" destination-id="0-0-0-1107">3-703</LINK> or from any person whose name appears in the doing business database as of the date of such donation; provided, however, that this limitation on donations shall not apply to any donation to a transition or inauguration entity authorized pursuant to subdivision one of this section made by a natural person who has business dealings with the city where such donation is from the candidate-elect or from the candidate-elect&apos;s parent, spouse, domestic partner, sibling, child, grandchild, aunt, uncle, cousin, niece or nephew by blood or by marriage.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1615" number="2323" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Donations that do not exceed the limitations set forth in paragraph (b) of subdivision 2 of this section may be accepted only from political committees that register with the campaign finance board, as shall be provided for in rules issued by such board. Any donation accepted from a political committee that has not registered with the board prior to making the donation must be returned to the political committee. However, a subsequent donation may be accepted if such political committee registers with the board in accordance with the rules issued by the board.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1616" number="2324" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To the extent not repaid by the date of the candidate&apos;s inauguration into office, a loan received by such entity shall be deemed a donation subject to the limits and restrictions set forth in paragraph (b) of subdivision 2 and subdivision 3 of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1617" number="2325" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each transition and inauguration entity authorized pursuant to subdivision one of this section shall report to the campaign finance board every donation of money, goods, or services, and every loan, it receives, the full name, residential address, occupation, employer, and business address of each individual, corporation, partnership, political committee, employee organization or other entity making or serving as the intermediary for such donation or loan, and every expenditure it makes.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1618" number="2326" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Donations aggregating not more than ninety-nine dollars from any one donor need not be separately itemized in disclosure reports submitted to the campaign finance board. The treasurer of such entity need not collect or disclose the occupation, employer, or business address of any donor making donations aggregating not more than ninety-nine dollars.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1619" number="2327" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Disclosure reports shall be submitted at such times and in such form as the campaign finance board shall require and shall be clearly legible. The campaign finance board shall make available to the public a copy of these disclosure reports within two business days after they are accepted by the campaign finance board.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1620" number="2328" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The final disclosure report submitted by such entity shall set forth the disposition of any funds remaining after all liabilities are paid, after which the entity shall be terminated. If an entity has funds remaining after all liabilities have been paid, it shall return those funds to one or more of the entity&apos;s donors, or if that is impracticable, to the New York city election campaign finance fund.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1621" number="2329" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Entities required to be registered pursuant to subdivision one of this section shall not incur liabilities for purposes other than transition or inauguration into office.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1622" number="2330" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section shall apply to every candidate elected to the office of mayor, public advocate, comptroller, borough president, or member of the city council, regardless whether such candidate filed a written certification pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="3-703" destination-id="0-0-0-1107">3-703</LINK> of this code.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1623" number="2331" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of this chapter, the terms &quot;intermediary&quot; and &quot;political committee&quot; shall have such meanings as are set forth in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="3-702" destination-id="0-0-0-967">3-702</LINK> of this code.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1624" number="2332" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>10.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any restriction in this section, a candidate may self-fund his or her own entity. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1626" number="2333" version="702">
											<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2016/166, 12/22/2016, eff. 12/22/2016; Am. L.L. 2019/128, 7/14/2019, eff. 7/14/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-039]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112905" number="2334" version="2278">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1998/039" destination-id="0-0-0-25800">L.L. 1998/039</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2004/058" destination-id="0-0-0-25252">L.L. 2004/058</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2007/034" destination-id="0-0-0-25028">L.L. 2007/034</LINK>, and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2007/067" destination-id="0-0-0-25010">L.L. 2007/067</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-207550" number="2335" version="1433">
										<HEADING>§ 3-802 Penalties. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1157" name="3-802"/>§ 3-802 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Penalties. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1627" number="2336" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any candidate whose transition or inauguration entity fails to file in a timely manner a statement or record required to be filed by this chapter or the rules of the board in implementation thereof or who violates any other provisions of the chapter or rules promulgated thereunder, and any transition or inauguration entity treasurer or any other agent of the candidate who commits such a violation, shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount not in excess of ten thousand dollars. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1628" number="2337" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to the penalties provided in subdivision one of this section, if the amount of a donation to the candidate&apos;s transition or inauguration entity exceeds the limitations contained in this chapter such candidate, such entity shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed three times the sum by which such donation exceeds the applicable donation limitation.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1629" number="2338" version="1759">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The intentional or knowing furnishing of any false or fictitious evidence, books, or information to the board under this chapter, or the inclusion of any evidence, books, or information so furnished of a misrepresentation of a material fact, or the intentional or knowing violation of any other provision of this chapter shall be punishable as a class A misdemeanor in addition to any other penalty as may be provided under law. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1630" number="2339" version="1540">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1998/039" destination-id="0-0-0-25800">L.L. 1998/039</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>