<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-24775" number="28691" version="802">
			<HEADING>Chapter 6: Investment by Pension Funds or Retirement Systems</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5747" name="T13C006"/>Chapter 6: Investment by Pension Funds or Retirement Systems</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-24776" number="28692" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 13-701 Investments by pension funds or retirement systems maintained, administered or supported by the city or an agency, in notes or bonds secured by certain purchase money mortgages. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5749" name="13-701"/>§ 13-701 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Investments by pension funds or retirement systems maintained, administered or supported by the city or an agency, in notes or bonds secured by certain purchase money mortgages. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24777" number="28693" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The trustee or trustees of a pension fund or retirement system maintained, administered or supported by the city or an agency or by city funds may invest the funds of such pension fund or retirement system in any notes or bonds secured by purchase money mortgages accepted by the city at the time of the sale of real property acquired by virtue of tax enforcement foreclosure proceedings or by deed in lieu thereof, and any other notes or bonds secured by purchase money mortgages accepted by the city, provided however, no such other note or bond may be purchased by said trustee or trustees at a price in excess of two-thirds of the selling price of the real property secured by such purchase money mortgage at the time of its execution in connection with a sale resulting from a public auction of such real property, without regard to any limitations or restrictions contained in this code or in the provisions of article four-a of the retirement and social security law or section two hundred thirty-five of the banking law or any other law and in addition to the powers conferred by any such law. The aggregate unpaid principal amount of bonds and notes secured by such mortgages held at any time in such a fund or system shall not exceed two per centum of the assets of such fund or system. Any assignment of such a note or bond and mortgage to a pension fund or retirement system pursuant to this section shall contain a provision that if property which is collateral security for such bond or note and mortgage shall be acquired by the City of New York as a result of a foreclosure in rem proceeding and/or if a deficiency judgment is obtained by such fund or system by reason of a default under the terms of the note or bond and mortgage, the city will reimburse such fund or system by payment to said pension fund or retirement system of the amounts due under such note or bond and mortgage, including principal, interest, and any costs and expenses involved in obtaining such deficiency judgment by appropriation in the annual expense budget, provided that (1) the trustee or trustees of such pension fund or retirement system shall certify and include the amounts due, including principal, interest, and any costs and expenses, in the annual estimate of the requirements of such fund or system submitted to the director of the budget pursuant to charter section one hundred fourteen; and (2) upon the effective date of the budget containing the appropriation for such amounts due as specified herein, the trustee or trustees of such fund or system shall assign any deficiency judgment thus obtained to the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24778" number="28694" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to affect any lawful investment made prior to the effective date of this section by the trustee or trustees of any such fund or system, and any such investment may be retained or disposed of by such trustee or trustees in accordance with any other provision of law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24779" number="28695" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other provision in this section, or any other law, a pension fund or retirement system in connection with any note or bond and mortgage heretofore or hereafter acquired by it pursuant to this section may, where there has occurred or shall occur a default under the terms of any such note or bond and mortgage, for a period of one year, tender an assignment of such note or bond or mortgage to the city of New York. The city shall accept the same and pay said pension fund or retirement system the amounts due under such note or bond and mortgage including principal, interest and any costs involved in effectuating such assignment. A bond or note and mortgage assigned by the city of New York to a pension fund or retirement system shall be subject to the provisions of this subdivision c and in the future any such assignment shall contain a clause to such effect. The provisions of this section shall only relate to and be binding between the city of New York and the said pension fund or retirement system and shall not inure to the benefit of any other person, party or entity.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24780" number="28696" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to the provisions and remedies set forth in subdivisions a, b and c of this section, a pension fund or retirement system may tender to the city of New York a deed of title to property to which it had acquired title and which had been subject to a vote or bond and mortgage which had been assigned to it pursuant to the aforesaid subdivisions. The said city shall accept the deed and pay to the pension fund or retirement system as consideration therefor, the principal that was due under such note or bond and mortgage with interest thereon from the due date of the principal to the date of delivery of the deed to the city, together with any costs and expenditures incurred by the said pension fund or retirement system in acquiring the title and conveying it to said city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24781" number="28697" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The intent of this section is to reimburse and make whole the pension funds or retirement systems against any loss incurred by reason of the investments in the purchase money mortgages as described in this section. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-24782" number="28698" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 13-702 Delegation of investing powers to comptroller. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5751" name="13-702"/>§ 13-702 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Delegation of investing powers to comptroller. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24783" number="28699" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any provisions of the code or any other law to the contrary, the trustee, trustees, or other officer, board or body having the power to invest the funds of a pension fund or retirement system maintained, administered, or supported by the city or an agency, or by city funds may delegate such power either in its entirety or with any limitations including limitations with respect to the type and amount of investments, to the comptroller. Such delegation shall be in writing, and shall be filed in the office of such trustee, trustees, officer, board or body making such delegation, and in the office of the comptroller. Every such delegation shall be effective for a period specified therein, not to exceed one year, and shall automatically terminate and expire at the end of such specific period. Renewals or new delegations may be granted for additional periods in the same manner as herein provided for original delegations, but each such renewal or new delegation shall be effective for a specified period, not to exceed one year. Upon the filing of such delegation or renewal thereof as herein prescribed the comptroller shall, subject to the terms of such delegation, have the power:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24784" number="28700" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To make any investment which the trustee, trustees, officer, board or body delegating such power is or are authorized by law to make;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24785" number="28701" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To hold, sell, assign, transfer or dispose of any of the properties, securities or investments in which any of the funds of said fund or system shall have been invested, including the proceeds of such investments and any moneys belonging to such funds, subject to the terms, conditions, limitations and restrictions imposed by law upon such trustee, trustees, officer, board or body delegating such power; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24786" number="28702" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In his or her name as agent of such trustee, trustees, officer, board or body making such delegation and of such fund or system, to foreclose mortgages upon default or to take title to real property in such proceedings in lieu thereof or to lease and sell such property so acquired.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24787" number="28703" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The comptroller shall exercise any power delegated pursuant to this section until the expiration date specified in such delegation or any renewal thereof unless the trustee, trustees, officer, board, or body making such delegation shall sooner elect to reassume such power by filing a written revocation of the delegation in the office of such trustee, trustees, officer, board or body and in the office of the comptroller.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24788" number="28704" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the termination, expiration or revocation of any delegation of power or renewal thereof, as herein provided, shall not affect any binding commitment previously made by the comptroller pursuant to such delegation and the comptroller shall have the power to fully discharge any such binding commitment according to its terms. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-24789" number="28705" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 13-703 Investments in railroad, industrial, electric and gas, telephone and waterworks obligations. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5753" name="13-703"/>§ 13-703 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Investments in railroad, industrial, electric and gas, telephone and waterworks obligations. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24790" number="28706" version="3">
											<PARA>Notwithstanding the provisions of the code or any other law to the contrary, the trustee, trustees or other officer, board or body having the power to invest the funds of a pension fund or retirement system maintained, administered, or supported by the city or an agency, or by city funds, may, in addition, invest in obligations consisting of notes, bonds, debentures or equipment trust certificates issued under an indenture which are the direct obligations of, or in the case of equipment trust certificates, are secured by the direct obligations of, a railroad or industrial corporation, or a corporation engaged directly and primarily in the production, transportation, distribution or sale of electricity or gas, or the operation of telephone or telegraph systems or waterworks, or in some combination of them; provided the obligor corporation is one which is incorporated under the laws of the United States, or any state thereof, of the District of Columbia, and said obligations shall be rated at the time of purchase within the three highest classifications established by at least two standard rating services. The maximum amount that they may invest in such obligations pursuant to this subdivision shall not exceed ten per centum of the assets of a fund; and provided further that of said ten per centum not more than two per centum of the assets of a fund shall be invested in the obligations of any one corporation of the highest classification and subsidiary or subsidiaries thereof, that not more than one and one-half per centum of the assets of a fund shall be invested in the obligations of any one corporation of the second highest classification and subsidiary or subsidiaries thereof, that not more than one per centum of the assets of a fund shall be invested in the obligations of any one corporation of the third highest classification and subsidiary or subsidiaries thereof.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-24791" number="28707" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 13-704 Graduated crediting of gains and amortization of losses on dispositions of securities by certain retirement systems. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4813" name="13-704"/>§ 13-704 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Graduated crediting of gains and amortization of losses on dispositions of securities by certain retirement systems. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24792" number="28708" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>As used in this section, the following terms shall mean and include:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24793" number="28709" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Retirement system&quot;. Any of the following: the New York city employees&apos; retirement system; the teachers&apos; retirement system; the police pension fund provided for by subchapter two of chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T13C002" destination-id="0-0-0-4747">two</LINK> of this title; the fire department pension fund provided for by subchapter two of chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T13C003" destination-id="0-0-0-4865">three</LINK> of this title; and the board of education retirement system of the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24794" number="28710" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Teachers&apos; retirement system&quot;. The retirement system of the teachers&apos; retirement association provided for by chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T13C004" destination-id="0-0-0-5377">four</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24795" number="28711" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Contingent reserve fund&quot;. The contingent reserve fund of a retirement system; provided, however, that such term, where used in relation to public employer contributions payable to the fire department pension fund subchapter two during any period preceding the starting date of the improved benefits plan, as defined in subdivision twenty-seven of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="13-313" destination-id="0-0-0-5179">13-313</LINK> of this title, shall mean the retirement allowance accumulation fund provided for by section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="13-325" destination-id="0-0-0-5205">13-325</LINK> of this title, as in effect before such starting date.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24796" number="28712" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Responsible public employer&quot;. The city and in any case where the state or any public authority, corporation, body corporate or entity is required by any provision of this title or any other law to make contributions to a retirement system on behalf of any members thereof, such term, as applicable to such retirement system, shall mean, collectively, the city, the state and each such authority, corporation, body corporate and entity; subject, however, to the mutual rights, obligations and responsibilities in relation to such retirement system, as prescribed by law, of the city, the state and such authority, corporation, body corporate or entity.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24797" number="28713" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Retirement system act&quot;.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24798" number="28714" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of the New York city employees&apos; retirement system, such term shall mean chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T13C001" destination-id="0-0-0-4687">one</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24799" number="28715" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of the teachers&apos; retirement system, such term shall mean chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T13C004" destination-id="0-0-0-5377">four</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24800" number="28716" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of the police pension fund, article two, such term shall mean subchapter two of chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T13C002" destination-id="0-0-0-4747">two</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24801" number="28717" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of the fire department pension fund subchapter two, such term shall mean subchapter two of chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T13C003" destination-id="0-0-0-4865">three</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24802" number="28718" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of the board of education retirement system, such term shall mean the rules and regulations of such retirement system and subdivisions sixteen, seventeen and eighteen of section twenty-five hundred seventy-five of the education law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24803" number="28719" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Securities&quot;. Bonds, obligations, and mortgages which constitute lawful investments for a retirement system.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24804" number="28720" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Sell&quot;. To carry out a transaction whereby a retirement system transfers title to any securities which it holds, or exchanges or otherwise disposes of any such securities.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24805" number="28721" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Sale&quot;. The carrying out of any transaction described in paragraph seven of this subdivision a.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24806" number="28722" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the provisions of paragraph two of this subdivision shall apply in any case where, on or after May twentieth, nineteen hundred seventy and prior to July first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24807" number="28723" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a retirement system sells securities in which any of its funds are invested; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24808" number="28724" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>realizes a gain or sustains a loss with respect to such sale; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24809" number="28725" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>under the retirement system act governing such retirement system, the responsible public employer is entitled to credit for any such gain in the determination of its required contributions to such retirement system, or is required to reimburse such retirement system for any such loss.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24810" number="28726" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such gain or loss shall be treated in the manner prescribed by the applicable provisions of subdivisions c, d, e, f and g of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24811" number="28727" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any such sale occurring in the city&apos;s nineteen hundred sixty-nine-nineteen hundred seventy fiscal year or in any subsequent fiscal year up to and including the nineteen hundred seventy-nine-nineteen hundred eighty fiscal year results in a gain, the amount of such gain shall be credited in favor of the responsible public employer with respect to such retirement system, pursuant to the applicable provisions of paragraphs two to eight inclusive, of this subdivision c, in relation to the required contributions of such responsible public employer to such retirement system.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24812" number="28728" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any such gain referred to in paragraph two of this subdivision c was realized in the city&apos;s nineteen hundred sixty-nine-nineteen hundred seventy fiscal year or in any subsequent city fiscal year up to and including the nineteen hundred seventy-eight-nineteen hundred seventy-nine fiscal year, there shall be computed twenty equal annual installments of credit, the aggregate of which, if one of such installments were credited in favor of such responsible public employer in each of the twenty city fiscal years commencing with the second fiscal year succeeding the fiscal year in which such gain was realized, would be the actuarial equivalent of the amount of such gain. For the purpose of making such computation with respect to any such gains realized prior to July first, nineteen hundred seventy-five, an interest rate of four per centum per annum shall be used and for the purpose of making such computation with respect to any such gains realized during the period beginning on July first, nineteen hundred seventy-five and ending on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy-nine, an interest rate of five and one-half per centum per annum shall be used.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24813" number="28729" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of any such gain referred to in paragraph one of this subdivision c which was realized in any city fiscal year occurring during the period beginning on July first, nineteen hundred sixty-nine and ending on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy-eight, the first of such installments shall be credited in favor of such responsible public employer in the second city fiscal year succeeding that in which such gain was realized and one such installment shall be so credited in each succeeding fiscal year to and including the nineteen hundred seventy-nine-nineteen hundred eighty fiscal year. Such crediting in any such fiscal year shall be effected with respect to any such retirement system in the manner prescribed by the provisions of this section and of the retirement system act governing such retirement system, as such provisions were in effect during such fiscal year.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24814" number="28730" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to each gain to which paragraph two of this subdivision c applies, there shall be computed the present value, as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty, of the annual installments of credit thereon remaining uncredited as of such June thirtieth. For the purpose of making such calculation, an interest rate of five and one-half per centum shall be used.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24815" number="28731" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to each present value computed pursuant to paragraph four of this subdivision c, there shall be computed a number of equal annual installments of credit in favor of the responsible public employer, which number shall equal one less than the number of such uncredited installments referred to in such paragraph four, and the aggregate of which computed installments, on the basis of crediting the first of such installments to such responsible public employer in the city&apos;s nineteen hundred eighty-nineteen hundred eighty-one fiscal year and one of such installments in each subsequent fiscal year until all of such installments are so credited, shall be the actuarial equivalent of such present value referred to in such paragraph four. For the purpose of making such computation, an interest rate of seven and one-half per centum per annum shall be used.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24816" number="28732" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>One of such installments computed pursuant to paragraph five of this subdivision c shall be credited in favor of such responsible public employer in each of the city&apos;s nineteen hundred eighty-nineteen hundred eighty-one and nineteen hundred eighty-one-nineteen hundred eighty-two fiscal years.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24817" number="28733" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In each city fiscal year occurring during the period beginning on July first, nineteen hundred eighty-two and ending on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-eight, there shall be credited in favor of such responsible public employer an installment computed in accordance with items (ii) and (iii) of this subparagraph (b).</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24818" number="28734" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to each present value computed pursuant to paragraph four of this subdivision c, there shall be computed as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-two, using an interest rate of seven and one-half per centum per annum, the present value of the annual installments of credit in favor of the responsible public employer determined in accordance with paragraph five of this subdivision c and allocated to fiscal years subsequent to June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-two.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24819" number="28735" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The annual installments to be credited, for each city fiscal year occurring during the period beginning on July first, nineteen hundred eighty-two and ending on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-eight, in respect of each present value computed in accordance with item (ii) of this subparagraph (b) shall be an amount which, when credited in equal annual installments commencing with the city&apos;s nineteen hundred eighty-two-nineteen hundred eighty-three fiscal year and continuing for the number of fiscal years equal to the number of installments used in computing such present value, would be the actuarial equivalent, as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-two on the basis of eight per centum interest per annum, of an amount equal to such present value.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24820" number="28736" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>As used in this item (iv), the term &quot;remaining uncredited installments as of July first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight&quot; shall mean, in relation to any gain referred to in paragraph two of this subdivision c, the number of installments, if any, obtained by subtracting eight installments from the number of installments computed pursuant to paragraph five of this subdivision c in relation to such gain.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24821" number="28737" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be computed, as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-eight, using an interest rate of eight per centum per annum, the present value of the remaining uncredited installments as of July first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight, if any, with respect to any such gain referred to in paragraph two of this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24822" number="28738" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The annual installments to be credited with respect to such gain in each city fiscal year occurring during the period beginning on July first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight and ending with the last day of a number of fiscal years equal to the number of remaining uncredited installments as of July first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight with respect to such gain, shall be an amount which, when credited in equal annual installments, commencing with the city&apos;s nineteen hundred eighty-eight-nineteen hundred eighty-nine fiscal year and continuing during each fiscal year of the period above mentioned in this sub-item (C), shall be the actuarial equivalent, as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-eight on the basis of eight and one-quarter per centum interest per annum, of such present value computed pursuant to sub-item (B) of this item (iv).</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24823" number="28739" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any such gain referred to in paragraph one of this subdivision c was realized in the city&apos;s nineteen hundred seventy-nine-nineteen hundred eighty fiscal year, the amount of such gain shall, beginning with the nineteen hundred eighty-nineteen hundred eighty-one fiscal year, be credited in favor of such responsible public employer in twenty successive equal annual installments determined in the manner provided for by subparagraphs (b), (c) and (d) of this paragraph seven.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24824" number="28740" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The first and second annual installments referred to in subparagraph (a) of this paragraph seven shall be determined so that if they were the first and second of twenty equal annual installments of the amount of such gain, the present value of such twenty equal annual installments, computed at an interest rate of seven and one-half per centum per annum, would be equal to the amount of such gain.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24825" number="28741" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The next six annual installments required to be credited under the provisions of subparagraph (a) of this paragraph seven shall be determined so as to be equal and so that the present value of such six equal annual installments, computed as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-two at an interest rate of eight per centum per annum as if they were part of a remainder of eighteen equal annual installments so computed, shall be equal to the present value, computed as of such June thirtieth at an interest rate of seven and one-half per centum per annum, of the corresponding next six of the twenty equal annual installments computed pursuant to the provisions of subparagraph (b) of this paragraph seven.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24826" number="28742" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The remaining twelve annual annual installments required to be credited under the provisions of subparagraph (a) of this paragraph seven shall be determined so as to be equal and so that the present value of such twelve equal annual installments, computed as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-eight at an interest rate of eight and one-quarter per centum per annum, shall be equal to the present value, computed as of such June thirtieth at an interest rate of eight per centum per annum, of such last twelve equal annual installments.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24827" number="28743" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any such sale occurring in the city&apos;s nineteen hundred sixty-nine-nineteen hundred seventy fiscal year or in any subsequent fiscal year up to and including the nineteen hundred seventy-nine-nineteen hundred eighty fiscal year results in a loss, the responsible public employer with respect to such retirement system shall make payments to the contingent reserve fund of such retirement system on account of such loss in the manner prescribed by paragraphs two to seven, inclusive, of this subdivision d.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24828" number="28744" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any such loss referred to in paragraph one of this subdivision d was sustained in the city&apos;s nineteen hundred sixty-nine-nineteen hundred seventy fiscal year or in any subsequent city fiscal year up to and including the nineteen hundred seventy-eight-nineteen hundred seventy-nine fiscal year, there shall be computed twenty equal annual installments of payment on account of such loss, the aggregate of which installments, if one of such installments were paid by such responsible public employer to the contingent reserve fund in each of the twenty city fiscal years commencing with the second fiscal year succeeding the fiscal year in which such loss occurred, would be the actuarial equivalent of the amount of such loss. For the purpose of making such computation with respect to losses which occurred prior to July first, nineteen hundred seventy-five, an interest rate of four per centum per annum shall be used and for the purpose of making such computation with respect to losses which occurred during the period beginning on July first, nineteen hundred seventy-five and ending on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy-nine, an interest rate of five and one-half per centum per annum shall be used.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24829" number="28745" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of any such loss referred to in paragraph one of this subdivision d which was sustained in any city fiscal year occurring during the period beginning on July first, nineteen hundred sixty-nine and ending on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy-eight, one of such installments shall be paid by such responsible public employer to the contingent reserve fund of such retirement system in the second city fiscal year succeeding that in which such loss was sustained and one such installment shall be so paid by such responsible public employer in each succeeding fiscal year to and including the nineteen hundred seventy-nine-nineteen hundred eighty fiscal year.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24830" number="28746" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to each loss to which paragraph two of this subdivision d applies, there shall be computed the present value, as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty, of the annual installments of such loss remaining unpaid by such responsible public employer as of such June thirtieth. For the purpose of making such calculation, an interest rate of five and one-half per centum per annum shall be used.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24831" number="28747" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to each present value computed pursuant to paragraph four of this subdivision d, there shall be computed a number of equal annual installments of loss to be paid by such responsible public employer to the contingent reserve fund, which number shall equal one less than the number of the unpaid installments of such loss to which such present value relates, and the aggregate of which computed installments, on the basis of payment of the first of such installments by such responsible public employer in the city&apos;s nineteen hundred eighty-nineteen hundred eighty-one fiscal year and one of such installments in each subsequent fiscal year until all of such installments are paid, shall be the actuarial equivalent of such present value. For the purpose of making such computation, an interest rate of seven and one-half per centum per annum shall be used.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24832" number="28748" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such responsible public employer shall pay one of such installments computed pursuant to paragraph five of this subdivision d to the contingent reserve fund of such retirement system in each of the city&apos;s nineteen hundred eighty-nineteen hundred eighty-one and nineteen hundred eighty-one-nineteen hundred eighty-two fiscal years.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24833" number="28749" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such responsible public employer, in each city fiscal year occurring during the period beginning on July first, nineteen hundred eighty-two and ending on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-eight, shall pay an installment computed in accordance with items (ii) and (iii) of this subparagraph (b).</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24834" number="28750" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to each present value computed pursuant to paragraph four of this subdivision d, there shall be computed as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-two, using an interest rate of seven and one-half per centum per annum, the present value of the annual installments of loss determined in accordance with paragraph five of this subdivision d and allocated to fiscal years subsequent to June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-two.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24835" number="28751" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The annual installments of loss required to be paid by such responsible public employer, for each city fiscal year occurring during the period beginning on July first, nineteen hundred eighty-two and ending on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-eight, in respect of each present value computed in accordance with item (ii) of this subparagraph (b) shall be the applicable installments of an amount which, if paid in equal annual installments commencing with the city&apos;s nineteen hundred eighty-two-nineteen hundred eighty-three fiscal year and continuing for the number of fiscal years equal to the number of installments used in computing such present value, would be the actuarial equivalent, as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-two on the basis of eight per centum interest per annum, of an amount equal to such present value.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24836" number="28752" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>As used in this item (iv), the term &quot;remaining unpaid installments as of July first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight&quot; shall mean, in relation to any loss referred to in paragraph two of this subdivision d, the number of installments, if any, obtained by subtracting eight installments from the number of installments computed pursuant to paragraph five of this subdivision d in relation to such loss.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24837" number="28753" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be computed, as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-eight, using an interest rate of eight per centum per annum, the present value of the remaining unpaid installments as of July first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight, if any, with respect to any such loss referred to in paragraph two of this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24838" number="28754" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The annual installments to be paid with respect to such loss in each city fiscal year occurring during the period beginning on July first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight and ending with the last day of a number of fiscal years equal to the number of remaining unpaid installments as of July first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight with respect to such loss, shall be an amount which, when paid in equal annual installments, commencing with the city&apos;s nineteen hundred eighty-eight-nineteen hundred eighty-nine fiscal year and continuing during each fiscal year of the period above mentioned in this sub-item (C), shall be the actuarial equivalent, as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-eight on the basis of eight and one-quarter per centum interest per annum, of such present value computed pursuant to sub-item (B) of this item (iv).</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24839" number="28755" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any such loss referred to in paragraph one of this subdivision was sustained in the city&apos;s nineteen hundred seventy-nine-nineteen hundred eighty fiscal year, such responsible public employer shall, beginning with the nineteen hundred eighty-nineteen hundred eighty-one fiscal year, pay to the contingent reserve fund of such retirement system on account of such loss, twenty successive equal annual installments in amounts determined in the manner provided for in subparagraphs (b), (c) and (d) of this paragraph seven.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24840" number="28756" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The first and second annual installments referred to in subparagraph (a) of this paragraph seven shall be determined so that if they were the first and second of twenty equal annual installments of the amount of such loss, the present value of such twenty equal annual installments, computed at an interest rate of seven and one-half per centum per annum, would be equal to the amount of such loss.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24841" number="28757" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The next six annual installments required to be paid under the provisions of subparagraph (a) of this paragraph seven shall be determined so as to be equal and so that the present value of such six equal annual installments, computed as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-two at an interest rate of eight per centum per annum as if they were a part of a remainder of eighteen equal annual installments so computed, shall be equal to the present value, computed as of June thirtieth at an interest rate of seven and one-half per centum per annum, of the corresponding next six of the twenty equal annual installments computed pursuant to the provisions of subparagraph (b) of this paragraph seven.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24842" number="28758" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The remaining twelve annual installments required to be paid under the provisions of subparagraph (a) of this paragraph seven shall be determined so as to be equal and so that the present value of such twelve equal annual installments, computed as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-eight at an interest rate of eight and one-quarter per centum per annum, shall be equal to the present value, computed as of such June thirtieth at an interest rate of eight per centum per annum, of such last twelve equal annual installments.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24843" number="28759" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of sales occurring in the city&apos;s nineteen hundred eighty-nineteen hundred eighty-one fiscal year or in any subsequent fiscal year ending before July first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight, the retirement system making such sales shall, with respect to any such fiscal year above specified in this paragraph, provide credit for realized gains and amortization of realized losses for each responsible public employer pursuant to the applicable provisions of paragraphs two and three of this subdivision e.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24844" number="28760" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each fiscal year to which paragraph one of this subdivision e applies, there shall be calculated for each retirement system the net amount of aggregate gains and aggregate losses produced by sales in such fiscal year and such net amount shall be transferred to a special account in the retirement system to be known as the &quot;deferred charge on account of security sales&quot;. Such net amount for each such fiscal year shall be amortized within such account, commencing with such fiscal year, over the average maturity, rounded to the nearest year, of all securities (excluding securities maturing in less than one year) acquired in such fiscal year or sold in such fiscal year by the retirement systems, whichever is less.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24845" number="28761" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The amount to be amortized in each fiscal year over the period of average maturity referred to in paragraph two of this subdivision e shall be computed on a scientific basis, (a) using a reinvestment rate of seven and one-half per centum per annum with respect to any such net amount computed for the city&apos;s nineteen hundred eighty-nineteen hundred eighty-one fiscal year, and (b) using a reinvestment rate of eight per centum per annum with respect to any such net amount computed for any city fiscal year occurring during the period beginning on July first, nineteen hundred eighty-one and ending on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-four and (c) in the case of any such net amount computed for any city fiscal year occurring thereafter, using a reinvestment rate equivalent to that prescribed by the legislature as the rate to be used for the purpose of any actuarial valuation, determination or appraisal made in determining the employer contributions to be paid by responsible public employers to the contingent reserve fund of such retirement system in the city fiscal year next succeeding that for which such net amount was computed.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24846" number="28762" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any account constituting a deferred charge on account of security sales (whether a positive or negative quantity) which, in the absence of the enactment of a chapter of the laws of nineteen hundred eighty-nine which added this paragraph, would exist with respect to any retirement system as of July first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight, shall be cancelled and terminated as of such July first, and shall not be applied in the determination of the normal contribution or any other contribution payable by any responsible public employer to such retirement system with respect to any fiscal year beginning on or after such July first. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24847" number="28763" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e-1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of sales by any retirement system occurring in any fiscal year of the city beginning on or after July first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24848" number="28764" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>any gain resulting from any such sale shall not be directly and separately credited against contributions otherwise required to be made by the responsible public employer or employers to such retirement system; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24849" number="28765" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>any loss resulting from any such sale shall not be directly and separately charged as additional contributions payable to such retirement system by the responsible public employer or employers; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24850" number="28766" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the effects of such gains or losses shall be actuarially reflected in the valuations made for the purpose of determining contributions payable to such retirement system.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24851" number="28767" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In relation to determination of the normal contribution for any fiscal year beginning on or after July first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight, the provisions of sub-item (C) of item (i) of subparagraph (b) of paragraph two of subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="13-127" destination-id="0-0-0-4713">13-127</LINK> of the code, and sub-item (D) of item (i) of subparagraph (i) of paragraph two of subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="13-228" destination-id="0-0-0-5017">13-228</LINK> of the code, and sub-item (E) of item (i) of subparagraph (b) of paragraph two of subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="13-331" destination-id="0-0-0-5177">13-331</LINK> of the code, and item (iii) of subparagraph (a) of paragraph two of subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="13-527" destination-id="0-0-0-5405">13-527</LINK> of the code, or paragraph three of sub-item (A) of item (ii) of subparagraph four of paragraph (c) of subdivision sixteen of section twenty-five hundred seventy-five of the education law (relating to the actuarial treatment of certain losses on sales of fixed-income securities in the determination of the normal contribution) shall not be deemed to refer to or include any gains or losses on any such sales occurring in any fiscal year of the city beginning on or after July first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24852" number="28768" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of section one hundred seventy-seven-b of the retirement and social security law shall be inapplicable to any sale described in subdivisions b and e-1 of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24853" number="28769" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing contained in this section shall be construed as applicable to any sale of securities constituting an investment made with funds which are a part of a variable annuity program in the teachers&apos; retirement system or the board of education retirement system of the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24854" number="28770" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the purpose of determining the balance sheet liability of any retirement system as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty pursuant to the provisions of the retirement system act of such retirement system governing such determination, the &quot;annual contribution, for balance sheet liability purposes, on account of amortization of losses on dispositions of certain securities within the meaning of this section&quot;, as referred to in such provisions, shall be a hypothetical amount computed pursuant to the provisions of paragraphs two to four, inclusive, of this subdivision g.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24855" number="28771" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to each city fiscal year (the &quot;subject fiscal year&quot;) occurring during the period beginning on July first, nineteen hundred seventy-four and ending on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty, there shall be determined the amount by which:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24856" number="28772" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The total of the annual installments of losses which, under the provisions of this section as in effect prior to July first, nineteen hundred eighty, was or would have been payable by the responsible public employer in the second city fiscal year succeeding the subject fiscal year, exceeds</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24857" number="28773" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The total of the installments of gain required by such provisions of this section as they are in effect to be credited to the responsible public employer in such second fiscal year.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24858" number="28774" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be computed the discounted value of the amount of such excess as of January first of the subject fiscal year, such discounting being calculated on the basis of the applicable interest rate prescribed in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph three and a discount period of two years extending retroactively from December thirty-first of such second fiscal year succeeding the subject fiscal year to January first of the subject fiscal year.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24859" number="28775" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to the nineteen hundred seventy-four-nineteen hundred seventy-five subject fiscal year, the rate of interest to be used in calculating such discounted value shall be five and one-half per centum per annum for the period beginning on July first, nineteen hundred seventy-five and ending on December thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-six and four per centum per annum for the period beginning on January first, nineteen hundred seventy-five and ending on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy-five. With respect to each subject fiscal year occurring during the period beginning on July first, nineteen hundred seventy-five and ending on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty, the rate of interest used in calculating such discounted value shall be five and one-half per centum per annum.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24860" number="28776" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The amount of such discounted value, as so computed with respect to each subject fiscal year, shall be the annual contribution, for balance sheet liability purposes, on account of amortization of losses on dispositions of certain securities within the meaning of this section, which annual contribution is deemed to have been hypothetically payable in such subject fiscal year. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-24861" number="28777" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 13-705 Acquisition, management and protection of investments of retirement system funds. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4763" name="13-705"/>§ 13-705 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Acquisition, management and protection of investments of retirement system funds. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24862" number="28778" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>As used in this section, the term &quot;retirement system&quot; shall mean any of the following: the New York city employees&apos; retirement system, the New York city teachers&apos; retirement system, the New York city board of education retirement system, the police pension fund maintained pursuant to subchapter two of chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T13C002" destination-id="0-0-0-4747">two</LINK> of this title and the fire department pension fund maintained pursuant to subchapter two of chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T13C003" destination-id="0-0-0-4865">three</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24863" number="28779" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, such expenses as may necessarily be incurred by a retirement system in acquiring, managing and protecting investments of its funds may be paid from any income, interest or dividends derived from deposits or investments of such funds.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24864" number="28780" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of this section shall not be applicable:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24865" number="28781" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>to the acquisition, management or protection of investments of variable annuity funds of the New York city teachers&apos; retirement system or of variable annuity funds of any other retirement system which may at any time have a variable annuity program; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24866" number="28782" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>to contracts for services in relation to the acquisition, management or protection of investments of any variable annuity funds referred to in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph one.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24867" number="28783" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing contained in this section shall be construed as amending, modifying or affecting section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="13-570" destination-id="0-0-0-5459">13-570</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-24868" number="28784" version="1773">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In each city fiscal year, beginning with investment expenses paid during the nineteen hundred ninety-eight – nineteen hundred ninety-nine fiscal year, whenever the income, interest or dividends derived from deposits or investments of the funds of a retirement system are used pursuant to subdivision b of this section to pay the expenses incurred by such retirement system in acquiring, managing or protecting investments of its funds, the monies so paid shall be made a charge to be paid by each participating employer otherwise required to make contributions to such retirement system no later than the end of the fiscal year next succeeding the fiscal year during which such monies were drawn upon, provided, however, that where such charge is for such investment expenses paid during fiscal year two thousand four – two thousand five or during any subsequent fiscal year, such charge shall be paid by each such participating employer no later than the end of the second fiscal year succeeding the fiscal year during which such monies were drawn upon, provided further that the provisions of this subdivision shall not apply to investment expenses paid during the two thousand nine – two thousand ten fiscal year or during any subsequent fiscal year. In the event that such retirement system has more than one participating employer, the actuary shall calculate and allocate to each such participating employer its share of such charge. All charges to be paid pursuant to this subdivision shall be paid at the regular rate of interest utilized by the actuary in determining employer contributions to the retirement system pursuant to the provisions of paragraph two of subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="13-638.2" destination-id="0-0-0-4715">13-638.2</LINK> of this title. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>