<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-15193" number="18456" version="802">
			<HEADING>Chapter 22: Tax on Owners of Motor Vehicles</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2767" name="T11C022"/>Chapter 22: Tax on Owners of Motor Vehicles</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15194" number="18457" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2201 Definitions. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4275" name="11-2201"/>§ 11-2201 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15195" number="18458" version="3">
											<PARA>When used in this chapter, the following terms shall mean and include:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15196" number="18459" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;City&quot;. The city of New York.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15197" number="18460" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Commissioner of finance&quot;. The commissioner of finance of the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15198" number="18461" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Highway&quot;. The entire width between the boundary lines of every way publicly maintained when any part thereof is open to the use of the public for purposes of vehicular travel.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15199" number="18462" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Individual resident&quot;. One or more natural persons other than a firm, copartnership, trustee or trustees conducting a business or association who, or one of whom, owns a motor vehicle registered or required to be registered pursuant to section four hundred one of the vehicle and traffic law, the registration fees for which are provided for by subdivision six of said section, who, at the time he or she makes application for registration or renewal thereof of such motor vehicle (or such application is made on his or her behalf): (a) is domiciled in the city, unless he or she maintains no permanent place of abode in the city, maintains a permanent place of abode elsewhere, and during the period of one year next preceding the date upon which such application is made, spent in the aggregate not more than thirty days in the city; or (b) is not domiciled in the city but maintains a permanent place of abode in the city and, during the period of one year next preceding the date upon which such application is made, spent in the aggregate more than one hundred eighty-three days in the city, unless such individual is in the armed forces of the United States.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15200" number="18463" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Motor vehicle&quot;. Every vehicle, except electrically-driven invalid chairs being operated or driven by an invalid, operated or driven upon a public highway by any power, other than muscular power, which includes electric power obtained from overhead trolley wires, except vehicles which run only upon rails or tracks.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15201" number="18464" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Other resident&quot;. Every firm, copartnership, trustee or trustees conducting a business or association or a corporation, who or which regularly keeps, stores, garages or maintains within the city a motor vehicle owned by it which, at the time it makes application for registration or renewal of registration thereof, is registered or required to be registered pursuant to subdivision six of section four hundred one of the vehicle and traffic law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15202" number="18465" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Person&quot;. Unless otherwise indicated, an individual, partnership, society, association, joint-stock company, corporation, estate, receiver, trustee, assignee, referee or any other person acting in a fiduciary or representative capacity, whether appointed by a court or otherwise, and any other form of unincorporated enterprise.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15203" number="18466" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Owner&quot;. A person, other than a lien holder, having the property in or title to a vehicle. The term includes a person entitled to the use and possession of a vehicle subject to a security interest in another person.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15204" number="18467" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Vehicle&quot;. Every device in, upon or by which any person or property is or may be transported or drawn upon a highway, except devices moved by human power or used exclusively upon stationary rails or tracks.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15205" number="18468" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>10.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Leased or rented passenger motor vehicles&quot;. Any motor vehicle owned by any person engaged in the business of renting or leasing motor vehicles to be operated on the public highways for carrying passengers registered or required to be registered pursuant to any provision of section four hundred one of the vehicle and traffic law, which vehicle at the time when application is made for registration, re-registration or renewal thereof is regularly kept, stored, garaged or maintained in the city, including such vehicles which have been rented and leased by the owner and are in possession of lessees when such application for registration, re-registration or renewal is made.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15206" number="18469" version="677">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>11.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Tax appeals tribunal.&quot; The tax appeals tribunal established by section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="168" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred sixty-eight</LINK> of the charter. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15207" number="18470" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2202 Imposition of tax. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4277" name="11-2202"/>§ 11-2202 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Imposition of tax. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15208" number="18471" version="3">
											<PARA>Notwithstanding the provisions of section four hundred of the vehicle and traffic law and of subdivision ten of section four hundred one of the vehicle and traffic law to the contrary, a tax of fifteen dollars per annum is hereby imposed:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15209" number="18472" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to each motor vehicle registered or required to be registered pursuant to subdivision six of section four hundred one of the vehicle and traffic law: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15210" number="18473" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon each individual resident for each such motor vehicle registered or for which registration is renewed, or required to be registered or renewed by him or her; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15211" number="18474" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon each other resident of each such motor vehicle regularly kept, stored, garaged or maintained in the city and registered or required to be registered or renewed by such other resident; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15212" number="18475" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to each leased or rented passenger motor vehicle, upon the owner thereof. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15213" number="18476" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2203 Exemptions. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4279" name="11-2203"/>§ 11-2203 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Exemptions. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15214" number="18477" version="3">
											<PARA>The tax imposed by this chapter shall not be imposed upon: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15215" number="18478" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>owners of motor vehicles, the registration fees for which are or may be prescribed, governed or established by subdivisions seven (except for leased or rented passenger vehicles), eight, twelve, thirteen, sixteen of section four hundred one, articles fifteen and sixteen, or section four hundred twenty of the vehicle and traffic law;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15216" number="18479" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>any owner to whom the provisions of the vehicle and traffic law relative to registration and equipment of motor vehicles are made inapplicable by the provisions of article three of title two of such law, for the period of such inapplicability;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15217" number="18480" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the state of New York, or any of its agencies, instrumentalities, public corporations (including a public corporation created pursuant to agreement or compact with another state or the Dominion of Canada) or political subdivision;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15218" number="18481" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the United States of America, and any of its agencies and instrumentalities insofar as it is immune from taxation;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15219" number="18482" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the United Nations or other international organizations of which the United States of America is a member;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15220" number="18483" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>any corporation, or association, or trust, or community chest, fund or foundation, organized and operated exclusively for religious, charitable, or educational purposes, or for the prevention of cruelty to children or animals, and no part of the net earnings of which inures to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual and no substantial part of the activities of which is carrying on propaganda, or otherwise attempting to influence legislation; provided, however, that nothing in this subdivision shall include an organization operated for the primary purpose of carrying on a trade or business for profit, whether or not all of its profits are payable to one or more organizations described in this subdivision. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15221" number="18484" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2204 Payment of tax and evidence of tax payment. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4281" name="11-2204"/>§ 11-2204 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Payment of tax and evidence of tax payment. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15222" number="18485" version="3">
											<PARA>Every owner of a motor vehicle subject to tax hereunder shall pay the tax thereon to the commissioner of motor vehicles of the state of New York on or before the date upon which he or she registers or renews his or her registration thereof or is required to register or renew his or her registration thereof pursuant to section four hundred one of the vehicle and traffic law. Notwithstanding the provisions of section four hundred of the vehicle and traffic law to the contrary, the payment of such tax shall be a condition precedent to the registration or renewal thereof of such motor vehicle and to the issuance of any certificate of registration and plates or removable tag specified in subdivision three of section four hundred one and in sections four hundred three and four hundred four of the vehicle and traffic law, and no such certificate of registration, plates or tag shall be issued unless such tax has been paid. The commissioner of motor vehicles shall not issue a registration certificate for any motor vehicle for which the registrant&apos;s address is within any such city, except upon proof, in a form approved by the commissioner of motor vehicles, that such tax has been paid, or is not due, with respect to such motor vehicle. The commissioner of motor vehicles, upon the payment of such tax or upon the application of any person exempt therefrom, shall furnish to each taxpayer paying the tax a receipt for such tax and to each such taxpayer or exempt person a statement, document or other form approved by the commissioner of motor vehicles pursuant to the last sentence, showing that such tax has been paid or is not due, with respect to such motor vehicle. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15223" number="18486" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2205 Returns. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4283" name="11-2205"/>§ 11-2205 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Returns. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15224" number="18487" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>At the time the payment of the tax imposed by this chapter becomes due, every person subject to tax hereunder shall file a return with the commissioner of motor vehicles in form and containing such information as may be prescribed by such commissioner of motor vehicles. The taxpayer&apos;s application for registration or the renewal of registration shall constitute the return required under this chapter, unless the commissioner of motor vehicles, by regulation, shall otherwise provide.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15225" number="18488" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Returns shall be preserved for three years and thereafter until the commissioner of motor vehicles permits them to be destroyed.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15226" number="18489" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of motor vehicles may require amended returns or certificates of facts to be filed within twenty days after notice and to contain the information specified in the notice. Any such certificate shall be deemed to be part of the return required to be filed.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15227" number="18490" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If a return required by this chapter is not filed or if a return when filed is incorrect or insufficient on its face the commissioner of motor vehicles or the commissioner of finance if designated as his or her agent shall take the necessary steps to enforce the filing of such a return or of a corrected return. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15228" number="18491" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2206 Determination of tax. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4285" name="11-2206"/>§ 11-2206 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Determination of tax. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15229" number="18492" version="677">
											<PARA>If a return required by this chapter is not filed or if a return when filed is incorrect or insufficient, or if a tax or any part thereof due hereunder be not paid when required, the amount of tax due shall be determined by the commissioner of motor vehicles or by the commissioner of finance if designated as his or her agent, from such information as may be obtainable, including motor vehicle registration with the department of motor vehicles of the state of New York and/or other factors. Notice of such determination shall be given to the person liable for the tax. Such a determination by the commissioner of motor vehicles shall finally and irrevocably fix the tax unless the person against whom it is assessed, within ninety days after the giving of notice of such determination, shall apply to the commissioner of motor vehicles for a hearing, or unless such commissioner of his or her own motion shall redetermine the same. If the commissioner of finance is designated as the agent of the commissioner of motor vehicles, such a determination by the commissioner of finance shall finally and irrevocably fix the tax unless the person against whom it is assessed, within ninety days after the giving of such determination, or, if the commissioner of finance has established a conciliation procedure pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-124" destination-id="0-0-0-2745">11-124</LINK> of the code and the taxpayer has requested a conciliation conference in accordance therewith, within ninety days from the mailing of a conciliation decision or the date of the commissioner&apos;s confirmation of the discontinuance of the conciliation proceeding, both (1) serves a petition upon the commissioner of finance and (2) applies to the tax appeals tribunal for a hearing by filing a petition, or unless the commissioner of finance of his or her own motion shall redetermine the same. A hearing following a petition to the tax appeals tribunal and any appeal to the tax appeals tribunal sitting en banc from the decision rendered in such hearing shall be conducted in the manner and subject to the requirements prescribed by the tax appeals tribunal pursuant to sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="168" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred sixty-eight</LINK> through <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="172" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred seventy-two</LINK> of the charter. After such hearing by the commissioner of motor vehicles or the tax appeals tribunal, the commissioner of motor vehicles, if he or she holds the hearing, or the tax appeals tribunal if the tax appeals tribunal holds the hearing, shall give notice of the determination or decision to the person against whom the tax is assessed and in the case of a tax appeals tribunal decision, to the commissioner of finance. Such determination by the commissioner of motor vehicles, or a decision of the tax appeals tribunal sitting en banc shall be reviewable for error, illegality or unconstitutionality or any other reason whatsoever by a proceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules if application therefor is made to the supreme court by the person against whom the tax was assessed within four months after the giving of the notice of such determination or tax appeals tribunal decision. A proceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules shall not be instituted by a taxpayer unless (a) the amount of any tax sought to be reviewed, with penalties and interest thereon, if any, shall be first deposited with the commissioner of motor vehicles and there shall be filed with the commissioner of motor vehicles an undertaking, issued by a surety company authorized to transact business in this state and approved by the superintendent of insurance of this state as to solvency and responsibility, in such amount as a justice of the supreme court shall approve, to the effect that if such proceeding be dismissed or the tax confirmed, the taxpayer will pay all costs and charges which may accrue in the prosecution of the proceeding; or (b) at the option of the taxpayer such undertaking filed with the commissioner of motor vehicles may be in a sum sufficient to cover the taxes, penalties and interest thereon stated in such determination or decision, plus the costs and charges which may accrue against it in the prosecution of the proceeding, in which event the taxpayer shall not be required to deposit such taxes, penalties and interest as a condition precedent to the application.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15230" number="18493" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2207 Refunds for certain unused registrations. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4287" name="11-2207"/>§ 11-2207 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Refunds for certain unused registrations. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15231" number="18494" version="3">
											<PARA>Whenever any fee or portion of a fee paid for the registration of a motor vehicle under the provisions of the vehicle and traffic law is refunded pursuant to the provisions of subdivision one of section four hundred twenty-eight thereof, the amount of any tax paid pursuant to this chapter upon such registration shall also be refunded by the commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15232" number="18495" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2208 Refunds. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4289" name="11-2208"/>§ 11-2208 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Refunds. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15233" number="18496" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the manner provided in this section the commissioner of motor vehicles shall refund or credit, without interest, any tax, penalty or interest erroneously, illegally or unconstitutionally collected or paid if application for such refund shall be made within one year from the payment thereof to the commissioner of motor vehicles or to the commissioner of finance if designated as his or her agent. Whenever a refund is made or denied, the reasons therefor shall be stated in writing by the commissioner of motor vehicles or by the commissioner of finance, as the case may be, who in lieu of any refund, may allow credit therefor on payments due from the applicant. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15234" number="18497" version="1771">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the commissioner of motor vehicles has not designated the commissioner of finance as his or her agent, an application for a refund or credit made as herein provided shall be deemed an application for a revision of any tax, penalty or interest complained of and the commissioner of motor vehicles shall hold a hearing and receive evidence with respect thereto. After such hearing, the commissioner of motor vehicles shall give notice of the determination of such application to the applicant who shall be entitled to review such determination by a proceeding pursuant to article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules, provided such proceeding is instituted within four months after the giving of notice of such determination, and provided that a final determination of tax due was not previously made. Such a proceeding shall not be instituted unless an undertaking is filed with the commissioner of motor vehicles in such amount and with such sureties as a justice of the supreme court shall approve, to the effect that if such proceeding be dismissed or the tax confirmed, the petitioner will pay all costs and charges which may accrue in the prosecution of such proceeding.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15235" number="18498" version="1772">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the commissioner of motor vehicles has designated the commissioner of finance as his or her agent, a determination of the commissioner of finance denying a refund or credit pursuant to subdivision a of this section shall be final and irrevocable unless the applicant for such refund or credit, within ninety days from the mailing of notice of such determination, or, if the commissioner of finance has established conciliation procedure pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-124" destination-id="0-0-0-2745">11-124</LINK> of the administrative code and the applicant has requested a conciliation conference in accordance therewith, within ninety days from the mailing of a conciliation decision or the date of the commissioner&apos;s confirmation of the discontinuance of the conciliation proceeding, both (1) serves a petition upon the commissioner of finance and (2) files a petition with the tax appeals tribunal for a hearing. Such petition for a refund or credit, made as herein provided, shall be deemed an application for a revision of any tax, penalty or interest complained of. Such hearing and any appeal to the tax appeals tribunal sitting en banc from the decision rendered in such hearing shall be conducted in the manner and subject to the requirements prescribed by the tax appeals tribunal pursuant to sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="168" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred sixty-eight</LINK> through <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="172" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred seventy-two</LINK> of the charter. After such hearing, the tax appeals tribunal shall give notice of its decision to the applicant and to the commissioner of finance. The applicant shall be entitled to institute a proceeding pursuant to article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules to review a decision of the tax appeals tribunal sitting en banc if application to the supreme court be made therefor within four months after the giving of notice of such decision, and provided, in the case of an application by a taxpayer, that a final determination of tax due was not previously made. Such a proceeding shall not be instituted by a taxpayer unless an undertaking shall first be filed with the commissioner of motor vehicles, in such amount and with such sureties as a justice of the supreme court shall approve, to the effect that if such proceeding be dismissed or the tax confirmed, the taxpayer will pay all costs and charges which may accrue in the prosecution of such proceeding.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15236" number="18499" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A person shall not be entitled to a revision, refund or credit under this section of a tax, interest or penalty which has been determined to be due pursuant to the provisions of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2206" destination-id="0-0-0-4285">11-2206</LINK> of this chapter where he or she has had a hearing or an opportunity for a hearing, as provided in said section, or has failed to avail himself or herself of the remedies therein provided. No refund or credit shall be made of a tax, interest or penalty paid after a determination made pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2206" destination-id="0-0-0-4285">11-2206</LINK> of this chapter, unless it be found that such determination was erroneous, illegal or unconstitutional or otherwise improper after a hearing, or on his or her own motion, by the commissioner of motor vehicles or after a hearing by the tax appeals tribunal, or on his or her own motion by the commissioner of finance, as the case may be, or in a proceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules, pursuant to the provisions of said section, in which event refund or credit without interest shall be made of the tax, interest or penalty found to have been overpaid. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15237" number="18500" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2209 Reserves. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4291" name="11-2209"/>§ 11-2209 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Reserves. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15238" number="18501" version="3">
											<PARA>In cases where a taxpayer has applied for a refund and has instituted a proceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules to review a determination adverse to such taxpayer on his or her application for refund, the commissioner of motor vehicles shall set up appropriate reserves to meet any decision adverse to the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15239" number="18502" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2210 Remedies exclusive. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4293" name="11-2210"/>§ 11-2210 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Remedies exclusive. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15240" number="18503" version="3">
											<PARA>The remedies provided by sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2206" destination-id="0-0-0-4285">11-2206</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2208" destination-id="0-0-0-4289">11-2208</LINK> of this chapter shall be the exclusive remedies available to any person for the review of tax liability imposed by this chapter; and no determination or proposed determination of tax or determination on any application for refund by the commissioner of motor vehicles or by the commissioner of finance, nor any decision by the tax appeals tribunal or any of its administrative law judges, shall be enjoined or reviewed by an action for declaratory judgment, an action for money had and received or by any action or proceeding other than, in the case of a final determination by the commissioner of motor vehicles or a decision by the tax appeals tribunal sitting en banc, a proceeding in the nature of a certiorari proceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules; provided, however, that a taxpayer may proceed by declaratory judgment if he or she institutes suit within thirty days after a deficiency assessment is made and pays the amount of the deficiency assessment to the commissioner of motor vehicles prior to the institution of such suit and posts a bond for costs as provided in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2206" destination-id="0-0-0-4285">11-2206</LINK> of this chapter. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15241" number="18504" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2211 Proceedings to recover tax. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4295" name="11-2211"/>§ 11-2211 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Proceedings to recover tax. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15242" number="18505" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever any person shall fail to pay any tax, penalty or interest imposed by this chapter as herein provided, the corporation counsel, upon the request of the commissioner of motor vehicles or of the commissioner of finance if designated as his or her agent, shall bring or cause to be brought an action to enforce the payment of the same on behalf of the city of New York in any court of the state of New York or of any other state of the United States. However, if in his or her discretion the commissioner of motor vehicles, or the commissioner of finance if designated as his or her agent, believes that any such person subject to the provisions of this chapter is about to cease business, leave the state or remove or dissipate the assets out of which the tax or penalty might be satisfied, and that any such tax or penalty will not be paid when due, he or she may declare such tax or penalty to be immediately due and payable and may issue a warrant immediately.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15243" number="18506" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>As an additional or alternate remedy, the commissioner of motor vehicles, or the commissioner of finance if designated as his or her agent, may issue a warrant, directed to the city sheriff commanding him or her to levy upon and sell the real and personal property of the person liable for the tax which may be found within the city, for the payment of the amount thereof, with any penalty and interest, and the cost of executing the warrant, and to return such warrant to the person who issued it and to pay to him or her the money collected by virtue thereof within sixty days after the receipt of such warrant. The city sheriff shall within five days after the receipt of the warrant file with the county clerk a copy thereof, and thereupon such clerk shall enter in the judgment docket the name of the person mentioned in the warrant and the amount of the tax, penalty and interest for which the warrant is issued and the date when such copy is filed. Thereupon the amount of such warrant so docketed shall become a lien upon the title to and the interest in real and personal property of the person against whom the warrant is issued. The city sheriff shall then proceed upon the warrant in the same manner, and with like effect, as that provided by law in respect to executions issued against property upon judgments of a court of record and for services in executing the warrant such sheriff shall be entitled to the same fees, which he or she may collect in the same manner. In the discretion of the commissioner of motor vehicles, or of the commissioner of finance if designated as his or her agent, a warrant of like terms, force and effect may be issued and directed to an officer or employee of the department of finance of the city, and in the execution thereof such officer or employee shall have all the powers conferred by law upon sheriffs, but shall be entitled to no fee or compensation in excess of the actual expenses paid in the performance of such duty. If a warrant is returned not satisfied in full, the commissioner of motor vehicles or the commissioner of finance, as the case may be, may from time to time issue new warrants and shall also have the same remedies to enforce the amount due thereunder as if he or she had recovered judgment therefor and execution thereon had been returned unsatisfied.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15244" number="18507" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of finance, if he or she finds that the interests of the city will not thereby be jeopardized, and upon such conditions as the commissioner of finance may require, may release any property from the lien of any warrant or vacate such warrant for unpaid taxes, additions to tax, penalties and interest filed pursuant to subdivision b of this section, and such release or vacating of the warrant may be recorded in the office of any recording officer in which such warrant has been filed. The clerk shall thereupon cancel and discharge as of the original date of docketing the vacated warrant. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15245" number="18508" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2212 General powers of the commissioner of motor vehicles. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4297" name="11-2212"/>§ 11-2212 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">General powers of the commissioner of motor vehicles. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15246" number="18509" version="3">
											<PARA>In addition to the powers granted to the commissioner of motor vehicles in this chapter, he or she is hereby authorized and empowered:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15247" number="18510" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To make, adopt and amend rules and regulations appropriate to the carrying out of this chapter and the purposes thereof;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15248" number="18511" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For cause shown, to remit penalties; and to compromise disputed claims in connection with the taxes hereby imposed;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15249" number="18512" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To request information concerning motor vehicles and persons subject to the provisions of this chapter from the department of motor vehicles of any other state or the treasury department of the United States, or any city or county of the state of New York; and to afford such information to such other state, treasury department, city or county, any provision of this chapter to the contrary notwithstanding;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15250" number="18513" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To delegate his or her functions hereunder to a deputy commissioner in the department of motor vehicles or any employee or employees of his or her department or to any county clerk or other officer who acts as the agent of such commissioner in the registration of motor vehicles;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15251" number="18514" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To prescribe methods for determining the tax;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15252" number="18515" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To require all persons owning motor vehicles subject to tax to keep such records as he or she may prescribe and to furnish such information upon his or her request;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15253" number="18516" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To request the police department of the city to assist in the enforcement of the provisions of this chapter. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15254" number="18517" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2213 Administration of oaths and compelling testimony. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4299" name="11-2213"/>§ 11-2213 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Administration of oaths and compelling testimony. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15255" number="18518" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of motor vehicles or his or her employees or agents duly designated and authorized by such commissioner, and the tax appeals tribunal, shall have power to administer oaths and take affidavits in relation to any matter or proceeding in the exercise of the powers and duties under this chapter. The commissioner of motor vehicles, or the commissioner of finance if designated as his or her agent or the tax appeals tribunal, shall have the power to subpoena and require the attendance of witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents to secure information pertinent to the performance of the duties of the commissioner of motor vehicles, the commissioner of finance or the tax appeals tribunal hereunder and of the enforcement of this chapter and to examine them in relation thereto, and to issue commissions for the examination of witnesses who are out of the state or unable to attend before him or her or the tax appeals tribunal or excused from attendance.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15256" number="18519" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A justice of the supreme court either in court or at chambers shall have power summarily to enforce by proper proceedings the attendance and testimony of witnesses and production and examination of books, papers and documents called for by the subpoena of the commissioner of motor vehicles, or, if the commissioner of finance is designated as his or her agent under this chapter, of the commissioner of finance and the tax appeals tribunal.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15257" number="18520" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cross-reference; criminal penalties.</CHARFORMAT> For failure to obey subpoenas or for testifying falsely, see section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-4007" destination-id="0-0-0-3599">11-4007</LINK> of this title; for supplying false or fraudulent information, see section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-4009" destination-id="0-0-0-3647">11-4009</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15258" number="18521" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The officers who serve the summons or subpoena of the commissioner of motor vehicles, or the commissioner of finance if designated as his or her agent, or the tax appeals tribunal if the commissioner of finance is designated as the agent of the commissioner of motor vehicles, and witnesses attending in response thereto shall be entitled to the same fees as are allowed to officers and witnesses in civil cases in courts of record, except as herein otherwise provided. Such officers shall be the city sheriff and his or her duly appointed deputies, or any officers or employees of the department of motor vehicles designated by the commissioner of motor vehicles to serve such process or any officers or employees of the department of finance of the city designated by the commissioner of finance to serve such process or any officers or employees of the tax appeals tribunal designated to serve such process. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15259" number="18522" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2214 Penalties and interest. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4301" name="11-2214"/>§ 11-2214 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Penalties and interest. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15260" number="18523" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person failing to file a return or to pay any tax or any portion thereof within the time required by this chapter shall be subject to a penalty of five times the amount of the tax due, plus interest of five percent of such tax for each month of delay or fraction thereof, but the commissioner of motor vehicles, or the commissioner of finance if designated as his or her agent, if satisfied that the delay was excusable, may remit all or any part of such penalty, but not interest at the rate of six percent per year. Penalties and interest shall be paid and disposed of in the same manner as other revenues under this chapter. Unpaid penalties and interest may be enforced in the same manner as the tax imposed by this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15261" number="18524" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The certificate of the commissioner of motor vehicles or of the commissioner of finance if designated as his or her agent to the effect that a tax has not been paid, or that a return required by this chapter has not been filed, or that information has not been supplied pursuant to the provisions of this chapter shall be presumptive evidence thereof.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15262" number="18525" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cross-reference:</CHARFORMAT> For criminal penalties, see chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T11C040" destination-id="0-0-0-2809">forty</LINK> of this title. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15263" number="18526" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2215 Returns to be secret. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4303" name="11-2215"/>§ 11-2215 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Returns to be secret. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15264" number="18527" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except in accordance with proper judicial order or as otherwise provided by law, it shall be unlawful for the commissioner of motor vehicles, any officer or employee of the department of motor vehicles, the commissioner of finance, any officer or employee of the department of finance, the tax appeals tribunal, any commissioner or employee of such tribunal, any agent of the commissioner of motor vehicles, or any person who, pursuant to this section, is permitted to inspect any return or to whom a copy, an abstract or portion of any return is furnished, or to whom any information contained in any return is furnished to divulge or make known in any manner any information contained in or relating to any return provided for by this chapter. The officers charged with the custody of such returns shall not be required to produce any of them or evidence of anything contained in them in any action or proceeding in any court, except on behalf of the commissioner of motor vehicles or the commissioner of finance in an action or proceeding under the provisions of this chapter, or on behalf of any party to an action or proceeding under the provisions of this chapter when the returns or facts shown thereby are directly involved in such action or proceeding, in either of which events the court may require the production of, and may admit in evidence, so much of said returns or of the facts shown thereby, as are pertinent to the action or proceeding and no more. The commissioner of motor vehicles may, nevertheless, publish a copy or a summary of any determination or decision rendered after a formal hearing held pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2206" destination-id="0-0-0-4285">11-2206</LINK> or <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2208" destination-id="0-0-0-4289">11-2208</LINK> of this chapter. Nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit the delivery to a person or his or her duly authorized representative of a certified copy of any return filed by him or her pursuant to this chapter, or of the receipt, document or other form issued pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2204" destination-id="0-0-0-4281">11-2204</LINK> of this chapter, or a duplicate copy thereof; nor to prohibit the delivery of such a certified copy of such return or of any information contained in or relating thereto, to the United States of America or any department thereof, the state of New York or any department thereof, the city of New York or any department thereof provided the same is required for official business; nor to prohibit the inspection for official business of such returns by the corporation counsel or other legal representatives of the city or by the district attorney of any county within the city; nor to prohibit the publication of statistics so classified as to prevent the identification of particular returns or items thereof. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15265" number="18528" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any officer or employee of the state of New York or the city who willfully violates the provisions of subdivision a of this section shall be dismissed from office and be incapable of holding any public office in the state of New York or this city for a period of five years thereafter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15266" number="18529" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cross-reference:</CHARFORMAT> For criminal penalties, see chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T11C040" destination-id="0-0-0-2809">forty</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15267" number="18530" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section shall be deemed a state statute for purposes of paragraph (a) of subdivision two of section eighty-seven of the public officers law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15268" number="18531" version="677">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding anything in subdivision a of this section to the contrary, if a taxpayer has petitioned the tax appeals tribunal for administrative review as provided in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="170" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred seventy</LINK> of the charter, the commissioner of finance shall be authorized to present to the tax appeals tribunal any report or return of such taxpayer, or any information contained therein or relating thereto, which may be material or relevant to the proceeding before the tax appeals tribunal. The tax appeals tribunal shall be authorized to publish a copy or a summary of any decision rendered pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="171" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred seventy-one</LINK> of the charter. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15269" number="18532" version="1714">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1988/062" destination-id="0-0-0-27058">L.L. 1988/062</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-221913" number="18533" version="1714">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2216 Notices and limitations of time. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4305" name="11-2216"/>§ 11-2216 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Notices and limitations of time. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15270" number="18534" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any notice authorized or required under the provisions of this chapter may be given by mailing the same to the person for whom it is intended in a postpaid envelope addressed to such person at the address given in the last return filed by him or her pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, in any application made by him or her, or in any application for registration made by him or her pursuant to section four hundred one of the vehicle and traffic law or, if no return has been filed or application made, then to such address as may be obtainable. The mailing of such notice shall be presumptive evidence of the receipt of the same by the person to whom addressed. Any period of time which is determined according to the provisions of this chapter by the giving of notice shall commence to run from the date of mailing of such notice.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15271" number="18535" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of the civil practice law and rules or any other law relative to limitations of time for the enforcement of a civil remedy shall not apply to any proceeding or action taken by the commissioner of motor vehicles, or the commissioner of finance if designated as his or her agent, to levy, appraise, assess, determine or enforce the collection of any tax or penalty provided by this chapter. However, except in the case of a wilfully false or fraudulent return with intent to evade the tax, no assessment of additional tax shall be made after the expiration of more than three years from the date of the filing of a return; provided, however, that where no return has been filed as provided by law the tax may be assessed at any time.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15272" number="18536" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where, before the expiration of the period prescribed herein for the assessment of an additional tax, a taxpayer has consented in writing that such period be extended, the amount of such additional tax may be determined at any time within such extended period. The period so extended may be further extended by subsequent consents in writing made before the expiration of the extended period.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15273" number="18537" version="1772">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any return, claim, statement, notice, application, or other document required to be filed, or any payment required to be made, within a prescribed period or on or before a prescribed date under authority of any provision of this title is, after such period or such date, delivered by United States mail to the commissioner of motor vehicles, commissioner of finance, the tax appeals tribunal, bureau, office, officer or person with which or with whom such document is required to be filed, or to which or to whom such payment is required to be made, the date of the United States postmark stamped on the envelope shall be deemed to be the date of delivery. This subdivision shall apply only if the postmark date falls within the prescribed period or on or before the prescribed date for the filing of such document, or for making the payment, including any extension granted for such filing or payment, and only if such document or payment was deposited in the mail, postage prepaid, properly addressed to the commissioner of motor vehicles, commissioner of finance, the tax appeals tribunal, bureau, office, officer or person with which or with whom the document is required to be filed or to which or to whom such payment is required to be made. If any document is sent by United States registered mail, such registration shall be prima facie evidence that such document was delivered to the commissioner of motor vehicles, commissioner of finance, the tax appeals tribunal, bureau, office, officer or person to which or to whom addressed, and the date of registration shall be deemed the postmark date. The commissioner of motor vehicles is authorized to provide by regulation the extent to which the provisions of the preceding sentence with respect to prima facie evidence of delivery and the postmark date shall apply to certified mail. This subdivision shall apply in the case of postmarks not made by the United States Postal Service only if and to the extent provided by regulation of the commissioner of motor vehicles.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15274" number="18538" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the last day prescribed under authority of this title (including any extension of time) for performing any act falls on a Saturday, Sunday or legal holiday in the state of New York, the performance of such act shall be considered timely if it is performed on the next succeeding day which is not a Saturday, Sunday or legal holiday. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15275" number="18539" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2217 Commissioner of finance as agent. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4307" name="11-2217"/>§ 11-2217 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commissioner of finance as agent. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15276" number="18540" version="3">
											<PARA>The commissioner of motor vehicles is hereby authorized to designate the commissioner of finance his or her agent to exercise any or all of his or her functions and powers specified or provided for in subdivision (d) of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2205" destination-id="0-0-0-4283">11-2205</LINK> and in sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2206" destination-id="0-0-0-4285">11-2206</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2208" destination-id="0-0-0-4289">11-2208</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2211" destination-id="0-0-0-4295">11-2211</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2213" destination-id="0-0-0-4299">11-2213</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2214" destination-id="0-0-0-4301">11-2214</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2216" destination-id="0-0-0-4305">11-2216</LINK> of this chapter. Where the commissioner of finance has been so designated as agent, the commissioner of finance, in addition to the powers elsewhere granted to him or her in this chapter, is hereby authorized and empowered:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15277" number="18541" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To delegate such functions and powers to a commissioner or deputy commissioner in the department of finance or to any employee or employees of the department of finance;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15278" number="18542" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For cause shown, to remit penalties and to compromise disputed claims in connection with the taxes hereby imposed;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15279" number="18543" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To request information concerning motor vehicles and persons subject to the provisions of this chapter from the department of motor vehicles of any other state or the treasury department of the United States, or any city or county of the state of New York; and to afford such information to such other state, treasury department, city or county, any provision of this chapter to the contrary notwithstanding;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15280" number="18544" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To request the police department of the city to assist in the enforcement of the provisions of this chapter. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15281" number="18545" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2218 Agreement between commissioner of finance and commissioner of motor vehicles. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4309" name="11-2218"/>§ 11-2218 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Agreement between commissioner of finance and commissioner of motor vehicles. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15282" number="18546" version="3">
											<PARA>The commissioner of finance is hereby authorized and empowered to enter into an agreement with the commissioner of motor vehicles to govern the administration and collection of the taxes imposed by this chapter, which agreement shall provide for the exclusive method of collection of such taxes, custody and remittal of the proceeds of such tax; for the payment by the city of the reasonable expenses incurred by the department of motor vehicles in collecting and administering such tax; and for the audit, upon request of the commissioner of finance or his or her delegate, of the accuracy of the payments, distributions and remittances to the commissioner of finance pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, to be conducted at a time agreed upon by the state comptroller and to be allowed not more frequently than once in each calendar year. Such agreement shall have the force and effect of a rule or regulation of the commissioner of motor vehicles, and shall be filed and published in accordance with any statutory requirements relating thereto. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15283" number="18547" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2219 Notification to corporation counsel. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4311" name="11-2219"/>§ 11-2219 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Notification to corporation counsel. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15284" number="18548" version="3">
											<PARA>The commissioner of motor vehicles shall promptly notify the corporation counsel of the city of any litigation instituted against him or her which challenges the constitutionality or validity of any provision of this chapter, or of the enabling act pursuant to which it was adopted, or which attempts to limit or question the applicability of either such law, and such notification shall include a copy of the papers served upon him.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15285" number="18549" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2220 Construction and enforcement. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4313" name="11-2220"/>§ 11-2220 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction and enforcement. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15286" number="18550" version="3">
											<PARA>This chapter shall be construed and enforced in conformity with subdivisions (g) and (h) of section twelve hundred one of the tax law, pursuant to which it is enacted.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15287" number="18551" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2221 Disposition of revenues. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4315" name="11-2221"/>§ 11-2221 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Disposition of revenues. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15288" number="18552" version="3">
											<PARA>All revenues resulting from the imposition of the tax under this chapter shall be paid into the treasury of the city and shall be credited to and deposited in the general fund of the city, but no part of such revenues may be expended unless appropriated in the annual budget of the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>