<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-128428" number="39780" version="1272">
			<HEADING>Chapter 11: Citywide Greenway Plan </HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-24486" name="T19C011"/>Chapter 11: Citywide Greenway Plan </PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-201944" number="39781" version="1272">
										<HEADING>§ 19-1100 Citywide greenway plan.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-24488" name="19-1100"/>§ 19-1100 Citywide greenway plan.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201959" number="39782" version="1272">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in this section, the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201958" number="39783" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Greenway.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;greenway&quot; means a linear open space developed as a multi-use pathway on which motor vehicles are prohibited, except as authorized by any law enforcement agency or authority or by any federal, state, local or non-governmental agency, authority or other entity with jurisdiction over such greenway. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201957" number="39784" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Motor vehicle.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;motor vehicle&quot; has the meaning ascribed to such term by section 125 of the vehicle and traffic law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201956" number="39785" version="1272">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department and the department of parks and recreation, in consultation with the department of city planning, the department of design and construction, the department of environmental protection and a contracted entity, as defined in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-821" destination-id="0-0-0-10139">22-821</LINK>, shall develop a citywide greenway plan that details the development of greenways throughout the city, with the goal of achieving a comprehensive citywide network of greenways. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201955" number="39786" version="1272">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than March 30, 2023, the department and the department of parks and recreation shall create an internal working group to draft the citywide greenway plan required pursuant to subdivision b of this section. Such citywide greenway plan shall: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201954" number="39787" version="1272">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identify locations throughout the city that are feasible for development into a greenway or connection to the existing greenway network, including a description of the necessary steps associated with the completion of such development or connection; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201953" number="39788" version="1272">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Include a list of early action greenway projects prioritized for implementation, with priority given to proposed projects in low- and moderate-income communities; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201952" number="39789" version="1272">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identify opportunities for integrating green infrastructure, such as permeable surfaces and other flood mitigation interventions; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201951" number="39790" version="1272">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Include a map that shall be posted on the website of the department and to which a link shall be provided on the website of the department of parks and recreation. Such map shall be updated no less than annually. Such map shall display greenways currently available for public use as well as greenway projects and future greenways identified in such citywide greenway plan and their current status. Such map shall include, for any section of a greenway that is fully closed for public use for a period of at least three months, a description of the reason for such closure, a description of the alternate route designated in response to such closure, and the estimated timeline associated with reopening such section for public use. Such map shall also indicate the federal, state, local or non-governmental agency, authority or other entity with jurisdiction over greenway projects and future greenways identified in such citywide greenway plan and any such section of an existing greenway that is closed for public use. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201950" number="39791" version="1272">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The citywide greenway plan required pursuant to subdivision b of this section shall be completed by December 1, 2024, and shall be updated by December 1 of 2026 and by December 1 of every fifth year thereafter. The initial citywide greenway plan required pursuant to subdivision b of this section and all subsequent versions of such plan shall be posted on the websites of the department and the department of parks and recreation within 30 days after completion. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201949" number="39792" version="1272">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than February 1, 2025, and by February 1 of each year thereafter, the department and the department of parks and recreation shall submit to the mayor and the speaker of the council, and post on the websites of the department and the department of parks and recreation, respectively, a greenway development report that provides a summary of the implementation of the citywide greenway plan required pursuant to subdivision b of this section and the updating of such plan pursuant to subdivision d of this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201948" number="39793" version="1272">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the purposes of implementing the citywide greenway plan required pursuant to subdivision b of this section and submitting the report required pursuant to subdivision e of this section, the department and the department of parks and recreation shall regularly engage with community boards in community districts that contain thoroughfares or other locations that are potentially suitable for development into a section of greenway, and, where feasible, consult with any federal, state, local or non-governmental agency, authority or other entity that has jurisdiction over any respective aspect of greenway development. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201947" number="39794" version="1272">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For any greenway that is proposed for future development in the citywide greenway plan required pursuant to subdivision b of this section, within seven days after such plan containing such proposal is posted on the websites of the department and the department of parks and recreation pursuant to subdivision d of this section, the department or the department of parks and recreation shall provide notice and an opportunity to request a presentation on such proposal to the community board for each affected community district. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201946" number="39795" version="1272">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The citywide greenway plan required pursuant to subdivision b of this section shall not be construed as a plan for the purposes of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-a" destination-id="0-0-0-0">197-a</LINK> of the charter. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-201943" number="39796" version="1272">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2022/115, 11/27/2022, eff. 11/27/2022) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>