<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-1967" number="2704" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 2: Real Property Management</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1251" name="T04C002"/>Chapter 2: Real Property Management</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-1968" number="2705" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 4-201 Commissioner of citywide administrative services, functions. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1253" name="4-201"/>§ 4-201 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commissioner of citywide administrative services, functions. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1969" number="2706" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of citywide administrative services under the direction of the mayor may, in his or her discretion, require any person offering to sell to the city real property located within the city, or any agent of such person, or any officer or agent of a corporation offering to sell such real property to the city, to be sworn before the commissioner or a person deputized by the commissioner, and to answer orally as to the persons interested in the real property, the price paid by the owner therefor, the interest of any other person, as broker, agent or other intermediary, in effecting the proposed sale to the city, and as to any other facts and circumstances affecting the propriety of the purchase of such property by the city, and the fair market value thereof. Any other person having knowledge of any relevant and material fact or circumstance affecting the propriety of the proposed purchase by the city or the fair market value of the real property to be acquired, may likewise be examined under oath. Willful false swearing before the commissioner or a person deputized by the commissioner is perjury and punishable as such, and in a prosecution for perjury, it shall be no defense that such false swearing did not aid in effecting a sale of such property to the city, or in fixing the price paid therefor. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1970" number="2707" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner, under the direction of the board of estimate, shall:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1971" number="2708" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>After due inquiry to be made by the commissioner, present to the board, a statement, in writing, of the facts relating to any real property proposed to be leased and the purpose for which such property is required by the city, with a report embodying the commissioner&apos;s opinion, and the reasons therefor, as to the fair and reasonable rent of such premises. The commissioner shall enter into, on behalf of the city, any lease, authorized by the board, of property leased to the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1972" number="2709" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Recommend that legal proceedings be taken when necessary to enforce payment of rents or moneys due the city from city real property or to obtain possession of premises to which the city is entitled.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1973" number="2710" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Report to the board whether or not it will be in the public interest to lease or otherwise dispose of the property transferred to the commissioner pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="4-107" destination-id="0-0-0-1223">4-107</LINK> of the code, provided that no such report shall be required with respect to the leasing or renting or the granting of licenses, permits or other authorizations for the use of real property entered into by the commissioner pursuant to the provisions of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="4-203" destination-id="0-0-0-1255">4-203</LINK> of the code. The commissioner, under the sanction of the board, shall appoint experienced and qualified appraisers upon behalf of the city to settle the rent or renewal of any lease, or the value of the building, to be paid for on the expiration of any lease, in which the city is or shall be interested, whenever by the provisions of such lease the appointment of appraisers is required. All leases authorized by the board shall be executed by (a) either the mayor or the commissioner of citywide administrative services and (b) the city clerk, under their hands and the seal of the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1974" number="2711" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When any person offers to purchase or lease real property belonging to the city, have discretion to require such person to deposit with the department of finance a sum of money, prescribed by the commissioner, as security that such person will pay the amount bid by that person upon the sale or lease of such property at public auction or by sealed bids, and that such person will execute and deliver all papers necessary to carry such sale or lease into effect, if that person&apos;s bid for the purchase or lease of such property shall be accepted. Such deposit shall, in the event of the default of the person depositing the same, pay the amount bid by such person, or of that person&apos;s failure to execute and deliver the necessary papers as hereinbefore provided, become the property of the city as liquidated damages. Upon the sale or lease of real property belonging to the city as herein provided, if such real property shall be sold or leased to a purchaser or lessee procured by a broker and the purchase price or rental accepted by the city upon the consummation of the sale or lease shall equal or exceed the offer made by such broker in behalf of the purchaser or lessee, the city is hereby authorized to pay the usual commissions to such broker. No commissions shall be paid for the procuring of any sale or lease unless the written authority of the broker to make the offer, signed by the person for whom the broker is acting, shall be filed in the department of citywide administrative services before the day the sale or lease of the property is advertised to take place, or at such time prior thereto as may be fixed by the commissioner of citywide administrative services.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1975" number="2712" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Report to the board whether or not it is in the public interest to grant permission to the lessee or assignee of a lease made by the city for a term of one year or longer, to assign the same or to underlet the demised premises notwithstanding any provision in the lease to the contrary. A prerequisite to any favorable report shall be the prior payment of all arrears of rent on the premises.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1976" number="2713" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Preserve in a book to be kept in the commissioner&apos;s office for that purpose, to be called the &quot;record of quit-rents&quot;, maps of all grants of land heretofore made by the city, on which quit-rents are payable, showing the original grants and subdivisions thereof as definitely as these can be ascertained. The commissioner shall receive the sums proportionately due from each owner in payment of the portion of the moneys payable under the original grant, as such sums, from time to time, shall become payable and shall likewise receive any commuted quit-rents paid as hereinafter provided. The commissioner of citywide administrative services, on receiving written notice from the grantee of the city, or his or her assignee, of the sale of any portion of land subject to quit-rent, shall enter in the record of quit-rents the name of the purchaser, the date of the sale, and the portion of the land sold. The commissioner thereafter shall receive the sum proportionately due from such purchaser in payment of his or her portion of the moneys payable under the original grant, as the same, from time to time, shall become payable, and the commissioner shall receive from the owner of the lot or parcel mentioned in the notice, or the owner&apos;s legal representative, the sum proportionately due from the owner in payment of his or her proportion of the moneys payable under the original grant. When land heretofore granted by the city, subject to a quit-rent, portions of which have been assigned by the grantee, shall be re-entered by the city for nonpayment of the quit-rent, the commissioner may grant releases in severalty to such of the assignees of portions of the land granted as shall, within six months from the re-entry, pay to the commissioner their respective apportionments of commutation money and the expenses of re-entry and conveyance, with such portions of the rent as may be justly due from the respective assignees for the land held by them, as the same shall be apportioned by the commissioner. Whenever any person shall desire to commute any quit-rent due the city, the commissioner shall calculate such commutation at the rate of six per cent and, upon the production of evidence that such quit-rent and all arrears of rent have been paid into the treasury of the city to the credit of the real property fund, the mayor and city clerk shall execute a release of such quit-rent. All sums received by the commissioner pursuant to the provisions of this subdivision shall be paid daily to the commissioner of finance.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1977" number="2714" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon the payment in full of the principal and interest due on any bond and mortgage held by the city, the mayor and city clerk shall execute, under their hands and the seal of the city, upon evidence being exhibited to them showing that the principal and interest on such bond and mortgage have been paid into the treasury of the city to the credit of the appropriate fund an assignment or proper satisfaction of said bond and mortgage. The release by such officials of any part of the premises described in such mortgage from the lien created by such mortgage is prohibited.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1978" number="2715" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Keep on file in the department of citywide administrative services all title deeds, leases, bonds, mortgages, or other assurances of title, except as otherwise provided by law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1979" number="2716" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Record all grants, leases and counter-parts of leases, and all deeds executed by the city in proper books. The commissioner shall also keep a record of all property owned and acquired by the city. Such record shall show the date the property was acquired, the tax map description thereof, the borough in which the property is located, and shall be properly cross indexed with reference to the original deeds of acquisition. The commissioner shall also keep a record of all property on which rent is in arrears and the amounts of the arrearages.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1980" number="2717" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>10.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Submit to the corporation counsel for approval as to correctness of form all contracts, leases or other legal documents of similar character, except forms prepared or approved by the corporation counsel. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1981" number="2718" version="1582">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1996/059" destination-id="0-0-0-26052">L.L. 1996/059</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-216098" number="2719" version="1582">
										<HEADING>§ 4-202 Collection of rents. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1257" name="4-202"/>§ 4-202 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Collection of rents. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1982" number="2720" version="1759">
											<PARA>The commissioner of citywide administrative services shall collect all rents, charges and any other sums payable or due to the city from any tenant, occupant or other person, under any lease, rental agreement, permit, license or otherwise, for occupancy, use and occupation or other use of real property of the city or any portion of such property, which the commissioner is under the duty to manage and superintend. It shall be the duty of the commissioner to collect rental or other charges for temporary occupancy, use and occupation or other use of property acquired by the city for public purposes between the time of the acquisition thereof and the time when the same can be actually utilized for the purpose for which it was acquired, and for occupancy, use and occupation or other use of all property which, having been originally acquired for public purposes, has ceased to be used for such purposes. All such rents, charges and other sums collected by the commissioner as provided in this section shall be paid by the commissioner daily to the commissioner of finance and a public record thereof shall be kept in the commissioner&apos;s office.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1983" number="2721" version="1582">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1996/059" destination-id="0-0-0-26052">L.L. 1996/059</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-216099" number="2722" version="1582">
										<HEADING>§ 4-203 Leasing or renting of real property by commissioner of citywide administrative services. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1255" name="4-203"/>§ 4-203 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Leasing or renting of real property by commissioner of citywide administrative services. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1984" number="2723" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Under the conditions and subject to the restrictions hereinafter set forth in this section, the commissioner shall have power, without the concurrence of any other officer or agency, to lease or rent in behalf of the city to any person, or to grant to any person in behalf of the city, a permit or license or other authorization for the use of, any real property of the city or portion thereof which the commissioner is authorized to manage and super- intend. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1985" number="2724" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner may lease or rent, or grant any such permit, license or authorization with respect to any such property or portion thereof, for such rental or other charge and upon such terms and conditions as the commissioner may determine, in any case where the terms of such lease, rental agreement, permit, license or other authorization is less than one year except that where such property or portion thereof has previously been leased, rented, the subject of such a permit, license or other authorization, the term of such lease, rental agreement, permit, license or other authorization may be for a term of up to five years, and the rental or other charge fixed by the commissioner therein does not exceed five thousand dollars per month or any equivalent of such rental or charge. Before the commissioner shall enter into any such lease or rental agreement or issue any such permit, license or other authorization, there shall be filed in the department and with the board of estimate a written certification signed by two officers or employees of the department having the rank of senior real estate manager or an equivalent or higher rank, stating that the rental or other charge fixed therein is fair and reasonable.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1986" number="2725" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except as otherwise provided in subdivision d of this section, the commissioner may lease or rent or grant a permit, license or other authorization with respect to any such property or portion thereof, only for the highest marketable price or rental at public auction or by sealed bids and after advertisement for at least fifteen days in the City Record and after appraisal made within ninety days prior to such transaction, in any case where the term of such lease, rental agreement, permit, license or other authorization is less than one year, and the rental or other charge fixed therein is more than five thousand dollars per month or any equivalent thereof.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1987" number="2726" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In any case where, on the date of the acquisition of any such real property by the city by purchase, condemnation or otherwise, if any tenant, occupant or other person is lawfully in possession of such property or any portion thereof, or holds a permit, license or other authorization of use thereof, the commissioner may lease or rent to any such tenant, occupant or other person, the premises occupied by him or her on such date, or may grant to such holder the rights or privileges enjoyed by him or her on such date, at a rental or other charge in excess of five thousand dollars per month or any equivalent thereof, and upon such terms and conditions as the commissioner may determine, provided (i) the terms of such lease, rental agreement, permit, license or other authorization is no more than five years, and (ii) the possession of such tenant, occupant or other person, or the right or privilege of use enjoyed by such holder is continuous from such date and (iii) there shall be filed in the department, with respect to such lease, rental agreement, permit, license or other authorization, a written certification, signed by two officers or employees of the department having the rank of senior real estate manager or an equivalent or higher rank, stating that the rental or other charge fixed therein is fair and reasonable.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1988" number="2727" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In any case where the board of estimate and Triborough bridge and tunnel authority shall agree that any real property under the jurisdiction of such authority shall be managed and superintended by the commissioner, he or she shall, in accordance with the terms of such agreement, manage and superintend such property and collect the rents, charges and other proceeds therefrom, and shall dispose of such moneys in the manner provided in such agreement. The commissioner, with the prior approval of such authority, and in accordance with the applicable provisions of subdivisions b, c and d of this section, may lease or rent or grant permits, licenses or other authorizations with respect to any real property or any portion thereof subject to such agreement. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1989" number="2728" version="1582">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1996/059" destination-id="0-0-0-26052">L.L. 1996/059</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-216100" number="2729" version="1582">
										<HEADING>§ 4-204 Demolition of buildings and structures. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1259" name="4-204"/>§ 4-204 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Demolition of buildings and structures. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1990" number="2730" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of citywide administrative services or the commissioner of housing preservation and development, when requested to do so by the mayor, may cause to be demolished any buildings or structures located on any real property which the commissioner is authorized to manage and superintend. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1991" number="2731" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever a borough superintendent of the department of buildings requests, pursuant to the provisions of section 26-240 of the code, that the commissioner demolish any building or structure or part thereof as to which a precept has been issued pursuant to the provisions of section 26-239 of the code, the commissioner shall cause same to be demolished in accordance with such request.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1992" number="2732" version="1759">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner may effect any demolition work mentioned in subdivision a or b of this section, through personnel of the city or by letting a contract for such work, or where such board shall so direct, such demolition work shall be done, under the direction of the commissioner, by any other agency of the city designated by the board, through personnel of the city or through the letting of a contract by such agency for the work. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1993" number="2733" version="1582">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1996/059" destination-id="0-0-0-26052">L.L. 1996/059</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-216101" number="2734" version="1582">
										<HEADING>§ 4-205 Supervision of management activities of developers. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1261" name="4-205"/>§ 4-205 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Supervision of management activities of developers. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1994" number="2735" version="3">
											<PARA>The commissioner of citywide administrative services or, when designated by the mayor, the commissioner of design and construction, shall supervise the management activities of any party to a contract with the city which requires such party to develop any real property in accordance with the terms of such contract, in any case where such contract provides that the commissioner shall exercise such supervision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1995" number="2736" version="1582">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1996/059" destination-id="0-0-0-26052">L.L. 1996/059</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-216102" number="2737" version="1582">
										<HEADING>§ 4-206 Displaying a POW/MIA flag over public property. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1263" name="4-206"/>§ 4-206 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Displaying a POW/MIA flag over public property. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1996" number="2738" version="3">
											<PARA>Until such time as all persons listed as missing in action from any branch of the United States Armed Forces, and all persons from any branch of our armed forces who are prisoners of war, are accounted for by the United States government, the commissioner of citywide administrative services shall assure that the Prisoner of War/Missing in Action (POW/MIA) flag is flown: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1997" number="2739" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>over all borough halls every day the American flag is flown; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1998" number="2740" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>over all public property supervised by the commissioner on the dates when the American flag is flown in observance of Memorial Day, Veterans Day, and POW/MIA day. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-1999" number="2741" version="1582">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1996/059" destination-id="0-0-0-26052">L.L. 1996/059</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-216103" number="2742" version="1869">
										<HEADING>§ 4-207 Assessment of certain clean on-site power generation technologies. [Repealed]</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1265" name="4-207"/>§ 4-207 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Assessment of certain clean on-site power generation technologies. [Repealed]</CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-154524" number="2743" version="1914">
											<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2022/060, 5/15/2022, eff. 5/15/2022; Repealed L.L. 2023/069, 5/29/2023, eff. 6/28/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-086]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-224835" number="2744" version="1869">
										<HEADING>§ 4-207.1 Photovoltaic systems for city-owned buildings.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1267" name="4-207.1"/>§ 4-207.1 Photovoltaic systems for city-owned buildings.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229046" number="2745" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>As used in this section: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2005" number="2746" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">City building.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;city building&quot; shall have the meaning ascribed to such term in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="28-309.2" destination-id="0-0-0-1269">28-309.2</LINK> of the code. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229471" number="2747" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Contracted entity.</CHARFORMAT> The term “contracted entity” means a local development corporation or other not-for-profit corporation, a majority of whose members are appointed by the mayor, that contracts with the city to provide or administer economic development benefits on behalf of the city and expending city capital appropriations in connection therewith, except that such term does not include the Brooklyn navy yard development entity as defined in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-821" destination-id="0-0-0-10139">22-821</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229473" number="2748" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cost effective.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;cost effective&quot; means, with respect to the installation of a photovoltaic system or additional photovoltaic system capacity, one or more of the following determinations: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2007" number="2749" version="1811">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The cumulative savings expected to result from such installation, including expected savings in energy costs, will in 25 years or less, equal or exceed the expected costs of such installation, less all federal, state and other non-city governmental assistance available to offset the cost of such installation and including the social cost of carbon value, as described in paragraphs 3 and 4 of subdivision d of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="3-125" destination-id="0-0-0-879">3-125</LINK> of the code; provided, however, that a higher site- or project-specific social cost of carbon value may be developed and used in lieu of the social cost of carbon value described in such paragraphs. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2008" number="2750" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A power purchase agreement relating to such installation, entered into with the city, offers electricity rates for photovoltaic systems that meet or are lower than the average prevailing utility rates. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2009" number="2751" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;department&quot; means the department of citywide administrative services. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2010" number="2752" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eligible roof.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;eligible roof&quot; means a city building roof that is less than or equal to ten years old and in good condition, as defined by city asset management standards. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2011" number="2753" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>By December 31, 2035, the department, in coordination with any other relevant agency, shall install, maintain, and operate photovoltaic systems with a total power capacity of at least 150 megawatts on city building roofs and other city-owned property, including but not limited to parking lots, industrial sites, and property controlled, leased, or operated by a contracted entity. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229479" number="2754" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>By September 1, 2030, the department, in coordination with any other relevant agency, shall install at least 100 megawatts of the photovoltaic systems required to be installed pursuant to paragraph 1 of this subdivision. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229478" number="2755" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In meeting the requirements of subdivision b of this section, the department shall prioritize the installation of photovoltaic systems in disadvantaged communities, as defined by section 75-0101 of the environmental conservation law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229477" number="2756" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department, in coordination with any other relevant agency, shall set criteria for increasing the number of eligible roofs in order to meet the requirements of subdivision b of this section. The department shall identify such criteria and any increase in the number of eligible roofs in the report required by subdivision f of this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229476" number="2757" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>By September 1, 2028, the department shall submit to the speaker of the council and the mayor, and make publicly available online, a report that identifies factors to consider when making determinations about the long-term ownership, operation, and maintenance of photovoltaic systems installed pursuant to subdivision b of this section that are the subject of power purchase agreements. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229475" number="2758" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>By September 1, 2030, the department shall submit to the speaker of the council and the mayor, and make publicly available online, a report (i) identifying the expected location and size, expressed in total power capacity (in kilowatts), of each photovoltaic system to be installed pursuant to subdivision b of this section that has not been installed as of September 1, 2030, and (ii) indicating whether a request for proposals has been issued for all contracts necessary to install such photovoltaic systems, and, if so, providing a planned timeline, including a planned date of completion, for all work to be performed pursuant to such contracts. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229472" number="2759" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>By December 31, 2016, and by September 1 of every second year thereafter, the department, with the cooperation of all appropriate city agencies, shall submit to the speaker of the council and the mayor, and make publicly available online, a report containing, at a minimum, the following information for each city building, disaggregated by council district: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2012" number="2760" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The street address of such building; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2013" number="2761" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The age of such building&apos;s roof; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2014" number="2762" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whether such building&apos;s roof is in good condition, as defined by city asset management standards; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2015" number="2763" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The following information for 100 unique roofs that are not eligible roofs and for which such information has not been included in any prior report: the estimated photovoltaic system size that could be installed on each such roof, as expressed in installed power capacity (in kilowatts), if such roof were repaired or replaced so as to become an eligible roof; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229480" number="2764" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each eligible roof, the following information will be provided: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2016" number="2765" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The estimated potential photovoltaic system size that could be installed on such roof, as expressed in installed power capacity (in kilowatts); <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2017" number="2766" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The estimated potential energy that could be generated by such system annually (in kilowatt-hours); and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2018" number="2767" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The estimated amount of greenhouse gas emissions reduced or avoided annually due to the use of such system; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2019" number="2768" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whether a photovoltaic system has been installed at such building and, if such a system has been installed, a description thereof, including: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2020" number="2769" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The photovoltaic system size expressed in installed power capacity (in kilowatts), as a percentage of the maximum peak power need identified for such building and, if such building has an eligible roof, as a percentage of the maximum photovoltaic system size that could be cost effectively installed on the roof of such building; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2021" number="2770" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The energy generated by such system annually (in kilowatt-hours) and expressed as a percentage of the estimated energy consumption of such building; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2022" number="2771" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The date of such installation; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2023" number="2772" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The total cost of such system and a description of how the installation of such system was financed, including whether such financing involved a power purchase agreement entered into with the city; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2024" number="2773" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The energy cost savings resulting from and revenue generated by such system annually; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2026" number="2774" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The estimated amount of greenhouse gas emissions reduced or avoided due to such system annually; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229482" number="2775" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If such system was installed pursuant to a power purchase agreement, the legal name of the prime contractor responsible for such installation; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229481" number="2776" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If a photovoltaic system has not been installed at such building, the reasons that such a system was not installed and, where an alternate sustainability project, structural change or other use has been proposed or carried out for the roof of such building, a description of such alternate project, structural change or use including: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2027" number="2777" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The projected benefits thereof; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2028" number="2778" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The estimated energy cost savings, if applicable; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2029" number="2779" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The estimated amount of greenhouse gas emissions reduced or avoided annually due to such project, structural change or use, if applicable, and associated economic value as determined using the social cost of carbon value, as described in paragraphs 3 and 4 of subdivision d of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="3-125" destination-id="0-0-0-879">3-125</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2030" number="2780" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall also include in the report required by subdivision f of this section, the following information for each city-owned property, other than a city building, on which a photovoltaic system has been installed: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229493" number="2781" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The street address of such property; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229492" number="2782" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The property’s primary use; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229491" number="2783" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The photovoltaic system size expressed in installed power capacity (in kilowatts); <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229490" number="2784" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The energy generated by such system annually (in kilowatt-hours); <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229489" number="2785" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The date on which such system was installed; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229488" number="2786" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The total cost of such system and a description of how the installation of such system was financed, including whether such financing involved a power purchase agreement entered into with the city; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229487" number="2787" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The energy cost savings resulting from and revenue generated by such system annually; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229486" number="2788" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The estimated amount of greenhouse gas emissions reduced or avoided due to such system annually; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229485" number="2789" version="2115">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If such system was installed pursuant to a power purchase agreement, the legal name of the prime contractor responsible for such installation. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229483" number="2790" version="2115">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2016/024, 3/14/2016, eff. 3/14/2016; Am. L.L. 2024/099, 10/26/2024, eff. 12/10/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2031" number="2791" version="2106">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2024/099" destination-id="0-0-0-27852">L.L. 2024/099</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-229047" number="2792" version="2106">
										<HEADING>§ 4-207.2 Monitoring electricity and fossil fuel usage in certain facilities.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1271" name="4-207.2"/>§ 4-207.2 Monitoring electricity and fossil fuel usage in certain facilities.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2032" number="2793" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the purposes of this section: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2033" number="2794" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Covered facility.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;covered facility&quot; means a facility for which the city is responsible for the payment of electricity utility bills and where at least one electricity account exists for which demand was at least 300 kilowatts (kW) during the previous fiscal year. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2034" number="2795" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;department&quot; means the department of citywide administrative services. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2035" number="2796" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Electricity usage telemetry equipment.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;electricity usage telemetry equipment&quot; means equipment that allows electricity usage to be measured and reported in near real-time. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2036" number="2797" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than December 31, 2018, and every year for a period of three years from that date, the department shall submit to the speaker of the council and to the mayor, and make publicly available on its website, a report on electricity and fossil fuel usage in, and assessments of or improvements made to the envelopes of, certain covered facilities. Such report shall include, but need not be limited to, the following information: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2037" number="2798" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each covered facility: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2038" number="2799" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Street address; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2039" number="2800" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A statement as to whether electricity usage telemetry equipment has been installed at such facility; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2040" number="2801" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If such electricity usage telemetry equipment has not been installed at such facility, whether such installation is appropriate and practicable and, if appropriate and practicable, the year such equipment is expected to be installed; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2041" number="2802" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The electricity usage of such facility during the previous fiscal year or the portion of such period of time that such facility was a covered facility; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2042" number="2803" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The change in such facility&apos;s electricity usage over the last five fiscal years or the portion of such period of time that such facility was a covered facility; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2043" number="2804" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The total change in electricity usage over the same period for all covered facilities. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2044" number="2805" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each covered facility that is a city-owned building: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2045" number="2806" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The amount of fossil fuel used by such facility during the previous fiscal year or the portion of such period of time that such facility was a covered facility and a city-owned building; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2046" number="2807" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The change in such facility&apos;s fossil fuel usage over the last five fiscal years or the portion of such period of time that such facility was a covered facility and a city-owned building; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2047" number="2808" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The total change in fossil fuel usage over the same period for all covered facilities that are city-owned buildings; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2048" number="2809" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A statement as to whether the city has assessed the envelope of such facility during the previous fiscal year; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2049" number="2810" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A description of any improvements made to the envelope of such facility that were commenced, continued or completed during the previous fiscal year. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2050" number="2811" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department, in conjunction with any other appropriate city agency, shall coordinate the installation of electricity usage telemetry equipment in any covered facility where the department has determined that installation of such equipment is appropriate and practicable. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2051" number="2812" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Following installation of electricity usage telemetry equipment by the department at a covered facility, the department shall train agency personnel responsible for such facility in using such equipment to monitor electricity usage. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2052" number="2813" version="702">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2018/045, 1/11/2018, eff. 1/11/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-113495" number="2814" version="212">
										<HEADING>§ 4-207.3 Utility-scale energy storage systems for city buildings.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-19325" name="4-207.3"/>§ 4-207.3 Utility-scale energy storage systems for city buildings.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113510" number="2815" version="212">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in this section, the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113509" number="2816" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Energy storage system.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;energy storage system&quot; means a set of methods and technologies for storing potential, kinetic, chemical, electromagnetic, thermal, or any other type of energy, including compressed air, flywheels, batteries, superconducting magnetic storage and ice storage, so that such energy may be used at a time other than when it is generated. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113508" number="2817" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">City building.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;city building&quot; means a building that is owned by the city or for which the city regularly pays all of the annual energy bills, or a cultural institution that is in the cultural institutions group as determined by the department of cultural affairs for which the city regularly pays all or part of the annual energy bills. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113507" number="2818" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commissioner.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;commissioner&quot; means the commissioner of citywide administrative services <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113506" number="2819" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cost effective.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;cost effective&quot; means, with respect to the installation of an energy storage system, that the cumulative savings in energy costs expected to result from the use of such system will, within 15 years of installation of such system, be equal to or exceed the expected costs of the acquisition, installation, and maintenance of such system during that same time period. The determination of cost effectiveness shall not include any savings in energy costs directly attributed to federal, state and other non-city governmental assistance, but shall include the social cost of carbon value, as provided in paragraph 3 of subdivision d of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="3-125" destination-id="0-0-0-879">3-125</LINK> or pursuant to paragraph 4 of subdivision d of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="3-125" destination-id="0-0-0-879">3-125</LINK>, provided however, that a site- or project-specific social cost of carbon value may be developed and used in lieu of the social cost of carbon value provided in or pursuant to such paragraphs if such site- or project-specific social cost of carbon value is higher than the social cost of carbon value provided in or pursuant to such paragraphs. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113505" number="2820" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;department&quot; means the department of citywide administrative services. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113504" number="2821" version="212">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than April 30, 2021, the department, or any other agency authorized by the commissioner, shall complete a study regarding the feasibility of the installation and use of each available type of utility-scale energy storage systems in each city building, and submit to the mayor and the speaker of the council a copy of such study. Such study shall include a review of any available federal or state funds or incentives for the acquisition, installation, operation or maintenance of such systems. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113503" number="2822" version="212">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department, or any other agency authorized by the commissioner, shall, in accordance with all applicable law, install utility-scale energy storage systems on all city buildings where the installation of such systems is cost effective, as determined by the study described in subdivision b. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113502" number="2823" version="212">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than December 15, 2021, the department shall report to the mayor and the speaker of the council: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113501" number="2824" version="212">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The types of utility-scale energy storage systems that were studied, as applied to various city buildings; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113500" number="2825" version="212">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The city buildings where the installation of a utility-scale energy storage system may be appropriate, as determined by the department and the projected annual energy and other cost savings for each such system, both individually and in the aggregate; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113499" number="2826" version="212">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of city buildings where the installation of a utility-scale energy storage system has been commenced by the department or other agency authorized by the commissioner; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113498" number="2827" version="217">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of city buildings where the installation of a utility-scale energy storage system has been completed by the department or other agency authorized by the commissioner, the type of such system installed on such building, and the annual energy and other cost savings associated with the installation and use of such systems. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113496" number="2828" version="702">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2019/181, 10/26/2019, eff. 10/26/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113511" number="2829" version="496">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2019/181" destination-id="0-0-0-20379">L.L. 2019/181</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-053]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-128552" number="2830" version="496">
										<HEADING>§ 4-207.4 Solar water heating and thermal energy systems for city-owned buildings.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-19327" name="4-207.4"/>§ 4-207.4 Solar water heating and thermal energy systems for city-owned buildings.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113525" number="2831" version="212">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>As used in this section, the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113524" number="2832" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">City building.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;city building&quot; means a building that is owned by the city or for which the city regularly pays all of the annual energy bills, or a cultural institution that is in the cultural institutions group as determined by the department of cultural affairs for which the city regularly pays all or part of the annual energy bills. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113523" number="2833" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commissioner.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;commissioner&quot; means the commissioner of citywide administrative services. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113522" number="2834" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cost effective.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;cost effective&quot; means, with respect to the installation of a solar water heating or thermal energy system, that the cumulative savings expected to result from the use of such system, including expected savings in energy costs, will, within 25 years of such installation, be equal to or exceed the expected costs of the acquisition, installation, and maintenance of such system during that same time period. The determination of cost effectiveness shall not include any savings in costs directly attributed to federal, state and other non-city governmental assistance, but shall include the social cost of carbon value, as provided in paragraph 3 of subdivision d of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="3-125" destination-id="0-0-0-879">3-125</LINK> or pursuant to paragraph 4 of subdivision d of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="3-125" destination-id="0-0-0-879">3-125</LINK>, provided, however, that a site- or project-specific social cost of carbon value may be developed and used in lieu of the social cost of carbon value provided in or pursuant to such paragraphs if such site- or project-specific social cost of carbon value is higher than the social cost of carbon value provided in or pursuant to such paragraphs. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113521" number="2835" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;department&quot; means the department of citywide administrative services. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113520" number="2836" version="217">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than April 30, 2021, the department, or any other agency authorized by the commissioner, shall conduct a study identifying the types of city-owned buildings where solar water heating and thermal energy systems may be appropriate and cost-effective, and submit such study to the mayor and the speaker of the council. Such study shall describe any federal or state funds or incentives that would be available to defray costs related to the installation, operation or maintenance of such systems. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113519" number="2837" version="212">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department, or any other agency authorized by the commissioner, shall, in accordance with all applicable law, install a solar water heating system or a thermal energy system on all city-owned buildings where the traditional hot water or space heating equipment has reached the end of its useful life, provided that such a solar water heating system or thermal energy system is cost effective, as determined by the study described in subdivision b. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113518" number="2838" version="212">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than December 15, 2021, the department shall report to the mayor and the speaker of the council: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113517" number="2839" version="212">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The types of city buildings where the installation of a solar water heating or thermal energy system may be appropriate, as determined by the department; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113516" number="2840" version="217">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of city buildings where the installation of a solar water heating or thermal energy system has been commenced by the department of other agency authorized by the commissioner; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113515" number="2841" version="212">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of city buildings where the installation of a solar water heating or thermal energy system has been completed by the department of other agency authorized by the commissioner; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113514" number="2842" version="212">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The annual energy and other cost savings, and any other environmental benefits associated with the use of such completed systems. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113512" number="2843" version="702">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2019/183, 10/26/2019, eff. 10/26/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-2053" number="2844" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 4-208 List of city-owned and operated real property. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1273" name="4-208"/>§ 4-208 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">List of city-owned and operated real property. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2054" number="2845" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department of citywide administrative services shall keep and maintain a complete list of the location and current use of all real property owned or leased by the city. For each parcel of property, such list shall include, but need not be limited to, the following information to the extent such information is available: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2055" number="2846" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the map on which the property appears in the most recent atlas of the property; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2056" number="2847" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the tax block number; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2057" number="2848" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the tax lot number; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2058" number="2849" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the address or name of the property, if applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2059" number="2850" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the agency to which the property is assigned; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2060" number="2851" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>sufficient information to determine the property&apos;s current use or to determine that it has no current use; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2061" number="2852" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>total area of the property, expressed in square feet and rounded to the nearest integer; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2062" number="2853" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the property contains the presence of an open petroleum spill; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2063" number="2854" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the property is enrolled in a government cleanup program, and if so, the name of such program; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2064" number="2855" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(10)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the year construction of the structure or structures was completed and whether such year is an estimate, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2065" number="2856" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(11)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of structures, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2066" number="2857" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(12)<TAB tab-count="1"/>total gross area of all structures expressed in square feet and rounded to the nearest integer, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2067" number="2858" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(13)<TAB tab-count="1"/>ratio of building floor area to the area of the property, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2068" number="2859" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(14)<TAB tab-count="1"/>allowable ratio of building floor area to the area of the property, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2069" number="2860" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(15)<TAB tab-count="1"/>land use category as defined by the department of city planning; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2070" number="2861" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(16)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the community district; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2071" number="2862" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(17)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the most recent census tract; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2072" number="2863" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(18)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the most recent census block; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2073" number="2864" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(19)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the community school district; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2074" number="2865" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(20)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the city council district; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2075" number="2866" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(21)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the zip code; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2076" number="2867" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(22)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the fire company that services the property; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2077" number="2868" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(23)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the health area; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2078" number="2869" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(24)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the health center district; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2079" number="2870" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(25)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the police precinct; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2080" number="2871" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(26)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the major use of the structure or structures, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2081" number="2872" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(27)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of easements, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2082" number="2873" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(28)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the exterior dimensions of the portion of the structure or structures allocated for commercial use, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2083" number="2874" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(29)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the exterior dimensions of the portion of the structure or structures allocated for residential use, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2084" number="2875" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(30)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the exterior dimensions of the portion of the structure or structures allocated for office use, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2085" number="2876" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(31)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the exterior dimensions of the portion of the structure or structures allocated for retail use, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2086" number="2877" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(32)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the exterior dimensions of the portion of the structure or structures allocated for garage use, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2087" number="2878" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(33)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the exterior dimensions of the portion of the structure or structures allocated for storage or loft use, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2088" number="2879" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(34)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the exterior dimensions of the portion of the structure or structures allocated for factory use, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2089" number="2880" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(35)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the exterior dimensions of the portion of the structure or structures allocated for a use or uses other than residential, office, retail, garage, storage, loft or factory use, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2090" number="2881" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(36)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of full and partial stories starting from the ground floor in the primary structure, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2091" number="2882" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(37)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the sum of residential units in all structures, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2092" number="2883" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(38)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the sum of residential and non-residential units in all structures, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2093" number="2884" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(39)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the frontage, measured in feet; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2094" number="2885" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(40)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the depth, measured in feet; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2095" number="2886" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(41)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the frontage along the street, measured in feet; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2096" number="2887" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(42)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the depth of the structure or structures, which is the effective perpendicular distance, measured in feet, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2097" number="2888" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(43)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the structure or structures are detached, semi-detached or attached to neighboring structures, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2098" number="2889" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(44)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the property is irregularly shaped; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2099" number="2890" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(45)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the location relative to another lot or the water, expressed as mixed or unknown, block assemblage, waterfront, corner, through, inside, interior, island, alley or submerged land; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2100" number="2891" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(46)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a description of the basement, expressed as none, full basement that is above grade, full basement that is below grade, partial basement that is above grade, partial basement that is below grade or unknown; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2101" number="2892" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(47)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the actual assessed value as of the most recent fiscal year; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2102" number="2893" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(48)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the actual exempt land value as of the most recent fiscal year; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2103" number="2894" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(49)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the actual exempt total value as of the most recent fiscal year; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2104" number="2895" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(50)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the year of the most recent alteration, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2105" number="2896" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(51)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the year of the second most recent alteration, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2106" number="2897" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(52)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the name of the historic district, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2107" number="2898" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(53)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the property is a landmark and, if so, the name of such landmark, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2108" number="2899" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(54)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the condominium number assigned to the complex, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2109" number="2900" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(55)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the coordinate of the XY coordinate pair that depicts the property&apos;s approximate location as expressed in the New York-Long Island state plane coordination system; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2110" number="2901" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(56)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the e-designation number associated with the property, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2111" number="2902" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(57)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the property is located in an industrial business zone;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2112" number="2903" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(58)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the primary zoning classification of the property; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2113" number="2904" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(59)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the zoning designation occupying the second greatest percentage of the property&apos;s area, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2114" number="2905" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(60)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the primary commercial overlay assigned to the property, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2115" number="2906" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(61)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the commercial overlay occupying the second greatest percentage of the property&apos;s area, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2116" number="2907" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(62)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the special purpose or limited height district assigned to the property, where applicable;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2117" number="2908" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(63)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the special purpose or limited height district assigned to the property occupying the second greatest percentage of the property&apos;s area, where applicable; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2118" number="2909" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(64)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the land is potentially suitable for urban agriculture; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2119" number="2910" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(65)<TAB tab-count="1"/>agency contact information, including name, telephone number and email address.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2120" number="2911" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each property managed by the economic development corporation, such list shall include the percentage of usable space actually occupied by a tenant or tenants.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2121" number="2912" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such list shall be made available to the public at no charge on a website maintained by or on behalf of the city of New York in a sortable and searchable format and for download at no charge from such website in a non-proprietary database format. Such list shall be completely updated no less than once every two years.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-2122" number="2913" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 4-209 Automated external defibrillators at youth baseball and youth softball games and practices on city land leased to youth leagues. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1275" name="4-209"/>§ 4-209 Automated external defibrillators at youth baseball and youth softball games and practices on city land leased to youth leagues. </PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113024" number="2914" version="248">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions. </CHARFORMAT>As used in this section, the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2124" number="2915" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Automated external defibrillator.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;automated external defibrillator&quot; means a medical device, approved by the United States food and drug administration, that: (i) is capable of recognizing the presence or absence in a patient of ventricular fibrillation and rapid ventricular tachycardia; (ii) is capable of determining, without intervention by an individual, whether defibrillation should be performed on a patient; (iii) upon determining that defibrillation should be performed, automatically charges and requests delivery of an electrical impulse to a patient&apos;s heart; and (iv) upon action by an individual, delivers an appropriate electrical impulse to a patient&apos;s heart to perform defibrillation. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2125" number="2916" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department. </CHARFORMAT>The term &quot;department&quot; means the department of citywide administrative services or any successor of such department. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2126" number="2917" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Training course. </CHARFORMAT>The term &quot;training course&quot; means a course approved by a nationally-recognized organization or the state emergency medical services council in the operation of automated external defibrillators. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2127" number="2918" version="248">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Youth baseball league.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;youth baseball league&quot; means a youth league that plays baseball. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-044]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-114286" number="2919" version="248">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Youth league.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;youth league&quot; means youth recreation sports leagues other than the public school leagues, including school leagues, little leagues, community based organization leagues, and unaffiliated leagues. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-044]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-114288" number="2920" version="248">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Youth recreation.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;youth recreation&quot; means athletic activity with participants who are all 17 years old or younger, but includes grade school through high school athletic programs regardless of the age of the participants. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-044]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-114289" number="2921" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Youth softball league.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;youth softball league&quot; means a youth league that plays softball. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-044]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2130" number="2922" version="248">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Subject to the provision of a sufficient number of automated external defibrillators and training courses by the department pursuant to subdivision c or subdivision k, a youth league provided with an automated external defibrillator pursuant to this section using a field for which the department is the lessor shall: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-044</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-114290" number="2923" version="248">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>make available an automated external defibrillator at every game and practice occurring at such field in which a team of such league participates; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-044]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2131" number="2924" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>where practicable, ensure that there is at least one coach, umpire or other qualified adult who is present at each such game and practice who has successfully completed a training course within 24 months of each such game and practice. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2132" number="2925" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall provide to youth baseball leagues and youth softball leagues subject to the requirements of subdivision b a sufficient number of automated external defibrillators and training courses at no cost to such leagues. Any defibrillator provided by the department to such a league shall be returned in satisfactory condition at the end of the lease or upon request of such department. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-032]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2133" number="2926" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall not lease a ballfield to a youth baseball league or a youth softball league unless such lease requires that the lessee comply with subdivision b. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-032]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2134" number="2927" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who voluntarily and without expectation of monetary compensation renders first aid or emergency treatment using an automated external defibrillator that has been made available pursuant to this section, to a person who is unconscious, ill or injured, and any individual or entity that purchases or makes available an automated external defibrillator as required by this section, is entitled to the limitation of liability provided in section 3000-a of the New York state public health law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2135" number="2928" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing contained in this section imposes any duty or obligation on any person to provide assistance with an automated external defibrillator to a victim of a medical emergency. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2136" number="2929" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing contained in this section affects the obligations or liability of emergency health providers pursuant to section 3000-b of the New York state public health law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2137" number="2930" version="248">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any youth league that violates the provisions of subdivision b shall receive a warning for a first violation, and shall be liable for a civil penalty of $500 for each subsequent violation, recoverable in a proceeding before any tribunal established within the office of administrative trials and hearings or within any agency of the city of New York designated to conduct such proceedings. Any youth league provided with a device pursuant to this section that violates the provisions of subdivision c or subdivision k shall be liable for a civil penalty of no more than $2,500 for each automated external defibrillator that is not returned in satisfactory condition, recoverable in a proceeding before any tribunal established within the office of administrative trials and hearings or within any agency of the city of New York designated to conduct such proceedings. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-044]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2138" number="2931" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provision of automated external defibrillators and training courses authorized by this section shall be limited to the appropriation of funds available for this program. To the extent the department anticipates that the number of automated external defibrillators and training courses requested by youth baseball leagues and youth softball leagues will exceed the funds available, the department shall provide such defibrillators and training courses authorized by subdivision c on an equitable basis until such funds are exhausted. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-032]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2139" number="2932" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>j.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of the department shall promulgate any rules as may be necessary for the purposes of carrying out the provisions of this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2140" number="2933" version="248">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>k.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the department has any undistributed automated external defibrillators remaining after complying with subdivision c of this section, the department may distribute such automated external defibrillators to any other youth league at no cost to such youth league. Any automated external defibrillator so distributed shall be returned in satisfactory condition upon request of the department. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-044]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-114291" number="2934" version="248">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2016/057, 5/10/2016, eff. 1/1/2017; Am. L.L. 2016/104, 8/31/2016, eff. 1/1/2017; Am. L.L. 2018/119, 6/23/2018, eff. 1/1/2019; Am. L.L. 2019/140, 7/27/2019, eff. 1/1/2020) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-044]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-2141" number="2935" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 4-210 Access to city property.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1277" name="4-210"/>§ 4-210 Access to city property.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2142" number="2936" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in this section, the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2143" number="2937" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">City property.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;city property&quot; means any real property leased or owned by the city that serves a city governmental purpose and over which the city has operational control. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2144" number="2938" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Human services.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;human services&quot; has the meaning as set forth in subdivision c of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="6-129" destination-id="0-0-0-1279">6-129</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2145" number="2939" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Judicial warrant.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;judicial warrant&quot; means a warrant issued by a judge appointed pursuant to article III of the United States constitution or a federal magistrate judge appointed pursuant to section 631 of title 28 of the United States code, or any successor provision, or by a court of the state of New York, that authorizes a law enforcement officer to take into custody the person who is the subject of such warrant or to conduct a search or otherwise enter the premises at issue in accordance with the terms of the warrant. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2146" number="2940" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Limited access to city property.</CHARFORMAT> The city shall not knowingly permit governmental personnel who are empowered to enforce civil or criminal laws, other than personnel of the city, the department of education, or a local public benefit corporation or local public authority, to have access to non-public areas of city property unless: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2147" number="2941" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>such personnel are authorized to have access pursuant to an agreement, contract, or subcontract; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2148" number="2942" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>such personnel present a judicial warrant; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2149" number="2943" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>access is otherwise required by law; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2150" number="2944" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>such personnel are accessing such property as part of a cooperative arrangement involving city, state, or federal agencies; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2151" number="2945" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>access furthers the purpose or mission of a city agency; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2152" number="2946" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>exigent circumstances exist. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2153" number="2947" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Human services contractors and subcontractors.</CHARFORMAT> Agencies shall require any contractor having regular contact with the public in the daily administration of human services to apply the requirements of subdivision b to any location, whether or not on city property, where such services are provided under a city contract, whether through such contractors or their subcontractors. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2154" number="2948" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Guidelines and rules.</CHARFORMAT> Any agency with jurisdiction over city property shall adopt guidelines or rules, as appropriate, to implement this section or, alternatively, the mayor or an office or agency designated by the mayor may adopt guidelines or rules applicable to multiple agencies, in furtherance of the efficient implementation of this section. Any guidelines or rules shall provide for designating an individual at each city agency who shall be responsible for the implementation of this local law and any such guidelines or rules. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2155" number="2949" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Posting on city website.</CHARFORMAT> The mayor, or an office or agency designated by the mayor, shall ensure that any generalized guidelines or rules, including agency-wide guidelines or rules, regarding limited access to city property are posted on a website maintained by or on behalf of the city. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2156" number="2950" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Training.</CHARFORMAT> All new or renewed city contracts for security services on city property at which there is regular contact with the public in the daily administration of human services by or on behalf of the city shall contain a provision requiring relevant employees of the security contractor or subcontractor be provided with training on the requirements of this section, at no cost to such employees. Any employees subject to this requirement shall be compensated at their regular rate of compensation for time spent participating in such training, where applicable. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2157" number="2951" version="3">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2017/246, 12/17/2017, eff. 4/16/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2158" number="2952" version="561">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2017/246" destination-id="0-0-0-20511">L.L. 2017/246</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-053]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-129557" number="2953" version="561">
										<HEADING>§ 4-211 Green energy in city-owned buildings.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1281" name="4-211"/>§ 4-211 Green energy in city-owned buildings.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2159" number="2954" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>As used in this section: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2160" number="2955" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">City-owned building.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;city-owned building&quot; shall have the meaning ascribed to the term &quot;city building&quot; in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="28-308.1" destination-id="0-0-0-1283">28-308.1</LINK> of the code. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2161" number="2956" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Green energy source.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;green energy source&quot; means a source of energy that is: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2162" number="2957" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A qualified energy resource, as such term is defined in section 45 of title 26 of the United States code in effect on January 1, 2017; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2163" number="2958" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A source that is determined to be renewable by the head of an office or agency designated by the mayor; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2164" number="2959" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A source that is determined by such head to have (i) a positive environmental impact or (ii) a substantially lower negative environmental impact than fossil fuel-based energy sources. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2165" number="2960" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Green energy system.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;green energy system&quot; means a system that generates energy (i) substantially from one or more green energy sources, in accordance with rules promulgated by an office or agency designated by the mayor, or (ii) wholly from one or more green energy sources. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2166" number="2961" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>On and after January 1, 2050, 100 percent of electricity use by city-owned buildings shall be (i) generated from a green energy system owned or installed by the city or (ii) purchased by the city and generated from a green energy system. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2167" number="2962" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every 10 years after the effective date of the local law that added this section, the commissioner of citywide administrative services shall electronically submit to the mayor and speaker of the council, and make publicly available online, a report concerning the implementation of this section, including, but not limited to, the following: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2168" number="2963" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The percentage of electricity used by city-owned buildings that comes from green energy sources; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2169" number="2964" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any difficulties in complying with this section and recommendations for addressing such difficulties; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2170" number="2965" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The types of green energy sources utilized for electricity used by city-owned buildings and recommendations for expanding or limiting the definition of green energy sources in this section, if any; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2171" number="2966" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The costs attributable to complying with this section; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2172" number="2967" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Reductions in greenhouse gas emissions attributable to complying with this section and any other environmental or electricity-related benefits attributable to such compliance. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2173" number="2968" version="611">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The mayor shall include in each long-term sustainability plan required by subdivision e of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="20" destination-id="0-0-0-0">20</LINK> of the charter a report analyzing subjects including, but not limited to, the following: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2174" number="2969" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Compliance with the requirements of this section; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2175" number="2970" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The feasibility of using green energy systems for providing building heating and hot water; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2176" number="2971" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The amount and percentage of building heating and hot water provided from green energy systems; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2177" number="2972" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The types of green energy sources currently being used to provide building heating and hot water and the limitations to expanding these sources to additional buildings; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2178" number="2973" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification of building heating and hot water systems or technologies using green energy systems, the current limitations of building heating and hot water systems or technologies and a timeline for when such systems or technologies may be commercially viable for installation in city-owned buildings; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2179" number="2974" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The costs associated with providing building heating and hot water from green energy systems; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2180" number="2975" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The risks associated with providing building heating and hot water from green energy systems; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2181" number="2976" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Reductions in greenhouse gases and any other environmental or energy benefits associated with providing building heating and hot water from green energy systems. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2182" number="2977" version="702">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2018/107, 5/26/2018, eff. 5/26/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-2183" number="2978" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 4-212 School siting task force.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1285" name="4-212"/>§ 4-212 School siting task force.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2184" number="2979" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be an interagency task force to review relevant city real estate transactions to identify opportunities for potential school sites. Such task force shall also review city-owned buildings, city-owned property and vacant land within the city to evaluate potential opportunities for new school construction or leasing for school use. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2185" number="2980" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The task force shall consist of the members specified in this subdivision, or their designees: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2186" number="2981" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The chancellor of the city school district of the city of New York; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2187" number="2982" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of citywide administrative services; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2188" number="2983" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The director of city planning; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2189" number="2984" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of housing and preservation development; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2190" number="2985" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The speaker of the council; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2191" number="2986" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The president and chief executive officer of the New York city school construction authority, and the president or chief executive officer of a local development corporation or other not-for-profit corporation, a majority of whose members are appointed by the mayor, that contracts with the city to provide or administer economic development benefits on behalf of the city, may participate in the task force as members at the invitation of the mayor and the speaker. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2192" number="2987" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>One member shall be designated as chairperson by the mayor after consultation with the speaker. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2193" number="2988" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The task force shall consult with agencies or offices with jurisdiction over environmental and planning concerns as appropriate, and may consult with interested members of the public, including but not limited to parents of students currently enrolled in the city school district of the city of New York. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2194" number="2989" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than July 31, 2019, the task force shall submit a report to the mayor, the speaker, the chancellor of the city school district of the city of New York and the president and chief executive officer of the New York city school construction authority on the results of its review pursuant to this section. Such report shall be updated thereafter as necessary, as determined by the task force. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2195" number="2990" version="702">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2018/168, 10/13/2018, eff. 10/13/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-2196" number="2991" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 4-213 Notice to department of education and school construction authority regarding city-owned or leased property.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1287" name="4-213"/>§ 4-213 Notice to department of education and school construction authority regarding city-owned or leased property.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2197" number="2992" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> For the purposes of this section, the term &quot;<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">department</CHARFORMAT>&quot; means the department of citywide administrative services. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2198" number="2993" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within 30 days of a determination by the department that city-owned or leased property with a lot size of at least 20,000 square feet has no current use, the department shall provide written notice to the department of education and the New York city school construction authority, which notice shall include the information required by subdivision a of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="4-208" destination-id="0-0-0-1273">4-208</LINK>, to the extent such information is available. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2199" number="2994" version="702">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2018/166, 10/13/2018, eff. 10/13/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-111726" number="2995" version="44">
										<HEADING>§ 4-214 Notice of soil contaminants in city development projects.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-18965" name="4-214"/>§ 4-214 Notice of soil contaminants in city development projects.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111737" number="2996" version="44">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> For the purposes of this section, the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111736" number="2997" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">City development project.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;city development project&quot; means a project undertaken by an agency, a city economic development entity, or by a party in contract with the city, for the purpose of improvement or development of real property, including, but not limited to, street, road and sewer improvements and maintenance. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111735" number="2998" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">City economic development entity</CHARFORMAT>. The term &quot;city economic development entity&quot; means an entity that provides or administers economic development benefits under contract with the department of small business services. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111734" number="2999" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hazardous level of lead in soil.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;hazardous level of lead in soil&quot; means soil containing a lead level of five parts per million or above as determined by the toxicity characteristic leaching procedure as defined in subpart C of part 261 of subchapter I of chapter I of title 40 of the code of federal regulations or any subsequent provisions. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111733" number="3000" version="44">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within five business days of discovering or becoming aware of a hazardous level of lead in soil as a result of an environmental subsurface investigation in any city development project that will expose such soil as part of the project, the agency or city economic development entity that is supervising a capital project shall: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111732" number="3001" version="44">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notify the community board and the council member in whose district the city development project is located of such results; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111731" number="3002" version="44">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Post such results within the appropriate website; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111730" number="3003" version="44">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Develop air monitoring instructions for all relevant parties in contract with the city, including a community air monitoring plan that complies with all applicable local, state and federal guidance documents. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111728" number="3004" version="779">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2019/072, 4/14/2019, eff. 10/11/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-131656" number="3005" version="779">
										<HEADING>§ 4-215 Transfer of Rikers Island to the commissioner of citywide administrative services.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-20784" name="4-215"/>§ 4-215 Transfer of Rikers Island to the commissioner of citywide administrative services.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-131667" number="3006" version="779">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to the location that is known as Rikers Island: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-131666" number="3007" version="779">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>By no later than July 1, 2021, and every six months thereafter until charge and control over the entirety of Rikers Island has been transferred pursuant to this section, the mayor shall transfer charge over every portion of Rikers Island that the mayor determines is not in active use for the housing of incarcerated persons, or in active use for the providing of direct services to such persons, such as medical care, training, storage, employment training and services, re-entry services, educational services, visitation, legal services, or administrative hearings, to the charge of the commissioner of citywide administrative services. For the purposes of this paragraph, the use of each building, facility, and structure, as well as the use of every piece of unimproved land greater than 20,000 square feet, shall be evaluated. By no later than August 31, 2027, all portions of Rikers Island shall be fully transferred and under the charge and control of the commissioner of citywide administrative services and shall no longer be used by the department of correction for the housing of incarcerated persons; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-131665" number="3008" version="779">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon the transfer of any portion of Rikers Island pursuant to this section, the commissioner of citywide administrative services shall have charge over the portion of land transferred, including all buildings, structures, facilities, and property located thereon, with all of the powers and duties, with respect to such real property, buildings, structures, facilities, and property, as described in <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="Chapter 35" destination-id="0-0-0-0">chapter 35</LINK> of the charter. The commissioner of citywide administrative services shall notify the Rikers Island advisory committee, established pursuant to subdivision b of this section, of each such transfer within 30 days of such transfer; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-131664" number="3009" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Until the entirety of Rikers Island is transferred to, and under the charge and control of, the commissioner of citywide administrative services, maintenance and operation of any portion of Rikers Island transferred to the charge of the commissioner of citywide administrative services shall be subject to guidelines agreed upon by the departments of correction and citywide administrative services, provided that such guidelines shall not be established or exercised so as to prohibit the commissioner of citywide administrative services&apos; access to, or the productive use of, portions of Rikers Island under the charge of the commissioner of citywide administrative services; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-131663" number="3010" version="779">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of citywide administrative services shall, in communication with the Rikers Island advisory committee, have the authority to plan and coordinate the actions of city agencies with respect to prospective uses of Rikers Island for sustainability and resiliency purposes, including but not limited to renewable energy generation and storage, wastewater treatment, and organic waste processing, provided that such planning shall include consideration of whether the use of existing structures would best contribute to environmental or sustainability goals; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-131662" number="3011" version="779">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Prior to August 31, 2027 or the date by which Rikers Island is fully transferred pursuant to paragraph 1 of this subdivision, whichever comes first, any portions of Rikers Island still in active use by the department of correction, as described in paragraph 1 of this subdivision, shall remain under the jurisdiction of the commissioner of correction pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="624" destination-id="0-0-0-0">624</LINK> of the charter, and the care, custody and control of persons therein shall remain under the care and management of such commissioner pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="623" destination-id="0-0-0-0">623</LINK> of the charter. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-131661" number="3012" version="779">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rikers Island advisory committee.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-131660" number="3013" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be established a Rikers Island advisory committee, which shall consist of 15 members, as follows: the commissioner of citywide administrative services or such commissioner&apos;s designee, the commissioner of environmental protection or such commissioner&apos;s designee, the commissioner of parks and recreation or such commissioner&apos;s designee, the commissioner of sanitation or such commissioner&apos;s designee, the commissioner of buildings or such commissioner&apos;s designee, the director of long-term planning and sustainability or such director&apos;s designee, two members appointed by the mayor, and seven members appointed by the speaker of the council. No less than four of the nine members appointed by the mayor and the speaker of the council shall be persons who have been impacted directly by incarceration on Rikers Island, provided that not less than two of such four members shall be persons who were in custody at a facility on Rikers Island and the remainder of whom may be persons whose immediate family members were in custody at a facility on Rikers Island. No less than three of the nine members appointed by the mayor and the speaker of the council shall be persons with an expertise in environmental justice or sustainability. The nine members appointed by the mayor and speaker of the council should represent the geographic diversity of communities impacted by incarceration on Rikers Island or environmental justice communities. The commissioner of citywide administrative services shall serve as chairperson of the committee. The commissioner of correction, or such commissioner&apos;s designee, may participate as a non-voting member in the meetings of the advisory committee, for the purpose of providing operational information, up to and until August 31, 2027, or the date by which Rikers Island is fully transferred, whichever comes first. Members shall serve without compensation. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-131659" number="3014" version="779">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than 180 days after the effective date of this subdivision, the Rikers Island advisory committee shall hold its initial meeting, and thereafter shall meet at least quarterly, to evaluate and make recommendations regarding prospective uses of Rikers Island, both with regard to those portions of Rikers Island transferred to the commissioner of citywide administrative services pursuant to paragraph 1 of subdivision a of this section and with regard to the entirety of Rikers Island, for sustainability and resiliency purposes, including but not limited to renewable energy, wastewater treatment, organics removal, organic waste processing, and other purposes conforming to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-803" destination-id="0-0-0-10965">24-803</LINK> of this code. Such evaluations shall consider the potentially beneficial uses of existing buildings, structures, and facilities. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-131658" number="3015" version="779">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The advisory committee may make recommendations on prospective uses to the mayor and the speaker of the council at any time after the date of its initial meeting. Additionally, no later than three years after the date of its initial meeting, the advisory committee shall submit recommendations to the mayor and the speaker of the council regarding prospective uses of Rikers Island that shall include no less than three options that the committee recommends be considered for further study or possible implementation. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-131657" number="3016" version="1129">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2021/016, 2/25/2021, eff. 2/25/2021) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-137445" number="3017" version="1159">
										<HEADING>§ 4-216 Limitation on lighting in city-owned buildings.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-21578" name="4-216"/>§ 4-216 Limitation on lighting in city-owned buildings.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137459" number="3018" version="1129">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>As used in this section: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137458" number="3019" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Compliant building</CHARFORMAT>&quot; means a building in which all covered spaces comply with the occupancy sensor requirements of section C405.2 of the New York city energy conservation code for new construction. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137457" number="3020" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Covered building</CHARFORMAT>&quot; means a city-owned building that is under the jurisdiction of and is operated by the department of citywide administrative services. For the purposes of this section, a covered building shall not include either a high-occupancy building or a critical facility for which such occupancy sensor requirements shall not apply. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137456" number="3021" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Covered space</CHARFORMAT>&quot; means space that is located within a city-owned building that is under the jurisdiction of and is operated by the department citywide administrative services and which is required to comply with the occupancy sensor requirements of section C405.2 of the New York city energy conservation code. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137455" number="3022" version="1129">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Existing covered spaces shall comply with the occupancy sensor installation requirements of section C405.2 of the New York city energy conservation code for new construction as follows: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137454" number="3023" version="1129">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>by January 1, 2023, at least 25 percent of covered buildings shall be compliant buildings; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137453" number="3024" version="1129">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>by January 1, 2025, at least 50 percent of covered buildings shall be compliant buildings; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137452" number="3025" version="1129">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>by January 1, 2027, at least 75 percent of all covered buildings shall be compliant buildings. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137451" number="3026" version="1129">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>by January 1, 2030, all remaining covered buildings shall be compliant buildings. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137450" number="3027" version="1129">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>By January 1, 2024 and every third year thereafter until 2030, the department of citywide administrative services shall, with the cooperation of all relevant agencies, report to the mayor and the speaker of the council the following information: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137449" number="3028" version="1129">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of covered buildings as of the end of the previous three calendar years;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137460" number="3029" version="1129">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of compliant buildings and the percentage of covered buildings that are compliant buildings, as of the end of the previous three calendar years; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137448" number="3030" version="1129">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of covered buildings that became compliant buildings during the previous three calendar years. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137446" number="3031" version="1130">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2022/030, 1/15/2022, eff. 1/15/2022) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-137461" number="3032" version="1130">
										<HEADING>§ 4-217 Limitation on nighttime illumination in city-owned or leased buildings during peak avian migration periods.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-21580" name="4-217"/>§ 4-217 Limitation on nighttime illumination in city-owned or leased buildings during peak avian migration periods.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137468" number="3033" version="1130">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the purposes of this article, the following terms shall have the following meanings. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137467" number="3034" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Non-essential outdoor lighting.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;non-essential outdoor lighting&quot; means lighting that has not been deemed essential for either safety or functionality as determined by an agency designated by the mayor or by the owner of a leased building. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137466" number="3035" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Peak avian migration period.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;peak avian migration period&quot; means the period from August 15 through November 15, and the period from April 1 through May 31 as recommended by New York City Audubon or such other dates determined by an agency designated by the mayor. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137465" number="3036" version="1130">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For city-owned buildings, and buildings leased by the city in which the city is the only tenant, non-essential outdoor lighting shall be turned off between the hours of 11:00 p.m. and 6:00 a.m. during peak avian migration periods. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137464" number="3037" version="1130">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For buildings leased by the city, where the city is not the only tenant, the agency leasing such building shall use its best efforts to include a provision in such lease requiring that non-essential outdoor lighting be turned off between the hours of 11:00 p.m. and 6:00 a.m. during peak avian migration periods. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-137462" number="3038" version="1130">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2022/031, 1/15/2022, eff. 1/15/2022) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-2200" number="3039" version="1130">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2022/031" destination-id="0-0-0-21582">L.L. 2022/031</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-069]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-137480" number="3040" version="2048">
										<HEADING>§ 4-218 Solar energy generation on city-controlled parking lots.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-27738" name="4-218"/>§ 4-218 Solar energy generation on city-controlled parking lots.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227793" number="3041" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>As used in this section, the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227792" number="3042" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">City-controlled parking lot.</CHARFORMAT> The term “city-controlled parking lot” means an open parking lot, as such term is defined in the New York city building code, that the city operates on property that is owned by the city or leased by the city pursuant to an agreement that would allow the city to install a solar canopy on such lot in accordance with this section, provided, however, that city-controlled parking lot does not mean a parking lot that is leased to or operated by a person or entity other than the city. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227791" number="3043" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cost-effective.</CHARFORMAT> The term “cost-effective” means, with respect to the installation of a solar canopy on a city-controlled parking lot, that the cumulative savings with respect to such solar canopy will, within 25 years of such installation, be equal to or exceed the expected net cost of such solar canopy over the same period. The calculation of cost-effectiveness shall include: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227790" number="3044" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The expected net present value to the city of the energy that would be produced by such canopy, if such canopy remained active, over such 25 year period after such canopy is installed, or, where a city-controlled parking lot is not owned by the city, over the lesser of such 25 year period or the length of time remaining before the lease for such lot expires or is due to be renewed; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227789" number="3045" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The value of emissions reductions attributable to such canopy over the applicable time period described in paragraph 1 of this term, which shall be calculated using a social cost of carbon value, as provided in a rule promulgated pursuant to paragraph 4 of subdivision d of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="3-125" destination-id="0-0-0-879">3-125</LINK>, or if no such rule exists, the greater of a social cost of carbon value, if any, determined by the United States environmental protection agency for the applicable year or $142 per metric ton of carbon dioxide equivalent, provided, however, that a site- or project-specific social cost of carbon value may be developed and used in lieu of the social cost of carbon value provided herein if such site- or project-specific social cost of carbon value is higher than the social cost of carbon value provided by this paragraph. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227788" number="3046" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department.</CHARFORMAT> The term “department” means the department of citywide administrative services. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227787" number="3047" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Net cost.</CHARFORMAT> The term “net cost” means the gross cost to the city of the acquisition, installation, and maintenance of a solar canopy on a city-controlled parking lot minus an amount equal to the sum of all federal, state, and other non-city governmental assistance utilized by the city to offset such gross cost. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227786" number="3048" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Solar canopy.</CHARFORMAT> The term “solar canopy” means a structure covering 1 or more parking spaces that is designed and constructed to capture solar radiation for the purpose of producing usable energy. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227785" number="3049" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Identification of locations.</CHARFORMAT> The department shall, with the cooperation of all other relevant agencies, review all city-controlled parking lots and identify city-controlled parking lots where the installation of solar canopies would be cost-effective. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227784" number="3050" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Pilot program</CHARFORMAT>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227783" number="3051" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department, or another agency designated by the mayor, with the cooperation of all other relevant agencies, shall establish a pilot program to install and maintain solar canopies on city-controlled parking lots. Such pilot program shall include the installation of a solar canopy on at least 1 city-controlled parking lot in each borough where there is a city-controlled parking lot identified by the department pursuant to subdivision b of this section. To the extent practicable, such solar canopies shall be installed no later than 2 years after the effective date of the local law that added this section. In the event that the department or such agency designated by the mayor determines that it will be unable to install such solar canopies by such deadline, the department or such agency shall immediately notify the mayor and the speaker of the council and provide an explanation for the delay, along with the anticipated date on which such installations will be complete. Such pilot program shall continue for 1 year following such installation. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227782" number="3052" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each city-controlled parking lot at which a solar canopy is installed under this subdivision, the department shall install no fewer than 5 electric vehicle chargers, each of which shall have a minimum charging capacity of 6 kilowatts. Such electric vehicle chargers shall be installed no later than the date on which such solar canopies are installed. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227781" number="3053" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing in this subdivision shall be interpreted so as to limit any obligation of the department or any other agency to install electric vehicle charging stations or related equipment pursuant to any other provision of law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227780" number="3054" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Report.</CHARFORMAT> No later than 6 months after the pilot program ends, the department or other agency designated by the mayor shall, with the cooperation of all other relevant agencies, submit to the mayor and the speaker of the council a report that includes the following: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227779" number="3055" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of city-controlled parking lots at the start of the pilot program, and the locations of such parking lots; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227778" number="3056" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number and location of city-controlled parking lots the department identified as cost-effective for the installation of solar canopies pursuant to subdivision b of this section; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227777" number="3057" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number and location of city-controlled parking lots where solar canopies were installed as part of the pilot program established by subdivision c of this section; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227776" number="3058" version="2048">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any recommendations as to whether and how such pilot program may be expanded and made permanent. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227774" number="3059" version="2048">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2024/063, 5/18/2024, eff. 5/18/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-097]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>