<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-131137" number="6616" version="746">
			<HEADING>Chapter 2: Certain Unlawful Real Estate Practices</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2115" name="T08C002"/>Chapter 2: Certain Unlawful Real Estate Practices</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-5132" number="6617" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 8-201 Declaration of policy. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2117" name="8-201"/>§ 8-201 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Declaration of policy. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5133" number="6618" version="3">
											<PARA>It is hereby declared to be the policy of the city of New York and the purpose of this chapter to promote fair dealing in real estate transactions, to maintain community stability and security, and to foster racial and social harmony.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-5134" number="6619" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 8-202 Definitions. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2119" name="8-202"/>§ 8-202 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5135" number="6620" version="3">
											<PARA>As used in this chapter:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5136" number="6621" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Chairperson&quot; means the chairperson of the New York city commission on human rights.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5137" number="6622" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Commission&quot; means the New York city commission on human rights.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5138" number="6623" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Dwelling or real property&quot; means one, two, three or four family residences, and any vacant land which is offered for sale or lease for the construction or location thereon of any such residence.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5139" number="6624" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Legal notice&quot; means publication daily for one week in a newspaper of general circulation within the city of New York and written notice to all real estate brokers in the area.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5140" number="6625" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Real estate broker&quot; means a real estate broker as defined in article twelve-A of the real property law of the state of New York.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5141" number="6626" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Real estate dealer&quot; means any firm, partnership, association, corporation or person which or who has within the preceding twelve months, sold, traded or exchanged two or more dwellings other than, in the case of a person, such person&apos;s own residence.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5142" number="6627" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Real estate office&quot; means an office or other place of business which is primarily engaged in the business of selling, buying, leasing, or renting real property; listing real property for sale, purchase, lease or rental; or providing brokerage services in connection with such selling, buying, leasing, renting, or listing.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5143" number="6628" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Solicitation&quot; means requesting, inviting, or inducing by any means, including, but not limited to:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5144" number="6629" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>going in or upon the property of the person to be solicited, except when invited by such person;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5145" number="6630" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>communicating with the person to be solicited by mail, telephone, telegraph or messenger service, except when requested by such person;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5146" number="6631" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>canvassing in streets or other public places;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5147" number="6632" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>distributing handbills, circulars, cards or other advertising matter;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5148" number="6633" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>using loudspeakers, soundtrucks, or other voice-amplifying equipment;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5149" number="6634" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>displaying signs, posters, billboards, or other advertising devices other than signs placed upon a real estate office for the purpose of identifying the occupants and services provided therein, provided, however, that the term &quot;solicitation&quot; shall not include advertising in newspapers of general circulation, magazines, radio, television, or telephone directories.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5150" number="6635" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Block, neighborhood or area&quot; means any forty square blocks within the city of New York. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-5151" number="6636" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 8-203 Unlawful real estate practices. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2121" name="8-203"/>§ 8-203 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Unlawful real estate practices. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5152" number="6637" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any real estate broker or dealer or any agent or employee of a real estate broker or dealer, except in honest reply to an unprompted question by a prospective buyer or seller: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5153" number="6638" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>to represent, for the purpose of inducing or discouraging the purchase, sale, or rental, or the listing for purchase, sale, or rental, of any real property, that a change has occurred or will or may occur in the racial or religious composition of any block, neighborhood, or area.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5154" number="6639" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>to represent, implicitly or explicitly, for the purpose of inducing or discouraging the purchase, sale, or rental or the listing for purchase, sale, or rental of any real property, that the presence of persons of any particular race, religion or ethnic background in an area will or may result in:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5155" number="6640" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a lowering of property values in the area;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5156" number="6641" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>change in the racial, religious or ethnic composition of the area;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5157" number="6642" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>an increase in criminal or anti-social behavior in the area; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5158" number="6643" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a change in the racial, religious or ethnic composition of schools or other public facilities or services in the area.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5159" number="6644" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any real estate broker or dealer or any agent or employee of a real estate broker or dealer:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5160" number="6645" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>to make any misrepresentation in connection with the purchase, sale, or rental of any real property, that there will or may be physical deterioration of dwellings in any block, neighborhood or area.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5161" number="6646" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>to refer to race, color, religion or ethnic background in any advertisement offering or seeking real property for purchase, sale or rental.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5162" number="6647" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, partnership, association, or corporation, to knowingly aid, abet, or coerce the commission of any act made unlawful by subdivisions one and two of this section. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-5163" number="6648" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 8-204 Non-solicitation areas. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2123" name="8-204"/>§ 8-204 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Non-solicitation areas. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5164" number="6649" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commission may designate an area as a non-solicitation area for a period of up to one year upon making written findings based on substantial evidence introduced at a public hearing that: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5165" number="6650" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>practices made unlawful by section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="8-203" destination-id="0-0-0-2121">8-203</LINK> of this chapter, the inducement or encouragement by brokers or dealers of the use of fraudulent mortgage applications for the purchase of dwellings, or the direction based on race, creed, color or national origin by brokers or dealers of prospective purchasers or applicants to dwellings, or an unusually great incidence of solicitation are consistently occurring within the area, and that</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5166" number="6651" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>such practices are causing, or are likely to cause, residents within the area to believe that:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5167" number="6652" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>property values in the area are declining, or about to decline rapidly; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5168" number="6653" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the area is experiencing, or is about to experience:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5169" number="6654" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a declining level of maintenance of its housing stock; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5170" number="6655" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>an increase in criminal behavior; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5171" number="6656" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a change in the racial, religious or ethnic composition of the schools in the area; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5172" number="6657" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the area is experiencing, or is about to experience, a material change in its racial, religious or ethnic composition; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5173" number="6658" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>therefore, the temporary prohibition in the area of the real estate activities described in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="8-205" destination-id="0-0-0-2125">8-205</LINK> of this chapter is necessary to prevent a material change in the area&apos;s racial, religious or ethnic composition.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5174" number="6659" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commission may extend one or more times the designation of a non-solicitation area made pursuant to subdivision one of this section for a period of up to one year upon making written findings, based on substantial evidence introduced at a public hearing, that such extension is necessary to achieve the designation&apos;s purpose, as described in paragraph (c) of subdivision one of this section, provided, however, that no extension may be granted which, together with the original designation and all previous extensions, will maintain a non-solicitation area for a continuous period greater than two years. The public hearing on any extension shall be held not more than thirty days before the day on which the designation or earlier extension is scheduled to expire.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5175" number="6660" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commission shall promptly announce by legal notice each designation made pursuant to subdivision one of this section and each extension made pursuant to subdivision two of this section, describing the area to which it applies by references to named streets and landmarks. Any designation shall take effect upon the completion of the publication required for legal notice. Any extension shall take effect at the time at which the designation or earlier extension would otherwise expire.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5176" number="6661" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commission shall maintain, and make available to all interested persons, a current listing of designated non-solicitation areas.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5177" number="6662" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commission may, at any time, terminate the designation of a non-solicitation area made pursuant to subdivision one of this section or the extension of a designation made pursuant to subdivision two of this section upon making findings, based on substantial evidence introduced at a public hearing, that the continuation of the designation or its extension is no longer necessary to achieve the designation&apos;s purpose, as described in this section. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-5178" number="6663" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 8-205 Activities prohibited with respect to non-solicitation areas. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2125" name="8-205"/>§ 8-205 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Activities prohibited with respect to non-solicitation areas. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5179" number="6664" version="3">
											<PARA>It shall be unlawful for any real estate broker or dealer or any agent or employee of a real estate broker or dealer to solicit, directly or indirectly, the sale, purchase, or rental of any dwelling located within a non-solicitation area.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-5180" number="6665" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 8-206 Hearings; rules; enforcement. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2127" name="8-206"/>§ 8-206 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hearings; rules; enforcement. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5181" number="6666" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commission may conduct investigations, studies, and hearings concerning practices and activities governed by this chapter. In conducting hearings, the commission shall have the power to subpoena witnesses, to compel their attendance, to administer oaths, to examine witnesses under oath, and to require the production of documents. A written record shall be made of every such hearing. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5182" number="6667" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commission shall have the authority from time to time to make, amend, and rescind such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5183" number="6668" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The chairperson or his or her designated representative shall have the power to enforce the provisions of this chapter by signing criminal complaints against any person, firm, partnership, association, or corporation for violation of this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5184" number="6669" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The chairperson shall report to the secretary of state of New York all violations of this chapter by real estate brokers and salespersons. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-5185" number="6670" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 8-207 Violations. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2129" name="8-207"/>§ 8-207 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Violations. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5186" number="6671" version="3">
											<PARA>Any person, firm, partnership, association, or corporation convicted of violating this chapter shall be guilty of a class A misdemeanor.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-5187" number="6672" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 8-208 Civil remedies. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2131" name="8-208"/>§ 8-208 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Civil remedies. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5188" number="6673" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any owner of real property who is induced to sell his or her property through or to a real estate broker or real estate dealer by acts committed by such broker or dealer in violation of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="8-203" destination-id="0-0-0-2121">8-203</LINK> or section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="8-205" destination-id="0-0-0-2125">8-205</LINK> of this chapter may institute a civil action against such broker or dealer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5189" number="6674" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If, in an action instituted pursuant to this subdivision, judgment is rendered in favor of plaintiff, such plaintiff shall be awarded as damages</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5190" number="6675" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the amount of any gains, whether in the form of profits, commission, or otherwise, realized by defendant as the result of the first subsequent arm&apos;s length sale, exchange, or transfer of the property, or, if defendant acted as a broker, the amount of any commissions received by defendant through the sale, exchange, or transfer of plaintiff&apos;s property, such gains in all cases to be calculated without regard to any expenses incurred by the defendant, and may in addition be awarded reasonable attorneys&apos; fees and court costs; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5191" number="6676" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>if the defendant has not realized any gains as defined in this subdivision, an amount equal to the difference between the price for which plaintiff sold his or her property and the fair market value at the time of the sale, or the fair market value of the property at the time the action is commenced, whichever difference is greater, and may in addition be awarded reasonable attorneys&apos; fees and court costs.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5192" number="6677" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any buyer, through or from a real estate broker or real estate dealer, of real property the last owner of which, excluding such broker or dealer, was induced to sell, exchange or transfer his or her property by acts committed by such broker or dealer in violation of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="8-203" destination-id="0-0-0-2121">8-203</LINK> or section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="8-205" destination-id="0-0-0-2125">8-205</LINK> of this chapter may institute a civil action against such broker or dealer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5193" number="6678" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If, in an action instituted pursuant to paragraph (a) of this subdivision, judgment is rendered in favor of plaintiff, the plaintiff shall be awarded as damages the amount of any gains, whether in the form of profits, commission, or otherwise, realized by defendant as the result of such plaintiff&apos;s purchase of the property, such gains in all cases to be calculated without regard to any expenses incurred by the defendant, and may in addition be awarded reasonable attorneys&apos; fees and court costs.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-5194" number="6679" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to the sale, exchange or transfer of any property, the liability of a broker or dealer created by subdivision two of this section shall be independent of and additional to the liability of such broker or dealer created by subdivision one of this section. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>