<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-38818" number="49646" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 16: Reporting on School Applications, Offers of Admission, Enrollment and Available Seats</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9777" name="T21-aC016"/>Chapter 16: Reporting on School Applications, Offers of Admission, Enrollment and Available Seats</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-38819" number="49647" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 21-978 Reporting on school applications, offers of admission, enrollment and available seats.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9779" name="21-978"/>§ 21-978 Reporting on school applications, offers of admission, enrollment and available seats.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-38820" number="49648" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the purposes of this section, the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-38821" number="49649" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">School.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;school&quot; means a school of the city school district of the city of New York that contains any combination of grades from and including pre-kindergarten through grade twelve, including early education centers with which the department contracts to provide pre-kindergarten. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-38822" number="49650" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Student.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;student&quot; means any pupil under the age of twenty-one as of September first of the school year being reported, who does not have a high school diploma and who is enrolled in a school, excluding any child who is less than four years of age on or before December thirty-first of the school year being reported. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-38823" number="49651" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall submit to the speaker of the council, and post conspicuously on the department&apos;s website, the following reports regarding application, offer, available seat and enrollment information: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-38824" number="49652" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Not later than May 15, 2018, and annually thereafter on or before May 15, a report including, but not limited to (a) for each community school district, the total number of individuals who (1) applied for admission to grades pre-kindergarten, kindergarten or six in a school located in such community school district for the following school year; and (2) received an offer of admission to grades pre-kindergarten, kindergarten or six in a school located in such community school district for the following school year; and (b) for each school, the total number of individuals who (1) applied for admission to grades pre-kindergarten, kindergarten, six or nine in such school, as applicable, for the following school year; and (2) received an offer of admission to grades pre-kindergarten, kindergarten, six or nine in such school, as applicable, for the following school year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-38825" number="49653" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Not later than March 15, 2019, and annually thereafter on or before March 15, a report including, but not limited to (a) for each community school district, the total number of students who enrolled in grades pre-kindergarten, kindergarten or six in a school located in such community school district in the current school year; and (b) for each school, the total number of students who enrolled in grades pre-kindergarten, kindergarten, six or nine in such school, as applicable, in the current school year. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-38826" number="49654" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>The data required to be reported pursuant to this subdivision b shall be disaggregated by (i) community school district of residence of individuals or students, as applicable; (ii) zip code of residence of individuals or students, as applicable; (iii) primary home language of individuals or students, as applicable and (iv) grade level. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-38827" number="49655" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Not later than May 15, 2018, and annually thereafter on or before May 15, the department shall submit to the speaker of the council and post conspicuously on the department&apos;s website a report that shall include, but not be limited to, for each school, the total number of seats anticipated to be available in the following school year. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-38828" number="49656" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No information that is otherwise required to be reported pursuant to this section shall be reported in a manner that would violate any applicable provision of federal, state or local law relating to the privacy of student information or that would interfere with law enforcement investigations or otherwise conflict with the interests of law enforcement. If a category contains between 1 and 5 students, or contains an amount that would allow the amount of another category that is five or less to be deduced, the number shall be replaced with a symbol. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-38829" number="49657" version="709">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2018/072, 1/19/2018, eff. 1/19/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>