<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-12624" number="15794" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 9: Tax Upon Foreign and Alien Insurers</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2753" name="T11C009"/>Chapter 9: Tax Upon Foreign and Alien Insurers</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-12625" number="15795" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-901 Definitions. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3657" name="11-901"/>§ 11-901 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12626" number="15796" version="3">
											<PARA>Wherever used in this chapter, the following words and phrases shall mean and include: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12627" number="15797" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Alien insurer.&quot; Any insurer incorporated or organized under the laws of any foreign nation, or of any province or territory not included under the definition of a foreign insurer. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12628" number="15798" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Foreign insurer.&quot; Any insurer, except a mutual insurance company taxed under the provisions of section nine thousand one hundred five of the insurance law, incorporated or organized under the laws of any state, as herein defined, other than this state. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12629" number="15799" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Fire insurance corporation, association or individuals.&quot; Any insurer, regardless of the name, designation or authority under which it purports to act, which insures property of any kind or nature against loss or damage by fire. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12630" number="15800" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Loss or damage by fire.&quot; Loss or damage by fire, lightning, smoke or anything used to combat fire, regardless of whether such risks or the premiums therefor are stated or charged separately and apart from any other risk or premium. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12631" number="15801" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;State.&quot; Any state of the United States and the District of Columbia. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12632" number="15802" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Commissioner of finance.&quot; The commissioner of finance of the city or any other officer of the city designated to perform the same functions. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12633" number="15803" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Department of finance.&quot; The department of finance of the city or any other agency or department designated to perform the same functions. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12634" number="15804" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Fire commissioner.&quot; The fire commissioner of the city. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12635" number="15805" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Comptroller.&quot; The comptroller of the city. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12636" number="15806" version="676">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Tax appeals tribunal.&quot; The tax appeals tribunal established by section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="168" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred sixty-eight</LINK> of the charter. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-12637" number="15807" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-902 General powers of the commissioner of finance. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3659" name="11-902"/>§ 11-902 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">General powers of the commissioner of finance. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12638" number="15808" version="3">
											<PARA>In addition to all other powers granted to the commissioner of finance under this chapter, the commissioner is hereby authorized and empowered:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12639" number="15809" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To make, adopt and amend rules and regulations appropriate to the carrying out of this chapter and the purposes thereof.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12640" number="15810" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To compromise disputed claims in connection with taxes hereby imposed.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12641" number="15811" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To delegate his or her functions hereunder to any officer or employee of the department of finance.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12642" number="15812" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To prescribe reasonable methods, approved by the New York superintendent of insurance, for determining the amounts of premiums subject to the tax.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12643" number="15813" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To require any foreign or alien insurer subject to the tax to keep detailed records of the premiums in a manner reasonably designed to show the amounts thereof subject to the tax and to furnish such information on request.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12644" number="15814" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To assess, determine, revise and adjust the tax imposed under this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12645" number="15815" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To audit the reports of any insurer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12646" number="15816" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To allow an extension of time not in excess of thirty days for filing the report and paying the tax required by this chapter, provided the taxpayer requests such extension in writing prior to the date prescribed for such filing and such payment by sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-904" destination-id="0-0-0-3661">11-904</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-903" destination-id="0-0-0-3663">11-903</LINK> of this chapter. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-12647" number="15817" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-903 Tax on premiums on policies of foreign and alien insurers. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3663" name="11-903"/>§ 11-903 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Tax on premiums on policies of foreign and alien insurers. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12648" number="15818" version="3">
											<PARA>There shall be paid to the department of finance for the use and benefit of the fire department of the city, on or before the first day of March, in each year by every foreign and alien fire insurance corporation, association or individuals which insure property against loss or damage by fire, the sum of two percent of all gross direct premiums less return premiums which, during the year ending on the preceding thirty-first day of December, shall have been received by any such insurer for any insurance against loss or damage by fire in the city. Any such insurer which in any year shall cease or terminate doing business in the city shall pay the tax for such year within thirty days after such cessation or termination.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-12649" number="15819" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-904 Report of premiums by insurers. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3661" name="11-904"/>§ 11-904 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Report of premiums by insurers. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12650" number="15820" version="3">
											<PARA>Each insurer required to pay a tax under this chapter shall, at the time such tax is paid or payable, whichever is sooner, render to the commissioner of finance a verified report setting forth such information as may be required by the commissioner for the determination of the tax and the proper administration of this chapter. The commissioner of finance shall prescribe the form and furnish the necessary forms to enable such insurers to make such reports. The commissioner or the commissioner&apos;s designated representative or the tax appeals tribunal or its designated representative shall have power to examine any such insurer under oath and to require the production by such insurer of all books and papers as the commissioner or the tax appeals tribunal may deem necessary. All expenses of collecting such tax shall be paid by the commissioner of finance from the funds received under this chapter prior to the distribution thereof as hereinafter authorized.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-12651" number="15821" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-905 Interest and penalties. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3665" name="11-905"/>§ 11-905 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Interest and penalties. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12652" number="15822" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Interest on underpayments.</CHARFORMAT> If any amount of tax is not paid on or before the last date prescribed for payment (without regard to any extension of time granted for payment), interest on such amount at the underpayment rate set by the commissioner of finance pursuant to subdivision (g) of this section, or, if no rate is set, at the rate of seven and one-half percent per annum, shall be paid for the period from such last date to the date of payment. In computing the amount of interest to be paid, such interest shall be compounded daily. Interest under this subdivision shall not be paid if the amount thereof is less than one dollar.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12653" number="15823" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Failure to file return. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12654" number="15824" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In case of failure to file a return under this chapter on or before the prescribed date (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not due to willful neglect, there shall be added to the amount required to be shown as tax on such return five percent of the amount of such tax if the failure is for not more than one month, with an additional five percent for each additional month or fraction thereof during which such failure continues, not exceeding twenty-five percent in the aggregate.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12655" number="15825" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of a failure to file a return of tax within sixty days of the date prescribed for filing of such return (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not due to willful neglect, the addition to tax under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall not be less than the lesser of one hundred dollars or one hundred percent of the amount required to be shown as tax on such return.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12656" number="15826" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of this paragraph, the amount of tax required to be shown on the return shall be reduced by the amount of any part of the tax which is paid on or before the date prescribed for payment of the tax and by the amount of any credit against the tax which may be claimed upon the return.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12657" number="15827" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Failure to pay tax shown on return.</CHARFORMAT> In case of failure to pay the amount shown as tax on a return required to be filed under this chapter on or before the prescribed date (determined with regard to any extension of time for payment), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not due to willful neglect, there shall be added to the amount shown as tax on such return one-half of one percent of the amount of such tax if the failure is not for more than one month, with an additional one-half of one percent for each additional month or fraction thereof during which such failure continues, not exceeding twenty-five percent in the aggregate. For the purpose of computing the addition for any month the amount of tax shown on the return shall be reduced by the amount of any part of the tax which is paid on or before the beginning of such month and by the amount of any credit against the tax which may be claimed upon the return. If the amount of tax required to be shown on a return is less than the amount shown as tax on such return, this paragraph shall be applied by substituting such lower amount.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12658" number="15828" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Failure to pay tax required to be shown on return.</CHARFORMAT> In case of failure to pay any amount in respect of any tax required to be shown on a return required to be filed under this chapter which is not so shown (including a determination made pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-906" destination-id="0-0-0-3667">11-906</LINK> of this chapter) within ten days of the date of a notice and demand therefor, unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not due to willful neglect, there shall be added to the amount of tax stated in such notice and demand one-half of one percent of such tax if the failure is not for more than one month, with an additional one-half of one percent for each additional month or fraction thereof during which such failure continues, not exceeding twenty-five percent in the aggregate. For the purpose of computing the addition for any month, the amount of tax stated in the notice and demand shall be reduced by the amount of any part of the tax which is paid before the beginning of such month.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12659" number="15829" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Limitations on additions.</CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12660" number="15830" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to any return, the amount of the addition under paragraph one of this subdivision shall be reduced by the amount of the addition under paragraph two of this subdivision for any month to which an addition applies under both paragraphs one and two of this subdivision. In any case described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) of this subdivision, the amount of the addition under such paragraph (1) shall not be reduced below the amount provided in such subparagraph.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12661" number="15831" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to any return, the maximum amount of the addition permitted under paragraph three of this subdivision shall be reduced by the amount of the addition under paragraph one of this subdivision (determined without regard to subparagraph (B) of such paragraph (1)) which is attributable to the tax for which the notice and demand is made and which is not paid within ten days of such notice and demand.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12662" number="15832" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Underpayment due to negligence. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12663" number="15833" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any part of an underpayment of tax is due to negligence or intentional disregard of this chapter or any rules and regulations hereunder (but without intent to defraud), there shall be added to the tax a penalty equal to five percent of the underpayment.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12664" number="15834" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be added to the tax (in addition to the amount determined under paragraph (1) of this subdivision) an amount equal to fifty percent of the interest payable under subdivision (a) of this section with respect to the portion of the underpayment described in such paragraph (1) which is attributable to the negligence or intentional disregard referred to in such paragraph (1), for the period beginning on the last date prescribed by law for payment of such underpayment (determined without regard to any extension) and ending on the date of the assessment of the tax (or, if earlier, the date of the payment of the tax).</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12665" number="15835" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Underpayment due to fraud. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12666" number="15836" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any part of an underpayment of tax is due to fraud, there shall be added to the tax a penalty equal to fifty percent of the underpayment.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12667" number="15837" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be added to the tax (in addition to the penalty determined under paragraph (1) of this subdivision) an amount equal to fifty percent of the interest payable under subdivision (a) of this section with respect to the portion of the underpayment described in such paragraph (1) which is attributable to fraud, for the period beginning on the last day prescribed by law for payment of such underpayment (determined without regard to any extension) and ending on the date of the assessment of the tax (or, if earlier, the date of the payment of the tax).</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12668" number="15838" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The penalty under this subdivision shall be in lieu of any other addition to tax imposed by subdivision (b) or (c) of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12669" number="15839" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Additional penalty.</CHARFORMAT> Any insurer who, with fraudulent intent, shall fail to pay any tax imposed by this chapter, or to make, render, sign or certify any return, or to supply any information within the time required by or under this chapter, shall be liable for a penalty of not more than one thousand dollars, in addition to any other amounts required under this chapter to be imposed, assessed and collected by the commissioner of finance. The commissioner of finance shall have the power, in his or her discretion, to waive, reduce or compromise any penalty under this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12670" number="15840" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The interest and penalties imposed by this section shall be paid and disposed of in the same manner as other revenues from this chapter. Unpaid interest and penalties may be enforced in the same manner as the tax imposed by this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12671" number="15841" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Authority to set interest rates.</CHARFORMAT> The commissioner of finance shall set the overpayment and underpayment rates of interest to be paid pursuant to subdivision (a) of this section and subdivision (a) of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-906" destination-id="0-0-0-3667">11-906</LINK> of this chapter, but if no such overpayment rate of interest are set, such rate or rates shall be deemed to be set at six percent per annum and such underpayment rate shall be deemed to be set at seven and one-half percent per annum. Such rates shall be the overpayment and underpayment rates prescribed in paragraph two of this subdivision but the underpayment rate shall not be less than seven and one-half percent per annum. Any such rates set by the commissioner of finance shall apply to taxes, or any portion thereof, which remain or become due or overpaid on or after the date on which such rates become effective and shall apply only with respect to interest computed or computable for periods or portions of periods occurring in the period in which such rates are in effect.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12672" number="15842" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">General rule.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12673" number="15843" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Overpayment rate.</CHARFORMAT> The overpayment rate set under this subdivision shall be the sum of (i) the federal short-term rate as provided under paragraph three of this subdivision, plus (ii) two percentage points.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12674" number="15844" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Underpayment rate.</CHARFORMAT> The underpayment rate set under this subdivision shall be the sum of (i) the federal short-term rate as provided under paragraph three of this subdivision, plus (ii) seven percentage points.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12675" number="15845" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Federal short-term rate.</CHARFORMAT> For purposes of this subdivision:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12676" number="15846" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The federal short-term rate for any month shall be the federal short-term rate determined by the United States secretary of the treasury during such month in accordance with subsection (d) of section twelve hundred seventy-four of the internal revenue code for use in connection with section six thousand six hundred twenty-one of the internal revenue code. Any such rate shall be rounded to the nearest full percent (or, if a multiple of one-half of one percent, such rate shall be increased to the next highest full percent).</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12677" number="15847" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Period during which rate applies.</CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12678" number="15848" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">In general.</CHARFORMAT> Except as provided in clause (ii) of this subparagraph, the federal short-term rate for the first month in each calendar quarter shall apply during the first calendar quarter beginning after such month.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12679" number="15849" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Special rule for the month of September, nineteen hundred eighty-nine.</CHARFORMAT> The federal short-term rate for the month of April, nineteen hundred eighty-nine shall apply with respect to setting the rate of interest for the month of September, nineteen hundred eighty-nine.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12680" number="15850" version="676">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Publication of interest rate.</CHARFORMAT> The commissioner of finance shall cause to be published in the city record, and give other appropriate general notice of, the interest rate to be set under this subdivision no later than twenty days preceding the first day of the calendar quarter during which such interest rate applies. The setting and publication of such interest rate shall not be included within paragraph (a) of subdivision five of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="1041" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one thousand forty-one</LINK> of the city charter relating to the definition of a rule. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-12681" number="15851" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-906 Assessment, refund, collection, review and reserves. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3667" name="11-906"/>§ 11-906 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Assessment, refund, collection, review and reserves. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12682" number="15852" version="676">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of the civil practice law and rules or any other law relative to limitations of time for the enforcement of a civil remedy shall not apply to any proceeding or action by the commissioner of finance to levy, assess, determine or enforce the collection of tax, interest or penalty imposed by this chapter. However, except in the case of a wilfully false or fraudulent report, no assessment of additional tax, interest or penalty shall be made after the expiration of more than three years from the date of the filing of a report, provided, however, that where no report has been filed as provided by law the tax may be assessed at any time. The commissioner of finance shall refund or credit, with interest at the overpayment rate set by the commissioner of finance pursuant to subdivision (g) of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-905" destination-id="0-0-0-3665">11-905</LINK> of this chapter or, if no rate is set, at the rate of six percent per annum computed from the date of overpayment to a date (to be determined by the commissioner of finance) preceding the date of a refund check by not more than thirty days, any tax, penalty or interest erroneously, illegally or unconstitutionally collected or paid if application to the commissioner of finance for such refund shall be made within six months from the payment thereof. Notice of any determination of the commissioner of finance with respect to an assessment of tax, interest or penalty or with respect to a claim for refund or any other notice, demand or request shall be given by mailing the same to the insurer to the address of its New York city office last filed with the commissioner of finance or, if there is no such office, to the address of its main office last filed with the commissioner of finance or, in the absence of any filed address, to such address as may be obtainable. The mailing of any notice, demand or request by the commissioner of finance shall be presumptive evidence of its receipt by the insurer and any period of time to be determined with reference to the giving of such notice, demand or request shall commence to run from the date of such mailing. The determination of the commissioner of finance shall finally and irrevocably fix the amount of any tax, interest or penalty due or to be refunded unless the taxpayer, within ninety days after the giving of notice of such determination, or if the commissioner of finance has established a conciliation procedure pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-124" destination-id="0-0-0-2745">11-124</LINK> of the code and the taxpayer has requested a conciliation conference in accordance therewith, within ninety days from the mailing of a conciliation decision or the date of the commissioner&apos;s confirmation of the discontinuance of the conciliation proceeding, both (1) serves a petition upon the commissioner of finance and (2) files a petition with the tax appeals tribunal for a hearing, or unless the commissioner of finance of his or her own motion shall redetermine the same. Such hearing and any appeal to the tax appeals tribunal sitting en banc from the decision rendered in such hearing shall be conducted in the manner and subject to the requirements prescribed by the tax appeals tribunal pursuant to sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="168" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred sixty-eight</LINK> through <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="172" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred seventy-two</LINK> of the charter. After such hearing the tax appeals tribunal shall give notice of its decision to the taxpayer and to the commissioner of finance with reference to the amount of the tax, interest or penalty assessed or to be refunded. The decision of the tax appeals tribunal sitting en banc shall be reviewable for error, illegality or unconstitutionality or any other reason, by a proceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules if such proceeding is commenced by the person against whom the tax was assessed within four months after the giving of the notice of such tax appeals tribunal decision. Such proceeding shall not be commenced by the taxpayer unless: (1) the amount of any tax assessed and sought to be reviewed with penalties and interest thereon, if any, shall be first deposited with the commissioner of finance and there shall be filed with the commissioner of finance an undertaking in such amount and with such sureties as a justice of the supreme court shall approve, to the effect that if such proceeding be dismissed or the decision confirmed, the taxpayer will pay all costs and charges which may accrue against the taxpayer in the prosecution of the proceeding, or (2) in the case of a review of a decision assessing any taxes, penalties and interest, at the option of the taxpayer, such undertaking may be in a sum sufficient to cover all of the taxes, penalties and interest assessed by such decision plus the costs and charges which may accrue against the taxpayer in the prosecution of the proceeding, in which event the taxpayer shall not be required to deposit such taxes, penalties and interest as a condition precedent to the commencement of the proceeding. No determination or proposed determination of tax, interest or penalty due or to be refunded shall be reviewed or enjoined in any manner except as set forth herein.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12683" number="15853" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In cases where the taxpayer has applied for a refund and has commenced a proceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules to review a decision of the tax appeals tribunal adverse to such taxpayer on its application for a refund, the commissioner of finance shall set up appropriate reserves to meet any decision adverse to the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12684" number="15854" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In computing the amount of interest to be paid under this section, such interest shall be compounded daily. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-12685" number="15855" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-907 Place of business to be reported. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3669" name="11-907"/>§ 11-907 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Place of business to be reported. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12686" number="15856" version="3">
											<PARA>Every insurer, on or before the first day of March in each year, and as often in each year as such insurer shall change its principal place of business or change or terminate any office or place of business in the city, shall report in writing, to the commissioner of finance, the location of its principal place of business and any new principal place of business or of any new office or place of business in the city or of the termination of any such office or place of business. In the event of such change or termination, such report shall be made no later than fifteen days after such change or termination. Any insurer who fails or neglects to make such report within the time limited therefor shall be subject to a penalty of one hundred dollars and, in addition thereto, fifty dollars for each month or part thereof during which such report is not made. The total of such penalties shall not exceed one thousand dollars.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-12687" number="15857" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-908 Suits for violations. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3671" name="11-908"/>§ 11-908 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Suits for violations. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12688" number="15858" version="3">
											<PARA>The tax provided to be paid by this chapter, and the pecuniary penalties and interest imposed therein, or any or either of them, may be sued for and recovered, with costs of suit, in any court of record, by the commissioner of finance.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-12689" number="15859" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-909 Distribution of tax on policies covering property in the city of New York. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3673" name="11-909"/>§ 11-909 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Distribution of tax on policies covering property in the city of New York. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12690" number="15860" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The moneys received by the commissioner of finance as a tax on policies covering property in each borough of the city shall be disbursed by the commissioner of finance as follows:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12691" number="15861" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Ten percent to the firemen&apos;s association of the state of New York, for the endowment, benefit and maintenance of the volunteer firemen&apos;s home at Hudson, but in no event to exceed the sum of thirty-five thousand dollars ($35,000) annually.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12692" number="15862" version="676">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The balance to the general fund of the city established pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="109" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred nine</LINK> of the charter, except as provided in paragraph three of this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12693" number="15863" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Volunteer firemen&apos;s benevolent fund; trustee. From the balance specified in paragraph two of this subdivision, a sum, not to exceed one hundred fifty thousand dollars in any one year, shall be paid into a fund to be known as the volunteer firemen&apos;s benevolent fund, which shall be administered as hereinafter provided by the fire commissioner, as trustee of such fund, for the benefit of indigent volunteer firefighters, their surviving spouses and orphans.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12694" number="15864" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Persons entitled to benefits from fund. All funds received by the fire commissioner as trustee under this paragraph shall be expended by the fire commissioner for the relief of:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12695" number="15865" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>all indigent volunteer firefighters who served as such for a period of five years in a duly organized volunteer fire company in the former towns of New Lots, Flatlands, Gravesend, New Utrecht and Flatbush in the county of Kings, or in the territory now included in the borough of Richmond, or in the territory now included in the borough of Queens, or in the territory now included in the borough of the Bronx, and who were honorably discharged after such five years of service, or who having been members of a duly organized volunteer fire company within any such town or territory, which company was disbanded by reason of the installation of a paid fire department, and were members of such company for at least one year prior to its disbandment;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12696" number="15866" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the surviving spouses and orphans of any such volunteer firefighters.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12697" number="15867" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Fund benefits of beneficiaries on rolls as of December thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-one. During the lifetime of those relief beneficiaries who appear as such as of December thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-one upon the records of the trustees of the exempt firemen&apos;s benevolent fund of the county of Kings, or of the trustees of the exempt firemen&apos;s benevolent fund of the borough of Queens, or of the trustees of the exempt firemen&apos;s benevolent fund of the borough of Staten Island, or of the trustees of the exempt firemen&apos;s benevolent fund of the borough of the Bronx, it shall be the duty of the fire commissioner, as such trustee, to pay to such beneficiaries from the volunteer firemen&apos;s benevolent fund referred to in subparagraph a hereof, the same amounts as were being periodically paid to such beneficiaries as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred fifty-two.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12698" number="15868" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Fund benefits of residents of firemen&apos;s home. It shall be the duty of the fire commissioner, as such trustee, to pay from such fund referred to in subparagraph a, the sum of ten dollars monthly to each volunteer firefighter in residence at the volunteer firemen&apos;s home at Hudson, who qualified for entrance into such home by reason of service as a volunteer firefighter within the area now included within the boundaries of the city of New York. No other payments shall be made from such fund to any such volunteer firefighter while in residence at such home.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12699" number="15869" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Eligibility of persons who applied for fund benefits after December thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-one, and prior to the establishment of fund. Upon the establishment of the volunteer firemen&apos;s benevolent fund referred to in subparagraph a hereof, the fire commissioner or the fire commissioner&apos;s authorized subordinates shall investigate and determine the need for benefits of all persons who, after December thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-one and prior to the establishment of such volunteer firemen&apos;s benevolent fund, applied for benefits payable from any of the benevolent funds mentioned in subparagraph c hereof, and who are receiving benefits therefrom at the time of the establishment of such fund referred to in subparagraph a. No such person shall be found to be in need of benefits, nor shall any such person be paid any benefits from such last-mentioned fund unless the fire commissioner or the fire commissioner&apos;s authorized subordinates shall determine that such person is indigent. In the event that any such person is thus found to be in need of benefits, the fire commissioner shall pay to such person from such last-mentioned fund, the same periodic amounts as the trustees mentioned in subparagraph c hereof were paying as of June thirtieth, nineteen hundred fifty-two, to a person who had the same status and who was receiving benefits from the borough or county fund which would be currently liable for the payment of benefits to such person, but for the provision of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="13-532" destination-id="0-0-0-3675">13-532</LINK> of the code. It shall be the duty of the fire commissioner and the fire commissioner&apos;s authorized subordinates to maintain and carry out continuously, such investigation procedures as may be necessary to assure that benefits will not be paid from such fund to any persons who are not in need as herein specified.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12700" number="15870" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Eligibility for benefits of persons applying therefor after establishment of fund. All persons applying after the establishment of the volunteer firemen&apos;s benevolent fund for benefits payable therefrom shall be investigated as to need by the fire commissioner or the fire commissioner&apos;s authorized subordinates, and the eligibility of such persons for benefits and the amount thereof to be awarded and paid to them shall be determined by the fire commissioner or the fire commissioner&apos;s authorized subordinates in accordance with the standards specified in subparagraph e hereof. Benefits shall be paid from such fund to eligible persons in accordance with such determination and it shall be the duty of the fire commissioner and the fire commissioner&apos;s subordinates continuously to maintain and carry out as to such persons investigation procedures such as are described in subparagraph e hereof. The fire commissioner, as part of his or her investigation to determine eligibility of persons for fund benefits, shall request from the duly appointed representative of the volunteer firefighters in each borough a report on such person&apos;s service and indigency. Such report shall be solely for the information of the fire commissioner and shall not be binding upon the fire commissioner in arriving at a determination as to eligibility. In the event that such report is not submitted within ten days from the date of request, the fire commissioner shall determine eligibility on the basis of the facts developed in the fire commissioner&apos;s own investigation.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12701" number="15871" version="676">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Excess moneys. In the event that the benefits paid by the fire commissioner, as trustee, during any period of one year beginning on the first day of February shall not equal the sum of one hundred fifty thousand dollars, the unexpended balance shall be paid into the general fund of the city established pursuant to section<LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="109" destination-id="0-0-0-0"> one hundred nine</LINK> of the charter, except that the fire commissioner may retain in the volunteer firemen&apos;s benevolent fund such amount as may be necessary to meet the commitments of such fund until the revenue from the tax collected under this chapter in the ensuing taxable year shall become available.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12702" number="15872" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Depositories. The fire commissioner, as trustee, is hereby empowered and directed to receive all moneys and assets belonging or payable to such volunteer firemen&apos;s benevolent fund and shall deposit all such moneys to the credit of such fund in banks and trust companies to be selected by the fire commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12703" number="15873" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Bond. The fire commissioner, as trustee of such fund, shall give a bond with one or more sureties, in a sum sufficient for the faithful performance of his or her duties, such bond to be approved as to amount and adequacy, by the comptroller and filed in the comptroller&apos;s office.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12704" number="15874" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>j.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Records. The officers and employees of the fire department who are responsible for the maintenance of the books and records of the New York fire department pension fund shall have charge of, and keep the accounts of the fire commissioner as trustee of the volunteer firemen&apos;s benevolent fund.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12705" number="15875" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>k.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Reports. The fire commissioner, as trustee of such volunteer firemen&apos;s benevolent fund, shall submit to the mayor on or before the first day of April of each year, a verified report in which shall be set forth the account of the fire commissioner&apos;s proceedings as such trustee during the twelve-month period ending on the thirty-first day of January immediately preceding. Such report shall include a statement of all receipts and disbursements on account of such benevolent fund, a list of the names, residences and as nearly as possible, the ages of the beneficiaries of such fund and the respective amounts paid to them during such period.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12706" number="15876" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>l.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Audit. The comptroller shall have the power to audit the books and records of the fire commissioner as trustee of the volunteer firemen&apos;s benevolent fund.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-12707" number="15877" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The moneys received by the fire commissioner as trustee pursuant to the provisions of paragraph three of subdivision (a) of this section shall be expended by the fire commissioner only as provided in such paragraph. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>