<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-230945" number="49547" version="2157">
			<HEADING>Chapter 9. Career and Technical Education Reporting</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9749" name="T21-aC009"/>Chapter 9. Career and Technical Education Reporting</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-38704" number="49548" version="2112">
										<HEADING>§ 21-971 Reporting on career and technical education.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9751" name="21-971"/>§ 21-971 Reporting on career and technical education.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-38722" number="49549" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in this chapter, the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229425" number="49550" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Career and technical education.</CHARFORMAT> The term “career and technical education” or “CTE” means a curriculum designed to provide students with certain skills that will enable them to pursue a career in certain disciplines, including, but not limited to, agricultural education, business and marketing, family and consumer sciences, health occupations, technology and trade, or technical and industrial education. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229424" number="49551" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Certified instructor.</CHARFORMAT> The term “certified instructor” means a teacher who has earned a teaching license in a specific career and technical education subject. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229423" number="49552" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Student.</CHARFORMAT> The term “student&quot; means any pupil under the age of 21 as of the September 1 of the academic period being reported, who does not have a high school diploma and who is enrolled in a school of the city school district of the city of New York, not including a pre-kindergarten student or a preschool child as preschool child is defined in section 4410 of the education law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229422" number="49553" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Technical assessment.</CHARFORMAT> The term “technical assessment” has the same meaning as set forth in section 100.5 of title 8 of the New York codes, rules and regulations, regarding the elementary and secondary education school program, or a successor provision. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229421" number="49554" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Vocational program.</CHARFORMAT> The term “vocational program” means an educational institution, other than a 2- or 4-year college, offering skilled training programs or certificates at the postsecondary level. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229420" number="49555" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than April 30, 2025, and annually by April 30 thereafter, the chancellor shall submit to the mayor and the speaker of the council and post conspicuously on the department’s website, a report for the preceding academic year which shall include, but need not be limited to, the following: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229419" number="49556" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of high school-level CTE programs in schools of the city school district of the city of New York, including for each (i) the name of the program; (ii) the field, discipline, or industry for which the program prepares students; (iii) an outline of the skills students develop in the program; (iv) the number of courses in the program; (v) the number of industry partners associated with the program; (vi) the school at which the program is located; (vii) whether the school is a CTE-designated high school; (viii) whether the CTE program has received approval through the New York state department of education’s CTE approval process; (ix) the grade levels served by the program; (x) the number of students enrolled in the program; and (xi) the annual attendance rate of students in the program; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229418" number="49557" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each school offering at least one CTE program, the number and percentage of age- or grade-eligible students enrolled in any such program; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229417" number="49558" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where such information is available, the number and percentage of students in a CTE program who engaged in a related (i) un-paid internship; and (ii) paid internship; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229416" number="49559" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number and percentage of applicants who listed a CTE-designated high school as their first choice in the high school application process during the previous application year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229415" number="49560" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number and percentage of applicants who listed a CTE-designated high school as their second choice in the high school application process during the previous application year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229414" number="49561" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number and percentage of applicants who participated in the high school application process who enrolled in a CTE-designated high school; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229413" number="49562" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the cohort of students who entered ninth grade 4 years prior to the academic period being reported and the cohort of students who entered ninth grade 6 years prior to the academic period being reported, the number and percentage of students who (i) enrolled in a CTE program; (ii) completed the full sequence of courses for such program; (iii) completed a technical assessment; (iv) passed each individual component of the three-part technical assessment; (v) received a high school diploma; and (vi) received industry credentials; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229412" number="49563" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the cohort of students who entered ninth grade 6 years prior to the academic period being reported, the number and percentage of students who (i) enrolled in a 2- or 4-year college within 1 year of graduation; and (ii) enrolled in a vocational program within 1 year of graduation; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229411" number="49564" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of designated full-time and part-time certified instructors providing instruction at each school with a CTE program; and for each CTE-designated high school, the ratio of full-time certified instructors to students at such school; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229410" number="49565" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>10.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of staff in each school or program who received professional development or training administered by the department and relating to CTE as of the prior school year. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229409" number="49566" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The data required to be reported pursuant to paragraphs 2 through 8 of subdivision b of this section shall be disaggregated by (i) race/ethnicity; (ii) gender; (iii) special education status; (iv) English language learner status; (v) eligibility for the free and reduced price lunch program; (vi) status as a student in temporary housing; (vii) status as a student in foster care; and (viii) community school district. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229408" number="49567" version="2112">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No information that is otherwise required to be reported pursuant to this section shall be reported in a manner that would violate any applicable provision of federal, state or local law relating to the privacy of student information or that would interfere with law enforcement investigations or otherwise conflict with the interests of law enforcement. If a category contains between 1 and 5 students, or contains an amount that would allow the amount of another category that is 5 or less to be deduced, the number shall be replaced with a symbol. A category that contains zero shall be reported as 0, unless such reporting would violate any applicable provision of federal, state or local law relating to the privacy of student information. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229406" number="49568" version="2112">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2016/174, 12/22/2016, eff. 12/22/2016, repealed eff. 12/22/2021; Added L.L. 2024/114, 11/22/2024, eff. 11/22/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-103]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-38723" number="49569" version="598">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2016/174" destination-id="0-0-0-20581">L.L. 2016/174</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-053]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>