<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-228787" number="143648" version="2097">
			<HEADING>Chapter 1: General Provisions</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-27806" name="T34C001"/>Chapter 1: General Provisions</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-228786" number="143649" version="2097">
										<HEADING>§ 34-101 Legislative findings.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-27808" name="34-101"/>§ 34-101 Legislative findings.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228862" number="143650" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The council hereby finds that from 1626 to 1827, the city of New York was the site of the wrongful but legally sanctioned enslavement of human beings of African and indigenous American descent; that in the early 1700s, the city of New York had one of the highest rates of slave ownership in the country, with between 15 and 20 percent of New York city residents enslaved and deprived of their fundamental human rights; that after slavery was banned in the state in 1827, the city of New York continued to generate significant income from the illegal international trade of enslaved persons; and that racially motivated discrimination, riots, segregation, and violence continued after the United States formally abolished slavery in 1865, including through racially discriminatory laws, policies, and practices. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228861" number="143651" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The council further finds that on November 8, 2022, New Yorkers voted to adopt a new preamble to the charter acknowledging “the grave injustices and atrocities that form part of our country’s history, including the forced labor of enslaved Africans” and “the discrimination, racial segregation, mass incarceration, and other forms of violence and systemic inequity that continue to be experienced by marginalized groups.” The preamble also acknowledges that these systemic injustices continue to cause profound harms to individuals, families, and communities, and that “we must act intentionally to remedy these past and continuing harms and to reconstruct, revise and reimagine our foundations, structures, institutions, and laws to promote justice and equity for all New Yorkers.” <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228860" number="143652" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The council further finds that on November 8, 2022, when the preamble to the charter was approved, New Yorkers voted to affirm that “We, the people of New York city, united in our resolve to build a just and equitable city for all, recognize the efforts of those New Yorkers, past and present, who fought for racial equity and social justice, honor the contributions of those New Yorkers who have suffered in the name of freedom, and acknowledge all who fought, struggled, and dreamed for a better life and a better city. Together, we stand on their shoulders as we move boldly toward a brighter tomorrow for ourselves, our children, and future generations.” <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228859" number="143653" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Therefore, the council intends by this title to create a truth, healing, and reconciliation process, through which New Yorkers can publicly name and acknowledge the past, present, and ongoing harms and traumas caused by and associated with slavery and its legacies in the city of New York; and by which these grave harms and injustices can be publicly recognized, memorialized, and formally repudiated; and through which New Yorkers may promote accountability for such harms and injustices, including by ensuring that such harms and injustices are not forgotten, perpetuated, or repeated; and through which the city may take action to repair relationships and social bonds amongst all New Yorkers. The council further intends by this title to create a process by which to identify and pursue remedies and reparative measures that are responsive to the needs and priorities of New Yorkers affected by the city’s participation in and perpetuation of slavery and its legacies. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228858" number="143654" version="2097">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2024/091, 10/12/2024, eff. 10/12/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-228871" number="143655" version="2097">
										<HEADING>§ 34-102 Definitions.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-27810" name="34-102"/>§ 34-102 Definitions.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228857" number="143656" version="2097">
											<PARA>As used in this chapter, the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228856" number="143657" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Affected person or community.</CHARFORMAT> The terms “affected person” and “affected community” mean a person and a group of people, respectively, that have experienced harm or injustice as a result of the legacies, badges, and aftereffects of slavery, or whose ancestors were subjected to slavery. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228855" number="143658" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Chair.</CHARFORMAT> The term “chair” means the chair of the commission on racial equity pursuant to subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3404" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3404</LINK> of the charter of the city of New York. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228854" number="143659" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">CORE.</CHARFORMAT> The term “CORE” means the commission on racial equity established pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3404" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3404</LINK> of the charter of the city of New York. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228853" number="143660" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Community stakeholder.</CHARFORMAT> The term “community stakeholder” means a person who is an affected person or member of an affected community, a representative of a community-based organization, a community or religious leader, a scholar or expert, or a representative of a student group. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228852" number="143661" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Healing.</CHARFORMAT> The term “healing” means the process of recognizing psychological, social-emotional, or physical harm done to an individual or community and the process of repairing such harm. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228851" number="143662" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Office of racial equity.</CHARFORMAT> The term “office of racial equity” means the office established pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3401" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3401</LINK> of the charter of the city of New York. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228850" number="143663" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Public forum.</CHARFORMAT> The term “public forum” means a building or other physical location where, in accordance with rules promulgated by CORE, members of the public may learn about and engage with the history, personal experiences, and past or ongoing harms and injustices related to slavery and its legacies. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228849" number="143664" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Racial equity.</CHARFORMAT> The term “racial equity” means, when referring to an outcome, the achievement of equity with a particular focus on race or the intersection of race with other characteristics of identity. When referring to a process, the term &quot;racial equity&quot; means the closing of gaps in policy, practice, and allocation of city resources through the prioritization of access, opportunities, and resources to persons and communities who, based on or at least in part due to race, have historically faced or currently face marginalization or oppression, underinvestment, disinvestment, or under-resourcing. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228848" number="143665" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Reconciliation.</CHARFORMAT> The term “reconciliation” means an ongoing process of establishing and maintaining respectful societal relationships rooted in the acknowledgement of historical truths, universal human dignity, and the shared pursuit of racial equity. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228847" number="143666" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Reparation.</CHARFORMAT> The terms “reparation” or “reparative measure” mean a measure, policy, law, or program designed to remedy or redress one or more violations of human or civil rights by providing material or symbolic benefits to affected persons, families, or communities. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228846" number="143667" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Slavery and its legacies.</CHARFORMAT> The term “slavery and its legacies” means the legally sanctioned, race-based practice in New York of holding persons of African and indigenous American descent as chattels between the years 1626 and 1827, and the effects, legacies, badges, and aftereffects of that practice. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228845" number="143668" version="2097">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Truth and reconciliation.</CHARFORMAT> The term “truth and reconciliation” means public proceedings, including public hearings and research efforts, conducted for the purpose of investigating and recording serious human rights violations and abuses with the goal of achieving genuine healing, reconciliation, and progress toward a more just and equitable society. Such proceedings seek to establish patterns, practices, and chains of command that reveal the purposeful and systematic nature of such violations and abuses, potentially but not necessarily in concert with or in anticipation of reparative or restorative justice measures. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228844" number="143669" version="2097">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2024/091, 10/12/2024, eff. 10/12/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>