<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-201924" number="60099" version="1270">
			<HEADING>Chapter 4: Rent Stabilization</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2837" name="T26C004"/>Chapter 4: Rent Stabilization</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47299" number="60100" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-501 Findings and declaration of emergency. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11525" name="26-501"/>§ 26-501 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Findings and declaration of emergency. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47300" number="60101" version="3">
											<PARA>The council hereby finds that a serious public emergency continues to exist in the housing of a considerable number of persons within the city of New York and will continue to exist after April first, nineteen hundred seventy-four; that such emergency necessitated the intervention of federal, state and local government in order to prevent speculative, unwarranted and abnormal increases in rents; that there continues to exist an acute shortage of dwellings which creates a special hardship to persons and families occupying rental housing; that the legislation enacted in nineteen hundred seventy-one by the state of New York, removing controls on housing accommodations as they become vacant, has resulted in sharp increases in rent levels in many instances; that the existing and proposed cuts in federal assistance to housing programs threaten a virtual end to the creation of new housing, thus prolonging the present emergency; that unless residential rents and evictions continue to be regulated and controlled, disruptive practices and abnormal conditions will produce serious threats to the public health, safety and general welfare; that to prevent such perils to health, safety and welfare, preventive action by the council continues to be imperative; that such action is necessary in order to prevent exactions of unjust, unreasonable and oppressive rents and rental agreements and to forestall profiteering, speculation and other disruptive practices tending to produce threats to the public health, safety and general welfare; that the transition from regulation to a normal market of free bargaining between landlord and tenant, while still the objective of state and city policy, must be administered with due regard for such emergency; and that the policy herein expressed is now administered locally within the city of New York by an agency of the city itself, pursuant to the authority conferred by chapter twenty-one of the laws of nineteen hundred sixty-two. The council further finds that, prior to the adoption of local laws sixteen and fifty-one of nineteen hundred sixty-nine, many owners of housing accommodations in multiple dwellings, not subject to the provisions of the city rent and rehabilitation law enacted pursuant to said enabling authority either because they were constructed after nineteen hundred forty-seven or because they were decontrolled due to monthly rental of two hundred fifty dollars or more or for other reasons, were demanding exorbitant and unconscionable rent increases as a result of the aforesaid emergency, which led to a continuing restriction of available housing as evidenced by the nineteen hundred sixty-eight vacancy survey by the United States bureau of the census; that prior to the enactment of said local laws, such increases were being exacted under stress of prevailing conditions of inflation and of an acute housing shortage resulting from a sharp decline in private residential construction brought about by a combination of local and national factors; that such increases and demands were causing severe hardship to tenants of such accommodations and were uprooting long-time city residents from their communities; that recent studies establish that the acute housing shortage continues to exist; that there has been a further decline in private residential construction due to existing and proposed cuts in federal assistance to housing programs; that unless such accommodations are subjected to reasonable rent and eviction limitations, disruptive practices and abnormal conditions will produce serious threats to the public health, safety and general welfare; and that such conditions constitute a grave emergency.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47301" number="60102" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-502 Additional findings and declaration of emergency. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11527" name="26-502"/>§ 26-502 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Additional findings and declaration of emergency. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47302" number="60103" version="2023">
											<PARA>The council hereby finds that a serious public emergency continues to exist in the housing of a considerable number of persons within the city of New York and will continue to exist on and after April 1, 2024 and hereby reaffirms and repromulgates the findings and declaration set forth in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-501" destination-id="0-0-0-11525">26-501</LINK> of this title. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-095]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-130203" number="60104" version="2023">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2015/026, 3/30/2015, eff. 3/30/2015; Am. L.L. 2018/085, 3/27/2018, eff. 3/27/2018; Am. L.L. 2022/069, 6/27/2022, eff. 6/27/2022; Am. L.L. 2024/047, 3/25/2024, eff. 3/25/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-095]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-154630" number="60105" version="1215">
										<HEADING>§ 26-503 Short title. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11529" name="26-503"/>§ 26-503 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Short title. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47305" number="60106" version="3">
											<PARA>This law may be cited as the rent stabilization law of nineteen hundred sixty-nine.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47306" number="60107" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-504 Application. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11531" name="26-504"/>§ 26-504 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-231540" number="60108" version="2258">
											<PARA>This law shall apply to:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47308" number="60109" version="2258">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Class A multiple dwellings not owned as a cooperative or as a condominium, except as provided in section three hundred fifty-two-eeee of the general business law or as provided in section three hundred fifty-two-eeeee of the general business law, containing six or more dwelling units which: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-115]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47309" number="60110" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>were completed after February first, nineteen hundred forty-seven, except dwelling units (a) owned or leased by, or financed by loans from, a public agency or public benefit corporation, (b) subject to rent regulation under the private housing finance law or any other state law, (c) aided by government insurance under any provision of the national housing act, to the extent this chapter or any regulation or order issued thereunder is inconsistent therewith, or (d) located in a building for which a certificate of occupancy is obtained after March tenth, nineteen hundred sixty-nine; or (e) any class A multiple dwelling which on June first, nineteen hundred sixty-eight was and still is commonly regarded as a hotel, transient hotel or residential hotel, and which customarily provides hotel service such as maid service, furnishing and laundering of linen, telephone and bell boy service, secretarial or desk service and use and upkeep of furniture and fixtures, or (f) not occupied by the tenant, not including subtenants or occupants, as his or her primary residence, as determined by a court of competent jurisdiction, provided, however that no action or proceeding shall be commenced seeking to recover possession on the ground that a housing accommodation is not occupied by the tenant as his or her primary residence unless the owner or lessor shall have given thirty days notice to the tenant of his or her intention to commence such action or proceeding on such grounds. For the purposes of determining primary residency, a tenant who is a victim of domestic violence, as defined in section four hundred fifty-nine-a of the social services law, who has left the unit because of such violence, and who asserts an intent to return to the housing accommodation shall be deemed to be occupying the unit as his or her primary residence. For the purposes of this subparagraph where a housing accommodation is rented to a not-for-profit hospital for residential use, affiliated subtenants authorized to use such accommodations by such hospital shall be deemed to be tenants, or (g) became vacant on or after June thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy-one, or become vacant, provided however, that this exemption shall not apply or become effective with respect to housing accommodations which the commissioner determines or finds became vacant because the landlord or any person acting on his or her behalf, with intent to cause the tenant to vacate, engaged in any course of conduct (including but not limited to, interruption or discontinuance of essential services) which interfered with or disturbed or was intended to interfere with or disturb the comfort, repose, peace or quiet of the tenant in his or her use or occupancy of the housing accommodations and provided further that any housing accommodations exempted by this paragraph shall be subject to this law to the extent provided in subdivision b of this section; or </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47310" number="60111" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>were decontrolled by the city rent agency pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-414" destination-id="0-0-0-11521">26-414</LINK> of this title; or </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47311" number="60112" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>are exempt from control by virtue of item one, two, six or seven of subparagraph (i) of paragraph two of subdivision e of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-403" destination-id="0-0-0-11491">26-403</LINK> of this title; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47312" number="60113" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Other housing accommodations in class A or class B multiple dwellings made subject to this law pursuant to the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47313" number="60114" version="2258">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Dwelling units in a building or structure receiving the benefits of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-243" destination-id="0-0-0-2945">11-243</LINK> or section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-244" destination-id="0-0-0-2955">11-244</LINK> of the code or article eighteen of the private housing finance law, not owned as a cooperative or as a condominium, except as provided in section three hundred fifty-two-eeee of the general business law and not subject to chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T26C003" destination-id="0-0-0-2947">three</LINK> of this title. Upon the expiration or termination for any reason of the benefits of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-243" destination-id="0-0-0-2945">11-243</LINK> or section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-244" destination-id="0-0-0-2955">11-244</LINK> of the code or article eighteen of the private housing finance law any such dwelling unit shall be subject to this chapter until the occurrence of the first vacancy of such unit after such benefits are no longer being received or if each lease and renewal thereof for such unit for the tenant in residence at the time of the expiration of the tax benefit period has included a notice in at least twelve point type informing such tenant that the unit shall become subject to deregulation upon the expiration of such tax benefit period and states the approximate date on which such tax benefit period is scheduled to expire, such dwelling unit shall be deregulated as of the end of the tax benefit period; provided, however, that if such dwelling unit would have been subject to this chapter or the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four in the absence of this subdivision, such dwelling unit shall, upon the expiration of such benefits, continue to be subject to this chapter or the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four to the same extent and in the same manner as if this subdivision had never applied thereto.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235076" number="60115" version="2258">
											<PARA>(Am. 2025 N.Y. Laws Ch. 56, 5/9/2025, eff. 11/5/2025) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-115]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47314" number="60116" version="124">
										<HEADING>§ 26-504.1 Exclusion of accommodations of high income renters. [Repealed]</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11533" name="26-504.1"/>§ 26-504.1 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Exclusion of accommodations of high income renters. [Repealed]</CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47316" number="60117" version="606">
											<PARA>(Repealed 2019 N.Y. Laws Ch. 36 Pt. D § 5, 6/14/2019, eff. 6/14/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-112647" number="60118" version="124">
										<HEADING>§ 26-504.2 Exclusion of high rent accommodations. [Repealed]</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11537" name="26-504.2"/>§ 26-504.2 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Exclusion of high rent accommodations. [Repealed]</CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47320" number="60119" version="1914">
											<PARA>(Am. 2015 N.Y. Laws Ch. 20 Pt. A § 10, 6/26/2015, eff. 6/26/2015; Repealed 2019 N.Y. Laws Ch. 36 Pt. D § 5, 6/14/2019, eff. 6/14/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-112648" number="60120" version="124">
										<HEADING>§ 26-504.3 High income rent decontrol. [Repealed]</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11535" name="26-504.3"/>§ 26-504.3 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">High income rent decontrol. [Repealed]</CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47331" number="60121" version="1914">
											<PARA>(Am. 2015 N.Y. Laws Ch. 20 Pt. A § 16, 6/26/2015, eff. 6/26/2015; Repealed 2019 N.Y. Laws Ch. 36 Pt. D § 5, 6/14/2019, eff. 6/14/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47332" number="60122" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-505 Application to multiple family complex. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11539" name="26-505"/>§ 26-505 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application to multiple family complex. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47333" number="60123" version="3">
											<PARA>For purposes of this chapter a class A multiple dwelling shall be deemed to include a multiple family garden-type maisonette dwelling complex containing six or more dwelling units having common facilities such as sewer line, water main, and heating plant, and operated as a unit under a single ownership on May sixth, nineteen hundred sixty-nine, notwithstanding that certificates of occupancy were issued for portions thereof as one- or two-family dwellings.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47334" number="60124" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-506 Application to hotels. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11541" name="26-506"/>§ 26-506 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application to hotels. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47335" number="60125" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the provisions of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-504" destination-id="0-0-0-11531">26-504</LINK> of this chapter to the contrary, and irrespective of any decontrol pursuant to subparagraph (c) of paragraph two of subdivision e of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-403" destination-id="0-0-0-11491">26-403</LINK> of the city rent and rehabilitation law, this law shall apply to dwelling units in all hotels except hotels erected after July first, nineteen hundred sixty-nine, whether classified as a class A or a class B multiple dwelling, containing six or more dwelling units, provided that the rent charged for the individual dwelling units on May thirty-first, nineteen hundred sixty-eight was not more than three hundred fifty dollars per month or eighty-eight dollars per week; and further provided that, notwithstanding the foregoing, this law shall apply to dwelling units in any hotel, whether classified as a class A or a class B multiple dwelling, eligible for benefits pursuant to the provisions of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-244" destination-id="0-0-0-2955">11-244</LINK> of the code.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47336" number="60126" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon application by a tenant or owner, the division of housing and community renewal, shall determine if such building is a hotel covered by this law, based upon the services provided and other relevant factors. If it is determined that such building is not a hotel, it shall thereafter be subject to this law pursuant to subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-504" destination-id="0-0-0-11531">26-504</LINK> of this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47337" number="60127" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-507 Application to certain multiple dwellings purchased from the city. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11543" name="26-507"/>§ 26-507 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application to certain multiple dwellings purchased from the city. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47338" number="60128" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the provisions of any local law or regulation promulgated pursuant to the rent stabilization law of nineteen hundred sixty-nine or the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four, upon the sale in any manner authorized by law of a multiple dwelling which was previously subject to the provisions of any such laws or acts which was acquired by the city in a tax foreclosure proceeding or pursuant to article nineteen-A of the real property actions and proceedings law, all dwelling units within the multiple dwelling shall be subject to the rent stabilization law of nineteen hundred sixty-nine, as amended, at the last rent charged by the city, or on behalf of the city, for such dwelling unit.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47339" number="60129" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If a unit which was subject to this chapter at the time the city so acquired title is occupied by a tenant who was in occupancy at the time of acquisition and remains in occupancy at the time of sale, such tenant shall be offered a one or two year lease at the rent provided in this section as soon as practical at the sale of the multiple dwelling.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47340" number="60130" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section shall not apply to redemptions from city ownership pursuant to chapter four of title eleven of the code.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47341" number="60131" version="1788">
										<HEADING>§ 26-509 Application for rent increase exemptions and equivalent tax abatement for rent regulated property occupied by certain senior citizens or persons with disabilities. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2831" name="26-509"/>§ 26-509 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application for rent increase exemptions and equivalent tax abatement for rent regulated property occupied by certain senior citizens or persons with disabilities. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47342" number="60132" version="1590">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commencement of agency jurisdiction.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47343" number="60133" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any provisions of this chapter to the contrary, the department of finance shall grant rent increase exemption orders or tax abatement certificates to senior citizens pursuant to this section and applications for such orders and certificates and renewal applications shall be made to the department of finance.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47344" number="60134" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any provisions of this chapter to the contrary, such agency as the mayor shall designate (which agency may also be the department of finance) shall grant rent increase exemption orders or tax abatement certificates to persons with disabilities pursuant to this section and applications for such orders and certificates and renewal applications shall be made to such agency.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47345" number="60135" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department of finance and such other agency as the mayor shall designate shall have the power, in relation to any application for a rent increase exemption order or tax abatement certificate under such department&apos;s or agency&apos;s jurisdiction, to determine the lawful stabilization rent, but shall not receive applications for adjustment of the initial legal regulated rent pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-513" destination-id="0-0-0-11545">26-513</LINK> of this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47346" number="60136" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department of finance and such other agency as the mayor shall designate may promulgate such rules and regulations as may be necessary to effectively carry out the provisions of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47347" number="60137" version="1590">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rent increase exemptions for certain senior citizens and persons with disabilities.</CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47348" number="60138" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No increase in the legal regulated rent shall be collectible from a tenant to whom there has been issued a currently valid rent exemption order pursuant to this subdivision, except as provided in such order, if such increase is a lawful increase in the monthly legal regulated rent over the rent legally payable on the eligibility date which is provided under a two year lease, or under such other term as regards dwelling units subject to the hotel stabilization provisions of this chapter, for an increase in rent:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47349" number="60139" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>pursuant to an order of the New York city rent guidelines board, or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47350" number="60140" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>based upon an owner hardship rent increase order issued by the state division of housing and community renewal.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47351" number="60141" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A tenant is eligible for a rent exemption order pursuant to this section if:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47352" number="60142" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the head of the household residing in the housing accommodation is sixty-two years of age or older or is a person with a disability, and is entitled to the possession or to the use or occupancy of a dwelling unit. To qualify as a person with a disability for the purposes of this section, an individual shall submit to such agency as the mayor shall designate proof (as specified by regulation of such agency as the mayor shall designate) showing that such individual is currently receiving social security disability insurance (SSDI) or supplemental security income (SSI) benefits under the federal social security act or disability pension or disability compensation benefits provided by the United States department of veterans affairs, or was previously eligible by virtue of receiving disability benefits under the supplemental security income program or the social security disability program and is currently receiving medical assistance benefits based on determination of disability as provided in section three hundred sixty-six of the social services law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47353" number="60143" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the aggregate disposable income (as defined by regulation of the department of finance) of all members of the household residing in the housing accommodation whose head of the household is sixty-two years of age or older does not exceed twenty-five thousand dollars beginning July first, two thousand five, twenty-six thousand dollars beginning July first, two thousand six, twenty-seven thousand dollars beginning July first, two thousand seven, twenty-eight thousand dollars beginning July first, two thousand eight, twenty-nine thousand dollars beginning July first, two thousand nine, and fifty thousand dollars beginning July first, two thousand fourteen, per year, after deduction of federal, state and city income and social security taxes. For purposes of this subparagraph, &quot;aggregate disposable income&quot; shall not include gifts or inheritances, payments made to individuals because of their status as victims of Nazi persecution, as defined in P.L. 103-286, or increases in benefits accorded pursuant to the social security act or a public or private pension paid to any member of the household which increase, in any given year, does not exceed the consumer price index (all items United States city average) for such year which take effect after the eligibility date of the head of the household receiving benefits under this section whether received by the head of the household or any other member of the household;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47354" number="60144" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the aggregate disposable income (as defined by regulation of such agency as the mayor shall designate) for the current income tax year of all members of the household residing in the housing accommodation whose head of the household is a person with a disability does not exceed fifty thousand dollars beginning July first, two thousand fourteen. For purposes of this subparagraph, &quot;aggregate disposable income&quot; shall not include gifts or inheritances, payments made to individuals because of their status as victims of Nazi persecution, as defined in P.L. 103-286, or increases in benefits accorded pursuant to the social security act or a public or private pension paid to any member of the household which increase, in any given year, does not exceed the consumer price index (all items United States city average) for such year which take effect after the eligibility date of the head of the household receiving benefits under this section, whether received by the head of the household or any other member of the household.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47355" number="60145" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>in the case of a head of the household who does not receive a monthly allowance for shelter pursuant to the social services law, (A) the maximum rent for the housing accommodation exceeds one-third of the aggregate disposable income, or (B) subject to the limitations contained within item (d) of subparagraph (i) of paragraph three of this subdivision, if any expected lawful increase in the maximum rent would cause such maximum rent to exceed one-third of the aggregate disposable income, or (C) subject to the limitations contained within item (d) of subparagraph (i) of paragraph three of this subdivision, if such head of household has been granted a rent increase exemption order that is in effect as of January first, two thousand fifteen or takes effect on or before July first, two thousand fifteen regardless of whether the maximum rent or any expected lawful increase described in this clause exceeds one-third of the aggregate disposable income; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-010]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47356" number="60146" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>in the case of a head of the household who receives a monthly allowance for shelter pursuant to the social services law, the maximum rent for the housing accommodation exceeds the maximum allowance for shelter which the head of the household is entitled to receive pursuant to the social services law, or subject to the limitations contained within item (d) of subparagraph (i) of paragraph three of this subdivision, if any expected lawful increase in the maximum rent would cause such maximum rent to exceed the maximum allowance for shelter which the head of the household is entitled to receive. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-010]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47357" number="60147" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A rent exemption order pursuant to this subdivision shall provide:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47358" number="60148" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>in the case of a head of the household who does not receive a monthly allowance for shelter pursuant to the social services law, that the landlord may not collect from the tenant to whom it is issued rent at a rate in excess of either one-third of the aggregate disposable income, or the rent in effect immediately preceding the eligibility date, whichever is greater; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47359" number="60149" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>in the case of a head of the household who receives a monthly allowance for shelter pursuant to the social services law, that the landlord may not collect from the tenant to whom it is issued rent at a rate in excess of either the maximum allowance for shelter which the head of the household is entitled to receive, or the rent in effect immediately preceding the eligibility date, whichever is greater; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47360" number="60150" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>notwithstanding clause (a) of this subparagraph, in the case of an eligible head of the household who has been granted a rent increase exemption order that is in effect as of January first, two thousand fifteen or takes effect on or before July first, two thousand fifteen, that the landlord may not collect from the tenant to whom it is issued rent at a rate in excess of the amount specified in such order, except as may be adjusted by any other provision of this chapter; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-010]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47361" number="60151" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>that the landlord may collect from the tenant increases in rent based on an electrical inclusion adjustment or an increase in dwelling space, services or equipment. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-010]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47362" number="60152" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each such order shall expire upon termination of occupancy of the housing accommodation by the tenant to whom it is issued. The landlord shall notify the department of finance in the case of a household whose eligibility for such order is based on the fact that the head of such household is sixty-two years of age or older, or such agency as the mayor shall designate in the case of a household whose eligibility for such order is based on the fact that the head of such household is a person with a disability, on a form to be prescribed by such department or agency, within thirty days of each such termination of occupancy.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47363" number="60153" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When a rent reduction order is issued by the state division of housing and community renewal, the amount of the reduction shall be subtracted from the rent payable by the tenant specified in a currently valid rent exemption order issued pursuant to this subdivision. The landlord may not collect from the tenant a sum of rent exceeding the adjusted amount while the rent reduction order is in effect.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47364" number="60154" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any landlord who collects, or seeks to collect or enforce, rent from a tenant in violation of the terms of a rent exemption order shall, for the purposes of all remedies, sanctions and penalties provided in this chapter, be deemed to have collected or attempted to collect or enforce, a rent in excess of the legal regulated rent.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47365" number="60155" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A rent exemption order shall be issued to each tenant who applies to the department of finance in the case of a tenant who is sixty-two years of age or older or to such agency as the mayor shall designate in the case of a tenant who is a person with a disability, in accordance with such department&apos;s or agency&apos;s applicable regulations and who is found to be eligible under this subdivision. Such order shall take effect on the first day of the first month after receipt of such application by the department of finance or such agency as the mayor shall designate, except that where there is any other increase in the legal regulated rent within ninety days of the issuance of the order increasing the tenant&apos;s maximum rent which a tenant is not exempted from paying, the rent exemption order shall without further order of the department of finance or such agency as the mayor shall designate take effect as of the effective date of said order increasing the tenant&apos;s rent including any retroactive increments collectible pursuant to such order.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47366" number="60156" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A rent exemption order shall be valid for the period of the lease or renewal thereof upon application by the tenant; provided, that upon any such renewal application being made by the tenant, any rent exemption order then in effect with respect to such tenant shall be deemed renewed until such time as the department of finance or such agency as the mayor shall designate shall have found such tenant to be either eligible or ineligible for a rent exemption order but in no event for more than six additional months. If such tenant is found eligible, the order shall be deemed to have taken effect upon expiration of the exemption. In the event that any such tenant shall, subsequent to any such automatic renewal, not be granted a rent exemption order, such tenant shall be liable to the owner for the difference between the amounts the tenant has paid under the provisions of the automatically renewed order and the amounts which the tenant would have been required to pay in the absence of such order. Any rent exemption order issued pursuant to this subdivision shall include provisions giving notice as to the contents of this paragraph relating to automatic renewals of rent exemption orders and shall include provisions giving notice that the tenant must enter into either a one or two year renewal lease in order to be eligible for a rent exemption. The notice that each tenant receives from the owner relating to the right to a renewal lease shall contain similar information. Any application or renewal application for a rent exemption order shall also constitute an application for a tax abatement under such section. The department of finance and such other agency as the mayor shall designate may, with respect to renewal applications by the tenants who have been found eligible for rent exemption orders, prescribe a simplified form including a certification of the applicant&apos;s continued eligibility in lieu of a detailed statement of income and other qualifications.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47367" number="60157" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, when a head of a household to whom a then current, valid rent exemption order has been issued under this chapter, chapter three or chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T26C007" destination-id="0-0-0-2951">seven</LINK> of this title moves his or her principal residence to a subsequent dwelling unit subject to regulation under this chapter, the head of the household may apply to the department of finance or such other agency as the mayor shall designate for a rent exemption order relating to the subsequent dwelling unit, and such order may provide that the head of the household shall be exempt from paying that portion of the legal regulated rent for the subsequent dwelling unit which is the least of the following:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47368" number="60158" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the amount by which the rent for the subsequent dwelling unit exceeds the last rent, as reduced, which the head of the household was required to actually pay in the original dwelling unit;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47369" number="60159" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the last amount deducted from the maximum rent or legal regulated rent meaning the most recent monthly deduction for the applicant in the original dwelling unit pursuant to this section or section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-605" destination-id="0-0-0-11511">26-605</LINK> of this title; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47370" number="60160" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>where the head of the household does not receive a monthly allowance for shelter pursuant to the social services law, the amount by which the legal regulated rent of the subsequent dwelling unit exceeds one-third of the combined income of all members of the household except that this subparagraph shall not apply to any eligible head of the household who has been granted a rent increase exemption order that is in effect as of January first, two thousand fifteen or takes effect on or before July first, two thousand fifteen. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-010]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47371" number="60161" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such certificate shall be effective as of the first day of the month in which the tenant applied for such exemption or as of the date the tenant took occupancy of the subsequent dwelling unit, whichever is later provided both occur after the effective date of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47372" number="60162" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When a dwelling unit subject to regulation under this chapter is later reclassified to a dwelling unit subject to regulation under chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T26C003" destination-id="0-0-0-2947">three</LINK> of this title, the eligibility of a head of the household to receive a rent increase exemption order upon such reclassification shall be governed by paragraph eight of subdivision m of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-405" destination-id="0-0-0-11505">26-405</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47373" number="60163" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When a dwelling unit subject to regulation under this chapter is later reclassified to a dwelling unit subject to the provisions of article II, IV, V or XI of the private housing finance law or subject to a mortgage insured or initially insured by the federal government pursuant to section two hundred thirteen of the national housing act, as amended, the eligibility of a head of the household to receive a rent increase exemption order upon such reclassification shall be governed by section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-605.1" destination-id="0-0-0-11547">26-605.1</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47374" number="60164" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, where a head of household holds a current, valid rent exemption order and, after the effective date of this paragraph, there is a permanent decrease in aggregate disposable income in an amount which exceeds twenty percent of such aggregate disposable income as represented in such head of the household&apos;s last approved application for a rent exemption order or for renewal thereof, such head of the household may apply for a redetermination of the amount set forth therein. Upon application, such amount shall be redetermined so as to reestablish the ratio of adjusted rent to aggregate disposable income which existed at the time of approval of such head of the household&apos;s last application for a rent exemption order or for renewal thereof; provided, however, that in no event shall the amount of adjusted rent be redetermined to be (i) in the case of a head of the household who does not receive a monthly allowance for shelter pursuant to the social services law, less than one-third of the aggregate disposable income unless such head of the household has been granted a rent exemption order that is in effect as of January first, two thousand fifteen or takes effect on or before July first, two thousand fifteen; or (ii) in the case of a head of the household who receives a monthly allowance for shelter pursuant to such law, less than the maximum allowance for shelter which such head of the household is entitled to receive pursuant to the social services law. For purposes of this paragraph, a decrease in aggregate disposable income shall not include any decrease in such income resulting from the manner in which such income is calculated pursuant to any amendment to paragraph c of subdivision one of section four hundred sixty-seven-b of the real property tax law, any amendment to the regulations of the department of finance made on or after the effective date of the local law that added this clause, or any amendment to the regulations of such other agency as the mayor shall designate made on or after October tenth, two thousand five. For purposes of this paragraph, &quot;adjusted rent&quot; shall mean legal regulated rent less the amount set forth in a rent exemption order. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-010]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47375" number="60165" version="1590">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Tax abatement for properties subject to rent exemption order.</CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47376" number="60166" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Tax abatement, pursuant to the provisions of section four hundred sixty-seven-b of the real property tax law, shall be granted with respect to any real property for which a rent exemption order is issued under subdivision b of this section to the tenant of any housing accommodation contained therein. The rent exemption order shall also constitute the tax abatement certificate.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47377" number="60167" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The real estate tax imposed upon any real property for which a rent exemption is issued, shall be reduced and abated by an amount equal to the difference between:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47378" number="60168" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the sum of the maximum rents collectible under such orders, and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47379" number="60169" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the sum of rents that would be collectible from the tenants of such housing accommodations if no exemption had been granted pursuant to subdivision b of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47380" number="60170" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For any individual housing accommodation, the tax abatement computed pursuant to this subdivision shall be available with respect to a period commencing on the effective date of the initial rent exemption order, and ending on the expiration date of such order or on the effective date of an order terminating the rent exemption.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47381" number="60171" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Prior to the commencement of each fiscal year, the department of finance shall determine the total amount of taxes to be abated under this section with respect to each property for which rent exemption orders granted to persons sixty-two years of age or older were in effect for all or any part of the preceding calendar year. Prior to the commencement of each fiscal year, such agency as the mayor shall designate shall determine and, if such agency is not the department of finance, shall notify the department of finance of the total amount of taxes to be abated under this section with respect to each property for which rent exemption orders granted to persons with disabilities were in effect for all or any part of the preceding calendar year. The commissioner of finance shall make the appropriate adjustment in the real estate tax payable in such fiscal year.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47382" number="60172" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Tax abatement pursuant to this section shall be in addition to any other tax abatement authorized by law, but shall not reduce the tax for any fiscal year below zero. In the event that the tax abatement certificate authorizes an amount of deduction in excess of the real estate installment, then the balance may be applied to any subsequent installment until exhausted. In such a case the owner shall submit with his or her real estate tax bill and remittance, a verified statement in such form as prescribed by the commissioner of finance setting forth the carry over amount and the amounts previously applied; provided, however, that at the request of the owner such balance shall be paid to the owner by the commissioner of finance in lieu of being applied to any subsequent installment, except where the owner is in arrears in the payment of real estate taxes on any property. For the purposes of this paragraph, where the owner is a corporation, it shall be deemed to be in arrears when any of the officers, directors or any person holding an interest in more than ten percent of the issued and outstanding stock of such corporation is in arrears in the payment of real estate taxes on any property; where title is held by a nominee, the owner shall be deemed to be in arrears when the person for whose benefit such title is held is in arrears in the payment of real estate taxes on any property.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47383" number="60173" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the provisions of this chapter, a tenant who resides in a dwelling unit which becomes subject to this chapter upon the sale by the city of New York of the building in which such dwelling unit is situated may be issued a rent increase exemption order for increases in rent which occurred during ownership of such building by the city of New York provided that such tenant would have been otherwise eligible to receive a rent increase exemption order at the time of such increase but for the fact that such tenant occupied a dwelling unit owned by the city of New York and was therefore not subject to this chapter. Application for such rent increase exemption orders shall be made within one year from the date such building is sold by the city of New York or within one year of the effective date of this provision, whichever is later.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47384" number="60174" version="606">
											<PARA>(Am. 2015 N.Y. Laws Ch. 553, 12/11/2015, eff. 12/11/2015) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-010]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47385" number="60175" version="2279">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1986/052" destination-id="0-0-0-27260">L.L. 1986/052</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1988/067" destination-id="0-0-0-27052">L.L. 1988/067</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1992/040" destination-id="0-0-0-26588">L.L. 1992/040</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1992/096" destination-id="0-0-0-26504">L.L. 1992/096</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1996/001" destination-id="0-0-0-26132">L.L. 1996/001</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2003/056" destination-id="0-0-0-25326">L.L. 2003/056</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2003/067" destination-id="0-0-0-25312">L.L. 2003/067</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2005/021" destination-id="0-0-0-25224">L.L. 2005/021</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/044" destination-id="0-0-0-24908">L.L. 2009/044</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2014/019" destination-id="0-0-0-24558">L.L. 2014/019</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2014/039" destination-id="0-0-0-24564">L.L. 2014/039</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2017/024" destination-id="0-0-0-20125">L.L. 2017/024</LINK>, and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2020/112" destination-id="0-0-0-20720">L.L. 2020/112</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-131085" number="60176" version="2255">
										<HEADING>§ 26-509.1 Notice of rent increase exemption and tax abatement.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-28426" name="26-509.1"/>§ 26-509.1 Notice of rent increase exemption and tax abatement.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235042" number="60177" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> For the purposes of this section, the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235041" number="60178" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Available data.</CHARFORMAT> The term “available data” means data that is within the possession of the responsible agency and that such agency may use, obtain, or disclose, as applicable, for the purposes of this section, pursuant to law, rule, or an agreement. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235040" number="60179" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Identified head of household.</CHARFORMAT> The term “identified head of household” means a person who has been granted program rent benefits that the responsible agency has determined, based on available data, is a head of the household, as such term is defined in section 467-b of the real property tax law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235039" number="60180" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Identified landlord.</CHARFORMAT> The term “identified landlord” means a person whom the responsible agency has determined, based on available data, is a landlord or owner of a dwelling unit subject to the provisions of this chapter, other than a landlord of a dwelling unit for which the department of housing preservation and development administers program rent benefits. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235038" number="60181" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Program rent benefits.</CHARFORMAT> The term “program rent benefits” means a rent increase exemption order issued pursuant to subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-509" destination-id="0-0-0-2831">26-509</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235037" number="60182" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Program tax benefits.</CHARFORMAT> The term “program tax benefits” means a tax abatement authorized pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-509" destination-id="0-0-0-2831">26-509</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235036" number="60183" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Responsible agency.</CHARFORMAT> The term “responsible agency” means an agency responsible for administering the provisions of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-509" destination-id="0-0-0-2831">26-509</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235035" number="60184" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eligibility notice.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235034" number="60185" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible agency shall provide a notice of potential eligibility in accordance with this subdivision to each identified landlord at least 2 times each year, in a form and manner determined by the responsible agency. Such notice may be provided electronically. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235033" number="60186" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The notice of potential eligibility shall read substantially as follows: “YOU MAY BE ELIGIBLE FOR A TAX ABATEMENT IF ANY OF THE TENANTS IN A DWELLING UNIT ON YOUR PROPERTY RECEIVES A SENIOR CITIZEN RENT INCREASE EXEMPTION OR A DISABILITY RENT INCREASE EXEMPTION IN THE AMOUNT OF FORGONE RENT DUE TO SUCH AN EXEMPTION. For further information please contact (insert the responsible agency).” The responsible agency shall include information regarding program tax benefits with such notice. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235032" number="60187" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Renewal information notice.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235031" number="60188" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible agency shall provide a renewal information notice to each identified head of household regarding the renewal requirements for program rent benefits at least 60 days before the expiration of a rent increase exemption order, where such identified head of household has not yet submitted an applicable renewal application. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235030" number="60189" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The renewal information notice shall read substantially as follows: “YOU ARE ADVISED THAT YOUR SENIOR CITIZEN RENT INCREASE EXEMPTION OR DISABILITY RENT INCREASE EXEMPTION IS SCHEDULED TO EXPIRE ON (ENTER DATE).” The responsible agency shall either include the applicable renewal application forms for program rent benefits with such notice or include in such notice the address of the website containing such forms, the address of the responsible agency’s office where such forms are available in-person, and instructions for requesting such forms via telephone. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235029" number="60190" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Third party notice.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235028" number="60191" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An identified head of household may request that an additional notice be sent to an adult third party. Such request shall be submitted to the responsible agency in a form and manner determined by such agency, no later than 60 days before the expiration of rent increase exemption orders. Such form shall provide a section whereby the designated third party shall consent to such designation. The responsible agency shall maintain a record of all such third party notices. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235027" number="60192" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible agency shall provide the renewal information notice to a third party designated pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subdivision when such notice is sent to an identified head of household pursuant to subdivision c of this section. Such renewal notice shall read substantially as follows: “ON BEHALF OF (IDENTIFIED HEAD OF HOUSEHOLD), YOU ARE ADVISED THAT THE SENIOR CITIZEN RENT INCREASE EXEMPTION OR DISABILITY RENT INCREASE EXEMPTION IS SCHEDULED TO EXPIRE ON (ENTER DATE).” <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235026" number="60193" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible agency is not required to provide a notice to a third party after (i) an identified head of household notifies the responsible agency in writing that such identified head of household no longer wishes to notify such third party or (ii) such identified head of household ceases to qualify for program rent benefits. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235025" number="60194" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Transfer notice upon the death or permanent exit of an identified head of household.</CHARFORMAT> If the responsible agency identifies, based on a review of available data, that a program rent benefit may be transferred pursuant to subdivision 4-a of section 467-b of the real property tax law, the responsible agency shall send a notice to a surviving member of the household that the responsible agency has determined, based on available data, may be eligible for such benefit. The option to transfer a program rent benefit shall be available for 6 months after the identified head of household dies or permanently leaves the dwelling unit, or 90 days after the date of notice from the responsible agency that informed the household that the program rent benefit expired upon the death of the identified head of household, whichever is later. Such notice shall include an explanation of the process to transfer such benefit to an eligible surviving household member and the time period to do so, accompanied by the form necessary to transfer such benefit. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235024" number="60195" version="2255">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Failure to provide or receive required notice.</CHARFORMAT> Failure to provide any notice required by a provision of this section, or failure of a party to receive the same, shall not affect the validity of the levy, collection, or enforcement of taxes on property owned by a landlord or any obligation of a tenant to a landlord. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235022" number="60196" version="2255">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2025/147, 10/25/2025, eff. 7/22/2026) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-114]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-235021" number="60197" version="2255">
										<HEADING>§ 26-510 Rent guidelines board. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11549" name="26-510"/>§ 26-510 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rent guidelines board. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47386" number="60198" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be a rent guidelines board to consist of nine members, appointed by the mayor. Two members shall be representative of tenants, two shall be representative of owners of property, and five shall be public members each of whom shall have had at least five years experience in either finance, economics or housing. One public member shall be designated by the mayor to serve as chairman and shall hold no other public office. No member, officer or employee of any municipal rent regulation agency or the state division of housing and community renewal and no person who owns or manages real estate covered by this law or who is an officer of any owner or tenant organization shall serve on a rent guidelines board. One public member, one member representative of tenants and one member representative of owners shall serve for a term ending two years from January first next succeeding the date of their appointment; one public member, one member representative of tenants and one member representative of owners shall serve for terms ending three years from the January first next succeeding the date of their appointment and two public members shall serve for terms ending four years from January first next succeeding the dates of their appointment. The chairman shall serve at the pleasure of the mayor. Thereafter, all members shall continue in office until their successors have been appointed and qualified. The mayor shall fill any vacancy which may occur by reason of death, resignation or otherwise in a manner consistent with the original appointment. A member may be removed by the mayor for cause, but not without an opportunity to be heard in person or by counsel, in his or her defense, upon not less than ten days notice.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47387" number="60199" version="123">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The rent guidelines board shall establish annual guidelines for rent adjustments, and in determining whether rents for housing accommodations subject to the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four or this law shall be adjusted shall consider, among other things (1) the economic condition of the residential real estate industry in the affected area including such factors as the prevailing and projected (i) real estate taxes and sewer and water rates, (ii) gross operating maintenance costs (including insurance rates, governmental fees, cost of fuel and labor costs), (iii) costs and availability of financing (including effective rates of interest), (iv) over-all supply of housing accommodations and over-all vacancy rates, (2) relevant data from the current and projected cost of living indices for the affected area, (3) such other data as may be made available to it. Not later than July first of each year, the rent guidelines board shall file with the city clerk its findings for the preceding calendar year, and shall accompany such findings with a statement of the maximum rate or rates of rent adjustment, if any, for one or more classes of accommodations subject to this law, authorized for leases or other rental agreements commencing on the next succeeding October first or within the twelve months thereafter. Such findings and statement shall be published in the City Record. The rent guidelines board shall not establish annual guidelines for rent adjustments based on the current rental cost of a unit or on the amount of time that has elapsed since another rent increase was authorized pursuant to this title. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47388" number="60200" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such members shall be compensated on a per diem basis of one hundred dollars per day for no more than twenty-five days a year except that the chairman shall be compensated at one hundred twenty-five dollars a day for no more than fifty days a year. The chairman shall be chief administrative officer of the rent guidelines board and among his or her powers and duties he or she shall have the authority to employ, assign and supervise the employees of the rent guidelines board and enter into contracts for consultant services. The department of housing preservation and development shall cooperate with the rent guidelines board and may assign personnel and perform such services in connection with the duties of the rent guidelines board as may reasonably be required by the chairman.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47389" number="60201" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any housing accommodation covered by this law owned by a member in good standing of an association registered with the department of housing preservation and development pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-511" destination-id="0-0-0-11503">26-511</LINK> of this chapter which becomes vacant for any reason, other than harassment of the prior tenant, may be offered for rental at any price notwithstanding any guideline level established by the guidelines board for renewal leases, provided the offering price does not exceed the rental then authorized by the guidelines board for such dwelling unit plus five percent for a new lease not exceeding two years and a further five percent for a new lease having a minimum term of three years, until July first, nineteen hundred seventy, at which time the guidelines board shall determine what the rental for a vacancy shall be.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47390" number="60202" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to hotel dwelling units, covered by this law pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-506" destination-id="0-0-0-11541">26-506</LINK> of this chapter, the council, after receipt of a study from the rent guidelines board, shall establish a guideline for rent increases, irrespective of the limitations on amount of increase in subdivision d hereof, which guideline shall apply only to permanent tenants. A permanent tenant is an individual or family who at any time since May thirty-first, nineteen hundred sixty-eight, or hereafter, has continuously resided in the same hotel as a principal residence for a period of at least six months. On January first, nineteen hundred seventy-one and once annually each succeeding year the rent guidelines board shall cause a review to be made of the levels of fair rent increases provided under this subdivision and may establish different levels of fair rent increases for hotel dwelling units renting within different rental ranges based upon the board&apos;s consideration of conditions in the market for hotel accommodations and the economics of hotel real estate. Any hotel dwelling unit which is voluntarily vacated by the tenant thereof may be offered for rental at the guideline level for vacancies established by the rent guidelines board. If a hotel dwelling unit becomes vacant because the prior tenant was evicted therefrom, there shall be no increase in the rental thereof except for such increases in rental that the prior tenant would have had to pay had he or she continued in occupancy.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47391" number="60203" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>From September twenty-fifth, nineteen hundred sixty-nine until the rate of permissible increase is established by the council pursuant to subdivision e of this section, there shall not be collected from any permanent hotel tenant any rent increase in excess of ten percent over the rent payable for his or her dwelling unit on May thirty-first, nineteen hundred sixty-eight, except for hardship increases authorized by the conciliation and appeals board. Any owner who collects or permits any rent to be collected in excess of the amount authorized by this subdivision shall not be eligible to be a member in good standing of a hotel industry stabilization association.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47392" number="60204" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The rent guidelines board prior to the annual adjustment of the level of fair rents provided for under subdivision b of this section for dwelling units and hotel dwelling units covered by this law, shall hold a public hearing or hearings for the purpose of collecting information relating to all factors set forth in subdivision b of this section. Notice of the date, time, location and summary of subject matter for the public hearing or hearings shall be published in the City Record daily for a period of not less than eight days and at least once in one or more newspapers of general circulation at least eight days immediately preceding each hearing date, at the expense of the city of New York, and the hearing shall be open for testimony from any individual, group, association or representative thereof who wants to testify.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47393" number="60205" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Maximum rates of rent adjustment shall not be established more than once annually for any housing accommodation within the board&apos;s jurisdiction. Once established, no such rate shall, within the one-year period, be adjusted by any surcharge, supplementary adjustment or other modification.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112643" number="60206" version="132">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>j.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other provision of this law, the adjustment for vacancy leases covered by the provisions of this law shall be determined exclusively pursuant to this section. The rent guidelines board shall no longer promulgate adjustments for vacancy leases unless otherwise authorized by this chapter. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112645" number="60207" version="606">
											<PARA>(Am. 2019 N.Y. Laws Ch. 36 Pt. C §§ 1, 4, 6/14/2019, eff. 6/14/2019; Am. 2019 N.Y. Laws Ch. 39 Pt. Q § 1, 6/24/2019, retro eff. 6/14/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47394" number="60208" version="123">
										<HEADING>§ 26-511 Real estate industry stabilization association. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11503" name="26-511"/>§ 26-511 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Real estate industry stabilization association. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227719" number="60209" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The real estate industry stabilization association registered with the department of housing preservation and development is hereby divested of all its powers and authority under this law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47396" number="60210" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The stabilization code heretofore promulgated by such association, as approved by the department of housing preservation and development, is hereby continued to the extent that it is not inconsistent with law. Such code may be amended from time to time, provided, however, that no such amendments shall be promulgated except by action of the commissioner of the division of housing and community renewal and provided further, that prior to the adoption of any such amendments, the commissioner shall (i) submit the proposed amendments to the commissioner of the department of housing preservation and development and allow such commissioner thirty days to make comments or recommendations on the proposed amendments, (ii) review the comments or recommendations, if any, made pursuant to clause (i) of this subdivision and make any revisions to the proposed amendments which the commissioner of the division of housing and community renewal deems appropriate provided that any such review and revision shall be completed within thirty days of receipt of such comments or recommendations and (iii) thereafter hold a public hearing on the proposed amendments. No provision of such code shall impair or diminish any right or remedy granted to any party by this law or any other provision of law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47397" number="60211" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A code shall not be adopted hereunder unless it appears to the division of housing and community renewal that such code:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47398" number="60212" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>provides safeguards against unreasonably high rent increases and, in general, protects tenants and the public interest, and does not impose any industry wide schedule of rents or minimum rentals;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47399" number="60213" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>requires owners not to exceed the level of lawful rents as provided by this law;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47400" number="60214" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>provides for a cash refund or a credit, to be applied against future rent, in the amount of any rent overcharge collected by an owner and any penalties, costs, attorneys&apos; fees and interest from the date of the overcharge at the rate of interest payable on a judgment pursuant to section five thousand four of the civil practice law and rules for which the owner is assessed;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47401" number="60215" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>includes provisions requiring owners to grant a one or two year vacancy or renewal lease at the option of the tenant except where a mortgage or mortgage commitment existing as of April first, nineteen hundred sixty-nine, provides that the mortgagor shall not grant a one year lease;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47402" number="60216" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>includes guidelines with respect to such additional rent and related matters as, for example, security deposits, advance rental payments, the use of escalator clauses in leases and provision for increase in rentals for garages and other ancillary facilities, so as to insure that the level of fair rent increase established under this law will not be subverted and made ineffective, provided further that notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, rule, regulation, contract, agreement, lease or other obligation, no owner, in addition to the authorized collection of rent, shall demand, receive or retain a security deposit or advance payment which exceeds the rent of one month for or in connection with the use or occupancy of a housing accommodation by (a) any tenant who is sixty-five years of age or older or (b) any tenant who is receiving disability retirement benefit or supplemental security income pursuant to the federal social security act for any lease or lease renewal entered into after July 1, 2002;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47403" number="60217" version="128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5-a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>[repealed;] <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47404" number="60218" version="132">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>provides criteria whereby the commissioner may act upon applications by owners for increases in excess of the level of fair rent increase established under this law provided, however, that such criteria shall provide (a) as to hardship applications, for a finding that the level of fair rent increase is not sufficient to enable the owner to maintain approximately the same average annual net income (which shall be computed without regard to debt service, financing costs or management fees) for the three year period ending on or within six months of the date of an application pursuant to such criteria as compared with annual net income, which prevailed on the average over the period nineteen hundred sixty-eight through nineteen hundred seventy, or for the first three years of operation if the building was completed since nineteen hundred sixty-eight or for the first three fiscal years after a transfer of title to a new owner provided the new owner can establish to the satisfaction of the commissioner that he or she acquired title to the building as a result of a bona fide sale of the entire building and that the new owner is unable to obtain requisite records for the fiscal years nineteen hundred sixty-eight through nineteen hundred seventy despite diligent efforts to obtain same from predecessors in title and further provided that the new owner can provide financial data covering a minimum of six years under his or her continuous and uninterrupted operation of the building to meet the three year to three year comparative test periods herein provided; and (b) as to completed building-wide major capital improvements, for a finding that such improvements are deemed depreciable under the Internal Revenue Code and that the cost is to be amortized over a twelve-year period for a building with thirty-five or fewer housing accommodations, or a twelve and one-half-year period for a building with more than thirty-five housing accommodations, for any determination issued by the division of housing and community renewal after the effective date of the the chapter of the laws of two thousand nineteen that amended this paragraph and shall be removed from the legal regulated rent thirty years from the date the increase became effective inclusive of any increases granted by the applicable rent guidelines board. Temporary major capital improvement increases shall be collectible prospectively on the first day of the first month beginning sixty days from the date of mailing notice of approval to the tenant. Such notice shall disclose the total monthly increase in rent and the first month in which the tenant would be required to pay the temporary increase. An approval for a temporary major capital improvement increase shall not include retroactive payments. The collection of any increase shall not exceed two percent in any year from the effective date of the order granting the increase over the rent set forth in the schedule of gross rents, with collectability of any dollar excess above said sum to be spread forward in similar increments and added to the rent as established or set in future years. Upon vacancy, the landlord may add any remaining balance of the temporary major capital improvement increase to the legal regulated rent. Notwithstanding any other provision of the law, for any renewal lease commencing on or after June 14, 2019, the collection of any rent increases due to any major capital improvements approved on or after June 16, 2012 and before June 16, 2019 shall not exceed two percent in any year for any tenant in occupancy on the date the major capital improvement was approved or based upon cash purchase price exclusive of interest or service charges. Where an application for a temporary major capital improvement increase has been filed, a tenant shall have sixty days from the date of mailing of a notice of a proceeding in which to answer or reply. The state division of housing and community renewal shall provide any responding tenant with the reasons for the division&apos;s approval or denial of such application. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary contained herein, no hardship increase granted pursuant to this paragraph shall, when added to the annual gross rents, as determined by the commissioner, exceed the sum of, (i) the annual operating expenses, (ii) an allowance for management services as determined by the commissioner, (iii) actual annual mortgage debt service (interest and amortization) on its indebtedness to a lending institution, an insurance company, a retirement fund or welfare fund which is operated under the supervision of the banking or insurance laws of the state of New York or the United States, and (iv) eight and one-half percent of that portion of the fair market value of the property which exceeds the unpaid principal amount of the mortgage indebtedness referred to in subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph. Fair market value for the purposes of this paragraph shall be six times the annual gross rent. The collection of any increase in the stabilized rent for any apartment pursuant to this paragraph shall not exceed six percent in any year from the effective date of the order granting the increase over the rent set forth in the schedule of gross rents, with collectability of any dollar excess above said sum to be spread forward in similar increments and added to the stabilized rent as established or set in future years; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47405" number="60219" version="128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6-a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>provides criteria whereby as an alternative to the hardship application provided under paragraph six of this subdivision owners of buildings acquired by the same owner or a related entity owned by the same principals three years prior to the date of application may apply to the division for increases in excess of the level of applicable guideline increases established under this law based on a finding by the commissioner that such guideline increases are not sufficient to enable the owner to maintain an annual gross rent income for such building which exceeds the annual operating expenses of such building by a sum equal to at least five percent of such gross rent. For the purposes of this paragraph, operating expenses shall consist of the actual, reasonable, costs of fuel, labor, utilities, taxes, other than income or corporate franchise taxes, fees, permits, necessary contracted services and noncapital repairs, insurance, parts and supplies, management fees and other administrative costs and mortgage interest. For the purposes of this paragraph, mortgage interest shall be deemed to mean interest on a bona fide mortgage including an allocable portion of charges related thereto. Criteria to be considered in determining a bona fide mortgage other than an institutional mortgage shall include; condition of the property, location of the property, the existing mortgage market at the time the mortgage is placed, the term of the mortgage, the amortization rate, the principal amount of the mortgage, security and other terms and conditions of the mortgage. The commissioner shall set a rental value for any unit occupied by the owner or a person related to the owner or unoccupied at the owner&apos;s choice for more than one month at the last regulated rent plus the minimum number of guidelines increases or, if no such regulated rent existed or is known, the commissioner shall impute a rent consistent with other rents in the building. The amount of hardship increase shall be such as may be required to maintain the annual gross rent income as provided by this paragraph. The division shall not grant a hardship application under this paragraph or paragraph six of this subdivision for a period of three years subsequent to granting a hardship application under the provisions of this paragraph. The collection of any increase in the rent for any housing accommodation pursuant to this paragraph shall not exceed six percent in any year from the effective date of the order granting the increase over the rent set forth in the schedule of gross rents, with collectability of any dollar excess above said sum to be spread forward in similar increments and added to the rent as established or set in future years. No application shall be approved unless the owner&apos;s equity in such building exceeds five percent of: (i) the arms length purchase price of the property; (ii) the cost of any capital improvements for which the owner has not collected a surcharge; (iii) any repayment of principal of any mortgage or loan used to finance the purchase of the property or any capital improvements for which the owner has not collected a surcharge and (iv) any increase in the equalized assessed value of the property which occurred subsequent to the first valuation of the property after purchase by the owner. For the purposes of this paragraph, owner&apos;s equity shall mean the sum of (i) the purchase price of the property less the principal of any mortgage or loan used to finance the purchase of the property, (ii) the cost of any capital improvement for which the owner has not collected a surcharge less the principal of any mortgage or loan used to finance said improvement, (iii) any repayment of the principal of any mortgage or loan used to finance the purchase of the property or any capital improvement for which the owner has not collected a surcharge, and (iv) any increase in the equalized assessed value of the property which occurred subsequent to the first valuation of the property after purchase by the owner;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47406" number="60220" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>establishes a fair and consistent formula for allocation of rental adjustment to be made upon granting of an increase by the commissioner;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47407" number="60221" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>requires owners to maintain all services furnished by them on May thirty-first, nineteen hundred sixty-eight, or as otherwise provided by law, in connection with the leasing of the dwelling units covered by this law;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47408" number="60222" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9)<TAB tab-count="1"/>provides that an owner shall not refuse to renew a lease except:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47409" number="60223" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>where he or she intends in good faith to demolish the building and has obtained a permit therefor from the department of buildings; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47410" number="60224" version="132">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>where he or she seeks to recover possession of one dwelling unit because of immediate and compelling necessity for his or her own personal use and occupancy as his or her primary residence or for the use and occupancy of a member of his or her immediate family as his or her primary residence, provided however, that this subparagraph shall permit recovery of only one dwelling unit and shall not apply where a tenant or the spouse of a tenant lawfully occupying the dwelling unit is sixty-two years of age or older, has been a tenant in a dwelling unit in that building for fifteen years or more, or has an impairment which results from anatomical, physiological or psychological conditions, other than addiction to alcohol, gambling, or any controlled substance, which are demonstrable by medically acceptable clinical and laboratory diagnostic techniques, and which are expected to be permanent and which prevent the tenant from engaging in any substantial gainful employment, unless such owner offers to provide and if requested, provides an equivalent or superior housing accommodation at the same or lower stabilized rent in a closely proximate area. The provisions of this subparagraph shall only permit one of the individual owners of any building to recover possession of one dwelling unit for his or her own personal use and/or for that of his or her immediate family. A dwelling unit recovered by an owner pursuant to this subparagraph shall not for a period of three years be rented, leased, subleased or assigned to any person other than a person for whose benefit recovery of the dwelling unit is permitted pursuant to this subparagraph or to the tenant in occupancy at the time of recovery under the same terms as the original lease; provided, however, that a tenant required to surrender a dwelling unit under this subparagraph shall have a cause of action in any court of competent jurisdiction for damages, declaratory, and injunctive relief against a landlord or purchaser of the premises who makes a fraudulent statement regarding a proposed use of the housing accommodation. In any action or proceeding brought pursuant to this subparagraph a prevailing tenant shall be entitled to recovery of actual damages, and reasonable attorneys&apos; fees. This subparagraph shall not be deemed to establish or eliminate any claim that the former tenant of the dwelling unit may otherwise have against the owner. Any such rental, lease, sublease or assignment during such period to any other person may be subject to a penalty of a forfeiture of the right to any increases in residential rents in such building for a period of three years; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47411" number="60225" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>where the housing accommodation is owned by a hospital, convent, monastery, asylum, public institution, college, school dormitory or any institution operated exclusively for charitable or educational purposes on a non-profit basis and either:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47412" number="60226" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the tenant&apos;s initial tenancy commenced after the owner acquired the property and the owner requires the unit in connection with its charitable or educational purposes including, but not limited to, housing for affiliated persons; provided that with respect to any tenant whose right to occupancy commenced prior to July first, nineteen hundred seventy-eight pursuant to a written lease or written rental agreement and who did not receive notice at the time of the execution of the lease that his or her tenancy was subject to non-renewal, the institution shall not have the right to refuse to renew pursuant to this subparagraph; provided further that a tenant who was affiliated with the institution at the commencement of his or her tenancy and whose affiliation terminates during such tenancy shall not have the right to a renewal lease; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47413" number="60227" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the owner requires the unit for a non-residential use in connection with its charitable or educational purposes; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47414" number="60228" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>on specified grounds set forth in the code consistent with the purposes of this law; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47415" number="60229" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>where a tenant violates the provisions of paragraph twelve of this sub- division.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47416" number="60230" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9-a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>provides that where an owner has submitted to and the attorney general has accepted for filing an offering plan to convert the building to cooperative or condominium ownership and the owner has presented the offering plan to the tenants in occupancy, any renewal or vacancy lease may contain a provision that if a building is converted to cooperative or condominium ownership pursuant to an eviction plan, as provided in section three hundred fifty-two-eeee of the general business law, the lease may only be cancelled upon the expiration of three years after the plan has been declared effective, and upon ninety days notice to the tenant that such period has expired or will be expiring.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47417" number="60231" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(10)<TAB tab-count="1"/>specifically provides that if an owner fails to comply with any order of the commissioner or is found by the commissioner to have harassed a tenant to obtain vacancy of his or her housing accommodation, he or she shall, in addition to being subject to any other penalties or remedies permitted by law, be barred thereafter from applying for or collecting any further rent increase. The compliance by the owner with the order of the commissioner or the restoration of the tenant subject to harassment to the housing accommodation or compliance with such other remedy as shall be determined by the commissioner to be appropriate shall result in the prospective elimination of such sanctions;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47418" number="60232" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(11)<TAB tab-count="1"/>includes provisions which may be peculiarly applicable to hotels including specifically that no owner shall refuse to extend or renew a tenancy for the purpose of preventing a hotel tenant from becoming a permanent tenant; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47419" number="60233" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(12)<TAB tab-count="1"/>permits subletting of units subject to this law pursuant to section two hundred twenty-six-b of the real property law provided that (a) the rental charged to the subtenant does not exceed the stabilized rent plus a ten percent surcharge payable to the tenant if the unit sublet was furnished with the tenant&apos;s furniture; (b) the tenant can establish that at all times he or she has maintained the unit as his or her primary residence and intends to occupy it as such at the expiration of the sublease; (c) an owner may terminate the tenancy of a tenant who sublets or assigns contrary to the terms of this paragraph but no action or proceeding based on the non-primary residence of a tenant may be commenced prior to the expiration date of his or her lease; (d) where an apartment is sublet the prime tenant shall retain the right to a renewal lease and the rights and status of a tenant in occupancy as they relate to conversion to condominium or cooperative ownership; (e) where a tenant violates the provisions of subparagraph (a) of this paragraph the subtenant shall be entitled to damages of three times the overcharge and may also be awarded attorneys fees and interest from the date of the overcharge at the rate of interest payable on a judgment pursuant to section five thousand four of the civil practice law and rules; (f) the tenant may not sublet the unit for more than a total of two years, including the term of the proposed sublease, out of the four-year period preceding the termination date of the proposed sublease. The provisions of this subparagraph shall only apply to subleases commencing on and after July first, nineteen hundred eighty-three; (g) for the purposes of this paragraph only, the term of the proposed sublease may extend beyond the term of the tenant&apos;s lease. In such event, such sublease shall be subject to the tenant&apos;s right to a renewal lease. The subtenant shall have no right to a renewal lease. It shall be unreasonable for an owner to refuse to consent to a sublease solely because such sublease extends beyond the tenant&apos;s lease; and (h) notwithstanding the provisions of section two hundred twenty-six-b of the real property law, a not-for-profit hospital shall have the right to sublet any housing accommodation leased by it to its affiliated personnel without requiring the landlord&apos;s consent to any such sublease and without being bound by the provisions of subparagraphs (b), (c) and (f) of this paragraph. Commencing with the effective date of this subparagraph, whenever a not-for-profit hospital executes a renewal lease for a housing accommodation, the legal regulated rent shall be increased by a sum equal to fifteen percent of the previous lease rental for such housing accommodation, hereinafter referred to as a vacancy surcharge, unless the landlord shall have received within the seven year period prior to the commencement date of such renewal lease any vacancy increases or vacancy surcharges allocable to the said housing accommodation. In the event the landlord shall have received any such vacancy increases or vacancy surcharges during such seven year period, the vacancy surcharge shall be reduced by the amount received by any such vacancy increase or vacancy surcharges.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47420" number="60234" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(13)<TAB tab-count="1"/>provides that an owner is entitled to a rent increase where there has been a substantial modification or increase of dwelling space, or installation of new equipment or improvements or new furniture or furnishings provided in or to a tenant&apos;s housing accommodation, on written informed tenant consent to the rent increase. In the case of a vacant housing accommodation, tenant consent shall not be required. Except as provided in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, increase in the legal regulated rent for the affected housing accommodation shall be one-one hundred sixty-eighth, in the case of a building with thirty-five or fewer housing accommodations or one-one hundred eightieth in the case of a building with more than thirty-five housing accommodations where such increase takes effect on or after the effective date of the chapter of the laws of two thousand nineteen that amended this paragraph, of the total actual cost incurred by the landlord in providing such reasonable and verifiable modification or increase in dwelling space, furniture, furnishings, or equipment, including the cost of installation but excluding finance charges and any costs that exceed reasonable costs established by rules and regulations promulgated by the division of housing and community renewal. Such rules and regulations shall include: (i) requirements for work to be done by licensed contractors and prohibit common ownership between the landlord and the contractor or vendor; and (ii) a requirement that the owner resolve within the dwelling space all outstanding hazardous or immediately hazardous violations of the Uniform Fire Prevention and Building Code (Uniform Code), New York City Fire Code, or New York City Building and Housing Maintenance Codes, if applicable. Provided further that an owner who is entitled to a rent increase pursuant to this paragraph shall not be entitled to a further rent increase based upon the installation of similar equipment, or new furniture or furnishings within the useful life of such new equipment, or new furniture or furnishings. Provided further that the recoverable costs incurred by the landlord, pursuant to this paragraph, shall be limited to an aggregate cost of an amount set forth in this paragraph beginning with the first individual apartment improvement on or after June fourteenth, two thousand nineteen. Provided further that increases to the legal regulated rent pursuant to this paragraph shall be limited to an aggregate cost pursuant to the following: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228763" number="60235" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>thirty thousand dollars that may be expended in a fifteen-year period beginning with the first individual apartment improvement on or after June fourteenth, two thousand nineteen, provided further that: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228762" number="60236" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>if there is a tenant in place at the time the individual apartment improvement is undertaken, no costs incurred by the landlord shall be recoverable pursuant to this subparagraph unless the landlord obtains written tenant consent from the tenant in place at the time the individual apartment improvement was undertaken; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228761" number="60237" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>increases to the legal regulated rent pursuant to this subparagraph shall be permanent; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228760" number="60238" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the thirty thousand dollars may be expended, in the aggregate, on any number of separate individual apartment improvements in a fifteen-year period, but in no event shall costs above thirty thousand dollars be recoverable in a fifteen-year period pursuant to this subparagraph. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228759" number="60239" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>fifty thousand dollars that may be expended in a fifteen-year period beginning with the first individual apartment improvement on or after June fourteenth, two thousand nineteen, pursuant to regulation, operational bulletin or such other guidance as the division of housing and community renewal may issue, provided further that: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228758" number="60240" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>costs shall only be recoverable by a landlord pursuant to this subparagraph for an individual apartment improvement undertaken during a vacancy; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228757" number="60241" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>costs shall only be recoverable by a landlord pursuant to this subparagraph for an individual apartment improvement if (i) the apartment was timely registered as vacant by no later than the thirty-first of December in each of two thousand twenty-two, two thousand twenty-three, and two-thousand twenty-four, provided that a landlord may recover costs on this basis no more than once, or (ii) if the apartment is vacant following a period of continuous occupancy of at least twenty-five years that occurred immediately prior to the commencement of such individual apartment improvement; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228756" number="60242" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>costs shall only be recoverable by a landlord pursuant to this subparagraph if such landlord has received prior certification to recover costs pursuant to this subparagraph from the division of housing and community renewal based on establishing that the landlord satisfies one of the eligibility criteria delineated in clause two of this subparagraph, provided further that such certification shall not be deemed as evidence that the work performed or costs claimed for the individual apartment improvement was substantiated or to otherwise act as a defense in any subsequent rent overcharge proceeding, determination, or audit; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228755" number="60243" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>increases to the legal regulated rent pursuant to this subparagraph shall be permanent; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228754" number="60244" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the increase in the legal regulated rent for the affected housing accommodation shall be one-one hundred forty-fourth, in the case of a building with thirty-five or fewer housing accommodations or one-one hundred fifty-sixth in the case of a building with more than thirty-five housing accommodations where such increase takes effect on or after the effective date of this chapter, of the total actual cost incurred by the landlord up to fifty thousand dollars in providing such reasonable and verifiable modification or increase in dwelling space, furniture, furnishings, or equipment, including the cost of installation but excluding finance charges and any costs that exceed reasonable costs established by rules and regulations promulgated by the division of housing and community renewal; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228753" number="60245" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>costs shall only be recoverable by a landlord pursuant to this subparagraph for an individual apartment improvement if, immediately prior to undertaking such individual apartment improvement, the landlord submits to the division of housing and community renewal any evidence that the division of housing and community renewal deems necessary and requests pursuant to regulation, operational bulletin or other guidance, demonstrating that the improvement was necessitated by a sub-standard condition or exceeding its useful life immediately prior to the landlord&apos;s work to improve the unit and the landlord&apos;s planned work to improve the unit. Such evidence shall include, but shall not be limited to, photos of any areas, aspects or appliances in the apartment that will be improved, and any necessary permits required to undertake the improvements; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228752" number="60246" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>costs shall only be recoverable by a landlord pursuant to this subparagraph for an individual apartment improvement if, immediately subsequent to undertaking the individual apartment improvement, the landlord submits to the division of housing and community renewal any evidence that the division of housing and community renewal deems necessary and requests pursuant to regulation, operational bulletin or other guidance, evidence of the completed work. Such evidence shall include, but shall not be limited to, photographs of the completed work, itemized receipts for all parts, materials, appliances, and labor costs, and proof of payment. Provided further, the division of housing and community renewal shall require the payment of a fee that equals one percent of the amount claimed for the individual apartment improvement at the time of such filing; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228751" number="60247" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>for costs recoverable pursuant to item (ii) of clause two of this subparagraph, the fifty thousand dollars may be expended, in the aggregate, on any number of separate individual apartment improvements in a fifteen-year period, but in no event shall costs above fifty thousand dollars be recoverable in a fifteen-year period pursuant to this subparagraph; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228750" number="60248" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the division of housing and community renewal may perform an audit of any individual apartment improvement conducted pursuant to this subparagraph to determine whether the individual apartment improvement was undertaken in the manner described and to the extent claimed by the landlord, whether the costs claimed were substantiated by records, and whether the rent was properly adjusted. Such audit may incorporate an inspection of the accommodation at bar. The landlord and the tenant living in the accommodation may participate in such audit. In the event the audit finds that the recoverable costs claimed by the landlord cannot be substantiated, the resulting overcharge shall be considered to be willful. In addition, the division of housing and community renewal may issue any fines or penalties set forth in regulations; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228749" number="60249" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(10)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the division of housing and community renewal shall perform random on-site inspections, as it deems necessary, for any unit for which the owner seeks to recover costs pursuant to this subparagraph; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-228748" number="60250" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(11)<TAB tab-count="1"/>no owner shall be eligible for the rent increase based on individual apartment improvements pursuant to this subparagraph if, within the five-year period prior to filing such individual apartment improvement, any unit within any building owned by any owner of the building in which the unit for which the owner seeks an individual apartment improvement is located, including but not limited to partial or beneficial owners, has been the subject of an award or determination by the division of housing and community renewal or a court of competent jurisdiction for treble damages due to an overcharge or the owner of the building in which the unit is located has been the subject of an award or determination by the division of housing and community renewal or a court of competent jurisdiction for harassment of any tenants, provided that such owner shall provide an affidavit confirming such owner&apos;s eligibility under this clause to the division of housing and community renewal at the same time as, and in addition to, any other materials the division of housing and community renewal shall require an owner to submit pursuant to clause six of this subparagraph, and provided further that such affidavit shall not be deemed to be evidence of compliance with this clause or a defense in any subsequent rent overcharge proceeding, determination, or audit. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47421" number="60251" version="132">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(14)<TAB tab-count="1"/>where the amount of rent charged to and paid by the tenant is less than the legal regulated rent for the housing accommodation, the amount of rent for such housing accommodation which may be charged upon vacancy thereof, may, at the option of the owner, be based upon such previously established legal regulated rent, as adjusted by the most recent applicable guidelines increases and any other increases authorized by law. For any tenant who is subject to a lease on or after the effective date of a chapter of the laws of two thousand nineteen which amended this paragraph, or is or was entitled to receive a renewal or vacancy lease on or after such date, upon renewal of such lease, the amount of rent for such housing accommodation that may be charged and paid shall be no more than the rent charged to and paid by the tenant prior to that renewal, as adjusted by the most recent applicable guidelines increases and any other increases authorized by law. Provided, however, that for buildings that are subject to this statute by virtue of a regulatory agreement with a local government agency and which buildings receive federal project based rental assistance administered by the United States department of housing and urban development or a state or local section eight administering agency, where the rent set by the federal, state or local governmental agency is less than the legal regulated rent for the housing accommodation, the amount of rent for such housing accommodation which may be charged with the approval of such federal, state or local governmental agency upon renewal or upon vacancy thereof, may be based upon such previously established legal regulated rent, as adjusted by the most recent applicable guidelines increases and other increases authorized by law; and further provided that such vacancy shall not be caused by the failure of the owner or an agent of the owner, to maintain the housing accommodation in compliance with the warranty of habitability set forth in subdivision one of section two hundred thirty-five-b of the real property law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226606" number="60252" version="1981">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(15)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>where an owner combines two or more vacant housing accommodations or combines a vacant housing accommodation with an occupied housing accommodation, such initial rent for such new housing accommodation shall be the combined legal rent for both previous housing accommodations, subject to any applicable guideline increases and any other increases authorized by this chapter including any individual apartment improvement increases applicable for both housing accommodations. If an owner combines a rent regulated accommodation with an apartment not subject to rent regulation, the resulting apartment shall be subject to this chapter. If an owner increases the area of an apartment not subject to rent regulation by adding space that was previously part of a rent regulated apartment, each apartment shall be subject to this chapter. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226607" number="60253" version="1981">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>where an owner substantially increases the outer dimension of a vacant housing accommodation, such initial rent shall be the prior rent of such housing accommodation, increased by a percentage that is equal to the percentage increase in the dwelling space and such other increases authorized by this chapter including any applicable guideline increase and individual apartment improvement increase that could be authorized for the unit prior to the alteration of the outer dimensions. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226608" number="60254" version="1981">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>notwithstanding subparagraphs (a) and (b) of this paragraph, such increases may be denied based on the occurrence of such vacancy due to harassment, fraud, or other acts of evasion which may require that such rent be set in accordance with section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-516" destination-id="0-0-0-11561">26-516</LINK> of this title. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226609" number="60255" version="2016">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>where the vacant housing accommodations are combined, modified, divided or the dimension of such housing accommodation otherwise altered and these changes are being made pursuant to a preservation regulatory agreement with a federal, state or local governmental agency or instrumentality, the rent stabilized rents charged thereafter shall be based on an initial rent set by such agency or instrumentality. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-095]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226610" number="60256" version="1981">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>where an owner substantially decreases the outer dimensions of a vacant housing accommodation, such initial rent shall be the prior rent of such housing accommodation, decreased by the same percentage the square footage of the original apartment was decreased by and such other increases authorized by this chapter including any applicable guideline increase and individual apartment improvement increase that could be authorized for the apartment prior to the alteration of the outer dimensions. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226611" number="60257" version="1981">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>when an owner combines two or more rent regulated apartments, the owner may use each of the previous apartments&apos; remaining individual apartment improvement allowances for the purposes of a temporary individual apartment improvement rent increase. The owner shall subsequently designate a surviving apartment for the purposes of registration that has the same apartment number as one of the prior apartments. If that prior apartment has any reimbursable individual apartment improvement money remaining after the combination, that money may be reimbursed for future individual apartment improvements undertaken within the subsequent fifteen years following the combination. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226612" number="60258" version="1981">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>in order for an owner to qualify for a temporary individual apartment improvement rent increase when apartments are combined, the requirements for an individual apartment improvement, including all notification requirements under this chapter shall be met. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226613" number="60259" version="1981">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>owners shall maintain the records and rent histories of all combined apartments, both prior to and post combination, for the purposes of rent setting, overcharge and all other proceedings to which the records are applicable. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226614" number="60260" version="1981">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each owner subject to the rent stabilization law shall furnish to each tenant signing a new or renewal lease, a rider describing the rights and duties of owners and tenants as provided for under the rent stabilization law of nineteen hundred sixty-nine. Such publication shall conform to the intent of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="5-702" destination-id="0-0-0-11551">5-702</LINK> of the general obligations law and shall be attached as an addendum to the lease. Upon the face of each lease, in bold print, shall appear the following: &quot;Attached to this lease are the pertinent rules and regulations governing tenants and landlords&apos; rights under the rent stabilization law of nineteen hundred sixty-nine&quot;.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226615" number="60261" version="1981">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The rider shall be in a form promulgated by the commissioner in larger type than the lease and shall be utilized as provided in paragraph one of this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226616" number="60262" version="1981">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each owner of premises subject to the rent stabilization law shall furnish to each tenant signing a new or renewal lease, a copy of the fully executed new or renewal lease bearing the signatures of owner and tenant and the beginning and ending dates of the lease term, within thirty days from the owner&apos;s receipt of the new or renewal lease signed by the tenant.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226617" number="60263" version="2094">
											<PARA>(Am. 2015 N.Y. Laws Ch. 20 Pt. A §§ 12, 16-a, 29, 6/26/2015, eff. 6/26/2015; Am. 2019 N.Y. Laws Ch. 36 Pt. B § 1, Pt. E § 2, Pt. I § 2, Pt. K §§ 2, 11, 12, 6/14/2019, eff. 6/14/2019; Am. 2019 N.Y. Laws Ch. 39 Pt. Q §§ 12, 13, 14, 28, 6/24/2019, retro eff. 6/14/2019; Am. 2023 N.Y. Laws Ch. 760, 12/22/2023, eff. 12/22/2023; Am. 2024 N.Y. Laws Ch. 95, 3/1/2024, eff. 12/22/2023; Am. 2024 N.Y. Laws Ch. 56 Pt. FF § 3, 4/20/2024, eff. 10/17/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-226618" number="60264" version="1981">
										<HEADING>§ 26-511.1 Major capital improvements and individual apartment improvements in rent regulated units.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-19219" name="26-511.1"/>§ 26-511.1 Major capital improvements and individual apartment improvements in rent regulated units.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-227720" number="60265" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the division of housing and community renewal, the &quot;division&quot;, shall promulgate rules and regulations applicable to all rent regulated units that shall: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112688" number="60266" version="127">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>establish a schedule of reasonable costs for major capital improvements, which shall set a ceiling for what can be recovered through a temporary major capital improvement increase, based on the type of improvement and its rate of depreciation; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112687" number="60267" version="127">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>establish the criteria for eligibility of a temporary major capital improvement increase including the type of improvement, which shall be essential for the preservation, energy efficiency, functionality or infrastructure of the entire building, including heating, windows, plumbing and roofing, but shall not be for operational costs or unnecessary cosmetic improvements. Allowable improvements must additionally be depreciable pursuant to the Internal Revenue Service, other than for ordinary repairs, that directly or indirectly benefit all tenants; and no increase shall be approved for group work done in individual apartments that is otherwise not an improvement to an entire building. Only such costs that are actual, reasonable, and verifiable may be approved as a temporary major capital improvement increase; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112686" number="60268" version="127">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>require that any temporary major capital improvement increase granted pursuant to these provisions be reduced by an amount equal to (i) any governmental grant received by the landlord, where such grant compensates the landlord for any improvements required by a city, state or federal government, an agency or any granting governmental entity to be expended for improvements and (ii) any insurance payment received by the landlord where such insurance payment compensates the landlord for any part of the costs of the improvements; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112685" number="60269" version="127">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>prohibit temporary major capital improvement increases for buildings with outstanding hazardous or immediately hazardous violations of the Uniform Fire Prevention and Building Code (Uniform Code), New York City Fire Code, or New York City Building and Housing Maintenance Codes, if applicable; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112684" number="60270" version="127">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>prohibit individual apartment improvement increases for housing accommodations with outstanding hazardous or immediately hazardous violations of the Uniform Fire Prevention and Building Code (Uniform Code), New York City Fire Code, or New York City Building and Housing Maintenance Codes, if applicable; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112683" number="60271" version="127">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>prohibit temporary major capital improvement increases for buildings with thirty-five per centum or fewer rent-regulated units; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112682" number="60272" version="127">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>establish that temporary major capital improvement increases shall be fixed to the unit and shall cease thirty years from the date the increase became effective. Temporary major capital improvement increases shall be added to the legal regulated rent as a temporary increase and shall be removed from the legal regulated rent thirty years from the date the increase became effective inclusive of any increases granted by the local rent guidelines board; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112681" number="60273" version="133">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>establish that temporary major capital improvement increases shall be collectible prospectively on the first day of the first month beginning sixty days from the date of mailing notice of approval to the tenant. Such notice shall disclose the total monthly increase in rent and the first month in which the tenant would be required to pay the temporary increase. An approval for a temporary major capital improvement increase shall not include retroactive payments. The collection of any increase shall not exceed two percent in any year from the effective date of the order granting the increase over the rent set forth in the schedule of gross rents, with collectability of any dollar excess above said sum to be spread forward in similar increments and added to the rent as established or set in future years. Upon vacancy, the landlord may add any remaining balance of the temporary major capital improvement increase to the legal regulated rent. Notwithstanding any other provision of the law, for any renewal lease commencing on or after June 14, 2019, the collection of any rent increases due to any major capital improvements approved on or after June 16, 2012 and before June 16, 2019 shall not exceed two percent in any year for any tenant in occupancy on the date the major capital improvement was approved; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112680" number="60274" version="127">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9)<TAB tab-count="1"/>ensure that the application procedure for temporary major capital improvement increases shall include an itemized list of work performed and a description or explanation of the reason or purpose of such work; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112679" number="60275" version="127">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(10)<TAB tab-count="1"/>provide, that where an application for a major capital improvement rent increase has been filed, a tenant shall have sixty days from the date of mailing of a notice of a proceeding in which to answer or reply; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112678" number="60276" version="127">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(11)<TAB tab-count="1"/>establish a notification and documentation procedure for individual apartment improvements that requires an itemized list of work performed and a description or explanation of the reason or purpose of such work, inclusive of photographic evidence documenting the condition prior to and after the completion of the performed work. Provide for the centralized electronic retention of such documentation and any other supporting documentation to be made available in cases pertaining to the adjustment of legal regulated rents; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112677" number="60277" version="2094">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(12)<TAB tab-count="1"/>establish a form in the top six languages other than English spoken in the state according to the latest available data from the U.S. Bureau of Census for an individual apartment improvement rent increase for a tenant in occupancy which shall be used by landlords to obtain written informed consent that shall include the estimated total cost of the improvement and the estimated monthly rent increase. Such consent shall be executed in the tenant&apos;s primary language. Such form shall be completed and preserved in the centralized electronic retention system to be operational by June 14, 2020, provided further that any changes to the form required due to the individual apartment improvement being permanent shall be completed as of October 14, 2024. Nothing herein shall relieve a landlord, lessor, or agent thereof of such person&apos;s duty to retain proper documentation of all improvements performed or any rent increases resulting from said improvements. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112676" number="60278" version="127">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The division shall establish an annual inspection and audit process which shall review twenty-five percent of applications for a temporary major capital improvement increase that have been submitted and approved. Such process shall include individual inspections and document review to ensure that owners complied with all obligations and responsibilities under the law for temporary major capital improvement increases. Inspections shall include in-person confirmation that such improvements have been completed in such way as described in the application. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112675" number="60279" version="127">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The division shall issue a notice to the landlord and all the tenants sixty days prior to the end of the temporary major capital improvement increase and shall include the initial approved increase and the total amount to be removed from the legal regulated rent inclusive of any increases granted by the applicable rent guidelines board. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112673" number="60280" version="2094">
											<PARA>(2019 N.Y. Laws Ch. 36 Pt. K § 4, 6/14/2019, eff. 6/14/2019; Am. 2019 N.Y. Laws Ch. 39 Pt. Q § 21, 6/24/2019, retro eff. 6/14/2019; Am. 2024 N.Y. Laws Ch. 56 Pt. FF § 4, 4/20/2024, eff. 10/17/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-102]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-112672" number="60281" version="127">
										<HEADING>§ 26-512 Stabilization provisions. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11553" name="26-512"/>§ 26-512 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Stabilization provisions. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47427" number="60282" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No owner of property subject to this law shall charge or collect any rent in excess of the initial legal regulated rent or adjusted initial legal regulated rent until the end of any lease or other rental agreement in effect on the local effective date until such time as a different legal regulated rent shall be authorized pursuant to guidelines adopted by a rent guidelines board.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47428" number="60283" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The initial regulated rent for housing accommodations subject to this law on the local effective date of the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four or which become subject to this law thereafter, pursuant to such act, shall be:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47429" number="60284" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For housing accommodations which were regulated pursuant to this law or the city rent and rehabilitation law prior to July first, nineteen hundred seventy-one, and which became vacant on or after such date and prior to the local effective date of the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four, the rent reserved in the last effective lease or other rental agreement; provided that such initial rent may be adjusted on application of the tenant pursuant to subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-513" destination-id="0-0-0-11545">26-513</LINK> of this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47430" number="60285" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For housing accommodations which were regulated pursuant to the city rent and rehabilitation law on the local effective date of the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four, and thereafter become vacant, the rent agreed to by the landlord and the tenant and reserved in a lease or provided for in a rental agreement; provided that such initial rent may be adjusted on application of the tenant pursuant to subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-513" destination-id="0-0-0-11545">26-513</LINK> of this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47431" number="60286" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For housing accommodations other than those described in paragraphs one and two of this subdivision, the rent reserved in the last effective lease or other rental agreement.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47432" number="60287" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For any plot or parcel of land which had been regulated pursuant to the city rent and rehabilitation law prior to July first, nineteen hundred seventy-one and which,</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47433" number="60288" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>became vacant on or after July first, nineteen hundred seventy-one and prior to July first, nineteen hundred seventy-four, the rent reserved in a lease or other rental agreement in effect on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy-four plus increases authorized by the rent guidelines board under this law for leases or other rental agreements commencing thereafter; provided that such initial rent may be adjusted on application of the tenant pursuant to subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-513" destination-id="0-0-0-11545">26-513</LINK> of this chapter or,</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47434" number="60289" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>became vacant on or after July first, nineteen hundred seventy-four, the rent agreed to by the landlord and the tenant and reserved in a lease or other rental agreement plus increases authorized by the rent guidelines board under this law for leases or other rental agreements commencing thereafter; provided that such initial rent may be adjusted on application of the tenant pursuant to subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-513" destination-id="0-0-0-11545">26-513</LINK> of this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47435" number="60290" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where the commissioner has determined that the rent charged is in excess of the lawful rents as stated in subparagraph (i) or (ii) hereof, plus lawful increases thereafter, he or she shall provide for a cash refund or a credit, to be applied against future rent, in the amount of any rent overcharge collected by an owner and any penalties, costs, attorneys&apos; fees and interest from the date of the overcharge at the rate of interest payable on a judgment pursuant to section five thousand four of the civil practice law and rules for which the owner is assessed.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47436" number="60291" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to accommodations for which the initial legal regulated rent is governed by paragraph two of subdivision b hereof, no increase of such initial legal regulated rent pursuant to annual guidelines adopted by the rent guidelines board shall become effective until the expiration of the first lease or rental agreement taking effect after the local effective date of the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four, but in no event before one year after the commencement of such rental agreement.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47437" number="60292" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to accommodations, other than those referred to in subdivision c, for which a lease is entered into after the local effective date of the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four, but before the effective date of the first guidelines applicable to such accommodations, the lease may provide for an adjustment of rent pursuant to such guidelines to be effective on the first day of the month next succeeding the effective date of such guidelines.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47438" number="60293" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any contrary provisions of this law, on and after July first, nineteen hundred eighty-four, the legal regulated rent authorized for a housing accommodation subject to the provisions of this law shall be the rent registered pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-517" destination-id="0-0-0-11555">26-517</LINK> of this chapter subject to any modification imposed pursuant to this law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47439" number="60294" version="1270">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No owner of a housing accommodation subject to the provisions of this law shall impose any surcharge for the installation and use of a tenant-installed air conditioner unit where the tenant pays for electric utility service. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47440" number="60295" version="1077">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>An owner, lessor or agent thereof shall be prohibited from assessing a lessee any fee, surcharge or other charges for legal services in connection with the operation or rental of a residential unit unless the owner, lessor or agent has the legal authority to do so pursuant to a court order. Legal services include, but are not limited to, court fees, legal representation, attorney fees, notary public charges, and administrative fees incurred by the owner, lessor or agent in connection with management of the building, including actions and proceedings in a court of law. Any agreement or assessment to the contrary shall be void as contrary to public policy. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-136085" number="60296" version="1270">
											<PARA>(Am. 2019 N.Y. Laws Ch. 36 Pt. B § 3, 6/14/2019, eff. 6/14/2019; Am. 2021 N.Y. Laws Ch. 695, 12/21/2021, eff. 12/21/2021; Am. 2022 N.Y. Laws Ch. 619, 11/21/2022, eff. 11/21/2022) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-079]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-136084" number="60297" version="1077">
										<HEADING>§ 26-513 Application for adjustment of initial rent. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11545" name="26-513"/>§ 26-513 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application for adjustment of initial rent. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47441" number="60298" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The tenant or owner of a housing accommodation made subject to this law by the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four may, within sixty days of the local effective date of this section or the commencement of the first tenancy thereafter, whichever is later, file with the commissioner an application for adjustment of the initial legal regulated rent for such housing accommodation. The commissioner may adjust such initial legal regulated rent upon a finding that the presence of unique or peculiar circumstances materially affecting the initial legal regulated rent has resulted in a rent which is substantially different from the rents generally prevailing in the same area for substantially similar housing accommodations.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47442" number="60299" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The tenant of a housing accommodation that was regulated pursuant to the city rent and rehabilitation law or this law prior to July first, nineteen hundred seventy-one and that became vacant on or after January first, nineteen hundred seventy-four may file with the commissioner within ninety days after notice has been received pursuant to subdivision d of this section, an application for adjustment of the initial legal regulated rent for such housing accommodation. Such tenant need only allege that such rent is in excess of the fair market rent and shall present such facts which, to the best of his or her information and belief, support such allegation. The rent guidelines board shall promulgate as soon as practicable after the local effective date of the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four guidelines for the determination of fair market rents for housing accommodations as to which any application may be made pursuant to this subdivision. In rendering a determination on an application filed pursuant to this subdivision b the commissioner shall be guided by such guidelines and by the rents generally prevailing in the same area for substantially similar housing accommodations. Where the commissioner has determined that the rent charged is in excess of the fair market rent he or she shall, in addition to any other penalties or remedies permitted by law, order a refund of any excess paid since January first, nineteen hundred seventy-four or the date of the commencement of the tenancy, whichever is later. Such refund shall be made by the landlord in cash or as a credit against future rents over a period not in excess of six months.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47443" number="60300" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of paragraph one of this subdivision shall not apply to a tenant of a housing accommodation for which the initial legal regulated rent is no greater than the maximum rent that would have been in effect under this law on December thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-three, or for the period commencing January first, nineteen hundred seventy-four and ending December thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-five as calculated pursuant to the city rent and rehabilitation law (if no such maximum rent has been calculated for a particular unit for the period commencing January first, nineteen hundred seventy-four and ending December thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-five, the division of housing and community renewal shall calculate such a rent), as the case may be, if such apartment had not become vacant on or after January first, nineteen hundred seventy-four, plus the amount of any adjustment which would have been authorized under this law for renewal leases or other rental agreement, whether or not such housing accommodation was subject to this law, for leases or other rental agreements commencing on or after July first, nineteen hundred seventy-four.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47444" number="60301" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon receipt of any application filed pursuant to this section, the commissioner shall notify the owner or tenant, as the case may be, and provide a copy to him or her of such application. Such owner or tenant shall be afforded a reasonable opportunity to respond to the application. A hearing may be held upon the request of either party, or the commissioner may hold a hearing on his or her own motion. The commissioner shall issue a written opinion to both the tenant and the owner upon rendering his or her determination.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47445" number="60302" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within thirty days after the local effective date of the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four the owner of housing accommodations as to which an application for adjustment of the initial legal regulated rent may be made pursuant to subdivision b of this section shall give notice in writing by certified mail to the tenant of each such housing accommodation on a form prescribed by the commissioner of the initial legal regulated rent for such housing accommodation, the maximum rent at the time such housing accommodation became vacant and of such tenant&apos;s right to file an application for adjustment of the initial legal regulated rent of such housing accommodation.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47446" number="60303" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any contrary provision in this law an application for an adjustment pursuant to this section must be filed within ninety days from the initial registration. This subdivision shall not extend any other time limitations imposed by this law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47447" number="60304" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-514 Maintenance of services. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11557" name="26-514"/>§ 26-514 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Maintenance of services. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47448" number="60305" version="3">
											<PARA>In order to collect a rent adjustment authorized pursuant to the provisions of subdivision d of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-510" destination-id="0-0-0-11549">26-510</LINK> of this chapter an owner must file with the state division of housing and community renewal, on a form which the commissioner shall prescribe, a written certification that he or she is maintaining and will continue to maintain all services furnished on the date upon which the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four becomes a law or required to be furnished by any state law or local law, ordinance or regulation applicable to the premises. In addition to any other remedy afforded by law, any tenant may apply to the state division of housing and community renewal, for a reduction in the rent to the level in effect prior to its most recent adjustment and for an order requiring services to be maintained as provided in this section, and the commissioner shall so reduce the rent if it is found that the owner has failed to maintain such services. The owner shall also be barred from applying for or collecting any further rent increases. The restoration of such services shall result in the prospective elimination of such sanctions. The owner shall be supplied with a copy of the application and shall be permitted to file an answer thereto. A hearing may be held upon the request of either party, or the commissioner may hold a hearing upon his or her own motion. The commissioner may consolidate the proceedings for two or more petitions applicable to the same building or group of buildings or development. If the commissioner finds that the owner has knowingly filed a false certification, it shall, in addition to abating the rent, assess the owner with the reasonable costs of the proceeding, including reasonable attorneys&apos; fees, and impose a penalty not in excess of two hundred fifty dollars for each false certification. The amount of the reduction in rent ordered by the state division of housing and community renewal under this subdivision shall be reduced by any credit, abatement or offset in rent which the tenant has received pursuant to section two hundred thirty-five-b of the real property law, that relates to one or more conditions covered by such order.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47449" number="60306" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-515 Recovery of possession. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11559" name="26-515"/>§ 26-515 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Recovery of possession. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47450" number="60307" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>An owner seeking to recover possession pursuant to subparagraph (c) of paragraph nine of subdivision c of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-511" destination-id="0-0-0-11503">26-511</LINK> of this chapter shall notify the tenant in occupancy not more than one hundred fifty and not less than one hundred twenty days prior to the end of the tenant&apos;s lease term, by mail, of such owner&apos;s intention not to renew such lease in order to recover the dwelling unit for its charitable or educational purposes. The owner may give such notice within one hundred twenty days of the expiration of the tenant&apos;s lease term, provided it may not commence a summary proceeding to recover the dwelling unit until the expiration of one hundred twenty days from the giving of such notice and, provided, further, that the tenant may remain in occupancy until the commencement of such proceeding at the same rent and upon the same terms and conditions as were provided in his or her expired lease. The notice of intention not to renew the tenant&apos;s lease shall be accompanied by a notice on a form prescribed by the division of housing and community renewal setting forth the penalties to which an owner may be subject for his or her failure to utilize the tenant&apos;s dwelling unit for the charitable or educational purpose for which recovery of the dwelling unit is sought.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47451" number="60308" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any owner who recovers a dwelling unit pursuant to such subparagraph (c), or any successor in interest, utilizes such unit for purposes other than those permitted under such subparagraph, then such owner or successor shall, unless for good cause shown, be liable to the removed tenant for three times the damages sustained on account of such removal plus reasonable attorney&apos;s fees and costs as determined by the court, provided that such tenant commences such action within three years from the date of recovery of the unit. The damages sustained by such tenant shall be the difference between the rent paid by such tenant for the recovered dwelling unit, and the rental value of a comparable rent regulated dwelling unit on the open market. In addition to any other damage, the reasonable cost of removal of the tenant&apos;s property shall be a lawful measure of damages.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47452" number="60309" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where a dwelling unit has been recovered pursuant to such subparagraph (c) and within four years of such recovery is rented to a person or entity for purposes other than those permitted pursuant to such subparagraph (c), unless for good cause shown, the rent charged by such owner or any successor in interest for four years following such recovery shall not exceed the last regulated rent payable prior to such recovery.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47453" number="60310" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the owner is found by the commissioner, to have recovered possession of a dwelling unit pursuant to such subparagraph (c) and within four years of such recovery such owner or any successor in interest shall have utilized such unit for purposes other than those permitted pursuant to such subparagraph (c), unless for good cause shown, the commissioner shall impose upon such owner or successor in interest, by administrative order after hearing, a civil penalty for any such violation. Such penalty shall be in an amount of up to one thousand dollars for each offense. Such order shall be deemed a final determination for the purposes of judicial review. Such penalty may, upon the expiration of the period for seeking review pursuant to article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules, be docketed and enforced in the manner of a judgment of the supreme court.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47454" number="60311" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-516 Enforcement and procedures. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11561" name="26-516"/>§ 26-516 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Enforcement and procedures. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47460" number="60312" version="128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Subject to the conditions and limitations of this subdivision, any owner of housing accommodations who, upon complaint of a tenant, or of the state division of housing and community renewal, is found by the state division of housing and community renewal, after a reasonable opportunity to be heard, to have collected an overcharge above the rent authorized for a housing accommodation subject to this chapter shall be liable to the tenant for a penalty equal to three times the amount of such overcharge. If the owner establishes by a preponderance of the evidence that the overcharge was not willful, the state division of housing and community renewal shall establish the penalty as the amount of the overcharge plus interest. After a complaint of rent overcharge has been filed and served on an owner, the voluntary adjustment of the rent and/or the voluntary tender of a refund of rent overcharges shall not be considered by the division of housing and community renewal or a court of competent jurisdiction as evidence that the overcharge was not willful. (i) Except as to complaints filed pursuant to clause (ii) of this paragraph, the legal regulated rent for purposes of determining an overcharge, shall be the rent indicated in the most recent reliable annual registration statement filed and served upon the tenant six or more years prior to the most recent registration statement, (or, if more recently filed, the initial registration statement) plus in each case any subsequent lawful increases and adjustments. The division of housing and community renewal or a court of competent jurisdiction, in investigating complaints of overcharge and in determining legal regulated rent, shall consider all available rent history which is reasonably necessary to make such determinations. (ii) As to complaints filed within ninety days of the initial registration of a housing accommodation, the legal regulated rent shall be deemed to be the rent charged on the date six years prior to the date of the initial registration of the housing accommodation (or, if the housing accommodation was subject to this chapter for less than six years, the initial legal regulated rent) plus in each case, any lawful increases and adjustments. Where the rent charged on the date six years prior to the date of the initial registration of the accommodation cannot be established, such rent shall be established by the division. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112666" number="60313" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where the prior rent charged for the housing accommodation cannot be established, such rent shall be established by the division provided that where a rent is established based on rentals determined under the provisions of the local emergency housing rent control act such rent must be adjusted to account for no less than the minimum increases which would be permitted if the housing accommodation were covered under the provisions of this chapter, less any appropriate penalties. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112665" number="60314" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The order of the state division of housing and community renewal or court of competent jurisdiction shall apportion the owner&apos;s liability between or among two or more tenants found to have been overcharged by such owner during their particular tenancy of a unit. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112664" number="60315" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A complaint under this subdivision may be filed with the state division of housing and community renewal or in a court of competent jurisdiction at any time, however any recovery of overcharge penalties shall be limited to the six years preceding the complaint. A penalty of three times the overcharge shall be assessed upon all overcharges willfully collected by the owner starting six years before the complaint is filed. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112663" number="60316" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any affected tenant shall be notified of and given an opportunity to join in any complaint filed by an officer or employee of the state division of housing and community renewal. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112662" number="60317" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An owner found to have overcharged shall be assessed the reasonable costs and attorney&apos;s fees of the proceeding and interest from the date of the overcharge at the rate of interest payable on a judgment pursuant to section five thousand four of the civil practice law and rules. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112661" number="60318" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The order of the state division of housing and community renewal awarding penalties may, upon the expiration of the period in which the owner may institute a proceeding pursuant to article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules, be filed and enforced by a tenant in the same manner as a judgment or not in excess of twenty percent thereof per month may be offset against any rent thereafter due the owner. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47461" number="60319" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to issuing the specific orders provided for by other provisions of this law, the state division of housing and community renewal shall be empowered to enforce this law and the code by issuing, upon notice and a reasonable opportunity for the affected party to be heard, such other orders as it may deem appropriate.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47462" number="60320" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the owner is found by the commissioner:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47463" number="60321" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>to have violated an order of the division the commissioner may impose by administrative order after hearing, a civil penalty at minimum in the amount of one thousand but not to exceed two thousand dollars for the first such offense, and at a minimum in the amount of two thousand but not to exceed three thousand dollars for each subsequent offense; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-002]</HIGHLIGHTER>&#160;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47464" number="60322" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>to have harassed a tenant to obtain vacancy of his or her housing accommodation, the commissioner may impose by administrative order after hearing, a civil penalty for any such violation. Such penalty shall be at a minimum in the amount of two thousand but not to exceed three thousand dollars for the first such offense, and at minimum in the amount of ten thousand but not to exceed eleven thousand dollars for each subsequent offense or for a violation consisting of conduct directed at the tenants of more than one housing accommodation. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-002]</HIGHLIGHTER>&#160;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47465" number="60323" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any proceeding pursuant to article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules seeking review of any action pursuant to this chapter shall be brought within sixty days of the expiration of the ninety day period and any extension thereof provided in subdivision h of this section or the rendering of a determination, whichever is later. Any action or proceeding brought by or against the commissioner under this law shall be brought in the county in which the housing accommodation is located.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47466" number="60324" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Violations of this law, or of the code and orders issued pursuant thereto may be enjoined by the supreme court upon proceedings commenced by the state division of housing and community renewal which shall not be required to post bond.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47467" number="60325" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In furtherance of its responsibility to enforce this law, the state division of housing and community renewal shall be empowered to administer oaths, issue subpoenas, conduct investigations, make inspections and designate officers to hear and report. The division shall safeguard the confidentiality of information furnished to it at the request of the person furnishing same, unless such information must be made public in the interest of establishing a record for the future guidance of persons subject to this law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47468" number="60326" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except where a specific provision of this law requires the maintenance of rent records for a longer period, including records of the useful life of improvements made to any housing accommodation or any building, any owner who has duly registered a housing accommodation pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-517" destination-id="0-0-0-11555">26-517</LINK> of this chapter shall not be required to maintain or produce any records relating to rentals of such accommodation for more than six years prior to the most recent registration or annual statement for such accommodation. However, an owner&apos;s election not to maintain records shall not limit the authority of the division of housing and community renewal and the courts to examine the rental history and determine legal regulated rents pursuant to this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112659" number="60327" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The division of housing and community renewal, and the courts, in investigating complaints of overcharge and in determining legal regulated rents, shall consider all available rent history which is reasonably necessary to make such determinations, including but not limited to (i) any rent registration or other records filed with the state division of housing and community renewal, or any other state, municipal or federal agency, regardless of the date to which the information on such registration refers; (ii) any order issued by any state, municipal or federal agency; (iii) any records maintained by the owner or tenants; and (iv) any public record kept in the regular course of business by any state, municipal or federal agency. Nothing contained in this subdivision shall limit the examination of rent history relevant to a determination as to: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112658" number="60328" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the legality of a rental amount charged or registered is reliable in light of all available evidence including but not limited to whether an unexplained increase in the registered or lease rents, or a fraudulent scheme to destabilize the housing accommodation, rendered such rent or registration unreliable; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112657" number="60329" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether an accommodation is subject to the emergency tenant protection act or the rent stabilization law; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112656" number="60330" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether an order issued by the division of housing and community renewal or by a court, including, but not limited to an order issued pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-514" destination-id="0-0-0-11557">26-514</LINK> of this chapter, or any regulatory agreement or other contract with any governmental agency, and remaining in effect within six years of the filing of a complaint pursuant to this section, affects or limits the amount of rent that may be charged or collected; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112655" number="60331" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether an overcharge was or was not willful; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112654" number="60332" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether a rent adjustment that requires information regarding the length of occupancy by a present or prior tenant was lawful; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112653" number="60333" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vi)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the existence or terms and conditions of a preferential rent, or the propriety of a legal registered rent during a period when the tenants were charged a preferential rent; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112652" number="60334" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the legality of a rent charged or registered immediately prior to the registration of a preferential rent; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112651" number="60335" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(viii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the amount of the legal regulated rent where the apartment was vacant or temporarily exempt on the date six years prior to a tenant&apos;s complaint. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47469" number="60336" version="124">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The state division of housing and community renewal may, by regulation, provide for administrative review of all orders and determinations issued by it pursuant to this chapter. Any such regulation shall provide that if a petition for such review is not determined within ninety days after it is filed, it shall be deemed to be denied. However, the division may grant one extension not to exceed thirty days with the consent of the party filing such petition; any further extension may only be granted with the consent of all parties to the petition. No proceeding may be brought pursuant to article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules to challenge any order or determination which is subject to such administrative review unless such review has been sought and either (1) a determination thereon has been made or (2) the ninety day period provided for determination of the petition for review (or any extension thereof) has expired. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47471" number="60337" version="606">
											<PARA>(Am. 2015 N.Y. Laws Ch. 20 Pt. A § 23, 6/26/2015, eff. 6/26/2015; Am. 2019 N.Y. Laws Ch. 36 Pt. F §§ 4, 5, 6/14/2019, eff. 6/14/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-112649" number="60338" version="124">
										<HEADING>§ 26-517 Rent registration. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11555" name="26-517"/>§ 26-517 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rent registration. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47472" number="60339" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each housing accommodation which is subject to this law shall be registered by the owner thereof with the state division of housing and community renewal prior to July first, nineteen hundred eighty-four upon forms prescribed by the commissioner. The data to be provided on such forms shall include the following: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47473" number="60340" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the name and address of the building or group of buildings or development in which such housing accommodation is located and the owner and the tenant thereof; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47474" number="60341" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of housing accommodations in the building or group of buildings or development in which such housing accommodation is located; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47475" number="60342" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of housing accommodations in such building or group of buildings or development subject to this code and the number of such housing accommodations subject to the local emergency housing rent control act; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47476" number="60343" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the rent charged on the registration date; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47477" number="60344" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of rooms in such housing accommodation; and </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47478" number="60345" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>all services provided on the date that the housing accommodation became subject to this chapter. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47479" number="60346" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a-1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within thirty days of changing his address, the managing agent or, if there is no managing agent, the owner, of a building or group of buildings or development, such agent or owner shall advise the state division of housing and community renewal and all tenants of his new address.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47480" number="60347" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Registration pursuant to this section shall not be subject to the freedom of information law provided that registration information relative to a tenant, owner, lessor or subtenant shall be made available to such party or his or her authorized representative.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47481" number="60348" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Housing accommodations which become subject to this chapter after the initial registration period must be registered within ninety days thereafter. Registration of housing accommodations subject to the local emergency housing rent control act immediately prior to the date of initial registration as provided in this section shall include, in addition to the items listed above, where existing, the maximum base rent immediately prior to the date that such housing accommodations become subject to this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47482" number="60349" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Copies of the registration shall be filed with the state division of housing and community renewal in such place or places as it may require. In addition, one copy of that portion of the registration statement which pertains to the tenant&apos;s unit must be mailed by the owner to the tenant in possession at the time of initial registration or to the first tenant in occupancy if the apartment is vacant at the time of initial registration.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47483" number="60350" version="1981">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The failure to file a proper and timely initial or annual rent registration statement shall, until such time as such registration is filed, bar an owner from applying for or collecting any rent in excess of the legal regulated rent in effect on the date of the last preceding registration statement or if no such statements have been filed, the legal regulated rent in effect on the date that the housing accommodation became subject to the registration requirements of this section. The filing of a late registration shall result in the prospective elimination of such sanctions and provided that increases in the legal regulated rent were lawful except for the failure to file a timely registration, the owner, upon the service and filing of a late registration, shall not be found to have collected an overcharge at any time prior to the filing of the late registration. In addition to all other requirements set forth in this subdivision, in the event a timely rent registration is not filed and after notice of such delinquency is provided by the state division of housing and community renewal to the owner in the form of electronic mail and mail to the address listed in the owner&apos;s most recent registration statement, the owner shall be subject to a fine of five hundred dollars per unregistered unit for each month the registration is delinquent. Such a fine shall be imposed by order, and such order imposing a fine shall be deemed a final determination for the purposes of judicial review. Such fine may, upon the expiration of the period for seeking review pursuant to article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules, be docketed and enforced in the manner of a judgment of the supreme court by the state division of housing and community renewal. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47484" number="60351" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>An annual statement shall be filed containing the current rent for each unit and such other information contained in subdivision a of this section as shall be required by the division. The owner shall provide each tenant then in occupancy with a copy of that portion of such annual statement as pertains to the tenant&apos;s unit.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47485" number="60352" version="1981">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each housing accommodation for which a timely registration statement was filed between April first, nineteen hundred eighty-four and June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-four, pursuant to subdivision a of this section shall designate the rent charged on April first, nineteen hundred eighty-four, as the rent charged on the registration date.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226605" number="60353" version="1981">
											<PARA>(Am. 2023 N.Y. Laws Ch. 760, 12/22/2023, eff. 12/22/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47486" number="60354" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-517.1 Fees. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2739" name="26-517.1"/>§ 26-517.1 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Fees. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47487" number="60355" version="128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department of finance shall collect from the owner of each housing accommodation registered pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-517" destination-id="0-0-0-11555">26-517</LINK> of this chapter an annual fee in the amount of twenty dollars per year for each unit subject to this law, in order to defray costs incurred by the city pursuant to subdivision c of section eight of the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen hundred seventy-four. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47488" number="60356" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pursuant to the provisions of subdivision d of section eight of the emergency tenant protection act of nineteen seventy-four, the failure to pay the fee imposed by the provisions of subdivision a of this section shall constitute a charge due and owing the city. All such fees due and owing the city shall constitute a debt recoverable from the owner and the city may commence an action or proceeding for the recovery of such fees or may file a lien upon the building and lot. If the payment of such fees is not received by the city within sixty days of the date contained in the written notice requesting such payment, the city shall provide a second written notice to the owner setting forth the amount of fees due and owing the city and a demand for payment within thirty days thereof.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47489" number="60357" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If such payment is not made to the city within such time, all unpaid fees shall constitute a lien upon the premises and shall be filed in the office of the city collector as an entry of the account stated in the book in which such charges against the premises are to be entered. Such lien shall have priority over all other liens and encumbrances on the premises except for the lien of taxes and assessments. However, no lien created pursuant to this subdivision against any premises shall be enforced against an owner or mortgagee of such premises who acquired in good faith an interest therein subsequent to the period for which the fee was imposed but prior to the creation of any such lien.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47490" number="60358" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A notice pursuant to paragraph one of this subdivision, stating the amount due and the nature of the charge, shall be mailed by the city collector, within five days after such entry, to the last known address of the owner or agent.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47491" number="60359" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If such charge is not paid within thirty days from the date of entry, it shall be the duty of the city collector to receive interest thereon at the same rate as is imposed on a delinquent tax on real property, to be calculated to the date of payment from the date of entry.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47492" number="60360" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such charge and the interest thereon shall continue to be, until paid, a lien on the premises. Such lien shall be a tax lien within the meaning of sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-319" destination-id="0-0-0-2799">11-319</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-401" destination-id="0-0-0-2801">11-401</LINK> of this code and may be sold, enforced or foreclosed in the manner provided in chapters three and four of title eleven of this code.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47493" number="60361" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions set forth in this subdivision shall be the sole remedy for the enforcement of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47494" number="60362" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of subdivision a of this section shall be deemed to have been in full force and effect as of April first, nineteen hundred eighty-four.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47495" number="60363" version="606">
											<PARA>(Am. 2019 N.Y. Laws Ch. 36 Pt. K § 15, 6/14/2019, eff. 6/14/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-038]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-112708" number="60364" version="2279">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1986/026" destination-id="0-0-0-27294">L.L. 1986/026</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1986/066" destination-id="0-0-0-27238">L.L. 1986/066</LINK>, and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2001/036" destination-id="0-0-0-25484">L.L. 2001/036</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-212987" number="60365" version="1519">
										<HEADING>§ 26-518 Hotel industry stabilization association. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11563" name="26-518"/>§ 26-518 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hotel industry stabilization association. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47496" number="60366" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The hotel industry stabilization association registered with the department of housing preservation and development is hereby divested of all its powers and authority under this law. The stabilization code heretofore promulgated by such association, as approved by the department of housing preservation and development, is hereby continued to the extent that it is not inconsistent with law. Such code may be amended from time to time provided, however, that no such amendments shall be promulgated except by action of the commissioner of the division of housing and community renewal and provided further, that prior to the adoption of any such amendments, the commissioner shall (i) submit the proposed amendments to the commissioner of the department of housing preservation and development and allow such commissioner thirty days to make comments or recommendations on the proposed amendments, (ii) review the comments or recommendations, if any, made pursuant to clause (i) of this subdivision and make any revisions to the proposed amendments which the commissioner of the division of housing and community renewal deems appropriate provided that any such review and revision shall be completed within thirty days of receipt of such comments or recommendations and (iii) thereafter hold a public hearing on the proposed amendments. No provision of such code shall impair or diminish any right or remedy granted to any party by this law or any other provision of law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47497" number="60367" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A code shall not be approved hereunder unless it appears to the commissioner of the division of housing and community renewal that it provides for a cash refund or a credit to be applied against future rent, in the amount of the excess, if any, of rent paid since January first, nineteen hundred sixty-nine, over the permissible fair increase, and that it gives a hotel tenant the right to request a six month lease at the permissible rent rate within thirty days of the approval of such code, or, if his or her tenancy commences after such thirty day period, within thirty days of the commencement of his or her tenancy, and that is in compliance with the standards set forth in subdivision c of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-511" destination-id="0-0-0-11503">26-511</LINK> to the extent such standards are applicable to the hotel industry, and that it provides specifically that no owner shall refuse to extend or renew a tenancy for the purpose of preventing a hotel tenant from becoming a permanent tenant.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47498" number="60368" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each landlord who is made subject to this law pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-505" destination-id="0-0-0-11539">26-505</LINK> or <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-506" destination-id="0-0-0-11541">26-506</LINK> of this code shall furnish to each permanent tenant signing a new or renewal lease, a rider describing the rights and duties of owners and tenants as provided under the rent stabilization law of nineteen hundred sixty-nine. Such rider shall be in a form promulgated by the commissioner and shall conform to the intent of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="5-702" destination-id="0-0-0-11551">5-702</LINK> of the general obligations law and shall be in a print size larger than the print size of the lease to which the rider is attached.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47499" number="60369" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-519 Suspension of registration. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11565" name="26-519"/>§ 26-519 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Suspension of registration. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47500" number="60370" version="3">
											<PARA>The department of housing preservation and development may, after notice and opportunity for hearing, suspend the registration of an association if it finds that the articles, code, rules or other conduct thereof do not conform to the requirements of this law and any such suspension shall remain in effect until such administration issues an order determining that such articles, rules, code or other conduct have been modified to conform with such requirements. For the purposes of this law, the members in good standing of the association shall be deemed to be members in good standing of an association registered with the department of housing preservation and development during and only during, the first sixty days of such period of suspension.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47501" number="60371" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-520 Expiration date. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11567" name="26-520"/>§ 26-520 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Expiration date. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47502" number="60372" version="2023">
											<PARA>This chapter shall expire on April 1, 2027 unless rent control shall sooner terminate as provided in subdivision three of section one of the local emergency housing rent control law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-095]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47503" number="60373" version="2023">
											<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2015/026, 3/30/2015, eff. 3/30/2015; Am. L.L. 2018/085, 3/27/2018, eff. 3/27/2018; Am. L.L. 2020/113, 11/15/2020, eff. 11/15/2020; Am. L.L. 2022/055, 3/30/2022, eff. 3/30/2022; Am. L.L. 2022/069, 6/27/2022, eff. 6/27/2022; Am. L.L. 2024/047, 3/25/2024, eff. 3/25/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-095]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>