<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-230304" number="9196" version="2138">
			<HEADING>Chapter 2: Unlawful Sale or Possession of Controlled Substances</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2531" name="T10C002"/>Chapter 2: Unlawful Sale or Possession of Controlled Substances</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-6835" number="9197" version="1705">
				<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
					<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1989/010" destination-id="0-0-0-27014">L.L. 1989/010</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-221656" number="9198" version="1705">
										<HEADING>§ 10-201 Unlawful possession of controlled substances. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2533" name="10-201"/>§ 10-201 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Unlawful possession of controlled substances. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6836" number="9199" version="3">
											<PARA>No person shall unlawfully posses or sell any controlled substance the possession or sale of which would constitute a felony pursuant to articles two hundred twenty or two hundred twenty-one of the penal law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6837" number="9200" version="1705">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1989/010" destination-id="0-0-0-27014">L.L. 1989/010</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-221654" number="9201" version="1705">
										<HEADING>§ 10-202 Civil action. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2535" name="10-202"/>§ 10-202 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Civil action. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6838" number="9202" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who has been convicted of the possession or sale of a controlled substance in an amount which constitutes a felony pursuant to articles two hundred twenty or two hundred twenty-one of the penal law shall be liable to the city for a civil penalty in the amount of not less than ten thousand dollars nor more than one hundred thousand dollars for each count of an indictment for unlawful possession or sale which has resulted in a conviction under the penal law. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6839" number="9203" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The corporation counsel, upon notification by an appropriate law enforcement agency that there is reason to believe that a person who has been convicted of an offense under articles two hundred twenty or two hundred twenty-one of the penal law has substantial assets and that there is a significant likelihood that a civil judgment obtained pursuant to this section shall be capable of satisfaction, may commence a civil action under this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6840" number="9204" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In any civil action brought pursuant to this section, the city may recover, in addition to the amount set forth in subdivision a, the costs of the investigation and prosecution of the person in the criminal action resulting in conviction pursuant to articles two hundred twenty and two hundred twenty-one of the penal law, and the costs of the civil action, including reasonable attorney&apos;s fees. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6841" number="9205" version="1705">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1989/010" destination-id="0-0-0-27014">L.L. 1989/010</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-221655" number="9206" version="1705">
										<HEADING>§ 10-203 Unlawful manufacture, distribution or sale of a synthetic cannabinoid or synthetic phenethylamine.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1951" name="10-203"/>§ 10-203 Unlawful manufacture, distribution or sale of a synthetic cannabinoid or synthetic phenethylamine.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6842" number="9207" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No person or entity shall knowingly manufacture, sell, offer for sale, display for sale, distribute for sale, or possess with intent to sell: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6843" number="9208" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>any synthetic cannabinoid or synthetic phenethylamine, as such terms are defined by part 9 of title 10 of the New York codes, rules and regulations as of the date of the violation, or as included in schedule I of the federal drug enforcement administration schedules of controlled substances, as listed in 21 CFR § 1308.11, or successor regulation, as of the date of the violation, or any cannabimimetic agent, as defined in 21 U.S.C. § 812, as of the date of the violation; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6844" number="9209" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>any analogue of a synthetic cannabinoid, synthetic phenethylamine or cannabimimetic agent. For the purposes of this paragraph, &quot;analogue of a synthetic cannabinoid, synthetic phenethylamines or cannabimimetic agent&quot; means a substance that has a chemical structure that is substantially similar to the chemical structure of a substance described in paragraph 1 of this subdivision and has a stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system that is substantially similar to or greater than the stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system of such a substance described in paragraph 1 of this subdivision; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6845" number="9210" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>any substance commonly known as synthetic marijuana, K-2 or bath salts, including but not limited to a substance so identified as an embargoed product by order of the commissioner of the department of health and mental hygiene, that is represented as being intended for human consumption. Evidence of representations that a substance commonly known as synthetic marijuana, K-2 or bath salts is intended for human consumption may include, but is not limited to, oral, visual or written representations by the manufacturer, distributor or seller about the substance with regard to its nature, use or effect; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6846" number="9211" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>any purported synthetic drug. In any proceeding commenced in connection with an alleged violation of this paragraph, it shall be necessary to prove that the purported synthetic drug was represented to be a substance described in paragraph 1, 2 or 3 of this subdivision; provided, however, that it shall not be a defense to prosecution under this section that the accused believed the purported synthetic drug to be such a substance. For the purposes of this subdivision, the term &quot;purported synthetic drug&quot; means a substance that, by dosage unit appearance, including color, shape and size, and by a representation, is represented to be a substance described in paragraph 1, 2 or 3 of this subdivision. Evidence of such a representation may include, but is not limited to, oral, visual or written representations by the manufacturer, distributor or seller about the substance with regard to: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6847" number="9212" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>its price, nature, use or effect as a substance described in paragraph 1, 2 or 3 of this subdivision; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6848" number="9213" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>its packaging in a manner normally used for substances described in paragraph 1, 2 or 3 of this subdivision. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6849" number="9214" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Possession of ten or more packets, individual containers or other separate units of a substance described in subdivision a of this section is presumptive evidence that the possessing person or entity is distributing such substance for sale or possesses such substances with intent to sell. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6850" number="9215" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person or entity that violates subdivision a of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of not more than $5,000 or imprisonment of up to one year, or both. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6851" number="9216" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to the penalties prescribed in subdivision c of this section, any person or entity that violates subdivision a of this section shall be liable for a civil penalty of not less than $1,000 and not more than $10,000 recoverable in a proceeding before any tribunal established within the office of administrative trials and hearings or within any agency of the city of New York designated to conduct such proceedings, provided that upon the first such violation, and any other such violations by the same person or entity on the same day as such first violation, such person or entity shall be liable for a civil penalty of not less than $500 and not more than $5,000 if such violation is not in conjunction with the commission of any crime other than possession, manufacture, distribution or sale of any synthetic cannabinoid, synthetic phenethylamine, or other substance described in subdivision a of this section. The manufacture, distribution, sale, offer for sale, display for sale, or possession with intent to sell of each packet, individual container or other separate unit of substance described in subdivision a of this section shall constitute a separate violation under this subdivision, with a maximum civil liability of $50,000 for violations in a day for a single person or entity under this subdivision. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6852" number="9217" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any police officer, or sheriff, undersheriff, or deputy sheriff of the city of New York, or any peace officer acting pursuant to his or her special duties may enforce the provisions of this section. A proceeding to recover any civil penalty authorized pursuant to subdivision d of this section shall be commenced by the service of a notice of violation returnable to any tribunal established within the office of administrative trials and hearings or within any agency of the city of New York designated to conduct such proceedings. The notice of violation or copy thereof when filled in and served shall constitute notice of the violation charged. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6853" number="9218" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever a police officer, or sheriff, undersheriff, or deputy sheriff of the city of New York, or any peace officer acting pursuant to his or her special duties, discovers any substance described in subdivision a being possessed in a manner that violates such subdivision, such officer is authorized and empowered to seize and take possession of such substance, which shall be destroyed or used either for law enforcement purposes or for evidentiary purposes in connection with any enforcement proceeding conducted pursuant to this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6854" number="9219" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In any proceeding commenced pursuant to this section, it shall be no defense that the substance&apos;s packaging or other representation states or indicates that the substance is not intended for human consumption. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6855" number="9220" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who engages in business as a retail dealer pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="20-202" destination-id="0-0-0-2537">20-202</LINK> of the code shall be subject to: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6856" number="9221" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>a mandatory suspension of his or her retail dealer license for a period of thirty days for a violation of this section; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6857" number="9222" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>a mandatory revocation of his or her retail dealer license, or of any subsequent license holder, for a second or subsequent violation of this section occurring on a different day at the same place of business within a three-year period, unless the subsequent license holder provides the commissioner of the agency that has commenced the proceeding to recover a civil penalty pursuant to subdivision d of this section with adequate documentation demonstrating that such subsequent license holder acquired the premises or business through an arm&apos;s length transaction, as defined in paragraph 5 of subdivision d of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="20-202" destination-id="0-0-0-2537">20-202</LINK> of the code, and that the sale or lease was not conducted, in whole or in part, for the purpose of permitting the original licensee to avoid the effect of violations on the premises. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6858" number="9223" version="3">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2015/097, 10/20/2015, eff. 12/19/2015; Am. L.L. 2015/095, 10/20/2015, eff. 12/19/2015) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6859" number="9224" version="663">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2015/095" destination-id="0-0-0-20641">L.L. 2015/095</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2015/097" destination-id="0-0-0-20643">L.L. 2015/097</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-053]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>