<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-130512" number="9225" version="662">
			<HEADING>Chapter 3: Firearms</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2539" name="T10C003"/>Chapter 3: Firearms</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-6860" number="9226" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 10-301 Control and regulation of the disposition, purchase and possession of firearms, rifles, shotguns and assault weapons. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-817" name="10-301"/>§ 10-301 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Control and regulation of the disposition, purchase and possession of firearms, rifles, shotguns and assault weapons. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113552" number="9227" version="214">
											<PARA>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> Whenever used in this chapter the following terms shall mean and include:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6862" number="9228" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Firearm.&quot; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6863" number="9229" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any pistol or revolver; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6864" number="9230" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a shotgun having one or more barrels less than eighteen inches in length; or </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6865" number="9231" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a rifle having one or more barrels less than sixteen inches in length; or </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6866" number="9232" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>any weapon made from a shotgun or rifle whether by alteration, modification, or otherwise if such weapon as altered, modified, or otherwise has an overall length of less than twenty-six inches. For the purpose of this subdivision the length of the barrel on a shotgun or rifle shall be determined by measuring the distance between the muzzle and the face of the bolt, breech, or breechlock when closed and when the shotgun or rifle is cocked; the overall length of a weapon made from a shotgun or rifle is the distance between the extreme ends of the weapon measured along a line parallel to the center line of the bore. Firearm does not include an antique firearm. The provisions of this chapter relating to firearms shall not apply to assault weapons except as specifically provided.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6867" number="9233" version="1766">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Rifle.&quot; A weapon designed or redesigned, made or remade, and intended to be fired from the shoulder, and, even if not designed or redesigned, made or remade, and intended to be fired from the shoulder, is not a firearm as defined in subdivision one of this section, and designed or redesigned and made or remade to use the energy of the explosive in a fixed metallic cartridge to fire only a single projectile through a rifled bore for each pull of the trigger. The provisions of this chapter relating to rifles shall not apply to assault weapons except as specifically provided.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6868" number="9234" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Shotgun.&quot; A weapon designed or redesigned, made or remade, and intended to be fired from the shoulder, and, even if not designed or redesigned, made or remade, and intended to be fired from the shoulder, is not a firearm as defined in subdivision one of this section, and designed or redesigned and made or remade to use the energy of the explosive in a fixed shotgun shell, to fire through a smooth bore either a number of ball shot or a single projectile for each single pull of the trigger. The provisions of this chapter relating to shotguns shall not apply to assault weapons except as specifically provided.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6869" number="9235" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Gunsmith.&quot; Any person, firm, partnership, corporation, or company who engages in the business of repairing, altering, assembling, manufacturing, cleaning, polishing, engraving, or trueing, or who in the course of such business performs any mechanical operation on any rifle, shotgun, firearm, assault weapon or machine gun.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6870" number="9236" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Dealer in firearms.&quot; Any person, firm, partnership, corporation or company who engages in the business of purchasing, selling, keeping for sale, loaning, leasing, or in any manner disposing of any pistol or revolver or other firearms which may be concealed upon the person. Dealer in firearms shall not include a wholesale dealer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6871" number="9237" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Dealer in rifles and shotguns.&quot; Any person, firm, partnership, corporation or company who engages in the business of purchasing, selling, keeping for sale, loaning, leasing, or in any manner disposing of any rifle, or shotgun. Dealer in rifles and shotguns shall not include a wholesale dealer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6872" number="9238" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Ammunition.&quot; Explosives suitable to be fired from a firearm, machine gun, pistol, revolver, rifle, shotgun, assault weapon or other dangerous weapon.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6873" number="9239" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Dispose of.&quot; To dispose of, give away, give, lease, loan, keep for sale, offer, offer for sale, sell, transfer and otherwise dispose of.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6874" number="9240" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Deface.&quot; To remove, deface, cover, alter, or destroy the manufacturer&apos;s serial number or any other distinguishing number or identification mark.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6875" number="9241" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>10.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Commissioner.&quot; The police commissioner of the city of New York or the commissioner&apos;s designee.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6876" number="9242" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>11.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Permit.&quot; The permit for purchase and possession of rifles and shotguns issued by the commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6877" number="9243" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>12.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Certificate.&quot; The certificate of registration for possession of rifles and shotguns.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6878" number="9244" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>13.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Serious offense.&quot; A serious offense as defined in subdivision seventeen of section 265.00 of the penal law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6879" number="9245" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>14.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Business enterprise.&quot; Any proprietorship, company, partnership, corporation, association, cooperative, nonprofit organization or other entity engaged or seeking to engage in the activities regulated pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-302" destination-id="0-0-0-2409">10-302</LINK> of this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6880" number="9246" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>15.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Semiautomatic.&quot; Any firearm, rifle or shotgun that uses part of the energy of a fired cartridge to expel the case of the fired cartridge and load another cartridge into the firing chamber, and which requires a separate pull of the trigger to fire each cartridge.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6881" number="9247" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>16.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Assault weapon.&quot;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6882" number="9248" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any semiautomatic centerfire or rimfire rifle or semiautomatic shotgun which has one or more of the following features:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6883" number="9249" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>folding or telescoping stock or no stock;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6884" number="9250" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>pistol grip that protrudes conspicuously beneath the action of the weapon; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6885" number="9251" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>bayonet mount;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6886" number="9252" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>flash suppressor or threaded barrel designed to accommodate a flash suppressor;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6887" number="9253" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>barrel shroud;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6888" number="9254" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>grenade launcher; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6889" number="9255" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>modifications of such features, or other features, determined by rule of the commissioner to be particularly suitable for military and not sporting purposes. In addition, the commissioner shall, by rule, designate specific semiautomatic centerfire or rimfire rifles or semiautomatic shotguns, identified by make, model and/or manufacturer&apos;s name, as within the definition of assault weapon, if the commissioner determines that such weapons are particularly suitable for military and not sporting purposes. The commissioner shall inspect such specific designated semiautomatic centerfire or rimfire rifles or semiautomatic shotguns at least three times per year, and shall revise or update such designations as he or she deems appropriate.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6890" number="9256" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any shotgun with a revolving-cylinder magazine.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6891" number="9257" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any part, or combination of parts, designed or redesigned or intended to readily convert a rifle or shotgun into an assault weapon.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6892" number="9258" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Assault weapon&quot; shall not include any rifle or shotgun modified to render it permanently inoperative.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6893" number="9259" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>17.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Ammunition feeding device.&quot; Magazines, belts, feedstrips, drums or clips capable of being attached to or utilized with firearms, rifles, shotguns or assault weapons.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6894" number="9260" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>18.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Antique firearm.&quot; Any unloaded muzzle loading pistol or revolver with a matchlock, flintlock, percussion cap, or similar type of ignition system, or a pistol or revolver which uses fixed cartridges which are no longer available in the ordinary channels of commercial trade.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6895" number="9261" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>19.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Special theatrical dealer.&quot; Any person, firm, partnership, corporation or company who possesses assault weapons exclusively for the purpose of leasing such assault weapons to special theatrical permittees within the city and for theatrical purposes outside the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6896" number="9262" version="214">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>20.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Acquire.&quot; To gain possession of or title to a weapon through purchase, gift, lease, loan, or otherwise.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113554" number="9263" version="1765">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>21.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Frame or receiver.&quot; Part of a firearm, rifle, shotgun or assault weapon that provides housing for the hammer, bolt or breechblock, and firing mechanism, and that is usually threaded at its forward portion to receive the barrel. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113555" number="9264" version="1811">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>22.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Unfinished frame or receiver.&quot; A piece of any material that does not constitute the frame or receiver of a firearm, rifle, shotgun or assault weapon but that has been shaped or formed in any way for the purpose of becoming the frame or receiver of a firearm, rifle, shotgun or assault weapon with modification by the user and that is not engraved with a serial number that meets or exceeds requirements pursuant to subsection (i) of section 923 of title 18 of the United States code and regulations issued pursuant thereto. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113553" number="9265" version="214">
											<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2019/187, 10/26/2019, eff. 2/23/2020) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6897" number="9266" version="1664">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1991/078" destination-id="0-0-0-26668">L.L. 1991/078</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2006/031" destination-id="0-0-0-25074">L.L. 2006/031</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-208354" number="9267" version="1450">
										<HEADING>§ 10-302 Licensing of gunsmiths, of wholesale manufacturers of firearms, or assemblers of firearms, dealers in firearms, dealers in rifles and shotguns, and special theatrical dealers. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2409" name="10-302"/>§ 10-302 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Licensing of gunsmiths, of wholesale manufacturers of firearms, or assemblers of firearms, dealers in firearms, dealers in rifles and shotguns, and special theatrical dealers. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6898" number="9268" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any person or business enterprise to engage in the business of gunsmith, wholesale manufacturer of firearms, assembler of firearms, dealer in firearms, dealer in rifles and shotguns, or special theatrical dealer, unless such person, or business enterprise, has obtained a license to engage in such business in the manner prescribed in this section. No person shall engage in the business of dealer in rifles and shotguns or special theatrical dealer unless he or she has been issued a permit for the possession of shotguns and rifles pursuant to the provisions of this chapter. No person or business enterprise shall be eligible to apply for or to hold a license as a special theatrical dealer unless such person or business enterprise (1) possesses both a license as a dealer in firearms and a license as a dealer in rifles and shotguns and (2) has possessed such licenses and engaged in such businesses for at least one year.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6899" number="9269" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No license shall be issued or renewed pursuant to this section except by the police commissioner, and then only after investigation and finding that all statements in a proper application for a license or renewal are true. No license shall be issued or renewed except for any applicant:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6900" number="9270" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>of good moral character;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6901" number="9271" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>who has not been convicted anywhere of a felony or of any serious offense;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6902" number="9272" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>who has stated whether he or she has ever suffered any mental illness or been confined to any hospital or institution, public or private, for mental illness and who is free from any mental disorder, defects or diseases that would impair the ability safely to possess or use a firearm, rifle or shotgun;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6903" number="9273" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>who has not been convicted of violating section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-303.1" destination-id="0-0-0-2541">10-303.1</LINK> of this chapter; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6904" number="9274" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>concerning whom no good cause exists for the denial of a license.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6905" number="9275" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An applicant to engage in such business shall also be a citizen of the United States, more than twenty-one years of age and maintain a place of business in the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6906" number="9276" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each applicant to engage in such business shall comply with all the requirements set forth in this section. If the applicant is a partnership, each partner thereof shall comply with all the requirements set forth in this section and if the applicant is a corporation, each officer thereof shall so comply.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6907" number="9277" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No applicant for a special theatrical dealer&apos;s license or renewal thereof shall be issued such license or renewal unless the applicant submits proof, in such form as the commissioner may require, that at least ten percent of the gross income earned by the applicant as a dealer in firearms, dealer in rifles and shotguns and, in the case of an application for renewal, special theatrical dealer, in the year preceding the application for such license or renewal, was earned from the lease for theatrical purposes of such ammunition feeding devices, firearms, rifles, shotguns or assault weapons as the applicant was authorized to lease. No applicant for a special theatrical dealer&apos;s license or renewal thereof shall be issued such license or renewal unless the gross income earned by the applicant as a dealer in firearms, dealer in rifles and shotguns and, in the case of an application for renewal, special theatrical dealer, in the year preceding the application for such license or renewal, exceeded fifty thousand dollars.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6908" number="9278" version="1767">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>An application for a license or renewal thereof shall be made to the police commissioner. An application shall include the full name, date of birth, residence, present occupation of each person or individual signing the same, whether he or she is a citizen of the United States, whether he or she complies with each requirement for eligibility specified in subdivision b of this section and such other facts as may be required to show the good character, competency and integrity of each person or individual signing the application. An application shall be signed and affirmed by the applicant. Each individual signing an application shall submit one photograph of himself or herself and a duplicate for each required copy of the application. Such photographs shall have been taken within thirty days prior to filing the application. The photographs submitted shall be two inches square, and the application shall also state the previous occupation of each individual signing the same and the location of the place of such business, or of the bureau, agency, subagency, office or branch office for which the license is sought, indicating the street and number and otherwise giving such apt description as to point out reasonably the location thereof. In such case, if the applicant is a business enterprise, its name, date and place of formation, and principal place of business shall be stated. For a partnership, the application shall be signed and affirmed by each partner, and for a corporation, by each officer thereof. With respect to an application for a license as a dealer in rifles and shotguns or as a special theatrical dealer, a written statement shall be submitted by the individual applicant, or in the case of a business enterprise a responsible officer or agent thereof, stating (a) the identification number of the shotgun and rifle permit issued to the individual applicant or the responsible officer or agent in the case of a business enterprise, (b) the address of a regular place of business maintained by the applicant, (c) that since the issuance of the rifle and shotgun permit the individual applicant or responsible officer or agent has not become disqualified for issuance of such a permit, (d) that he or she undertakes to supervise the acts of his or her, or in the case of a business enterprise, its employees, (e) that the applicant has not previously been refused a license as a dealer in shotguns and rifles or as a special theatrical dealer and that no such license issued to the applicant has ever been revoked.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6909" number="9279" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Before a license is issued or renewed, there shall be an investigation of all statements required in the application by the police department. For that purpose, the records of the department of mental hygiene concerning previous or present mental illness of the applicant shall be available for inspection by the investigating officer of the police department. In order to ascertain any previous criminal record, the investigating officer shall take the fingerprints and physical descriptive data in quadruplicate of each individual by whom the application is signed. Two copies of such fingerprints shall be taken on standard fingerprint cards eight inches square, and one copy may be taken on a card supplied for that purpose by the federal bureau of investigation. When completed, one standard card shall be promptly submitted to the division of criminal justice services where it shall be appropriately processed. A second standard card, or the one supplied by the federal bureau of investigation, as the case may be, shall be forwarded to that bureau at Washington with a request that the files of the bureau be searched and notification of the results of the search be made to the police department. The failure or refusal of the federal bureau of investigation to make the fingerprint check provided for in this section shall not constitute the sole basis for refusal to issue a license pursuant to the provisions of this section. Of the remaining two fingerprint cards, one shall be filed with the executive department, division of state police, Albany, within ten days after issuance of the license, and the other remain on file with the police department. No such fingerprints may be inspected by any person other than a peace officer, when acting pursuant to his or her special duties, or a police officer except on order of a judge or justice of a court of record either upon notice to the licensee or without notice, as the judge or justice may deem appropriate. Upon completion of the investigation, the police department shall report the results to the commissioner without unnecessary delay.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6910" number="9280" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications shall indicate and licenses shall be issued for a gunsmith, a wholesale manufacturer of firearms, an assembler of firearms, a dealer in firearms, a dealer in rifles and shotguns or a special theatrical dealer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6911" number="9281" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The application for any license, if granted, shall be a public record. Such application shall be kept on file in the office of the police commissioner and, within ten days after the issuance of a license, a duplicate copy shall be filed in the executive department, division of state police, Albany.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6912" number="9282" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No license shall be transferable to any other person or premises. The license shall mention and describe the premises for which it is issued and shall be valid only for such premises.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6913" number="9283" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A license issued pursuant to this section shall be prominently displayed on the licensed premises. Failure of any person or business enterprise to so exhibit or display such license shall be presumptive evidence that the person or business enterprise is not duly licensed.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6914" number="9284" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>j.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any license or renewal issued pursuant to this section shall expire on the first day of the second January following the date of issuance. Any application to renew a license that has not previously expired, been revoked or cancelled shall thereby extend the term of the license until disposition is made of the application by the police commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6915" number="9285" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>k.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The conviction of a licensee anywhere of a felony or a serious offense shall operate as a revocation of the license. Written notice of such revocation shall be forwarded to the executive division of state police in Albany.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6916" number="9286" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>l.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The police commissioner, upon evidence of any disqualification set forth in subdivision b of this section, may at any time suspend or revoke and cancel a license issued pursuant to this section. Written notice of such suspension or revocation shall be forwarded to the executive department, division of state police, Albany.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6917" number="9287" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>m.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No license shall be issued pursuant to this section unless the applicant therefor possesses and exhibits all licenses required under any federal or state law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6918" number="9288" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>n.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Records.</CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6919" number="9289" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person licensed under this section shall keep an accurate book record of every transaction involving a firearm, machine gun, rifle, shotgun or assault weapon. Such record shall be kept in the manner prescribed and contain the information required by the police commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6920" number="9290" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The records required by this section shall be subject to inspection at all times by members of the police department. Such records shall be maintained on the premises mentioned and described in the license, and preserved for record. In the event of suspension, cancellation or revocation of a license, or discontinuance of business by a licensee, such record shall be immediately surrendered to the police commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6921" number="9291" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person licensed under this section as a dealer in firearms or special theatrical dealer shall cause a physical inventory to be taken within the first five business days of April and October of each year, which shall include a listing of each firearm by make, caliber and serial number. The original copy of such inventory shall be securely maintained on the premises for which the license was issued. One or more additional copies shall be forwarded to such addresses as the commissioner may direct, by such means as the commissioner may direct.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6922" number="9292" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With each copy of the inventory required under paragraph three of this subdivision shall be included an affidavit signed by the licensee (or, if the licensee is not a natural person, by an officer, general manager, or other principal of the licensee) stating under penalties of perjury that within the first five business days of that April or October, as the case may be, the signer has personally observed the firearms reported. The affidavit shall also describe the date and contents of any report required to be made pursuant to section 400.10 of the penal law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6923" number="9293" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to the penalties specified in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-310" destination-id="0-0-0-2543">10-310</LINK>, any act or omission that constitutes a violation of this subdivision or of rules and regulations issued by the commissioner pursuant thereto shall be grounds for the revocation of a license issued by the commissioner pursuant to this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6924" number="9294" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>o.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rules and regulations.</CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6925" number="9295" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The police commissioner may make and promulgate such rules and regulations regarding the issuance and renewal of such licenses and the reporting of inventory of firearms, loss of firearms, and theft of firearms and may prescribe such forms as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6926" number="9296" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such rules and regulations shall prescribe reasonable standards and conditions under which firearms, component parts of firearms, rifles, shotguns, assault weapons and ammunition shall be kept at the store or premises of gunsmiths, including store and plant security, employment, record keeping and product quality control for the protection of the public safety, health and welfare. The foregoing enumeration shall not be construed as a limitation of the police commissioner&apos;s authority to promulgate rules and regulations hereunder.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6927" number="9297" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The violation of such rules and regulations shall be triable by a judge of the criminal court of the city of New York and punishable by not more than thirty days imprisonment or by a fine of not more than fifty dollars, or both.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6928" number="9298" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>p.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The annual license fee for a license issued pursuant to this section shall be twenty-five dollars for gunsmiths, wholesale manufacturers and assemblers of firearms, fifty dollars for dealers in firearms, and one hundred fifty dollars for dealers in rifles and shotguns and special theatrical dealers.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6929" number="9299" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>q.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Failure to obtain a license, by any person, firm, partnership, corporation or company, as required by the provisions of this section shall be punishable as a class A misdemeanor.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6930" number="9300" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>r.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No dealer in rifles and shotguns may dispose of a rifle or shotgun to any person unless such person produces a valid rifle and shotgun permit, or proof of lawful authority as a police or peace officer, or is an exempt person as provided in this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6931" number="9301" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>s.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any suspension, denial or revocation of a license may be appealed by the applicant or licensee pursuant to procedures established by the police commissioner for administrative review. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6932" number="9302" version="1664">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1991/078" destination-id="0-0-0-26668">L.L. 1991/078</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2006/030" destination-id="0-0-0-25076">L.L. 2006/030</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-219628" number="9303" version="1664">
										<HEADING>§ 10-302.1 Preventing the diversion of firearms, rifles and shotguns to criminals. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2545" name="10-302.1"/>§ 10-302.1 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Preventing the diversion of firearms, rifles and shotguns to criminals. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6933" number="9304" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No dealer in firearms and no dealer in rifles and shotguns shall: (i) sell or otherwise dispose of more than one firearm or more than one rifle or shotgun to any individual as part of the same sales transaction; or (ii) sell or otherwise dispose of a rifle or shotgun to any individual if the dealer knows or should know that such individual has purchased a rifle or shotgun within the prior ninety days, or (iii) sell or otherwise dispose of a firearm to any individual if the dealer knows or should know that such individual has purchased a firearm within the prior ninety days.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6934" number="9305" version="608">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No person shall acquire a firearm if such person has acquired a firearm within the previous ninety days. No person shall acquire a rifle or shotgun if such person has acquired a rifle or shotgun within the previous ninety days. For purposes of this subdivision when a firearm, rifle or shotgun is acquired by a corporation, partnership, or other entity, it shall be considered to have been acquired by each natural person who is an officer, director or other principal of such entity, unless the firearm, rifle or shotgun is acquired on behalf of such entity by a person who is licensed by the commissioner as gun custodian or special gun custodian, or acquired on behalf of an organization possessing an organization registration certificate, as those terms are used in <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="381572687-333571626-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Rules.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="Title 38" destination-id="0-0-0-0">title thirty-eight</LINK> of the rules of the city of New York.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6935" number="9306" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Before disposing of any firearm, rifle or shotgun to a person licensed by the commissioner to possess firearms, rifles or shotguns, any dealer in firearms, dealer in rifles and shotguns or other person shall contact the police department to ensure compliance with the requirements of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6936" number="9307" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any dealer in firearms, dealer in rifles and shotguns or other person who disposes of any firearm, rifle or shotgun to a person licensed by an authority other than the commissioner to possess firearms, rifles or shotguns shall make reasonable efforts to contact such licensing authority and to ascertain the most recent date of acquisition by such licensee of a firearm, in the case of disposition of a firearm, or of a rifle or shotgun, in the case of disposition of a rifle or shotgun.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6937" number="9308" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any dealer in firearms or dealer in rifles or shotguns who disposes of any firearm, rifle or shotgun shall, before or at the time of disposing of such firearm, rifle or shotgun, record, in the record book required to be kept by subdivision n of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-302" destination-id="0-0-0-2409">10-302</LINK>, the efforts made by such dealer to ensure compliance with the requirements of this section, any exception or exemption set forth in this section that such dealer reasonably believes would authorize the disposal of such firearm, rifle or shotgun, and the grounds for such dealer&apos;s belief that such exception or exemption applies.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6938" number="9309" version="608">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Exceptions.</CHARFORMAT> The provisions of this section shall not apply to the sale of firearms, rifles or shotguns to (i) a police officer, as such term is defined in section 1.20 of the criminal procedure law, (ii) a federal law enforcement officer, as such term is defined in section 2.15 of the criminal procedure law, (iii) a public agency in furtherance of official business, (iv) persons in the military service of the state of New York, when duly authorized by regulations issued by the adjutant general to possess such weapons, (v) persons in the military or other service of the United States, in pursuit of official duty or when duly authorized by federal law, regulation or order to possess such weapons, (vi) persons employed in fulfilling defense contracts with the government of the United States or agencies thereof when possession of such weapons is necessary for manufacture, transport, installation and testing under the requirements of such contract, (vii) peace officers as defined in section 2.10 of the criminal procedure law, provided that such peace officers are authorized pursuant to law or regulation of the state or city of New York to possess a firearm, rifle or shotgun within the city of New York without a license or permit therefor, and are authorized by their employer to possess such firearm, rifle or shotgun, (viii) persons licensed as dealers, manufacturers or importers of firearms pursuant to 18 U.S.C. Chapter 44, (ix) any motion picture, television or video production company or entertainment or theatrical company whose production involves the use of firearms, rifles or shotguns, provided that such weapons shall be properly registered and a special theatrical permit shall have been issued for such weapons pursuant to rules established by the commissioner, (x) with respect to the sale of firearms only, persons licensed by the commissioner as gun custodians or special gun custodians, as those terms are used in <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="381572687-333571626-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Rules.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="Title 38" destination-id="0-0-0-0">title thirty-eight</LINK> of the rules of the city of New York, and (xi) with respect to the sale of rifles and shotguns only, organizations possessing an organization registration certificate, as that term is used in <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="381572687-333571626-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Rules.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="Title 38" destination-id="0-0-0-0">title thirty-eight</LINK> of the rules of the city of New York.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6939" number="9310" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Exempt transactions.</CHARFORMAT> The requirements of this section shall not apply to: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6940" number="9311" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>any transaction in which a person acquires a firearm, rifle or shotgun by operation of law, or because of the death of another person for whom such person is an executor or administrator of an estate or a trustee of a trust created in a will, provided that within fifteen days such person surrenders such firearm, rifle or shotgun to the commissioner until it can be reacquired without violation of this section or other applicable law. If a firearm, rifle or shotgun is surrendered pursuant to this subdivision but no written request to reacquire it is received by the commissioner within two years of such surrender, the commissioner shall dispose of such firearm in accordance with the provisions of section 400.05 of the penal law;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6941" number="9312" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the exchange of a firearm, rifle or shotgun by a dealer in firearms or a dealer in rifles and shotguns for another firearm, rifle or shotgun previously purchased from such dealer by the person requesting such exchange, provided that such exchange takes place within thirty days of such request;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6942" number="9313" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the acquisition or disposal of an antique firearm, rifle or shotgun which is incapable of being fired or discharged or which does not fire fixed ammunition, or a firearm, rifle or shotgun manufactured prior to eighteen hundred ninety-four or whose design was patented and whose commercial manufacture commenced prior to eighteen hundred ninety-four and whose manufacture continued after such year without any substantial alteration in design or function, and for which cartridge ammunition is not commercially available and is possessed as a curiosity or ornament or for its historical significance and value;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6943" number="9314" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the acquisition or disposal of a firearm at an indoor or outdoor pistol range when such acquisition or disposal begins a period of possession or use of the firearm that is authorized by paragraphs 7-a, 7-b, or 7-e of subdivision a of section 265.20 of the penal law;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6944" number="9315" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the sale of a firearm by a dealer in firearms to a person whose firearm is stolen or irretrievably lost, provided that: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6945" number="9316" version="608">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>such person has complied with any legal requirement to report the loss or theft, including but not limited to the applicable provisions of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="381572687-333571626-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Rules.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="Title 38" destination-id="0-0-0-0">title thirty-eight</LINK> of the rules of the city of New York and section 400.10 of the penal law;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6946" number="9317" version="608">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>such person provides to such dealer a copy of a police report of the loss or theft or of any report made pursuant to the applicable provisions of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="381572687-333571626-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Rules.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="Title 38" destination-id="0-0-0-0">title thirty-eight</LINK> of the rules of the city of New York and section 400.10 of the penal law, which copy the dealer shall attach to the record book required to be kept by subdivision n of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-302" destination-id="0-0-0-2409">10-302</LINK>;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6947" number="9318" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the copy provided pursuant to subparagraph two of this paragraph contains the name and address of the regulated firearm owner, a description of the regulated firearm, the location of the loss or theft, if known, the date of the loss or theft, if known, and the date when the loss or theft was reported to the law enforcement agency; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6948" number="9319" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>such person&apos;s attempt to replace the regulated firearm occurs within thirty days of the loss or theft of such firearm, if known, or, if such date is not known, within thirty days of the date when the loss or theft was reported to the law enforcement agency, as reflected by the information recorded on the police report; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6949" number="9320" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vi)<TAB tab-count="1"/>any other transaction authorized in advance in writing by the commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6950" number="9321" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Penalties.</CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6951" number="9322" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to the penalties specified in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-310" destination-id="0-0-0-2543">10-310</LINK>, any act or omission that constitutes or would constitute a violation of this section or of rules and regulations issued by the commissioner pursuant thereto shall be grounds for the revocation of a license to deal in firearms, deal in rifles and shotguns, possess firearms, or possess a rifle or shotgun.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6952" number="9323" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any firearm disposed of or acquired in violation of this section shall be a nuisance subject to surrender and forfeiture in accordance with the procedures specified in section 400.05 of the penal law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6953" number="9324" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner may make and promulgate such rules and regulations as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this section. Such rules and regulations may address, but need not be limited to:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6954" number="9325" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>procedures for implementation of this section by the commissioner;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6955" number="9326" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>establishment of a database of firearm, rifle and shotgun purchases for the purpose of enforcing the requirements of this chapter; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6956" number="9327" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the specification of reasonable efforts required to comply with subdivision d of this section. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6957" number="9328" version="1474">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2005/009" destination-id="0-0-0-25238">L.L. 2005/009</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2006/031" destination-id="0-0-0-25074">L.L. 2006/031</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-208353" number="9329" version="1450">
										<HEADING>§ 10-303 Permits for possession and purchase of rifles and shotguns. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2411" name="10-303"/>§ 10-303 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Permits for possession and purchase of rifles and shotguns. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6958" number="9330" version="3">
											<PARA>It shall be unlawful to dispose of any rifle or shotgun to any person unless said person is the holder of a permit for possession and purchase of rifles and shotguns; it shall be unlawful for any person to have in his or her possession any rifle or shotgun unless said person is the holder of a permit for the possession and purchase of rifles and shotguns. The disposition of a rifle or shotgun, by any licensed dealer in rifles and shotguns, to any person presenting a valid rifle and shotgun permit issued to such person, shall be conclusive proof of the legality of such disposition by the dealer. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6959" number="9331" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Requirements.</CHARFORMAT> No person shall be denied a permit to purchase and possess a rifle or shotgun unless the applicant:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6960" number="9332" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>is under the age of twenty-one; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6961" number="9333" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>is not of good moral character; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6962" number="9334" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>has been convicted anywhere of a felony; of a serious offense as defined in §265.00 (17) of the New York State Penal Law; of a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence as defined in 18 U.S.C. § 921(a); of a misdemeanor crime of assault as defined in the penal law where the applicant was convicted of such assault within the ten years preceding the submission of the application; or of any three misdemeanors as defined in local, state or federal law, however nothing in this paragraph shall preclude the denial of a permit to an applicant with fewer than three misdemeanor convictions; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6963" number="9335" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>has not stated whether he or she has ever suffered any mental illness or been confined to any hospital or institution, public or private, for mental illness; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6964" number="9336" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>is not now free from any mental disorders, defects or diseases that would impair the ability safely to possess or use a rifle or shotgun; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6965" number="9337" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>has been the subject of a suspension or ineligibility order issue pursuant to §530.14 of the New York State Criminal Procedure Law or §842-a of the New York State Family Court Act; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6966" number="9338" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>who is subject to a court order that</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6967" number="9339" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>was issued after a hearing of which such person received actual notice, and at which such person had the opportunity to participate;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6968" number="9340" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>restrains such person from harassing, stalking, or threatening an intimate partner of such person or child of such intimate partner or person, or engaging in other conduct that would place an intimate partner in reasonable fear of bodily injury to the partner or child; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6969" number="9341" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>includes a finding that such person represents a credible threat to the physical safety of such intimate partner or child; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6970" number="9342" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>by its terms explicitly prohibits the use, attempted use, or threatened use of physical force against such intimate partner or child that would reasonably be expected to cause bodily injury;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6971" number="9343" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of this section only, &quot;intimate partner&quot; means, with respect to a person, the spouse of the person, a former spouse of the person, an individual who is a parent of a child of the person, and an individual who cohabitates or has cohabited with the person; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6972" number="9344" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>has been convicted of violating section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-303.1" destination-id="0-0-0-2541">10-303.1</LINK> of this chapter; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6973" number="9345" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9)<TAB tab-count="1"/>unless good cause exists for the denial of the permit.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6974" number="9346" version="1767">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application.</CHARFORMAT> Application for a rifle and shotgun permit shall be made to the police commissioner, shall be signed and affirmed by the applicant and shall state his or her full name, date of birth, residence, physical condition, occupation and whether he or she complies with each requirement specified in subdivision a of this section, and any other information required by the police commissioner to process the application. Each applicant shall submit with his or her application a photograph of himself or herself in duplicate, which shall have been taken within thirty days prior to the filing of the application. Any willful or material omission or false statement shall be a violation of this section and grounds for denial of the application.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6975" number="9347" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Before a permit is issued or renewed, the police department shall investigate all statements required in the application. For that purpose, the records of the department of mental hygiene concerning previous or present mental illness of the applicant shall be available for inspection by the investigating officer of the police department. In order to ascertain any previous criminal record, the investigating officer shall take the fingerprints and physical descriptive data in quadruplicate of each individual by whom the application is signed. Two copies of such fingerprints shall be taken on standard fingerprint cards eight inches square, and one copy may be taken on a card supplied for that purpose by the federal bureau of investigation. When completed, one standard card shall be promptly submitted to the division of criminal justice services where it shall be appropriately processed. A second standard card, or the one supplied by the federal bureau of investigation, as the case may be, shall be forwarded to that bureau at Washington with a request that the files of the bureau be searched and notification of the results of the search be made to the police department. The failure or refusal of the federal bureau of investigation to make the fingerprint check provided for in this section shall not constitute the sole basis for refusal to issue a permit pursuant to the provisions of this section. Of the remaining two fingerprint cards, one shall be filed with the executive department, division of state police, Albany, within ten days after issuance of the permit, and the other remain on file with the police department. No such fingerprints may be inspected by any person other than a peace officer, when acting pursuant to his or her special duties, or a police officer, except on order of a justice of a court of record either upon notice to the permittee or without notice, as the judge or justice may deem appropriate. Upon completion of the investigation, the police department shall report the results to the police commissioner without unnecessary delay.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6976" number="9348" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Fees.</CHARFORMAT> The fee for an application for a rifle and shotgun permit or renewal thereof shall be one hundred forty dollars.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6977" number="9349" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Issuance.</CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6978" number="9350" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon completion of the investigation, and in no event later than thirty days from the submission of the application, unless the police commissioner determines more time is needed for an investigation and then it shall not exceed sixty days, the commissioner shall issue the permit or shall notify the applicant of the denial of the application and the reason or reasons therefor. The applicant shall have the right to appeal said denial pursuant to procedures established by the police commissioner for administrative review.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6979" number="9351" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person holding a valid license to carry a concealed weapon in accordance with the provisions of the penal law, shall be issued such permit upon filing an application and upon paying the established fee therefor, without the necessity of any further investigation, affidavits or fingerprinting, unless the police commissioner has reason to believe that the status of the applicant has changed since the issuance of the prior license.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6980" number="9352" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Validity.</CHARFORMAT> Any person to whom a rifle and shotgun permit has been validly issued pursuant to this chapter may possess a rifle or shotgun. No permit shall be transferred to any other person. Every person carrying a rifle or shotgun shall have on his or her person a permit which shall be exhibited for inspection to any peace officer or police officer upon demand. Failure of any such person to so exhibit his or her permit shall be presumptive evidence that he or she is not duly authorized to possess a rifle or shotgun and the same may be considered by the police commissioner as cause for revocation or suspension of such permit. A permit shall be valid for three (3) years and shall be subject to automatic renewal, upon sworn application, and without investigation, unless the police commissioner has reason to believe that the status of the applicant has changed since the previous application.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6981" number="9353" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Revocation or suspension.</CHARFORMAT> A permit shall be revoked upon the conviction in this state, or elsewhere, of a person holding a rifle or shotgun permit, of a felony or a serious offense. A permit may be revoked or suspended at any time upon evidence of any other disqualification set forth in subdivision a of this section. Upon revocation or suspension of a permit for any reason, the police commissioner shall immediately notify the New York state division of criminal justice services. The police commissioner shall from time to time send a notice and supplemental report hereof, containing the names, addresses and permit numbers of each person whose rifle and shotgun permit has been revoked or suspended to all licensed dealers in rifles and shotguns throughout the city for the purpose of notifying such dealers that no rifles or shotguns may be issued or sold or in any way disposed of to any such persons. The police commissioner or any police officer acting at the police commissioner&apos;s direction shall forthwith seize any rifle and shotgun permit which has been revoked or suspended hereunder and shall seize any rifle or shotgun possessed by such person, provided that the person whose rifle or shotgun permit has been revoked or suspended, or such person&apos;s appointee or legal representative, shall have the right at any time up to one year after such seizure to dispose of such rifle or shotgun to any licensed dealer or any other person legally permitted to purchase or take possession of such rifle or shotgun. The permittee shall have the right to appeal any suspension or revocation pursuant to procedures established by the commissioner for administrative review.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6982" number="9354" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Non-residents.</CHARFORMAT> Non-residents of the city of New York may apply for a rifle or shotgun permit subject to the same conditions, regulations and requirements as residents of the city of New York. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6983" number="9355" version="1664">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1991/078" destination-id="0-0-0-26668">L.L. 1991/078</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-219629" number="9356" version="1664">
										<HEADING>§ 10-303.1 Prohibition of the possession or disposition of assault weapons. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2541" name="10-303.1"/>§ 10-303.1 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Prohibition of the possession or disposition of assault weapons. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6984" number="9357" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any person to possess or dispose of any assault weapon within the city of New York, except as provided in subdivision d, e or f of this section or section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-305" destination-id="0-0-0-2413">10-305</LINK>. A person who peaceably surrenders an assault weapon to the commissioner pursuant to subdivision d, e or f of this section or subdivision f of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-305" destination-id="0-0-0-2413">10-305</LINK> shall not be subject to the criminal or civil penalties set forth in this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6985" number="9358" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Criminal penalty.</CHARFORMAT> Any person who shall violate subdivision a of this section shall be guilty of an unclassified misdemeanor punishable by a fine of not more than five thousand dollars or by imprisonment of up to one year, or by both such fine and imprisonment, for each assault weapon disposed of or possessed, provided that the first violation of subdivision a of this section involving possession of an assault weapon as defined in paragraph c of subdivision 16 of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-301" destination-id="0-0-0-817">10-301</LINK> shall be an offense punishable by a fine of not more than three hundred dollars of imprisonment of not more than fifteen days, or both, on condition that (1) such first violation is not in conjunction with the commission of a crime and (2) the possessor has not been previously convicted of a felony or a serious offense.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6986" number="9359" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Civil penalty.</CHARFORMAT> In addition to the penalties prescribed in subdivision b of this section, any person who shall violate subdivision a of this section shall be liable for a civil penalty of not more than twenty-five thousand dollars for each assault weapon disposed of or possessed, to be recovered in a civil action brought by the corporation counsel in the name of the city in any court of competent jurisdiction, provided that the first violation by any person of subdivision a of this section involving possession of an assault weapon as defined in paragraph c of subdivision sixteen of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-301" destination-id="0-0-0-817">10-301</LINK> shall subject such person to a civil penalty of not more than five thousand dollars on condition that (1) such first violation is not in conjunction with the commission of a crime and (2) the possessor has not been previously convicted of a felony or a serious offense.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6987" number="9360" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Disposition of assault weapons by permittees, licensees and previously exempt persons.</CHARFORMAT> Any person who, on or after the effective date of this local law, shall possess an assault weapon and a valid permit for possession and purchase of rifles and shotguns and a certificate of registration for such assault weapon, and any licensed dealer in firearms or licensed dealer in rifles and shotguns who is not licensed as a special theatrical dealer and who, on or after the effective date of this local law, shall possess an assault weapon, and any police officer or peace officer who, before the effective date of this local law was exempt from the sections of the administrative code requiring rifle and shotgun permits and certificates, and who, upon the effective date of this local law, is not exempt from the sections of the administrative code prohibiting the possession or disposition of assault weapons, and who, on or after the effective date of this local law, shall possess an assault weapon, shall, within ninety days of the effective date of rules promulgated by the commissioner pursuant to subparagraph 7 of paragraph a of subdivision 16 of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-301" destination-id="0-0-0-817">10-301</LINK>, either:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6988" number="9361" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>peaceably surrender his or her assault weapon pursuant to subdivision f of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-305" destination-id="0-0-0-2413">10-305</LINK> for the purpose of destruction of such weapon by the commissioner, provided that the commissioner may authorize the use of such weapon by the department; or </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6989" number="9362" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>lawfully remove such assault weapon from the city of New York. All assault weapons possessed by such permittees, licensees and previously exempt persons shall be subject to the provisions of this subdivision, whether defined as assault weapons in subdivision 16 of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-301" destination-id="0-0-0-817">10-301</LINK> or in rules promulgated by the commissioner pursuant to subparagraph 7 of paragraph a of subdivision 16 of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-301" destination-id="0-0-0-817">10-301</LINK>.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6990" number="9363" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Disposition of assault weapons by non-permittees.</CHARFORMAT> Any person who, on or after the effective date of this local law, shall possess an assault weapon and who is not the holder of a valid permit for possession and purchase of rifles and shotguns and a certificate of registration for such assault weapon, shall peaceably surrender his or her assault weapon pursuant to subdivision f of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-305" destination-id="0-0-0-2413">10-305</LINK> for the purpose of destruction of such weapon by the commissioner, provided that the commissioner may authorize the use of such weapon by the department, and provided further that heirs and legatees may dispose of assault weapons pursuant to subdivision f of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6991" number="9364" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Disposition of assault weapons by heirs and legatees.</CHARFORMAT> Any person who acquires an assault weapon on or after the effective date of this local law by the laws of intestacy or by testamentary bequest shall, within ninety days of such acquisition, either: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6992" number="9365" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>peaceably surrender such assault weapon pursuant to subdivision f of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-305" destination-id="0-0-0-2413">10-305</LINK> for the purpose of destruction of such weapon by the commissioner, provided that the commissioner may authorize the use of such weapon by the department; or </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6993" number="9366" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>lawfully remove such assault weapon from the city of New York.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6994" number="9367" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within thirty days of the effective date of rules promulgated by the commissioner pursuant to subparagraph 7 of paragraph a of subdivision 16 of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-301" destination-id="0-0-0-817">10-301</LINK>, the commissioner shall send by regular mail to every person who has been issued a permit to possess a rifle or shotgun and whose rifle or shotgun the commissioner reasonably believes to be an assault weapon as defined in subdivision 16 of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-301" destination-id="0-0-0-817">10-301</LINK> or as defined in such rules, a written notice setting forth the requirements and procedures relating to the disposition of such weapons, and the criminal and civil penalties that may be imposed upon the permittee for unlawful possession or disposition of such weapons. Failure by the commissioner to send, or the permittee to receive, such notice, shall not excuse such permittee for unlawful possession or disposition of such weapons.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6995" number="9368" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Surrender of firearms.</CHARFORMAT> At the discretion of the police commissioner, any person convicted of violating this section may be subject to immediate surrender of all firearms in his or her possession. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6996" number="9369" version="1677">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1991/078" destination-id="0-0-0-26668">L.L. 1991/078</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1995/076" destination-id="0-0-0-26152">L.L. 1995/076</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-216696" number="9370" version="1597">
										<HEADING>§ 10-303.2 Civil penalty; firearms dealers and manufacturers. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2547" name="10-303.2"/>§ 10-303.2 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Civil penalty; firearms dealers and manufacturers. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6997" number="9371" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> For purposes of this section, the terms &quot;firearm,&quot; &quot;handgun,&quot; &quot;dealer,&quot; &quot;collector,&quot; and &quot;manufacturer&quot; shall have the meanings set forth in 18 U.S.C. § 921, as such section may be amended from time to time, or any successor provision thereto. The term &quot;transfer&quot; shall be deemed to include any sale, assignment, pledge, lease, loan, gift or other disposition. References to &quot;statutes, laws or regulations&quot; shall be deemed to include federal, state and local statutes, laws, local laws, ordinances, rules and regulations.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6998" number="9372" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Manufacturer and Dealer Liability.</CHARFORMAT> A manufacturer or dealer shall be liable for any injury or death caused by a firearm that it has transferred, if (i) such injury or death results from the use of such firearm by an individual not authorized by law to possess such firearm in the city of New York, and (ii) such manufacturer or dealer, or any other individual or entity acting subsequent to such manufacturer or dealer, unlawfully transferred such firearm at any time prior to such injury or death. Such liability also includes the possible imposition of punitive damages. Liability under this section does not extend to any manufacturer or dealer that has complied with the following standards during a period of one year immediately preceding and including the transfer of such firearm:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-6999" number="9373" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The manufacturer or dealer executes no transfers or agreements to transfer at gun shows except for gun shows that maintain a practice of performing instant criminal background checks consistent with 18 U.S.C. § 922 (t), as such subsection may be amended from time to time and any successor provision thereto, on all transfers, whether by licensed or unlicensed sellers.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7000" number="9374" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any place of business operated by the manufacturer or dealer is located at a fixed address where:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7001" number="9375" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a record is maintained, as may be required by any statute, law or regulation, of the make, model, caliber or gauge, and serial number of all firearms held in inventory or offered for sale; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7002" number="9376" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a record is maintained, as may be required by any statute, law or regulation, of the make, model, caliber or gauge, and serial number of all firearms sold, and of any identifying information required by any such statute, law or regulation to be obtained from purchasers;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7003" number="9377" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The manufacturer or dealer provides access to the aforementioned records to officers, employees and agents of public agencies conducting inspections, to the full extent required by applicable statutes, laws and regulations;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7004" number="9378" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The manufacturer or dealer limits transfers to any individual or entity to one handgun in any given thirty-day period, provided that this paragraph shall not apply to lawful transfers to (a) public agencies in furtherance of official business; (b) law enforcement officers employed by public agencies; (c) private security firms, holding any permits or licenses required by applicable statutes, laws and regulations, for the use of their agents and employees; (d) private operators of state and local correctional facilities, for the use of their agents and employees; or (e) licensed manufacturers, licensed dealers or licensed collectors, as those terms are defined by 18 U.S.C. § 921, as such section may be amended from time to time, or any successor provision thereto;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7005" number="9379" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The manufacturer or dealer has complied with all applicable statutes, laws and regulations governing the transfer of firearms; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7006" number="9380" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The manufacturer or dealer has not transferred a firearm to any other manufacturer or dealer in circumstances in which the manufacturer or dealer transferring such firearm knew or should have known that such manufacturer or dealer had not complied with the standards set forth in this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7007" number="9381" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Exceptions.</CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7008" number="9382" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No action may be commenced pursuant to this section by any person injured or killed by the discharge of a firearm that is lawfully possessed by a law enforcement official employed by a public agency.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7009" number="9383" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section shall not limit in scope any cause of action, other than that provided by this section, available to a person injured by or killed by a firearm.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7010" number="9384" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing in this section shall prevent a manufacturer or dealer from seeking whole or partial indemnity or contribution for any liability incurred under this section from any third party wholly or partially responsible for the injury or death.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7011" number="9385" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision b, there shall be no basis for liability under this section if the manufacturer or dealer proves by a preponderance of the evidence that: (i) the person injured or killed by the discharge of a firearm was committing or attempting to commit a crime (whether or not such crime is actually charged); (ii) the unlawful transfer or possession of the firearm is solely a result of the failure of the owner of the firearm to renew a license, permit or registration within six months of the date such renewal is required; or (iii) prior to the injury or death caused by the firearm, a lawful possessor of the firearm has reported its theft to a federal, state or local law enforcement agency, or reported its loss to an appropriate public agency.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7012" number="9386" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision b, there shall be no basis for liability under this section if the manufacturer or dealer proves by a preponderance of the evidence that the manufacturer or dealer lawfully transferred the firearm to: (i) a public agency in furtherance of official business; (ii) a law enforcement officer employed by a public agency; (iii) a private security firm, holding any permits or licenses required by applicable statutes, laws and regulations, for the use of its agents and employees; or (iv) a private operator of a state or local correctional facility for the use of its agents and employees.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7013" number="9387" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision b, there shall be no basis for liability under this section if the manufacturer or dealer proves by a preponderance of the evidence that the injury or death is not directly or indirectly related to any act or omission by such manufacturer or dealer, including but not limited to any failure by the manufacturer or dealer to comply with the standards set forth in subdivision b of this section. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7014" number="9388" version="1474">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2005/007" destination-id="0-0-0-25240">L.L. 2005/007</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-210079" number="9389" version="1474">
										<HEADING>§ 10-304 Certificates of registration. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2549" name="10-304"/>§ 10-304 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Certificates of registration. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7015" number="9390" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any person to have in his or her possession any rifle or shotgun unless said person is the holder of a certificate of registration for such rifle or shotgun.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7016" number="9391" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any person who is not a licensed dealer to dispose of any rifle or shotgun for which such person does not have a certificate of registration unless such person files with the police commissioner a declaration in duplicate, signed and affirmed by the declarant which shall list by caliber, make, model, manufacturer&apos;s name and serial number, or if none, any other distinguishing number or identification mark, of each rifle and shotgun possessed by the declarant. Upon receipt of acknowledgement of said declaration by the police commissioner, the declarant may lawfully sell, transfer, or otherwise dispose of such rifles or shotguns to a licensed dealer or any other person legally permitted to purchase or take possession of such rifles or shotguns. Any willful or material omission or false statement shall be a violation of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7017" number="9392" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Exhibition of certificate.</CHARFORMAT> Every person carrying a rifle or shotgun shall have on his or her person a certificate of registration valid for such weapon. Upon demand, the appropriate certificate shall be exhibited for inspection to any peace officer or police officer. Failure of any person to so exhibit his or her certificate shall be presumptive evidence that he or she is not duly authorized to possess such rifle or shotgun and may be considered by the police commissioner as cause for revocation or suspension of such person&apos;s permit.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7018" number="9393" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Revocation.</CHARFORMAT> The revocation of a rifle or shotgun permit shall automatically be deemed to be a revocation of all certificates of registration for rifles and shotguns held by the person whose permit has been revoked.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7019" number="9394" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Disposition of rifles and shotguns.</CHARFORMAT> No person lawfully in possession of a rifle or shotgun shall dispose of same except to a licensed dealer in firearms, licensed dealer in rifles and shotguns, the holder of a valid rifle and shotgun permit, an exempt person as enumerated in this chapter, or a non-resident of the city of New York not subject to the permit requirements of this chapter. Any person so disposing of a rifle or shotgun shall report the disposition on forms provided by the commissioner setting forth the rifle and shotgun permit number of both seller and purchaser, the make, caliber, type, model and serial number, if any, and if the seller is a licensed dealer the certificate of registration number, of all such rifles and shotguns. Such form shall be signed by both seller and purchaser and the original shall be forwarded to the police commissioner within seventytwo hours of the disposition, one copy shall be retained by the seller, another by the purchaser.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7020" number="9395" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the seller is a licensed dealer, he or she shall at the time of the sale issue a certificate of registration to the purchaser provided to the dealer for that purpose by the police commissioner and shall forward to the police commissioner the duplicate thereof, together with the report of disposition.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7021" number="9396" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the seller is not a licensed dealer, the police commissioner shall, if the purchaser&apos;s rifle permit is valid, issue the certificate of registration within ten days of the receipt by the police commissioner of the report of disposition. Pending receipt of the certificate, but in no event for any longer than fourteen days from the date of purchase, the copy of the report of disposition shall serve in lieu of the purchaser&apos;s certificate of registration.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7022" number="9397" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No fee shall be charged for a certificate of registration.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7023" number="9398" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section concerning the transfer, receipt, acquisition, or any other disposition of a rifle or shotgun, a rifle and shotgun permit shall not be required for the passing of a rifle or shotgun upon the death of an owner, to his or her heir or legatee, whether the same be by testamentary bequest or by the laws of intestacy, except that the person who shall so receive or acquire said rifle or shotgun shall be subject to all other provisions of this chapter, provided further that if the heir or legatee of the owner of such rifle or shotgun does not qualify to possess same under this chapter, the rifle or shotgun may be possessed by the heir or legatee for the purpose of sale as otherwise provided herein for a period not exceeding one hundred eighty days or for such further limited period beyond the one hundred eighty days as may be approved by the commissioner, said extensions in no event to exceed a total of ninety days. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7024" number="9399" version="1664">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1991/078" destination-id="0-0-0-26668">L.L. 1991/078</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-219630" number="9400" version="1664">
										<HEADING>§ 10-305 Exemptions. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2413" name="10-305"/>§ 10-305 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Exemptions. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7025" number="9401" version="3">
											<PARA>The sections requiring rifle and shotgun permits and certificates and prohibiting the possession or disposition of assault weapons shall not apply as follows:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7026" number="9402" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Minors.</CHARFORMAT> Any person under the age of twenty-one years may carry, fire, or use any rifle or shotgun in the actual presence or under the direct supervision of any person who is a holder of a rifle or shotgun permit, or for the purpose of military drill under the auspices of a legally recognized organization and under competent supervision or for the purpose of competition or target practice in and upon a firing range approved by the police commissioner or any other governmental agency authorized to provide such approval, or the national rifle association, which is under competent supervision at the time of such competition or target practice, provided that the rifle or shotgun is otherwise properly registered or exempt from registration by virtue of some other provision of this chapter. This exemption shall not apply to assault weapons.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7027" number="9403" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Antiques and ornaments.</CHARFORMAT> The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to antique rifles and shotguns which are incapable of being fired or discharged or which do not fire fixed ammunition, or those weapons manufactured prior to eighteen hundred ninety-four and those weapons whose design was patented and whose commercial manufacture commenced prior to eighteen hundred ninety-four and whose manufacture continued after eighteen hundred ninety-four without any substantial alteration in design or function, and for which cartridge ammunition is not commercially available and are possessed as curiosities or ornaments or for their historical significance and value. This exemption shall not apply to assault weapons.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7028" number="9404" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Persons in the military service in the state of New York, when duly authorized by regulations issued by the chief of staff to the governor to possess the same, and police officers, provided that such police officers shall not be exempt from the sections prohibiting the possession or disposition of assault weapons except during the performance of their duties as police officers, and other peace officers as defined in section 2.10 of the criminal procedure law, provided that such peace officers (1) are authorized pursuant to law or regulation of the state or city of New York to possess either (a) a firearm within the city of New York without a license or permit therefor, or (b) a rifle, shotgun or assault weapon within the city of New York without a permit therefor; and (2) are authorized by their employer to possess such rifle, shotgun or assault weapon; and (3) shall not possess such rifle, shotgun or assault weapon except during the performance of their duties as peace officers.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7029" number="9405" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Persons in the military or other service of the United States, in pursuit of official duty or when duly authorized by federal law, regulation or order to possess the same.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7030" number="9406" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Persons employed in fulfilling defense contracts with the government of the United States or agencies thereof when possession of the same is necessary for manufacture, transport, installation and testing under the requirements of such contract. Any such person exempted by subdivisions c, d and e above, may purchase a rifle or shotgun only from a licensed dealer, and must submit to the dealer full and clear proof of identification, including shield number, serial number, military or governmental order or authorization, and military or other official identification. Any dealer who disposes of a rifle or shotgun to any exempt person without securing such identification shall be in violation of these sections.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7031" number="9407" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A person may voluntarily surrender a rifle, shotgun or assault weapon to the police commissioner, provided, that the same shall be surrendered by such person only after he or she gives notice in writing to the police commissioner, stating such person&apos;s name, address, the type of gun to be surrendered, and the approximate time of day and the place where such surrender shall take place and such time of day and place have been approved in writing by the police commissioner. Nothing in this subdivision shall be construed as granting immunity from prosecution for any crime or offense except that of unlawful possession of such rifle, shotgun or assault weapon.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7032" number="9408" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The regular and ordinary transport of rifles, shotguns or assault weapons as merchandise provided that the person transporting such rifles, shotguns or assault weapons where he or she knows or has reasonable means of ascertaining what such person is transporting, notifies, in writing, the police commissioner of the name and address of the consignee and the place of delivery, and withholds delivery to the consignee for such reasonable period of time designated in writing by the police commissioner as the police commissioner may deem necessary for investigation as to whether the consignee may lawfully receive and possess such rifles, shotguns or assault weapons.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7033" number="9409" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Possession by retail customers for the purpose of firing at duly licensed rifle target concessions at amusement parks, piers, and similar locations provided that the rifles to be so used by firmly chained or affixed to the counter and that the individual rifles are registered by the proprietor and that the proprietor is in possession of a rifle and shotgun permit. This exemption shall not apply to assault weapons.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7034" number="9410" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Non-residents in transit.</CHARFORMAT> Any other provision of this chapter to the contrary notwithstanding, a non-resident of the city of New York who, without a rifle and shotgun permit issued hereunder, enters the city of New York possessing a rifle or shotgun in the course of transit to a destination outside the city of New York, or a non-resident of the city of New York who enters the city of New York possessing an assault weapon in the course of transit to a destination outside the city of New York, shall have a period of twenty-four hours subsequent to such entering to be exempt from penalty under this chapter for the unlawful possession of a rifle, shotgun or assault weapon, provided that such rifle, shotgun or assault weapon shall at all times be unloaded and in a locked case, or locked automobile trunk, and that said non-resident is lawfully in possession of said rifle, shotgun or assault weapon according to the laws of his or her place of residence.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7035" number="9411" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Non-residents purchasing a rifle or shotgun from a licensed dealer.</CHARFORMAT> Any other provision of this chapter notwithstanding, a non-resident of the city of New York may purchase a rifle or shotgun from a licensed dealer provided that he or she presents the dealer with documentary evidence of his or her identity and place of residence, and the rifle or shotgun purchased is either personally delivered to the purchaser or transmitted by the dealer directly to the purchaser&apos;s residence. In the event the purchaser is traveling from the city by rail, ship or plane, the dealer is hereby authorized to deliver such rifle or shotgun at the appropriate terminal to a representative of the railroad, airline or shipping company, for placement aboard such train, plane or ship. If the rifle or shotgun is personally delivered to the non-resident purchaser within the city of New York, the purchaser shall have the rifle or shotgun removed from the city no later than twenty-four hours after the time of purchase. This exemption shall not apply to assault weapons.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7036" number="9412" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>j.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing herein contained shall be construed to be a prohibition of the conduct of business by manufacturers, wholesale dealers, interstate shippers, or any other individuals or firms properly licensed by the federal government, where such prohibition would be preempted by federal law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7037" number="9413" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>k.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Special theatrical permit.</CHARFORMAT> Nothing herein contained is intended to prevent the possession or utilization of any rifle, shotgun or assault weapon during the course of any television, movie, stage or other similar theatrical production, or by a professional photographer in the pursuance of his or her profession, provided however, that the rifle or shotgun so used shall be properly registered and a special theatrical permit shall have been issued for the rifle, shotgun or assault weapon pursuant to rules established by the commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7038" number="9414" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>l.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Persons in possession of, using or transporting rifles which have been issued by the director of civilian marksmanship of the department of the army, pursuant to the provisions of 10 U.S.C. §§ 4307-4309, unto a civilian rifle club, or unto a rifle team representing an educational institution, provided that such persons are members in good standing of an accredited civilian rifle club, or are connected as students or coaches with such educational institution, shall not be required to obtain a certificate of registration for such rifle. This exemption shall not apply to assault weapons.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7039" number="9415" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>m.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any resident of the city of New York acquiring a rifle or shotgun outside the city of New York shall within seventy-two hours after bringing such weapon into the city make application for a rifle and shotgun permit, if such person does not already possess such permit, and for a certificate of registration. Pending the issuance of such permit and/or certificate of registration such resident shall deposit such weapon with a designated officer, at the police precinct in which such person resides, who shall issue a receipt therefor and said weapon shall be retained at the precinct until the resident shall produce the proper permit and registration certificate. This exemption shall not apply to assault weapons.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7040" number="9416" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>n.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-303" destination-id="0-0-0-2411">10-303</LINK> of this chapter shall not apply to persons who are members of units of war veterans organizations, which organizations are duly recognized by the veterans administration, pursuant to 38 U.S.C. § 3402, and who are specifically designated to carry rifles or shotguns by the commanders of said units, while actually participating in, going to or returning from, special events authorized by the commissioner. Said rifles or shotguns, to be carried, must be the property of the unit of the war veterans organization, must be registered with the police commissioner pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-304" destination-id="0-0-0-2549">10-304</LINK> of this chapter and must be kept at the unit&apos;s headquarters or some central place as registered.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7041" number="9417" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>o.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing herein shall exempt a member of a unit of a war veterans organization from possessing a permit issued pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-303" destination-id="0-0-0-2411">10-303</LINK>, to carry rifles or shotguns which are not the property of a war veterans organization; nor shall that member be exempt from registering such rifles or shotguns, pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-304" destination-id="0-0-0-2549">10-304</LINK>, which said member may personally own, possess or purchase.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7042" number="9418" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>p.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any gunsmith licensed pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-302" destination-id="0-0-0-2409">10-302</LINK> may engage in the business of gunsmith as authorized by such license.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7043" number="9419" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>q.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the provisions of this chapter prohibiting the possession or disposition of assault weapons, a special theatrical dealer may possess such weapons exclusively for the purpose of leasing such weapons to special theatrical permittees within the city and for theatrical purposes outside the city and may, in addition, with the written approval of the commissioner, permanently remove one or more assault weapons from the city. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7044" number="9420" version="1664">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1991/078" destination-id="0-0-0-26668">L.L. 1991/078</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-219631" number="9421" version="1664">
										<HEADING>§ 10-306 Disposition, purchase and possession of ammunition and ammunition feeding devices. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2407" name="10-306"/>§ 10-306 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Disposition, purchase and possession of ammunition and ammunition feeding devices. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7045" number="9422" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No person, except a dealer in rifles and shotguns, may dispose of to another person an ammunition feeding device which is designed for use in a rifle or shotgun and which is capable of holding more than five rounds of rifle or shotgun ammunition, except in the manner provided in this chapter for the disposition of assault weapons, provided that a person in lawful possession of such ammunition feeding devices may dispose of such ammunition feeding devices to a dealer in rifles and shotguns. No dealer in rifles and shotguns may dispose of such ammunition feeding devices except to a person who is exempt from subdivision a of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-303.1" destination-id="0-0-0-2541">10-303.1</LINK> pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-305" destination-id="0-0-0-2413">10-305</LINK>.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7046" number="9423" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No person may possess an ammunition feeding device which is designed for use in a rifle or shotgun and which is capable of holding more than five rounds of rifle or shotgun ammunition, unless such person is exempt from subdivision a of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-303.1" destination-id="0-0-0-2541">10-303.1</LINK> pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-305" destination-id="0-0-0-2413">10-305</LINK>, provided that a dealer in rifles and shotguns may possess such ammunition feeding devices for the purpose of disposition authorized pursuant to subdivision a of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7047" number="9424" version="1767">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No ammunition suitable for use in a rifle of any caliber or for any shotgun or ammunition feeding device which is designed for use in a rifle or shotgun and which is capable of holding no more than five rounds of rifle or shotgun ammunition shall be disposed of to any person who has not been issued a rifle and shotgun permit and a certificate of registration and who does not exhibit same to the dealer at the time of the purchase. In no event shall rifle or shotgun ammunition be disposed of to or possessed by any such person except for a shotgun, or for the specific caliber of rifle, for which the certificate of registration has been issued. No ammunition feeding device which is designed for use in a rifle or shotgun and which is capable of holding more than five rounds of rifle or shotgun ammunition shall be disposed of by a dealer in rifles and shotguns to any person who does not exhibit proof that he or she is exempt from subdivision a of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-303.1" destination-id="0-0-0-2541">10-303.1</LINK> pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-305" destination-id="0-0-0-2413">10-305</LINK>.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7048" number="9425" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any person who is required to have a permit in order to possess a rifle or shotgun and who has not been issued such permit to possess rifle or shotgun ammunition or an ammunition feeding device which is designed for use in a rifle or shotgun.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7049" number="9426" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A record shall be kept by the dealer of each disposition of ammunition or ammunition feeding devices under this section which shall show the type, caliber and quantity of ammunition or ammunition feeding devices disposed of, the name and address of the person receiving same, the caliber, make, model, manufacturer&apos;s name and serial number of the rifle or shotgun for which the purchaser is purchasing ammunition, the date and time of the transaction, and the number of the permit and certificate exhibited or description of the proof of exemption exhibited as required by this section. Such information shall be made available to all law enforcement agencies.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7050" number="9427" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, ammunition and ammunition feeding devices which are designed for use in rifles or shotguns and which are capable of holding no more than five rounds of rifle or shotgun ammunition may be disposed of or possessed in the same manner and pursuant to the same requirements, rules and exemptions as apply to disposal or possession of rifles, shotguns or assault weapons under this chapter, provided that a special theatrical permittee may not possess live ammunition suitable for use in the rifle, shotgun or assault weapon such permittee is authorized to possess. Ammunition feeding devices which are designed for use in rifles or shotguns and which are capable of holding more than five rounds of rifle or shotgun ammunition may only be disposed of or possessed in the manner provided in this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7051" number="9428" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, any person authorized to possess a pistol or revolver within the city of New York may possess ammunition suitable for use in such pistol or revolver and a dealer in firearms or dealer in rifles and shotguns may dispose of such ammunition to such person pursuant to subdivision i of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-131" destination-id="0-0-0-2401">10-131</LINK>.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7052" number="9429" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Dealers in rifles and shotguns and special theatrical dealers may lease ammunition feeding devices which are designed for use in rifles or shotguns to special theatrical permittees. Special theatrical permittees may possess such ammunition feeding devices subject to the same conditions as apply with respect to such permittee&apos;s possession of rifles, shotguns and assault weapons. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7053" number="9430" version="1664">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1991/078" destination-id="0-0-0-26668">L.L. 1991/078</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-219632" number="9431" version="1664">
										<HEADING>§ 10-307 Supply of forms. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2551" name="10-307"/>§ 10-307 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Supply of forms. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7054" number="9432" version="3">
											<PARA>The commissioner shall provide all dealers in rifles and shotguns with adequate supplies of all forms including applications for permits as required by this chapter, without charge.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-7055" number="9433" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 10-308 Vehicles, rooms, dwellings or structures; possession therein. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2553" name="10-308"/>§ 10-308 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Vehicles, rooms, dwellings or structures; possession therein. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7056" number="9434" version="3">
											<PARA>The presence of a rifle, or shotgun, or rifle or shotgun ammunition, in a vehicle, room, dwelling or structure, without a rifle and shotgun permit therefor and a certificate of registration therefor, or the presence of an assault weapon in a vehicle, room, dwelling or structure, shall be presumptive evidence of possession thereof by all persons occupying the vehicle, room, dwelling or structure at the time. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7057" number="9435" version="1664">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1991/078" destination-id="0-0-0-26668">L.L. 1991/078</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-219633" number="9436" version="1664">
										<HEADING>§ 10-309 Identifying marks. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2555" name="10-309"/>§ 10-309 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Identifying marks. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7058" number="9437" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Defacing. Any person who alters, changes, removes, disfigures, obliterates or defaces the name of the maker, model, manufacturer&apos;s or serial number of a rifle, shotgun or assault weapon shall be in violation of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7059" number="9438" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any rifle or shotgun sold or otherwise disposed of by a licensed dealer, which does not contain a manufacturer&apos;s or serial number, must have imbedded into the metal portion of such rifle or shotgun a dealer&apos;s number. Failure to so mark and identify any rifle or shotgun shall be a violation of this section. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7060" number="9439" version="1664">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1991/078" destination-id="0-0-0-26668">L.L. 1991/078</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-219634" number="9440" version="1664">
										<HEADING>§ 10-310 Violation. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2543" name="10-310"/>§ 10-310 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Violation. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7061" number="9441" version="3">
											<PARA>Except as is otherwise provided in sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-302" destination-id="0-0-0-2409">10-302</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-303.1" destination-id="0-0-0-2541">10-303.1</LINK>, violation of sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-301" destination-id="0-0-0-817">10-301</LINK> through <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-309" destination-id="0-0-0-2555">10-309</LINK> and of rules and regulations issued by the commissioner pursuant thereto shall be a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of not more than one thousand dollars or imprisonment of not more than one year or both, provided that the first violation of such sections involving possession of an unregistered rifle or shotgun or rifle or shotgun ammunition or an ammunition feeding device which is designed for use in a rifle or shotgun and which is capable of holding no more than five rounds of rifle or shotgun ammunition shall be an offense punishable by a fine of not more than three hundred dollars or imprisonment of not more than fifteen days, or both on condition that (a) the first violation of possession of an unregistered rifle and shotgun or rifle and shotgun ammunition or an ammunition feeding device which is designed for use in a rifle or shotgun and which is capable of holding no more than five rounds of rifle or shotgun ammunition is not in conjunction with the commission of a crime and (b) the possessor has not been previously convicted of a felony or a serious offense and (c) the possessor has not previously applied for and been denied a permit for such possession.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7062" number="9442" version="2278">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1991/078" destination-id="0-0-0-26668">L.L. 1991/078</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1995/076" destination-id="0-0-0-26152">L.L. 1995/076</LINK>, and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2006/031" destination-id="0-0-0-25074">L.L. 2006/031</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-208352" number="9443" version="1450">
										<HEADING>§ 10-311 Sale of weapons without safety locking device prohibited. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2557" name="10-311"/>§ 10-311 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Sale of weapons without safety locking device prohibited. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7063" number="9444" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any person or business enterprise to dispose of any weapon which does not contain a safety locking device. For the purposes of this section and section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-312" destination-id="0-0-0-2559">10-312</LINK>: (1) weapon shall mean a firearm, rifle, shotgun, or assault weapon, as such terms are defined in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-301" destination-id="0-0-0-817">10-301</LINK>; or a machine gun, as defined in the penal law; and (2) a safety locking device shall mean a design adaptation or attachable accessory that will prevent the use of the weapon by an unauthorized user, and includes, but is not limited to, a trigger lock, which prevents the pulling of the trigger without the use of a key, or a combination handle, which prevents the use of the weapon without the alignment of the combination tumblers.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7064" number="9445" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any licensed manufacturer, licensed importer, or licensed dealer to dispose of any weapon in the city of New York unless it is accompanied by the following warning, which shall appear in conspicuous and legible type in capital letters, and which shall be printed on a label affixed to the weapon and on a separate sheet of paper included within the packaging enclosing the weapon: &quot;THE USE OF A LOCKING DEVICE OR SAFETY LOCK IS ONLY ONE ASPECT OF RESPONSIBLE WEAPON STORAGE. ALL WEAPONS SHOULD BE STORED UNLOADED AND LOCKED IN A LOCATION THAT IS BOTH SEPARATE FROM THEIR AMMUNITION AND INACCESSIBLE TO CHILDREN AND ANY OTHER UNAUTHORIZED PERSONS. NEW YORK CITY LAW PROHIBITS, WITH CERTAIN EXCEPTIONS, ANY PERSON FROM ACQUIRING MORE THAN ONE FIREARM, OR MORE THAN ONE RIFLE OR SHOTGUN, WITHIN A 90-DAY PERIOD.&quot;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7065" number="9446" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who applies for and obtains authorization to purchase a weapon or otherwise lawfully obtains a weapon pursuant to chapters one or three of title ten of this code shall be required to purchase or obtain a safety locking device at the time he or she purchases or obtains the weapon.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7066" number="9447" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The police commissioner is authorized to promulgate rules setting forth the types of safety locking devices which will comply with this section in accordance with subdivision a of this section. The city of New York and its agencies, officers or employees shall not be liable to any party by reason of any incident involving, or the use or misuse of, a safety locking device that may have been purchased in compliance with such rules promulgated by the commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7067" number="9448" version="1056">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The police commissioner shall provide written notice of the requirements of this section and section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-312" destination-id="0-0-0-2559">10-312</LINK> to all persons who receive an official authorization to purchase a weapon and all persons applying for renewal of a license or permit issued pursuant to chapters one or three of title ten, including any rules promulgated under this subdivision. All persons applying for a license or permit or applying for the renewal of a license or permit pursuant to chapters one or three of title ten of this code, shall receive from the commissioner information concerning the importance of using a safety locking device while a weapon is not in use, and a warning that weapons should be stored unloaded and locked in a location that is both separate from their ammunition and inaccessible to children and any other unauthorized persons. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7068" number="9449" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any violation of subdivisions a or b of this section or any rule promulgated thereunder shall be a misdemeanor and triable by a judge of the criminal court of the city of New York and punishable by imprisonment of not more than thirty days or by a fine of not more than five hundred dollars, or both. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7069" number="9450" version="1450">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2006/031" destination-id="0-0-0-25074">L.L. 2006/031</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-208351" number="9451" version="1450">
										<HEADING>§ 10-312 Use of safety locking device required under certain circumstances. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2559" name="10-312"/>§ 10-312 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Use of safety locking device required under certain circumstances. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7070" number="9452" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any person who is the lawful owner or lawful custodian of a weapon, as that term is defined in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="10-311" destination-id="0-0-0-2557">10-311</LINK>, to store or otherwise place or leave such weapon in such a manner or under circumstances that it is out of his or her immediate possession or control, without having rendered such weapon inoperable by employing a safety locking device. Any person who violates this subdivision shall be guilty of a violation, punishable by imprisonment of not more than ten days or by a fine of not more than two hundred fifty dollars, or both.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7071" number="9453" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who violates subdivision a of this section having previously been found guilty of a violation of such subdivision, or under circumstances which create a substantial risk of physical injury to another person, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor punishable by imprisonment of not more than thirty days or by a fine of not more than one thousand dollars, or both.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7072" number="9454" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of this section shall not apply to weapons owned or lawfully possessed by a police officer, as such term is defined in section 1.20 of the criminal procedure law, or a federal law enforcement officer, as such term is defined in section 2.15 of the criminal procedure law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-7073" number="9455" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 10-313 Mandatory disclosure of gun violence information.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2561" name="10-313"/>§ 10-313 Mandatory disclosure of gun violence information.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7074" number="9456" version="2268">
											<PARA style-name="EdNote" style-name-escaped="EdNote" style-id="0-0-0-17">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note: </CHARFORMAT>this section has been amended by <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-24" type="Web" url="https://legistar.council.nyc.gov/LegislationDetail.aspx?ID=6860165&amp;GUID=B5563DB0-5EEE-46C8-9FEC-D46418D8EE01&amp;Options=ID%7cText%7c&amp;Search=">L.L. 2025/164, 11/28/2025, eff. 6/26/2026</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-116]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235439" number="9457" version="2268">
											<PARA>Prior to issuing a license or permit for possession of a firearm, the department must provide applicants with the following statement in printed form:&quot;Warning: The presence of a firearm in the home is associated with an increased risk of suicide, death during domestic violence disputes, and unintentional deaths to children and others.&quot; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-7075" number="9458" version="3">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2017/236, 12/1/2017, eff. 3/31/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-020]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-7076" number="9459" version="214">
										<HEADING>§ 10-314 Prohibition on unfinished frames or receivers.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-19329" name="10-314"/>§ 10-314 Prohibition on unfinished frames or receivers.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113559" number="9460" version="214">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Restriction of possession.</CHARFORMAT> Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, no person shall dispose of or possess an unfinished frame or receiver. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113558" number="9461" version="214">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Penalties.</CHARFORMAT> The violation of this section constitutes a class A misdemeanor for each prohibited item disposed of or possessed. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113557" number="9462" version="1241">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2019/187, 10/26/2019, eff. 2/23/2020) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-043]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-155263" number="9463" version="1241">
										<HEADING>§ 10-315 Times Square sensitive location zone.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-22666" name="10-315"/>§ 10-315 Times Square sensitive location zone.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155266" number="9464" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the purposes of paragraph (t) of subdivision 2 of section 265.01-e of the penal law, the area commonly known as Times Square means and includes the following tract in Manhattan, bounded and described as follows: (i) BEGINNING at the point of intersection of the north side of West Forty-eighth Street and the west side of Ninth Avenue; (ii) thence southerly along the west side of Ninth Avenue to the point of intersection where the west side of Ninth Avenue meets the south side of West Fortieth Street; (iii) thence easterly along the south side of West Fortieth Street to the point of intersection where the south side of West Fortieth Street meets the east side of Sixth Avenue; (iv) thence northerly along the east side of Sixth Avenue to the point of intersection where the east side of Sixth Avenue meets the north side of West Fifty-third Street; (v) thence westerly along the northern side of West Fifty-third Street to the point of intersection where the north side of West Fifty-third Street meets the west side of Eighth Avenue; (vi) thence southerly along the west side of Eighth Avenue to the point of intersection where the west side of Eighth Avenue meets the north side of West Forty-eighth Street; and (vii) thence westerly along the north side of West Forty-eighth Street until the point of intersection where the north side of West Forty-eighth Street meets the west side of Ninth Avenue (the point of beginning). Where the area described in this subdivision is bounded and described by a side of a street or avenue, it shall be deemed to include the sidewalk of such side. For the purposes of paragraph (t) of subdivision 2 of section 265.01-e of the penal law, the area commonly known as Times Square does not include the interior of any building or other enclosed structure; provided, however, that such a building or structure may otherwise constitute a restricted or sensitive location pursuant to section 265.01-d or 265.01-e of the penal law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155265" number="9465" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The police department shall promulgate such rules as may be necessary to implement subdivision a of this section in accordance with applicable law, including rules applicable, as appropriate, to persons with a firearms license who live or work in the area commonly known as Times Square as described in such subdivision. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155264" number="9466" version="1241">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2022/091, 10/11/2022, eff. 10/11/2022) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-155267" number="9467" version="1241">
										<HEADING>§ 10-316 Firearm trafficking report.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-22668" name="10-316"/>§ 10-316 Firearm trafficking report.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155291" number="9468" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The mayor&apos;s office of criminal justice shall coordinate with the police department to conduct a study on reducing the flow of firearms into the city and shall submit a report to the mayor and the speaker of the council no later than December 1, 2022, and annually thereafter. Such study and report shall include the following information for the preceding calendar year: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155290" number="9469" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each firearm seized or surrendered in the city and obtained by the police department: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155289" number="9470" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whether the firearm was connected to a crime; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155288" number="9471" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where the firearm originated, including where it was first sold, manufactured, imported or assembled; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155287" number="9472" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The date such firearm was seized or surrendered and the date such firearm was last sold legally; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155286" number="9473" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The location of such seizure, including latitude and longitude if available, but in all cases at least as specific as the nearest intersection; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155285" number="9474" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The type of such firearm; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155284" number="9475" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The manufacturer or importer of such firearm; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155283" number="9476" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whether the firearm was a ghost gun or a firearm created using a three-dimensional printer, and if so, the entities that produced such firearm or parts thereof; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155282" number="9477" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The dealer of such firearm and whether such dealer was licensed; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155281" number="9478" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whether the firearm was registered in any registry, including the national firearms registration and transfer record. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155280" number="9479" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A review of the ways firearms are illegally transported into the city, including through roadways on and connected to interstate 95 and sea ports or bodies of water; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155279" number="9480" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A review of the ways states and municipalities collaborate to prevent illegal transportation of firearms, and recommendations to strengthen such collaboration, including: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155278" number="9481" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Recommendations for strengthening collaboration between the mayor&apos;s office of criminal justice, the police department, the bureau of alcohol, tobacco, firearms and explosives and other relevant state and federal agencies; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155277" number="9482" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Recommendations for strengthening law enforcement&apos;s ability to trace firearms, including whether increased microstamping would be feasible and effective; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155276" number="9483" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Recommendations for implementing a shared electronic tracking system to identify dealers who have sold a particular firearm; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155275" number="9484" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Examining the value of establishing a firearm dealer code of conduct, including recommendations for provisions that should be included in such dealer code of conduct; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155274" number="9485" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Recommendations for policies to prevent access to firearms by individuals who are likely to harm themselves or others; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155273" number="9486" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Recommendations for youth-related programs to discourage the use of firearms by minors; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155272" number="9487" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Recommendations for crime prevention through environmental design improvements, including additional lighting in public spaces; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155271" number="9488" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Impediments to reporting additional relevant data related to illegal firearms, including any legal restrictions on such reporting or the use of such data for such reporting. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155270" number="9489" version="1241">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Limitations on disclosure.</CHARFORMAT> If disclosure of any information specified in paragraph one of subdivision a of this section is prohibited by law, such study and report shall identify the information being withheld and the reason therefor, and shall, instead of such withheld information, include aggregate data to the extent available. Such study and report need not include information about any firearm obtained through a gun buy-back program or where disclosure would compromise the safety of the public or police officers or could otherwise compromise law enforcement investigations or operations. Such report shall include the total number of seizures for which reporting was withheld due to a pending criminal investigation, and upon completion of such investigations the information relating to such seizures shall be reflected in a subsequent report. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-155268" number="9490" version="1241">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2022/090, 10/11/2022, eff. 10/11/2022) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-078]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>