<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-130849" number="51138" version="804">
			<HEADING>Chapter 6: Rebates of Charges for Energy</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10073" name="T22C006"/>Chapter 6: Rebates of Charges for Energy</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-39853" number="51139" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 22-601 Definitions. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10075" name="22-601"/>§ 22-601 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39854" number="51140" version="3">
											<PARA>When used in this chapter the following terms shall have the following meanings: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39855" number="51141" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Commercial development pressure areas.&quot;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39856" number="51142" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The area delineated by a line beginning at the point of intersection of the Manhattan, Queens and Brooklyn borough lines and running easterly along the Queens borough line to the center line of Greenpoint Avenue; thence easterly along the center line of Greenpoint Avenue to the center line of Review Avenue; thence northerly along the center line of Review Avenue to the center line of Borden Avenue; thence easterly along the center line of Borden Avenue to the center line of Van Dam Street; thence northerly along the center line of Van Dam Street to the center line of Skillman Avenue; thence easterly along the center line of Skillman Avenue to the center line of Honeywell Street; thence northerly along the center line of Honeywell Street to the center line of Northern Boulevard; thence southwesterly along the center line of Northern Boulevard to the center line of Fortieth Road; thence westerly along the center line of Fortieth Road to the center line of Twenty-ninth Street; thence southerly along the center line of Twenty-ninth Street to the center line of Forty-first Avenue; thence westerly along the center line of Forty-first Avenue to the Queens borough line; thence southerly along the Queens borough line to the point of beginning; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39857" number="51143" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The area delineated by a line beginning at the point of intersection of the Brooklyn borough line and the center line of Fulton Street and running southerly along the center line of Fulton Street to the center line of Prospect Street; thence easterly along the center line of Prospect Street to the center line of Adams Street; thence southerly along the center line of Adams Street to the center line of Tillary Street; thence easterly along the center line of Tillary Street to the center line of Duffield Street; thence northerly along the center line of Duffield Street to the Brooklyn borough line; thence westerly along the Brooklyn borough line to the point of beginning.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39858" number="51144" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Eligible areas.&quot; All areas of the city except (i) with respect to a person relocating therefrom, those designated as commercial development pressure areas in subdivision (a) of this section, and (ii) the area lying south of the center line of 96th Street, in the borough of Manhattan.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39859" number="51145" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Eligible charges&quot;, &quot;eligible public utility service charges&quot; and &quot;eligible on-site cogenerator charges&quot;. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39860" number="51146" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Eligible charges are charges for energy services purchased from a utility or from a vendor of energy services at a rate or rates established pursuant to an order or rule of the New York state public service commission or the federal energy regulatory commission, other than charges for the purchase of the commodity of natural gas or electricity, and shall include applicable rate reductions for economic development or similar purposes, and all taxes payable thereon and shall exclude charges in accordance with paragraph two of this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39861" number="51147" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Eligible public utility service charges are actual charges for energy services made by a public utility service, and shall include all taxes payable thereon, and shall exclude charges in accordance with paragraph two of this subdivision, provided, however, that the commissioner of small business services may by rule adjust eligible public utility charges for purposes of adjusting the special rebate based thereon to an amount that would be comparable to the special rebate available to a comparable customer of a utility as determined by such commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39862" number="51148" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except as otherwise provided in paragraph five of subdivision (a) of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-602" destination-id="0-0-0-3727">22-602</LINK> of this chapter with respect to eligible on-site cogenerators certified before July first, two thousand three, and clean on-site cogenerators certified after June thirtieth, two thousand three, eligible on-site cogenerator charges are charges for energy services purchased from a utility related to the delivery of natural gas to an on-site cogenerator at rates established pursuant to an order or rule of the New York state public service commission or the federal energy regulatory commission, and shall include applicable rate reductions for economic development or similar purposes, and all taxes payable thereon and shall exclude charges in accordance with paragraph two of this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39863" number="51149" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Eligible charges, eligible public utility service charges, and, except as otherwise provided in paragraph five of subdivision (a) of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-602" destination-id="0-0-0-3727">22-602</LINK> of this chapter with respect to eligible on-site cogenerators certified before July first, two thousand three and clean on-site cogenerators certified after June thirtieth, two thousand three, eligible on-site cogenerator charges shall not include the following charges: (A) any special charges on bills relating to energy services, including, but not limited to, collection charges, late payment charges or excess distribution charges, or any additional fee charged by a vendor of energy services to an eligible energy user, qualified eligible energy user or on-site cogenerator for energy services, as authorized by subdivision (d) of this section; (B) charges for such energy services that are resold; and (C) charges for energy services used for heating the premises.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39864" number="51150" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Eligible charges and eligible public utility service charges shall not include charges for energy services used in the production of electricity.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39865" number="51151" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Eligible on-site cogenerator charges shall not include charges made by a utility for energy services relating to the sale or delivery of natural gas used by an on-site cogenerator to generate electricity used by any user not located on the same site as the on-site cogenerator or by any user for purposes of heating any premises.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39866" number="51152" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Eligible energy user.&quot; Any non-residential user of energy services, except a government agency, public benefit corporation, or instrumentality thereof, hotel, retail vendor or energy intensive facility, as defined in this section, that:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39867" number="51153" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>takes occupancy of non-residential premises after May third, nineteen hundred eighty-five, for which it has, after such date, entered into a written agreement to buy or lease, provided that such premises are located in an eligible area and that such premises are a replacement for premises previously occupied by such energy user for a continuous period of twenty-four months during the thirty-month period immediately preceding such user&apos;s taking occupancy, which previously occupied premises were: (i) outside an eligible area, or (ii) within a commercial development pressure area, provided that such replacement premises are not located in a commercial development pressure area; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39868" number="51154" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>occupies, operates or manages specially eligible premises as defined in this section. Eligible energy users shall not include an occupant of premises contained within a commercial development pressure area that have been used principally for manufacturing activities at any time during the twelve-month period prior to such occupant&apos;s taking occupancy unless such occupant uses such premises principally for manufacturing activities or such user takes occupancy of such premises after June thirtieth, two thousand. In addition, an occupant of premises described in paragraph one or two of this subdivision shall not be an eligible energy user unless: (i) the energy services used and electricity or natural gas consumed by such occupant at such premises are individually and accurately metered and billed so as to enable a determination of the occupant&apos;s usage of energy services, natural gas or electricity; and (ii) for any occupant purchasing energy services, natural gas or electricity from a vendor of energy services, (A) the price charged by such vendor for such energy services, electricity and natural gas shall be no higher than the price that would have been charged such occupant directly by a utility pursuant to the applicable tariffs of the New York state public service commission or the federal energy regulatory commission, provided that an additional fee, not exceeding twelve percent of such price, may be charged by such vendor, and (B) the price, charges, fees (if any) and other terms and conditions for the sale of such energy services, electricity or natural gas to such occupant are clearly and separately set forth in a written contract or lease agreement between such occupant and such vendor, and such vendor shall separately state in each bill for such services, electricity and natural gas the price, charges and fees (if any) that are included in such bill and the amount of the special rebate made to such occupant or that no special rebate has been made.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39869" number="51155" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Hotel.&quot; A building or portion of it which is regularly used and kept open as such for the lodging of guests. The term &quot;hotel&quot; includes an apartment hotel, a motel, boarding house or club, whether or not meals are served.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39870" number="51156" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Manufacturing activity.&quot; An activity involving the assembly of goods to create a different article, the processing or fabrication or packaging of goods.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39871" number="51157" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Discount.&quot; The amount of a reduction in a bill for energy services rendered to a vendor of energy services or a public utility service by a utility in accordance with the requirements of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-602" destination-id="0-0-0-3727">22-602</LINK> of this chapter equal to the special rebates made by such vendor or public utility service to eligible energy users.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39872" number="51158" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Retail Vendor.&quot; Any person, including any corporation or other business entity which is predominantly engaged in the sale, other than through the mail, of tangible personal property to any person, for any purpose unrelated to the trade or business of such person, or which is predominantly engaged in selling services to individuals which services generally involve the physical, mental and/or spiritual care of such individuals, or the physical care of the personal property of such person unrelated to the trade or business of such person, provided however, where such sale of tangible personal property or services is performed only by one or more operating units, divisions or subdivisions of any person, only such operating units, divisions or subdivisions shall come within the definition contained herein.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39873" number="51159" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Specially eligible premises.&quot;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39874" number="51160" version="1570">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Non-residential premises that are wholly contained in property that is eligible to obtain benefits under part four or part five of subchapter two of chapter two of title eleven of this code, or would be eligible to receive benefits under such chapter except that such property is exempt from real property taxation and the requirements of paragraph two of subdivision g of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-259" destination-id="0-0-0-3023">11-259</LINK> of this code, or the requirements of subparagraph (b) of paragraph two of subdivision e of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-270" destination-id="0-0-0-3073">11-270</LINK> of this code, whichever is applicable, have not been satisfied, provided that application for such benefits was made after May third, nineteen hundred eighty-five and prior to July first, two thousand twenty-seven, that construction or renovation of such premises was described in such application, that such premises have been substantially improved by such construction or renovation so described, that the minimum required expenditure as defined in such part four or part five, whichever is applicable, has been made, and that such real property is located in an eligible area; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39875" number="51161" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>non-residential premises that are wholly contained in real property that has obtained approval after May third, nineteen hundred eighty-five and prior to November first, two thousand for financing by the city industrial development agency established pursuant to section nine hundred seventeen of the general municipal law, provided that such financing has been used in whole or in part to substantially improve such premises (by construction or renovation), and that expenditures have been made for improvements to such real property in excess of twenty per centum of the value at which such real property was assessed for tax purposes for the tax year in which such improvements commenced, and that such real property is located in an eligible area; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39876" number="51162" version="1570">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>non-residential premises that are wholly contained in real property that has obtained approval after October thirty-first, two thousand and prior to July first, two thousand twenty-seven for financing by an industrial development agency established pursuant to article eighteen-A of the general municipal law, provided that such financing has been used in whole or in part to substantially improve such premises (by construction or renovation), and that expenditures have been made for improvements to such real property in excess of ten per centum of the value at which such real property was assessed for tax purposes for the tax year in which such improvements commenced, that such expenditures have been made within thirty-six months after the earlier of (i) the issuance by such agency of bonds for such financing, or (ii) the conveyance of title to such property to such agency, and that such real property is located in an eligible area; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39877" number="51163" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>non-residential premises that are wholly contained in real property owned by the city of New York or the New York state urban development corporation, or a subsidiary thereof, a lease for which was approved in accordance with the applicable provisions of the charter and such approval was obtained after May third, nineteen hundred eighty-five and prior to November first, two thousand, provided, however that such premises were constructed or renovated subsequent to such approval, that expenditures have been made subsequent to such approval for improvements to such real property (by construction or renovation) in excess of twenty per centum of the value at which such real property was assessed for tax purposes for the tax year in which such improvements commenced, and that such real property is located in an eligible area; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39878" number="51164" version="1570">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>non-residential premises that are wholly contained in real property owned by such city or the New York state urban development corporation, or a subsidiary thereof, a lease for which was approved in accordance with the applicable provisions of the charter of such city or by the board of directors of such corporation, and such approval was obtained after October thirty-first, two thousand and prior to July first, two thousand twenty-seven, provided, however, that such premises were constructed or renovated subsequent to such approval, that expenditures have been made subsequent to such approval for improvements to such real property (by construction or renovation) in excess of ten per centum of the value at which such real property was assessed for tax purposes for the tax year in which such improvements commenced, that such expenditures have been made within thirty-six months after the effective date of such lease, and that such real property is located in an eligible area; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39879" number="51165" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>non-residential premises contained in real property not located in an eligible area that otherwise meet the criteria of paragraph one, two, three, four or five of this subdivision, where such premises shall be used primarily for manufacturing activities and provided that such premises shall be improved as a result of expenditures in an amount in excess of ten per centum of the assessed value of such real property attributable to such premises at which such real property was assessed for tax purposes for the tax year in which such improvements commenced, except that the required expenditures for improvements to property eligible to obtain benefits under part five of subchapter two of chapter two of title eleven of this code shall be the amount that an applicant must expend on construction work for a project in order to qualify for benefits as provided in such part five. Attribution of value shall be made in accordance with the rules and regulations of the mayor. Only expenditures for improvements that have been identified as part of the construction or reconstruction project meeting the requirements of paragraph one, two, three, four or five of this subdivision, whichever is applicable, shall qualify for purposes of satisfying the minimum expenditure requirements of this subdivision. Notwithstanding the foregoing, for purposes of applying the criteria of this subdivision, the reference to May third, nineteen hundred eighty-five contained in paragraphs one, two and four of this subdivision shall be deemed a reference to May first, nineteen hundred eighty-six.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39880" number="51166" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>provided, however, that no such premises described in paragraph one, two, three, four, five or six of this subdivision, contained in a newly constructed structure or building, shall come within this definition unless such premises meet the requirements of the New York state energy conservation construction code promulgated pursuant to article eleven of the energy law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39881" number="51167" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Special rebate.&quot; The amount of a reduction in a bill rendered by a utility, a public utility service or a vendor of energy services for energy services to an eligible energy user or a qualified eligible energy user, or an agent of either, or an on-site cogenerator or a clean on-site cogenerator; and calculated in accordance with the applicable provisions of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-602" destination-id="0-0-0-3727">22-602</LINK> of this chapter and the rules of the department of small business services.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39882" number="51168" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Vendor of energy services.&quot; Any person, corporation or other entity not subject to the jurisdiction and general supervision of the New York state public service commission that furnishes or sells energy services to an eligible energy user, a qualified eligible energy user or an on-site cogenerator as an incident to leasing, subleasing, licensing or otherwise permitting such user to rent or occupy premises of such vendor.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39883" number="51169" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(l)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Empowerment zone&quot;. Empowerment zone shall mean an area within the city of New York that has been designated as an empowerment zone pursuant to the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39884" number="51170" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(m)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Public utility service&quot;. A service established by the city of New York pursuant to article fourteen-A of the general municipal law, including the New York city public utility service.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39885" number="51171" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(n)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Empire zone.&quot; An area within the city that has been designated as an empire zone pursuant to article eighteen-B of the general municipal law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39886" number="51172" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(o)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Utility&quot;. A person that provides energy services within the city of New York and is subject to the jurisdiction and general supervision of the New York state public service commission and to a tax imposed by such city under chapter eleven of title eleven of the code, except that the Long Island Power Authority, or its subsidiary, is a utility under this subdivision to the extent that it provides energy services within the city of New York and makes a payment to such city that is equivalent to the tax imposed on utilities pursuant to chapter eleven of title eleven of the code.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39887" number="51173" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(p)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Energy conservation measures&quot;. The construction, alteration, repair or improvement to a building or separate leased space within a building or to equipment affixed to, contained in, or on the grounds of a building, which reduces energy consumption.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39888" number="51174" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(q)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Simple payback period&quot;. The number of years necessary to recoup the cost of an energy conservation measure through annual energy cost savings.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39889" number="51175" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(r)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Qualified eligible energy user&quot;. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39890" number="51176" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A user of energy services that would have qualified as an eligible energy user under paragraph one of subdivision (d) of this section if the reference to May third, nineteen hundred eighty-five were deemed a reference to December thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety, and that (i) agrees to expand the number of its full-time employees, within two years from the date of certification, by fifty employees or ten percent of the number of its full-time employees as of January first, nineteen hundred ninety-one, whichever is greater; provided, however, that one economically disadvantaged or unemployed person hired as a full-time employee after the date of certification shall be counted as two full-time employees and two part-time employees shall be counted as one full-time employee; and provided, further, that the mayor may define by rule full-time employees, part-time employees, unemployed persons, economically disadvantaged persons, and criteria for continued eligibility in relation to fluctuations in employment levels; or (ii) develops, implements, and maintains, in consultation with the New York city department of social services, the department of small business services or the New York city department of youth and community development, job training program which shall be certified and monitored by such department and which shall meet the standards for such programs as are established by the rules of the mayor; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39891" number="51177" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any non-residential user of energy services, except a government agency, public benefit corporation, or instrumentality thereof, hotel or retail vendor as defined in this section, that occupies, operates or manages targeted eligible premises. An occupant of targeted eligible premises described in paragraph one or two of this subdivision shall not be a qualified eligible energy user unless the energy services used by such occupant at such premises are individually and accurately metered and billed so as to enable a determination of the occupant&apos;s usage of such energy services to be made.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39892" number="51178" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(s)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Targeted eligible premises&quot;. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39893" number="51179" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>non-residential premises that are wholly contained in property that is eligible to obtain benefits under part four of subchapter two of chapter two of title eleven, or would be eligible to receive benefits under such chapter except that such property is exempt from real property taxation and the requirements of paragraph two of subdivision g of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-259" destination-id="0-0-0-3023">11-259</LINK> of the code have not been satisfied, provided that application for such benefits was made after December thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety and prior to November first, two thousand, that construction or renovation of such premises was described in such application, that such premises have been substantially improved by such construction or renovation so described, that twice the minimum required expenditure as defined in such chapter has been made, and that such real property is located in an eligible area; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39894" number="51180" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>non-residential premises that are wholly contained in real property which has obtained approval after December thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety and prior to November first, two thousand for financing by an industrial development agency established pursuant to section nine hundred seventeen of the general municipal law, provided that such financing has been used in whole or in part to substantially improve such premises by construction or renovation, and that expenditures have been made for improvements to such real property in excess of forty per centum of the value at which such real property was assessed for tax purposes for the tax year in which such improvements commenced, and that such real property is located in an eligible area; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39895" number="51181" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>non-residential premises that are wholly contained in real property owned by the city or the New York state urban development corporation, or a subsidiary thereof, a lease for which was approved in accordance with the applicable provisions of the charter, and such approval was obtained after December thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety and prior to November first, two thousand, provided that such premises were constructed or renovated subsequent to such approval, that expenditures have been made subsequent to such approval for improvements to such real property by construction or renovation in excess of forty per centum of the value at which such real property was assessed for tax purposes for the tax year in which such improvements commenced, and that such real property is located in an eligible area; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39896" number="51182" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>non-residential premises contained in real property not located in an eligible area that otherwise meet the criteria of paragraph one, two or three of this subdivision, where such premises shall be used primarily for manufacturing activities and provided that such premises shall be improved as a result of expenditures in an amount in excess of twenty per centum of the assessed value of such real property attributable to such premises at which such real property was assessed for tax purposes for the tax year in which such improvements commenced. Attribution of value shall be made in accordance with the rules of the mayor. Only expenditures for improvements that have been identified as part of the construction or renovation project meeting the requirements of paragraph one, two or three of this subdivision, whichever is applicable, shall qualify for purposes of satisfying the minimum expenditure requirements of this sub- division. Provided, however, that no such premises described in paragraph one, two, three or four of this subdivision, contained in a newly constructed structure or building, shall come within this definition unless such premises meet the requirements of the New York state energy conservation construction code promulgated pursuant to article eleven of the energy law. And provided, further, that (i) the qualified eligible energy user shall submit on an annual basis proof that the heating and cooling systems within the premises continue to meet the performance standards specified in section 7813.21 of the energy conservation construction code, or such predecessor section to which the premises, when constructed or substantially renovated, were subject and (ii) to the extent that the cost of motors or lighting equipment described in sections 7813.52 and 7813.53 of the energy conservation construction code is included as part of the minimum expenditures required in paragraph one, two, three or four of this subdivision, the qualified eligible energy user shall certify that all such compatible equipment with a simple payback period of five years or less has been installed.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39897" number="51183" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(t)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Energy services&quot;. The transmission and distribution of electricity or gas, and such other services that are associated with such transmission and distribution as shall be designated as energy services by rule of the commissioner of small business services as such commissioner deems necessary to promote economic development, provided that energy services shall not include the commodity of gas or electricity.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39898" number="51184" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(u)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;On-site cogenerator&quot;. A person, other than a utility, that owns an electric generating facility that simultaneously or sequentially produces electricity and useful thermal energy, provided that substantially all of such electricity shall be used by an eligible energy user that occupies the same site as such generating facility. An on-site cogenerator may be the same or a separate person as such eligible energy user.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39899" number="51185" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Clean on-site cogenerator&quot;. An on-site cogenerator, the electricity generating facility of which has an emission rate for nitrous oxides of no more than three tenths of one pound per megawatt hour. The commissioner of the department of small business services shall establish by rule a megawatt hour equivalent for any useful thermal energy produced by the cogenerator for purposes of determining benefits under this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39900" number="51186" version="1570">
											<PARA>(Am. 2015 N.Y. Laws Ch. 20 Pt. A §§ 46, 47, 48, 6/26/2015, eff. 6/26/2015; Am. 2017 N.Y. Laws Ch. 61, 6/29/2017, eff. 6/29/2017; Am. 2020 N.Y. Laws Ch. 58, 4/3/2020, eff. 4/3/2020; Am. 2023 N.Y. Laws Ch. 55, 5/3/2023, eff. 5/3/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39901" number="51187" version="1493">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2003/052" destination-id="0-0-0-25332">L.L. 2003/052</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-211244" number="51188" version="1493">
										<HEADING>§ 22-602 Requirement of special rebates and discounts. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3727" name="22-602"/>§ 22-602 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Requirement of special rebates and discounts. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39902" number="51189" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Utilities that provide energy services within the city of New York shall be required to make special rebates to eligible energy users and on-site cogenerators certified after June thirtieth, two thousand three, other than clean on-site cogenerators, and to make discounts to vendors of energy services and the New York public utility service as follows: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39903" number="51190" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a utility that sells energy services to an eligible energy user shall be required to make a special rebate to such eligible energy user equal to the product of the applicable percentage specified for special rebates in the schedule contained in paragraph four of this subdivision and the eligible charges for such energy services.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39904" number="51191" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a utility that delivers natural gas to an on-site cogenerator, other than a clean on-site cogenerator, that uses such gas to produce electricity used by an eligible energy user, which cogenerator and user are certified after June thirtieth, two thousand three, shall be required to make a special rebate to such on-site cogenerator equal to the product of the applicable percentage specified for special rebates in the schedule contained in paragraph four of this subdivision and the eligible on-site cogenerator charges for the energy services related to such delivery of such gas.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39905" number="51192" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a utility that sells energy services to a vendor of energy services shall be required to make a discount to such vendor in an amount equal to the sum of the special rebates certified to such utility by such vendor as having been made by such vendor to eligible energy users in accordance with subparagraphs (i) through (iii) of paragraph three of this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39906" number="51193" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a utility that sells energy services to a public utility service shall be required to make a discount to such public utility service in an amount equal to the sum of the special rebates and discounts certified to such utility by such public utility service as having been made by such public utility service in accordance with subparagraphs (i) through (iii) of paragraph two of this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39907" number="51194" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A public utility service providing energy services within the city of New York shall be required to make special rebates to eligible energy users and qualified eligible energy users and discounts to vendors of energy services as follows:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39908" number="51195" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>where, pursuant to a written agreement between a public utility service and the power authority of the state of New York, such public utility service sells energy services to an eligible energy user that has been individually approved by such power authority and certified pursuant to subdivision (c) of this section prior to November first, two thousand, such special rebate shall be in the amount or amounts derived by calculating the full amount of the special rebate to which such eligible energy user would have been entitled pursuant to the schedule contained in paragraph four of this subdivision for eligible charges relating to the purchase of such energy services had such eligible energy user purchased such energy services directly from the utility and subtracting from such full amount the difference between the eligible charges relating to the purchase of such energy services had such eligible energy user purchased the energy services directly from the utility and the eligible public utility service charges relating to the purchase of such energy services actually charged to such eligible energy user by such public utility service for actual purchases of energy services from such public utility service; except that (A) in no event shall the amount of such special rebate exceed the amount of the special rebate to which such eligible energy user would have been entitled pursuant to the schedule contained in paragraph four of this subdivision had such eligible energy user purchased the energy services directly from the utility at the price charged by such utility, and (B) for any monthly billing period where the calculation of such special rebate results in a negative number, the amount of such special rebate shall be deemed to be zero.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39909" number="51196" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>where, pursuant to a written agreement between a public utility service and the power authority of the state of New York, such public utility service (A) sells energy services to an eligible energy user that has been individually approved by such power authority and certified pursuant to subdivision (c) of this section after October thirty-first, two thousand, or (B) sells energy services to a qualified eligible energy user that has been individually approved by such power authority and certified pursuant to subdivision (c) of this section prior to November first, two thousand, such special rebate shall be the product of the applicable percentage for special rebates specified in the schedule contained in paragraph four of this subdivision and the eligible public utility service charges for such energy services.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39910" number="51197" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a public utility service that sells energy services to a vendor of energy services shall be required to make a discount to such vendor of energy services equal to the sum of the special rebates certified to such public utility service by such vendor as having been made by such vendor to eligible energy users or qualified eligible energy users to which such vendor of energy services has resold such energy services in accordance with subparagraphs (i) through (iii) of paragraph three of this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39911" number="51198" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vendors of energy services may elect to provide a special rebate against an eligible energy user&apos;s, qualified eligible energy user&apos;s or on-site cogenerator&apos;s bill for energy services as follows:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39912" number="51199" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>in the case of a vendor of energy services that sells energy services provided by a utility to an eligible energy user, such special rebate shall be the product of the applicable percentage specified for a special rebate in the schedule contained in paragraph four of this subdivision and the eligible charges for such sales of energy services made by such vendor of energy services.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39913" number="51200" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>in the case of a vendor of energy services that delivers natural gas to an on-site cogenerator that is other than a clean on-site cogenerator and that uses such gas to produce electricity used by an eligible energy user, which cogenerator and user are certified after June thirtieth, two thousand three, such special rebate shall be equal to the product of the applicable percentage specified in the schedule contained in paragraph four of this subdivision and the eligible on-site cogenerator charges for the energy services related to such delivery of such gas.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39914" number="51201" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>in the case of a vendor of energy services that sells energy services provided by a public utility service to a qualified eligible energy user that was certified prior to November first, two thousand, or to an eligible energy user that was certified after October thirty-first, two thousand, such special rebate shall be the product of the applicable percentage specified for a special rebate in the schedule contained in paragraph four of this subdivision and the eligible public utility service charges for sales of energy services made by such vendor of energy services.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39915" number="51202" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of determining special rebates for energy services relating to electricity and natural gas under the provisions of this subdivision, the applicable percentages are as follows:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39916" number="51203" version="3">
											<PARA>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39917" number="51204" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TABLE>
													<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="3" left-border-space="43" left-border-width="15" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="43" right-border-width="15" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="43" top-border-width="15" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="43" bottom-border-width="15" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="43" horizontal-border-width="15" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="43" vertical-border-width="15" vertical-border-color="#000000">
														<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="20" percentage="yes"/>
														<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
														<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
													</TABLEFORMAT>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>Months Following Certification</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>Applicable % for Natural Gas</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>Applicable % for Electricity</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>first through ninety-sixth</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>35% </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>45% </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>ninety-seventh through one hundred eighth </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>28% </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>36% </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>one hundred ninth through one hundred twentieth</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>21% </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>27% </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>one hundred twenty-first through one hundred thirty-second</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>14% </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>18% </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>one hundred thirty-third through one hundred forty-fourth</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT> 7% </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT> 9% </CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>
																</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>
																</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>
																<CELLFORMAT>
																</CELLFORMAT>
															</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
												</TABLE>
											</PARA>
											<PARA>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39918" number="51205" version="3">
											<PARA>; provided, however, that the commissioner of the department of small business services may increase such percentages at the commissioner&apos;s discretion in order to maintain the special rebate at levels comparable to those historically provided under the program, pursuant to rules that are generally applicable to distinct classes of energy users.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39919" number="51206" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A utility that delivers natural gas to an on-site cogenerator that produces electricity for an eligible energy user, which cogenerator and user are certified before July first, two thousand three, or to a clean on-site cogenerator that produces electricity for an eligible energy user, shall be required to make special rebates against the energy bill rendered to such on-site cogenerator or clean on-site cogenerator by such utility for the sale or delivery, or both, of such gas in the amount or amounts derived by taking the product of a base adjustment multiplied by an eligibility factor, multiplied by the number of kilowatt hours of electricity produced by such on-site cogenerator or clean on-site cogenerator and used by such eligible energy user during the billing period, excluding charges for natural gas used to generate electricity used for heating any premises or by any energy user not located on the same site, any special charges on such bill, including but not limited to, collection charges, late payment charges, excess distribution charges, and charges for energy which is resold; where the base adjustment shall equal three cents increased by nine one-hundredths cent each January first occurring after December thirty-first, nineteen hundred eighty-seven, and ending on June thirtieth, two thousand three, and the eligibility factor shall equal one hundred percent during the first eight years after initial certification as an eligible energy user as defined in paragraphs one and two of subdivision (d) of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-601" destination-id="0-0-0-10075">22-601</LINK> of this chapter, eighty percent during the ninth such year, sixty percent during the tenth such year, forty percent during the eleventh such year and twenty percent during the twelfth and final such year, such years to be calculated in accordance with the provisions of this section, provided that the number of kilowatt hours on which the total of the special rebates payable to a clean on-site cogenerator is based in any year pursuant to this paragraph shall not exceed thirteen million one hundred forty thousand.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39920" number="51207" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any provision of this subdivision, the special rebates and discounts provided by the Long Island Power Authority, or its subsidiary, pursuant to this subdivision shall not exceed the amount of the payment made by or on behalf of such authority to the city of New York as a payment that is equivalent to the tax imposed by such city pursuant to chapter eleven of title eleven of the code. Special rebates and discounts shall be reduced and/or allocated proportionate to the benefit they would otherwise be eligible for among eligible energy users, public utility services, vendors of energy services, and on-site cogenerators where necessary to comply with this paragraph pursuant to rules of the commissioner of the department of small business services.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39921" number="51208" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any provisions of this subdivision, special rebates and discounts shall not exceed ten thousand dollars per year per employee or full-time equivalent with respect to applications certified pursuant to this chapter after June thirtieth, two thousand three.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39922" number="51209" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Eligible energy users meeting the criteria in paragraph one of subdivision (d) and qualified eligible energy users meeting the criteria in paragraph one of subdivision (r) of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-601" destination-id="0-0-0-10075">22-601</LINK> of this chapter shall be eligible for special rebates for a period not to exceed one hundred forty-four months calculated from the beginning of the month immediately following their date of certification of eligibility. Eligible energy users meeting the criteria of paragraph two of subdivision (d) of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-601" destination-id="0-0-0-10075">22-601</LINK> of this chapter shall be eligible for special rebates for a period calculated from the beginning of the month immediately following their date of certification for so long as they remain in occupancy in the specially eligible premises, but not beyond the period of one hundred forty-four months from the beginning of the month immediately following the date of certification of the first eligible energy user occupying such specially eligible premises. The amounts of rebates made to such an eligible energy user meeting the criteria of such paragraph two shall be determined in accordance with the schedule contained in paragraph four of subdivision (a) of this section as if such eligible energy user had been certified at the same time as such first eligible energy user was certified. A qualified eligible energy user that takes occupancy of targeted eligible premises shall be eligible for special rebates for a period calculated from the beginning of the month immediately following its date of certification as a qualified eligible energy user for so long as it remains in occupancy in the targeted eligible premises, but not beyond the period of one hundred forty-four months from the beginning of the month immediately following the date of certification of the first qualified eligible energy user occupying such targeted eligible premises. The amounts of rebates made to a qualified eligible energy user that takes occupancy of targeted eligible premises shall be determined in accordance with the schedule contained in paragraph four of subdivision (a) of this section as if such qualified eligible energy user had been certified at the same time as such first qualified eligible energy user was certified. An on-site cogenerator or clean on-site cogenerator shall be eligible for special rebates for a period not to exceed the period during which the eligible energy user served by such on-site cogenerator or clean on-site cogenerator would have been eligible for a special rebate under the provisions of this subdivision had it purchased energy services directly from a utility.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39923" number="51210" version="1570">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No eligible energy user, qualified eligible energy user, on-site cogenerator, clean on-site cogenerator or special eligible energy user shall receive a rebate pursuant to this chapter until it has obtained a certification as an eligible energy user, qualified eligible energy user, on-site cogenerator, clean on-site cogenerator or special eligible energy user, respectively, from the commissioner of small business services. No such certification for a qualified eligible energy user shall be issued on or after July first, two thousand three. No such certification of any other eligible energy user, on-site cogenerator or clean on-site cogenerator shall be issued on or after July first, two thousand twenty-seven. The commissioner of small business services, after notice and hearing, may revoke a certification issued pursuant to this subdivision where it is found that eligibility criteria have not been met or that compliance with conditions for continued eligibility has not been maintained. The corporation counsel may maintain a civil action to recover an amount equal to any benefits improperly obtained. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39924" number="51211" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A utility and a vendor of energy services shall keep records of all transactions subject to this article and make such records available to the department of small business services.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39925" number="51212" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Utilities subject to the provisions of subdivision (a) of this section shall reduce each bill for energy services or natural gas for each eligible energy user, vendor of energy services, on-site cogenerator or clean on-site cogenerator as follows:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39926" number="51213" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a bill for the sale and delivery of natural gas rendered to an on-site cogenerator or clean on-site cogenerator entitled to a special rebate pursuant to the provisions of paragraph five of subdivision (a) of this section shall be reduced by the full amount of the special rebate that shall have accrued for the period covered by each such bill;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39927" number="51214" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a bill for energy services rendered to any other eligible energy user or on-site cogenerator shall be reduced by the full amount of the special rebate that shall have accrued for the period covered by each such bill.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39928" number="51215" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a bill for energy services rendered to a vendor of energy services that has provided a special rebate to an eligible energy user or on-site cogenerator shall be reduced by such utility in accordance with paragraph three of subdivision (a) of this section by the aggregate amount of all such special rebates;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39929" number="51216" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>provided, however, such utility shall not be required to provide a special rebate or discount in an amount that exceeds the amount of such bill for the sale and delivery of natural gas rendered to an on-site cogenerator or clean on-site cogenerator entitled to a special rebate pursuant to the provisions of paragraph five of subdivision (a) of this section or, in the case of any other eligible energy user or on-site cogenerator, the amount of such bill for energy services, and provided, further, that no utility subject to the provisions of subdivision (a) of this section shall be required to carry forward on its books and records any special rebate or discounts not made in accordance with this sentence to such bills for subsequent periods. Such discount shall be made within four months from the time certification of special rebates is made in accordance with subparagraph (iii) or (iv) of paragraph one of subdivision (a) of this section. Such amount shall be separately stated and shown on each bill.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39930" number="51217" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A public utility service that provides special rebates for eligible energy users or qualified eligible energy users shall reduce each bill rendered to each such user by the full amount of the special rebate that shall have accrued for the period covered by each such bill in accordance with paragraph two of subdivision (a) of this section. Such amounts shall be separately stated and shown on such bills.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39931" number="51218" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each such vendor of energy services that has elected to provide special rebates for eligible energy users, qualified eligible energy users or on-site cogenerators shall reduce each bill rendered to each such energy user or cogenerator by the full amount of the special rebate that shall have accrued for the period covered by each such bill in accordance with paragraph three of subdivision (a) of this section. Such amounts shall be separately stated and shown on such bills.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39932" number="51219" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of small business services shall, for the purpose of calculating eligible charges, eligible public utility service charges and eligible on-site cogenerator charges, promulgate rules to determine that portion of such charges that shall be deemed attributable to energy services or natural gas used for heating the premises. He or she shall, in addition, promulgate any other rules and regulations necessary to effectuate the purposes of this chapter, including rules to determine the extent to which charges are eligible charges, eligible public utility service charges or eligible on-site cogenerator charges and rules to provide for such administrative charges or fees as are necessary to defray expenses in administering the special rebates and discounts provided pursuant to this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39933" number="51220" version="1570">
											<PARA>(Am. 2015 N.Y. Laws Ch. 20 Pt. A § 49, 6/26/2015, eff. 6/26/2015; Am. 2020 N.Y. Laws Ch. 58, 4/3/2020, eff. 4/3/2020; Am. 2023 N.Y. Laws Ch. 55, 5/3/2023, eff. 5/3/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-39934" number="51221" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 22-603 Construction. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10077" name="22-603"/>§ 22-603 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39935" number="51222" version="3">
											<PARA>Nothing contained in this title shall be construed as reducing the amount of a receipt for sales tax purposes under any of the sales taxes imposed or authorized by article twenty-eight or twenty-nine of the tax law, or as reducing the gross income of the gross operating income subject to tax pursuant to chapter eleven of title eleven of this code. The burden of establishing eligibility to receive the benefits of this chapter shall rest with the party claiming such benefits.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>