<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Title" style-name-escaped="Title" style-id="0-0-0-682" level-depth="1" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-245062" number="50275" version="2466">
			<HEADING>Title 22: Economic Affairs</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3283" name="T22"/>
				<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-27386" name=""/>Title 22: Economic Affairs</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-39081" number="50276" version="3">
				<HEADING>Chapter 1: Waterfront Properties Transactions and Trade</HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9837" name="T22C001"/>Chapter 1: Waterfront Properties Transactions and Trade</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-39082" number="50277" version="3">
					<HEADING>Subchapter 1: Waterfront Property</HEADING>
					<PARA>Subchapter 1: Waterfront Property</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39083" number="50278" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-101 Definitions. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9839" name="22-101"/>§ 22-101 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39084" number="50279" version="3">
												<PARA>As used in this title, the following terms shall have the following meanings: </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39085" number="50280" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Commissioner&quot; shall mean the commissioner of the department of ports and trade.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39086" number="50281" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Department&quot; shall mean the department of ports and trade.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39087" number="50282" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;No-discharge zone&quot; shall mean those bodies of water designated as vessel waste no-discharge zones pursuant to subdivision one of section thirty-three-e of the New York state navigation law.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39088" number="50283" version="1705">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1989/014" destination-id="0-0-0-27008">L.L. 1989/014</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-221616" number="50284" version="1705">
											<HEADING>§ 22-102 Secretary. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9841" name="22-102"/>§ 22-102 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Secretary. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39089" number="50285" version="1782">
												<PARA>The commissioner shall appoint a secretary.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39090" number="50286" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-103 Grant of lands under water within the projected boundary lines of streets. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9843" name="22-103"/>§ 22-103 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Grant of lands under water within the projected boundary lines of streets. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39091" number="50287" version="1784">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To the end that the city may make needful provisions for navigation, intercourse and commerce of the city and adequately to develop and secure the same there is hereby granted in fee to the city, in all the public streams, rivers, sounds, bays and waters of all descriptions at any and all places within the city or adjoining the limits of the city, all and singular the property, estate, right, title and interest of the people of the state of New York, in, to, of, and concerning such lands under water, as are embraced within the projected boundary lines of any street intersecting the shore line, and which street is in public use or which may be hereafter opened for public use extending from high-water mark out into such streams, rivers, sounds, bays and waters so far (and limits in existing grants to the contrary) as the city shall now or at any time hereafter in the opinion of the board of estimate or the commissioner of ports and trade require the same for ferries, public wharves, docks, piers, bulkheads, basins, slips or other public structures, adjuncts and facilities for navigation and commerce. This grant shall include the right to reclaim such lands from such waters, and also all riparian rights and all rents, issues and profit of the premises herein granted. The commissioner of the state department of general services, from time to time, shall convey or patent the lands therein granted to the city for such purposes as and whenever required by the commissioner of ports and trade.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39092" number="50288" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Subdivision a of this section shall not impair or affect any existing valid private rights, or the existing riparian rights of owners of private property, or the lawful rights of private owners of docks, piers and other structures in the city or any part thereof.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39093" number="50289" version="1705">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1989/014" destination-id="0-0-0-27008">L.L. 1989/014</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-221617" number="50290" version="1705">
											<HEADING>§ 22-104 Lands under water not within the projected boundary lines of streets; patenting of. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9845" name="22-104"/>§ 22-104 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Lands under water not within the projected boundary lines of streets; patenting of. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39094" number="50291" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Patents of land under water within the city shall be made only to the city or to the riparian proprietor. Where, pursuant to section seven hundred five of the charter or section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-132" destination-id="0-0-0-9847">22-132</LINK> of this chapter, a plan or plans for the construction of docks between street intersections shall be projected, the commissioner of ports and trade, with the approval of the board of estimate, may make application to the commissioner of the state department of general services for a grant of lands under water for that purpose. Such state commissioner thereupon shall give notice to the riparian proprietor before taking action in the matter and shall then make such grant to the city for the purposes specified in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-103" destination-id="0-0-0-9843">22-103</LINK> of this subchapter. Such grant, however, shall be subject to all the rights of the riparian proprietor, and before the city shall construct such public wharves or other structures in front of the land of such riparian proprietor, the city shall make just compensation to such proprietor for the value of all the riparian rights.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39095" number="50292" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where application is made to the commissioner of the state department of general services by the riparian proprietor for a grant of soil or lands under water within the city, such state commissioner shall give notice thereof to the commissioner of ports and trade who shall examine into such application and certify to such state commissioner whether in his or her opinion the granting of the same will conflict with the rights of the city or be otherwise injurious to the public interests of the city. Such grant, if made, shall be confined to lands under water in front of such riparian proprietor and such state commissioner may insert such terms and conditions in the grant as are recommended by the commissioner of ports and trade and as will protect the public interests of the city in respect to navigation and commerce. The validity of any such grant or patent may be judicially determined in an action brought by and in the name of the city.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39096" number="50293" version="1705">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1989/014" destination-id="0-0-0-27008">L.L. 1989/014</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-221618" number="50294" version="1705">
											<HEADING>§ 22-105 Wharf property; proceedings to acquire. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7699" name="22-105"/>§ 22-105 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Wharf property; proceedings to acquire. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39097" number="50295" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner may agree with the owners of any wharf property, or uplands upon a price for the same and shall certify such agreement to the mayor. If the mayor approve such agreement, the commissioner shall take from the owners at such price, the necessary conveyances and covenants for vesting such wharf property or uplands in, and assuring the same to the city of New York forever, and such owner shall be paid such price by the city. If, however, the commissioner shall determine that the city should acquire such wharf property or uplands by condemnation, without first attempting to agree with the owners thereof for its purchase, the commissioner may, with the approval of the mayor direct the corporation counsel to take legal proceedings to acquire the same for the city. Thereupon, the corporation counsel shall take the same proceedings to acquire such wharf property or uplands as are provided for the taking of private property in the city for public streets or places, and the provisions of subchapter one of chapter three of title five of the code are hereby made applicable, as far as may be necessary, in any legal proceeding taken under this section. Before any such proceeding shall be instituted, a statement shall be furnished to the mayor of the valuation of the real property to be acquired as assessed for purposes of taxation. The title to such property shall vest in the city upon the date of the filing of the survey or map showing the real property to be acquired subdivided into parcels corresponding with the separate ownerships thereof in the office of the clerk of the county where such proceeding is pending; and all of the rights, title and interest of any and all of the owners or persons interested in such wharf property or uplands, shall cease and determine and be extinguished at such time. All the awards made in such proceedings for the value of property acquired or interests extinguished shall draw interest from the time of the vesting of the title in the city.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39098" number="50296" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner, with the approval of the board of estimate, may agree, license and permit private owners of any wharf property, to make the necessary improvements upon their property, so as to conform to the water front plan during the period which shall intervene prior to the extinguishment of such private ownership by the city. Such improvements shall be made by such owners under the supervision of or by the commissioner, as may be agreed upon, at the cost and expense of such private owners, in the first instance, and upon such reasonable terms as to reimburse such private owners for such improvements, and as to wharfage and other riparian rights thereon and therefrom, as may be agreed upon.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39099" number="50297" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-106 Wharf property; acquisition; public hearing required. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9849" name="22-106"/>§ 22-106 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Wharf property; acquisition; public hearing required. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39100" number="50298" version="680">
												<PARA>The mayor, prior to approving or authorizing the acquisition of wharf property or uplands, or directing the vesting in the city of any title thereto, may hold a public hearing and shall refer any such proposed acquisition to the appropriate agency pursuant to the provisions of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="Chapter 8" destination-id="0-0-0-0">chapter eight</LINK> of the charter. Public notice of any hearing held by the mayor shall be given by publication for six consecutive days in the City Record, not less than seven, nor more than thirty days before such public hearing. Such publication shall contain in addition to such information as the commissioner may deem proper, a description of the property to be affected by the order to acquire such property, a statement by the mayor of the date, time and place of such public hearing, and an abstract of the recommendation of the commissioner in relation to such vesting of title.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39101" number="50299" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-107 Fixing the high water line. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9851" name="22-107"/>§ 22-107 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Fixing the high water line. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39102" number="50300" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner, by agreement with the upland owner, may fix, determine upon and establish the line of high water in front of the property of such upland owner upon such line or lines as the commissioner shall deem best adapted to the improvement of the water front.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39103" number="50301" version="680">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such agreement may provide for the sale and conveyance to the upland owner of lands under water inside of such line, and for the purchase from such upland owner of lands outside of such line, or for the exchange of lands under water inside of such line for lands outside of such line. Such agreement for sale and conveyance, together with a map showing the lines so fixed, determined upon and established shall be transmitted to the department of city planning pursuant to the provisions of sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-c" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred ninety-seven-c</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="199" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred ninety-nine</LINK> of the charter. If such agreement involves the purchase or acquisition of such lands, the agreement, together with a map showing the lines so fixed, determined upon and established shall be transmitted to the mayor. Upon approval by the board of estimate of such agreement for sale and conveyance and upon approval of such agreement for purchase or acquisition by the board of estimate and by the mayor such sale and conveyance shall be made upon such terms and conditions as the board shall deem proper, and such purchase or exchange shall be made upon such terms and conditions as the board and the mayor shall deem proper.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39104" number="50302" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-108 Sinking ships; placing at wharf property prohibited. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9853" name="22-108"/>§ 22-108 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Sinking ships; placing at wharf property prohibited. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39105" number="50303" version="3">
												<PARA>It shall be unlawful to place any vessel, craft or structure which is sinking or is in such condition that there is danger of it sinking or stranding, at any wharf property. Violation of this section shall be a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of not more than five hundred dollars and not less than ten dollars, or by imprisonment for not more than six months and not less than ten days, or by both, on complaint of the commissioner. One-half of any such fine shall be paid to the person or persons giving information which shall lead to the conviction of any person violating this section.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39106" number="50304" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-109 Removal of trucks, merchandise and vessels. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9855" name="22-109"/>§ 22-109 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Removal of trucks, merchandise and vessels. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39107" number="50305" version="3">
												<PARA>Where any wharf property or marginal street shall be encumbered or obstructed in its free use or navigation by merchandise or material not affixed to such wharf property or marginal street, or by an automobile, wagon, truck or cart, or by any floating, stranded or sunken vessel or craft, and the owner, consignee or person in charge thereof shall fail to remove the same when directed by an order issued by the commissioner, pursuant to section seven hundred four of the charter, the commissioner may employ such labor and equipment as may be necessary to carry out such order. The commissioner may store such merchandise, material, automobile, wagon, truck, cart, vessel or craft in a warehouse or other suitable place at the expense of the owner. Such owner, consignee or person in charge of the merchandise, material, automobile, wagon, truck, cart, vessel or craft so removed or stored may redeem the same upon payment to the commissioner of the amount of all expenses actually and necessarily incurred in effecting such removal, together with any charges for storage. The commissioner shall be deemed a creditor of such owner, consignee or person in charge and each of them for the amount of the expenses so incurred and the commissioner may maintain an action against them, or any of them, to recover the same.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39108" number="50306" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-110 Sale of unclaimed trucks, merchandise and vessels. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9857" name="22-110"/>§ 22-110 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Sale of unclaimed trucks, merchandise and vessels. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39109" number="50307" version="3">
												<PARA>Whenever such merchandise, material, automobile, wagon, truck, cart, vessel or craft shall remain unclaimed for thirty days after service of such order on such owner, consignee or person, the commissioner may then sell the same at pubic auction to the highest bidder, after advertisement for one week in the City Record. The commissioner shall deduct the expenses which have been incurred from the proceeds of such sale and shall hold the remainder of such proceeds in trust for such owner, consignee or person for twelve months. If such remainder is then unclaimed, it shall be paid into the general fund. Any excess of expenses which have been incurred in the removal, storage, advertisement and sale of such merchandise, material, automobile, wagon, truck, cart, vessel or craft over such proceeds of sale shall be recoverable from such owner or owners of the same in an action maintained by the commissioner.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39110" number="50308" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-111 Destruction of unclaimed trucks, merchandise and vessels. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9859" name="22-111"/>§ 22-111 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Destruction of unclaimed trucks, merchandise and vessels. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39111" number="50309" version="3">
												<PARA>If no bids are received at the public sale authorized in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-110" destination-id="0-0-0-9857">22-110</LINK> of this subchapter, the commissioner may remove, destroy and break up or otherwise dispose of such merchandise, material, automobile, wagon, truck, cart, vessel or craft without liability for damage to the owners of or to any person having or claiming any interest in the same. The expense of such removal, advertisement, sale, destruction and disposal shall be recoverable from such owner, owners or persons in an action maintained by the commissioner.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39112" number="50310" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-112 Navigable waters; fouling; obstructing. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-871" name="22-112"/>§ 22-112 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Navigable waters; fouling; obstructing. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39113" number="50311" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39114" number="50312" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To place, discharge or deposit, by any process or in any manner, offal, piles, lumber, timber, driftwood, dirt, ashes, cinders, mud, sand, dredging, sludge, acid, or any other refuse matters floatable or otherwise in the port of New York, except under the supervision of the United States supervisor of the harbor, provided, however, that it shall not be a violation of this section to feed fish or waterfowl in the port of New York.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39115" number="50313" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To discharge, or cause or permit to be discharged, into the port of New York, from any ship, steamer or other vessel, any oil, oil refuse, or other inflammable matter.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39116" number="50314" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To discharge, or cause or permit to be discharged, any vessel waste from any ship, steamer, or other vessel into the waters of any no-discharge zone within the city of New York, or adjacent to the city of New York within a distance of one thousand five hundred feet from shore. For the purposes of this section, &quot;vessel waste&quot; shall mean sewage, whether treated or untreated, from marine toilets.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39117" number="50315" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person violating paragraph one or two of subdivision a of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction therefor shall be punished by a fine of not more than two hundred fifty dollars nor less than five dollars, or imprisonment for not more than six months nor less than ten days, one-half of such fine to be paid to the person giving information which shall lead to the conviction of the offender.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39118" number="50316" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person violating paragraph one or two of subdivision a of this section, which is not concurrently a violation of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="16-119" destination-id="0-0-0-869">16-119</LINK> of this code, shall be liable for a civil penalty of not less than one thousand five hundred dollars nor more than ten thousand dollars for a first violation, and not less than five thousand dollars nor more than twenty thousand dollars for each subsequent violation of either paragraph. Such penalties may be recovered in a civil action brought in the name of the commissioner or in a proceeding before the environmental control board.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39119" number="50317" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner or operator of a ship, steamer, or vessel operating for commercial purposes, carrying passengers for hire, or serving primarily as a residence that violates paragraph three of subdivision a of this section shall be liable for a civil penalty of not less than five hundred dollars nor more than one thousand dollars for a first violation, and not less than one thousand five hundred dollars nor more than five thousand dollars for each subsequent violation. The owner or operator of any other vessel that violates paragraph three of subdivision a of this section shall be liable for a civil penalty of not more than five hundred dollars for a first violation, and not less than five hundred dollars nor more than one thousand dollars for each subsequent violation. All penalties set forth in this subdivision may be recovered in a civil action brought in the name of the commissioner or in a proceeding before the environmental control board.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39120" number="50318" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of this section may also be enforced by the commissioner of sanitation and the commissioner of environmental protection.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39121" number="50319" version="1992">
											<HEADING>§ 22-112.1 [No-discharge zones.]</HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-27664" name="22-112.1"/>§ 22-112.1 [No-discharge zones.]</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226811" number="50320" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> For purposes of this section, the term “pumpout facility” has the meaning ascribed to such term in the environmental conservation law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226810" number="50321" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than December 31, 2025, the department of environmental protection shall develop a report that would summarize the additional construction and installation needed for all coastal bodies of water of the city to be designated as no-discharge zones. Such report shall include, at a minimum: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226809" number="50322" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Which coastal bodies of water of the city have been designated as no-discharge zones; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226808" number="50323" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The existing number and locations of pumpout facilities in or adjacent to the city’s coastal bodies of water; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226807" number="50324" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Determine the number of additional pumpout facilities required to establish a no-discharge zone in each coastal body of water in the city, and the necessary locations of such pumpout facilities; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226806" number="50325" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The costs that would be incurred in order to establish a no-discharge zone in each remaining coastal body of water in the city; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226805" number="50326" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The coastal bodies of water in which the establishment of a no-discharge zone would be most beneficial to water quality. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226804" number="50327" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the department of environmental protection determines that establishing certain coastal bodies of water as no-discharge zones is not feasible despite the best efforts of city government, or if the fiscal cost of the installation of pumpout facilities along a particular coastal body of water would be significantly in excess of the typical cost of installation for equivalent pumpout facilities in other locations in the city, the department of environmental protection shall include such determination in the report and make recommendations with respect to actions that may be undertaken to achieve no-discharge zone status in all of the coastal bodies of water of the city. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226803" number="50328" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each calendar year, beginning in the calendar year following the issuance of the report required pursuant to subdivision b of this section, until all of the coastal bodies of water of the city are designated as no-discharge zones or the department of environmental protection determines that establishing all of the coastal bodies of water of the city as no-discharge zones is not feasible pursuant to subdivision c of this section, the department of environmental protection shall install at least 2 public pumpout facilities until each coastal body of water hosts the number of operational pumpout facilities the department of environmental protection determines is required to be established as a no-discharge zone pursuant to the report required by subdivision b of this section or any update of such report. The department of environmental protection shall prioritize installing pumpout facilities in or around the coastal bodies of water that would most benefit from being designated no-discharge zones, as identified pursuant to the report required by subdivision b of this section or any update of such report. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226802" number="50329" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>By December 31, 2027, and by December 31 of every second year thereafter, until all of the coastal bodies of water of the city have been designated as no-discharge zones by the United States environmental protection agency, other than any portions of such coastal bodies of water for which a determination has been made pursuant to subdivision c of this section, the department of environmental protection shall submit a report to the mayor and the council including but not limited to the following: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226801" number="50330" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number and locations of pumpout facilities constructed in or adjacent to the city’s coastal bodies of water since the date of the most recent report issued pursuant to this section and the number and locations of pumpout facilities to be constructed during the following calendar year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226800" number="50331" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Which coastal bodies of water of the city have been designated as a no-discharge zone since the date of the most recent report issued pursuant to this section; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226799" number="50332" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>An assessment of priorities pursuant to subdivision d of this section; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226798" number="50333" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>An assessment of progress toward establishing all of the city’s coastal bodies of water as no-discharge zones. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226797" number="50334" version="1992">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department of environmental protection shall use best efforts to ensure that all no-discharge zones continue to meet federal eligibility criteria for no-discharge zones promulgated pursuant to the clean water act.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226796" number="50335" version="1992">
												<PARA>(L.L. 2024/019, 1/20/2024, eff. 1/20/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226795" number="50336" version="1992">
											<HEADING>§ 22-113 Assignment of berths for vessels. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9861" name="22-113"/>§ 22-113 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Assignment of berths for vessels. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39122" number="50337" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications for berths shall be filed as the commissioner shall direct and shall be considered in the order of receipt. The commissioner shall have power:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39123" number="50338" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To provide and assign suitable accommodations for all ships and vessels, and to regulate them in the berths they are to occupy at wharf property;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39124" number="50339" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To remove from time to time such vessels not employed in receiving or discharging cargoes, to make room for such others as require to be more immediately accommodated for that purpose;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39125" number="50340" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To determine as to the fact of such vessels being, fairly and in good faith, employed in receiving and discharging cargoes;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39126" number="50341" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To determine how far and in what instance the master, and others having charge of ships and vessels, shall accommodate each other in their respective situations.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39127" number="50342" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any master or other person, having charge of any vessel, canal boat, barge or lighter, who shall refuse or neglect to move the same when ordered to do so by the commissioner or other proper officer of the department, or who shall resist or forcibly oppose such commissioner or officer in the discharge of his or her duties, for every such offense, shall forfeit and pay the sum of fifty dollars, to be recovered with costs by and in the name of the department of ports and trade.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39128" number="50343" version="1705">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1989/014" destination-id="0-0-0-27008">L.L. 1989/014</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-221619" number="50344" version="1705">
											<HEADING>§ 22-114 Erection of sheds and warehouses. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9863" name="22-114"/>§ 22-114 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Erection of sheds and warehouses. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39129" number="50345" version="3">
												<PARA>The commissioner with the approval of the board of estimate may erect and maintain within the lines of and upon any marginal street, sheds, warehouses, coal pockets and other buildings and structures devoted to commercial uses in connection with the adjacent piers and bulkheads. The commissioner with the approval of the board of estimate may authorize the lessee of any marginal street to erect and maintain upon the premises so demised sheds, warehouses, coal pockets or other buildings or structures devoted to commercial uses in connection with the adjacent piers and bulkheads.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39130" number="50346" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-115 Removal of sweepings, ashes and garbage. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9865" name="22-115"/>§ 22-115 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Removal of sweepings, ashes and garbage. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39131" number="50347" version="3">
												<PARA>The commissioner shall dispose of all sweepings, ashes and garbage removed by him or her in cleaning wharf property pursuant to subdivision b of section seven hundred four of the charter. For that purpose the commissioner may use concurrently with the department of sanitation, such dumping boards, slips and piers as may be assigned to and set apart for the use of such department.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39132" number="50348" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-116 Improvement of water front property; permit required. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9867" name="22-116"/>§ 22-116 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Improvement of water front property; permit required. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39133" number="50349" version="3">
												<PARA>A written permit shall be obtained from the commissioner before any building, platform, sign, advertising device or any construction or obstacle of any kind be placed or maintained, on water front property owned by the city and under the charge and control of the department. Such a permit shall also be required for erection of such structures or the placing and maintenance of such devices on any other water front property when used in conjunction with and in furtherance of water front commerce and/or navigation. Such a permit shall also be required before any piles shall be driven, or any filling-in or construction, repairs, alterations, removal, dredging or demolitions of any kind be made on any part of the water front, except as may be otherwise provided by the charter or code of the city of New York.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39134" number="50350" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-117 Unauthorized construction and maintenance of structures on water front property; penalty. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9869" name="22-117"/>§ 22-117 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Unauthorized construction and maintenance of structures on water front property; penalty. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39135" number="50351" version="3">
												<PARA>Any owner, lessee, occupant or agent of any water front property who shall place or permit the erection, placing or maintaining of any structure referred to in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-116" destination-id="0-0-0-9867">22-116</LINK> of this subchapter without a permit as required by such section, shall forfeit and pay a penalty of one hundred dollars, in addition to all damages resulting therefrom. There shall be a further penalty of twenty-five dollars a day for each and every day such structure shall be maintained after the expiration of the time specified for the removal thereof in any notice served upon such owner, lessee or occupant or agent.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39136" number="50352" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-118 Construction of sheds; regulation by commissioner. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9871" name="22-118"/>§ 22-118 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction of sheds; regulation by commissioner. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39137" number="50353" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever any person, shall be owner or lessee of any water front property, wharf, pier, dock or bulkhead, and shall use it for the purpose of regularly receiving and discharging cargo such owner or lessee, with the consent of the lessor, may erect and maintain thereon, sheds for the protection of property so received or discharged, provided they shall have obtained from the commissioner, license or authority to erect or maintain the same, subject to the conditions and restrictions contained in such license or authority. Such license or authority, after it has been granted and has been acted upon, shall not be revoked by such commissioner without the consent in writing of the mayor and the board of estimate. Notice shall be given to all parties having any interest therein of a hearing before the board of estimate to consider the application of the commissioner for the revocation of such license or authority. Such notice shall be given by publication thereof for six consecutive days in the City Record, not less than ten nor more than thirty days before such hearing, and by posting, not less than ten nor more than thirty days before such hearing, copies of such notice, in the form of handbills, upon the shed or sheds erected or maintained pursuant to such license or authority, or upon the water front property, wharf, pier, dock or bulkhead upon which such shed or sheds shall have been erected or maintained. Such sheds hereafter shall be constructed subject to the regulations and under the authority of the commissioner. The commissioner may build and maintain such sheds on any water front property, wharf, pier, dock or bulkhead owned by the city and under the charge and control of the department, and may lease the same; and any lessee thereof shall have all the rights and privileges above granted.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39138" number="50354" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing in subdivision a of this section shall be construed to authorize the erection or maintenance on any pier of any storehouse, booths, shops or other structures than the sheds mentioned with the proper doors and gates appertaining thereto. The commissioner may grant a permit or license, however, upon such terms and conditions as he or she may deem proper to the lessee of piers twelve, thirteen, fifteen, and sixteen owned by the city in the borough of Staten Island, to maintain a place for the keeping and care of goods, merchandise and materials discharged from vessels, upon any floor of any such pier.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39139" number="50355" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing contained in subdivision b of this section shall be construed as interfering in any respect with the government or regulation of the Staten Island free port.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39140" number="50356" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-119 Commissioner may repair certain structures on privately-owned water front property and deepen adjoining water. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9873" name="22-119"/>§ 22-119 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commissioner may repair certain structures on privately-owned water front property and deepen adjoining water. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39141" number="50357" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where the owner of any privately-owned water front property, wharf, pier, dock or bulkhead, the structures wholly or partly thereon or such other structures used on such water front property in conjunction with and in furtherance of water front commerce and/or navigation fails to comply with an order of the commissioner, made pursuant to section seven hundred four of the charter, directing that repairs be made to such structures for the purpose of keeping them in a proper condition for use, or fails to comply with an order made pursuant to such section directing that the water near or adjoining any privately-owned water front property be deepened by excavating or removing the earth, mud, dirt or sand therefrom in such places and at such times as the commissioner may determine, such commissioner may himself or herself perform any or all of such work.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39142" number="50358" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The expense incurred by such deepening or repairs shall be a lien or charge upon the property or premises benefited.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39143" number="50359" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-120 Commissioner may remove abandoned wharf structures. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9875" name="22-120"/>§ 22-120 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commissioner may remove abandoned wharf structures. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39144" number="50360" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever any pier, bulkhead, platform or other wharf structure shall be abandoned and constitute an obstruction to navigation, the commissioner shall notify the owner of such property, if known to him or her, to remove the same forthwith. If the owner is unknown, or is not within the city, or shall fail to comply with such notice, the commissioner shall cause such obstruction to be removed. The expense of such removal shall be recoverable by action from the owner and shall be a lien on the property so removed until paid.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39145" number="50361" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If such property is unclaimed within thirty days after removal, the commissioner shall advertise the same for sale, at public auction to the highest bidder, in the City Record for six days. The proceeds of each such sale shall be paid into the general fund.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39146" number="50362" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-121 Maintenance of a drift- and debris-free harbor. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9877" name="22-121"/>§ 22-121 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Maintenance of a drift- and debris-free harbor. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39147" number="50363" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>As used in this section the following terms shall have the following meanings:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39148" number="50364" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Debris&quot; means any substance or material, whether on land or water, which is capable of becoming drift.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39149" number="50365" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Drift&quot; means any substance or material, floatable or otherwise, which may cause damage to any vessel or craft or which may otherwise obstruct, impede or endanger the navigable capacity of the navigable waters of the city or cause any other condition hazardous to the life or safety of persons using such waters, including but not limited to piles, lumber, timber, driftwood, dirt, ashes, cinders, mud, sand, dredged materials, or refuse of any kind.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39150" number="50366" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Navigable waters&quot; means the waterways which are capable of carrying commerce, and the tributaries thereto, within the geographical limits of the city.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39151" number="50367" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Owner&quot; means a person having title to any premises or structure; a tenant, lessee or occupant; a mortgagee or vendee in possession; a trustee in bankruptcy; a receiver or any other person having legal ownership or control of any premises or structure.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39152" number="50368" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Premises&quot; means any land or land under water and improvements or appurtenances or any part thereof including but not limited to any structure.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39153" number="50369" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Structure&quot; means anything built or constructed including but not limited to a building, wharf, pier, dolphin, boom, weir, breakwater, bulkhead, jetty, derelict vessel, ship, barge, raft or floating craft of any kind.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39154" number="50370" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever the commissioner determines that material of any kind placed or deposited on any premises located on or along the shores or banks of any navigable water may be or become a source of drift or debris liable to be washed into such navigable water by any cause whatsoever or that because of the deteriorated or deteriorating condition of any premises or structure located on or along the banks or shores of any navigable water such premises or structure may be or become a source of drift or debris liable to be washed into such water by any cause whatsoever and thereby cause damage to vessels or craft or otherwise obstruct, impede or endanger the navigable capacity of such water or cause any other condition hazardous to the life or safety of persons using such water, the commissioner may declare the same to be a public nuisance and order the owner of such premises or structure to remove, repair, reconstruct, alter or abate it as such order shall specify. It shall be the duty of an owner upon whom such an order has been served to remove, repair, reconstruct, alter or abate such public nuisance in the manner and in the time provided by such order.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39155" number="50371" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>An order of the commissioner issued pursuant to subdivision b of this section shall specify the work to be performed and shall fix a reasonable time for compliance but not less than thirty days from the date of service of such order. Such order shall contain a statement that upon the failure of the owner to comply with the commissioner&apos;s order within the stated time, the department may perform the work specified in the order or apply for a court order directing the owner to comply with the commissioner&apos;s order or directing the department to perform the work specified in the commissioner&apos;s order. Such statement shall also indicate that if the department performs any of the work specified in the commissioner&apos;s order, the expense incurred by the department in performing such work shall be a debt recoverable from the owner and a lien on the premises with respect to which such order was issued.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39156" number="50372" version="1784">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Service of such order shall be made upon the owner personally or by certified mail addressed to the last known address of such person or in any manner provided for service of process by article three of the civil practice law and rules. The commissioner may serve a copy of such order on any mortgagee or lienor of record in the same manner.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39157" number="50373" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A copy of such order shall be filed with the office of the register in the county in which the premises with respect to which such order was issued are situated.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39158" number="50374" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within thirty days after service of such order upon an owner, such owner or a mortgagee or lienor upon whom a copy of such order has been served may request a hearing. At such hearing such person shall be entitled to be represented by counsel and to present evidence. The commissioner may affirm, modify or revoke the order.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39159" number="50375" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the owner fails to comply with the commissioner&apos;s order within the time fixed for compliance pursuant to subdivision c of this section, the department may perform the work specified in the order.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39160" number="50376" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>As an alternative to the remedy set forth in subdivision d of this section, if an owner fails to comply with the commissioner&apos;s order within the time fixed for compliance pursuant to subdivision c of this section, the commissioner may apply to any court of competent jurisdiction, upon such notice and in such manner as the court shall direct, for an order directing the owner to comply with the commissioner&apos;s order or directing the department to perform the work specified in the commissioner&apos;s order.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39161" number="50377" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The procedures set forth in subdivisions c, d and e shall not apply to the abatement of a nuisance with respect to any structure not affixed to real property, including but not limited to any derelict vessel, ship, barge, raft or floating craft of any kind. The commissioner shall provide for the abatement of a nuisance with respect to such structures pursuant to the procedures set forth in sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-109" destination-id="0-0-0-9855">22-109</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-110" destination-id="0-0-0-9857">22-110</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-111" destination-id="0-0-0-9859">22-111</LINK> of this subchapter.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39162" number="50378" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The expense of the department with respect to any work performed by or on behalf of the department pursuant to subdivisions d and e of this section shall be a debt recoverable from the owner and a lien upon the premises with respect to which such work was performed.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39163" number="50379" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall keep a record of all work performed by or on behalf of the department. Such records shall be accessible to the public during business hours. Within thirty days after the issuance of a purchase or work order for such work, such order shall be entered on the records of the department. Such entry shall constitute notice to all parties.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39164" number="50380" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All such expenses shall constitute a lien upon the premises when the amount thereof shall have been definitely computed as a statement of account by the department and the department shall cause to be filed in the office of the city collector an entry of the account stated in the book in which such charges against the premises are to be entered. Such lien shall have a priority over all other liens and encumbrances on the premises except for the lien of taxes and assessments. However, no lien created pursuant to this section shall be enforced against a subsequent purchaser in good faith or mortgagee in good faith unless such transaction occurred after the date of entry of a purchase or work order on the records of the department pursuant to paragraph two of this subdivision.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39165" number="50381" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A notice thereof stating the amount due and the nature of the charge shall be mailed by the city collector within five days after such entry to the last known address of the person whose name appears on the records in the office of the city collector as being the owner or agent or as the person designated by the owner to receive tax bills or, where no name appears, to the premises, addressed to either the owner or the agent. Such notice shall have stamped or printed thereon a reference to this section.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39166" number="50382" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If such charge is not paid within thirty days from the date of entry, it shall be the duty of the city collector to receive interest thereon at the rate of interest applicable to such property for a delinquent tax on real property to be calculated to the date of payment from the date of entry.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39167" number="50383" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such charge and the interest thereon shall continue to be, until paid, a lien on the premises. Such charge and interest may be collected and the lien thereof may be foreclosed in the manner provided by law for the collection and foreclosure of taxes, sewer rents, sewer surcharges and water charges due and payable to the city and the provisions of chapter four of title eleven of the code shall apply to such charges and the interest thereon and the lien thereof.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39168" number="50384" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In any proceedings to enforce or discharge the lien, the validity of the lien shall not be subject to challenge based on (i) the lawfulness of the work done; or (ii) the propriety and accuracy of the items of expenses for which a lien is claimed, except as provided in this paragraph.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39169" number="50385" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No such challenge may be made except by (a) the owner of the property, or (b) a mortgagee or lienor whose mortgage or lien would but for the provisions of this section have priority over the department&apos;s lien.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39170" number="50386" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An issue specified in subparagraph one which was decided or could have been contested in a prior court proceeding to secure a court order pursuant to subdivision e of this section shall not be open to reexamination, but if any mortgagee or lienor of record was not served with an order of the commissioner pursuant to paragraph two of subdivision c and with notice of such proceeding, his or her mortgage or lien shall have the same priority over the lien of the department that it would have had but for the provisions of this section.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39171" number="50387" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to establishing a lien, the department may recover such expenses and interest by bringing an action against the owner. The institution of such action shall not suspend or bar the right to pursue any other remedy provided by law for the recovery of such debt.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39172" number="50388" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-122 Floating drydocks lawful. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9879" name="22-122"/>§ 22-122 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Floating drydocks lawful. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39173" number="50389" version="3">
												<PARA>It shall be lawful for floating drydocks to be used, with the consent of the owners of the wharf property, occupied for such use, or of the persons entitled to collect wharfage thereon, for the purpose of taking up ships or vessels for repair, coppering or finishing.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39174" number="50390" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-123 Asphalt pavement on marginal streets; applications to open. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9881" name="22-123"/>§ 22-123 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Asphalt pavement on marginal streets; applications to open. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39175" number="50391" version="3">
												<PARA>Applications to open asphalt pavement under the control of the commissioner must be made to the commissioner and shall be subject to such rules and regulations as he or she shall establish pursuant to section seven hundred four of the charter.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39176" number="50392" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-124 Covenants to maintain marginal streets; water front covenants generally; release of. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9883" name="22-124"/>§ 22-124 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Covenants to maintain marginal streets; water front covenants generally; release of. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39177" number="50393" version="1784">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner of any lands in the city of New York formerly under water but now filled in and having streets physically laid out thereover or adjacent thereto, heretofore granted by the mayor, aldermen and commonalty of the city of New York, or by the city of New York, by a grant containing covenants or conditions requiring the maintenance of such streets, and otherwise, may file with the secretary of the board of estimate an application in writing for a release from such covenants and conditions setting forth a description of such lands, the ownership thereof, the number of feet fronting on the street and the width of such street together with a statement enumerating all of such covenants and conditions relating to such lands. Such application shall contain a statement that all covenants and conditions contained in such grant have been complied with except the covenant or condition for future maintenance of such street. Such secretary, upon payment by the applicant of a fee of fifty dollars to cover the expenses incident to investigating the truth of the statements contained in such application, shall make due inquiry and, if such statements are in fact true, shall present to such board a report and certificate as to the authenticity of the facts set forth in such application. Such board may thereafter adopt a resolution approving of the report of such secretary. If such report is approved by such board, such owner may obtain from the comptroller a release of all covenants and conditions contained in such grant insofar as such covenants and conditions affect the lands of the applicant, upon payment to the commissioner of finance of a sum equal to twenty dollars per front foot of such property based on a street sixty feet in width, or of a proportional sum based on streets having a greater or less width, and upon receipt of such sum, such comptroller for and on behalf of the city, shall issue to such owner a certificate evidencing such release, the same to be in form for recording. Such certificate shall be approved as to form by the corporation counsel and may be recorded in the same manner and in the same recording office as a deed of real property. After such release, with respect to any parcel, such city shall keep in repair or cause to be kept in repair the roadway portion of such street on which the parcel abuts.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39178" number="50394" version="1784">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the event that any such covenants or conditions, other than those requiring the maintenance of streets, have not been performed in whole or in part, a special application for a release from such covenants or conditions, on a form to be prescribed by the board of estimate, may be made by such owner to such board. Such application shall set forth a description of such land by metes and bounds, or by street and number, the dimensions of such land, a statement enumerating all the covenants and conditions relating to such land, or, in lieu thereof, a copy of the grant of such land, or other instrument, containing all such covenants and conditions and a statement of the particular covenants or conditions, specifying them, for the release from which the application is made, and such other information as such board may deem necessary or appropriate. Such board, upon payment of a fee of fifty dollars, shall cause an investigation to be made concerning the statement contained in such application. If satisfied from such investigation that the interests of the city will not be prejudiced thereby, such board, by resolution may authorize the comptroller to issue to such owner a release from such covenants and conditions for a sum of money to be agreed upon by and between such board and such owner. Upon receipt of such sum, such comptroller shall, for and on behalf of the city, issue to such owner a certificate evidencing such release. Such certificate shall be approved as to form by the corporation counsel and may be recorded in the office of the commissioner of transportation and in the same manner and in the same recording office as a deed of real property.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39179" number="50395" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-125 Wharf property; lease; period. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9885" name="22-125"/>§ 22-125 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Wharf property; lease; period. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39180" number="50396" version="3">
												<PARA>Any lease of wharf property belonging to the city shall be for a term not exceeding fifty years, and may include covenants for renewal or renewals at advanced rents of such lease for terms not exceeding ten years each but not exceeding in the aggregate ninety-nine years.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39181" number="50397" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-126 Recreation piers. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9887" name="22-126"/>§ 22-126 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Recreation piers. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39182" number="50398" version="3">
												<PARA>The commissioner may designate and set aside, as wholly free to the inhabitants of the city, the upper story of certain piers for the purpose of affording such inhabitants opportunity for healthful recreation. The commissioner may construct or rebuild such piers so as to provide such upper story or platform and approaches thereto.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39183" number="50399" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-127 Application of private wharf property to a particular use. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9889" name="22-127"/>§ 22-127 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application of private wharf property to a particular use. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39184" number="50400" version="3">
												<PARA>The commissioner may designate any wharf property which the owners thereof may apply to have set apart for the sole use of special kinds of commerce, or of steamboats, or of any other class or description of ships, or vessels, and may prohibit any ship, steamboat, or any other vessel or water craft whatever from entering or lying, mooring or anchoring at or within any such wharf property, except such as may be designated for their use.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39185" number="50401" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-128 Leasing of wharf property set aside for general and special purposes; contents of publication prior to public hearing. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9891" name="22-128"/>§ 22-128 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Leasing of wharf property set aside for general and special purposes; contents of publication prior to public hearing. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39186" number="50402" version="3">
												<PARA>Publication of notice of a public hearing to lease wharf property described in subdivision a of section seven hundred four of the charter, in addition to such information as the commissioner may deem proper, shall contain the following:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39187" number="50403" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name and address, by street and number, of the proposed lessees.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39188" number="50404" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A description of the property.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39189" number="50405" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The proposed rental.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39190" number="50406" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The proposed terms.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39191" number="50407" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whether the lessee is to have any special privilege under the lease, such as to erect and maintain a shed, ice bridge, or any privilege other than the right to collect cranage and wharfage.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39192" number="50408" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A statement by the board of estimate of the date, time and place of such public hearing.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39193" number="50409" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A copy of the recommendation of the commissioner to such board in relation to the proposed lease. Such proposed lease shall be open to inspection by any citizen at the office of the board of estimate at all times during business hours from the beginning of publication until the day of such hearing.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39194" number="50410" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-129 Rates to be printed in wharfage bills. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9893" name="22-129"/>§ 22-129 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rates to be printed in wharfage bills. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39195" number="50411" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All persons owning or having charge of any wharf property shall cause to be printed on the back of all bills presented by them for wharfage, cranage and dockage the provisions of subdivision j of section seven hundred four of the charter and the schedule of rates fixed pursuant thereto.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39196" number="50412" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner, consignee, or person in charge of any vessel may refuse to pay the wharfage, cranage or dockage due on such vessel unless, upon his or her demand, a bill is presented to him or her printed in conformity with this section. Any person, owning or having charge of any wharf property who shall receive for wharfage, cranage or dockage any rates in excess of those authorized in such schedule of rates shall forfeit to the party aggrieved treble the amount so charged as damages, to be sued for and recovered by the party aggrieved.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39197" number="50413" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-130 Seal; description; legal effect. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9895" name="22-130"/>§ 22-130 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Seal; description; legal effect. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39198" number="50414" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner may direct the use of the seal of the department. Such seal shall be a device of the arms of the city of New York surrounded by the words, &quot;Department of Ports and Trade. The City of New York,&quot; engraved upon a metal disc two and one-quarter inches in diameter, and the same may be renewed whenever necessary. An impression of such seal made directly on paper shall be as valid as if made on a wafer or on wax.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39199" number="50415" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every lease, contract or other instrument, executed in pursuance of authority conferred on such commissioner by law, and sealed with such seal, attested and proved according to law by the secretary appointed by such commissioner, shall be received in evidence, and may be recorded in the proper recording offices in the same manner and with the like effect as if sealed with the seal of the corporation of the city of New York, attested and approved by the clerk thereof.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39200" number="50416" version="1705">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1989/014" destination-id="0-0-0-27008">L.L. 1989/014</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-221620" number="50417" version="1705">
					<HEADING>Subchapter 2: Water Front Terminals</HEADING>
					<PARA>Subchapter 2: Water Front Terminals</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39201" number="50418" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-131 Definitions. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9897" name="22-131"/>§ 22-131 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39202" number="50419" version="3">
												<PARA>As used in this subchapter the following words shall mean:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39203" number="50420" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Marginal wharf&quot;: The area extending inshore from the bulkhead line shown on any plan for the improvement of the water front adopted pursuant to law and constructed in accordance with such plan.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39204" number="50421" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Terminal basin&quot;: All basins, harbors, graving or loading docks that may be provided by the inclosure, natural or artificial, of water for the flotation, protection or handling of shipping or freight, or for transport service of any class.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39205" number="50422" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Terminal ways&quot;: A way or ways constructed or operated for the transportation of freight to, from, across or along any wharf property, or canal of or in the city or any extension or extensions, branch or branches, approach or approaches, siding or sidings, bridge or bridges thereof or therefor, upon, lying upon, above or below any street, avenue, road, highway, park or parkway, bridge, viaduct or public place or slip, canal or waterway, public or private, wharf property, lands and lands under water of or in the city, including all equipment and terminal facilities, of every kind used or operated in connection with any such way so constructed or operated.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39206" number="50423" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Terminal stations&quot;: A building or buildings, structure or structures erected or acquired, occupied or used in connection with terminal ways for the receipt, handling, delivery or shipment of freight, including terminal stores and appurtenances and appliances necessary for the operation thereof, whether such buildings and other structures or portions thereof are used exclusively for terminal stations or terminal stores or in part for warehousing, manufacturing or other purposes.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39207" number="50424" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Terminal stores&quot;: A building or buildings or space for the temporary storage of freight while in the process of delivery, shipment or transport or for use for general warehouse purposes.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39208" number="50425" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Terminal factories&quot;: The space used for manufacture and for the storage incidental thereto of materials, supplies and products together with such power, light, machinery, and other facilities therefor as may be supplied in connection therewith.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39209" number="50426" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Terminal facilities&quot;: Any and all terminal way or ways, terminal station or stations, marginal wharf, terminal basin or basins, terminal store or stores, wharf property, and transportation of property thereon, thereby, thereto or therefrom by this subchapter provided for or mentioned and equipment thereof and therefor.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39210" number="50427" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Equipment&quot;: Elevators, conveyors and conveying apparatus, hoists, shutes, float bridges, transfer bridges and appliances for lighting, heating, or refrigerating, roadbed, tracks, switches, crossovers, spurs, signals, telphers, cars, motors, engines and rolling stock of all descriptions; tugs, floats and lighters; power plant, substations and transformers, appliances for transmission of power by third rail, overhead wires or other means; telephone and telegraph wires and other means of communication; together with all appurtenances and appliances appertaining thereto, connected therewith or used in the operation thereof.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39211" number="50428" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Street&quot;: Includes avenue, road, alley, lane, highway, viaduct, bridge, tunnel, subway, park, parkway, and every class of public road, square and place, except marginal wharf.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39212" number="50429" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>10.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Transportation&quot;: Includes any service in connection with the receipt, delivery, carriage, elevation, transfer in transit, sorting and handling of the property transported, or the handling of goods on or in terminal basins, terminal ways, terminal stations, terminal stores or wharf property by mechanical appliances or other means.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39213" number="50430" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-132 Plans. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9847" name="22-132"/>§ 22-132 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Plans. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39214" number="50431" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner, when directed by the board of estimate, or when the commissioner deems it to be for the interest of the city, shall prepare plans for terminal facilities, which shall consist of:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39215" number="50432" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A map or maps showing the area to be included in such terminal, together with the location of any buildings, railroad tracks, wharves, piers, bulkheads and other structures which are to form a part thereof;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39216" number="50433" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A description, by metes and bounds, of all property which it is proposed to acquire by purchase or otherwise as a part of such terminal facilities.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39217" number="50434" version="680">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such plans, or any modification or addition thereto shall be submitted to the board of estimate and when adopted pursuant to and in accordance with section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="199" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred ninety-nine</LINK> of the charter, and filed in the office of the commissioner, shall be the exclusive plans according to which any terminal facilities, wharf property, or other property required for such terminal facilities, shall be laid out or constructed by the city, its agents or contractors.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39218" number="50435" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever such plans shall include the narrowing or widening of a street or the opening and construction of a new street or the abandonment of a street already in existence, the power to narrow, widen, open, construct, abandon or close the same, or to cause the same to be narrowed, widened, opened, constructed, abandoned or closed, shall be exercised by the board of estimate which is hereby authorized to take such steps as may be necessary in that regard.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39219" number="50436" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-133 Acquisition of the necessary real property. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9899" name="22-133"/>§ 22-133 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Acquisition of the necessary real property. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39220" number="50437" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>After the adoption and certification of such plans, and the filing thereof in the office of the commissioner, the mayor may direct the commissioner to acquire any and all real property included in such plans or any interest therein, which may be necessary for the creation of the terminal facilities shown upon the map or maps forming part of such plans. The proceedings for the acquisition of the title to such property shall be taken and conducted in the manner prescribed in subchapter one of chapter three of title five of the code.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39221" number="50438" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever, at any height, or depth, an area of land is required for the purposes of such terminal facilities, the entire fee of land furnishing such area, or such lesser estate therein, as the board of estimate shall deem needed for public use may be so acquired; and the city may use for other public purposes, or may lease or permit the use for storage, warehousing, manufacturing or otherwise, of such levels and parts of levels thereof as from time to time may not be required for such terminal facilities.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39222" number="50439" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The area of land to be so acquired may include such area, additional and adjacent to that required for the structure of such terminal ways or stations, as such board may authorize and certify as required to be replotted, regraded or otherwise adapted for convenient access to and use of such ways or stations or other improvement of the water front of the city in connection therewith.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39223" number="50440" version="680">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such parts of the lands acquired by the city under and pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter which in the judgment of the board of estimate are no longer required for the improvement of the water front facilities of the city or for any other public purpose, except the part of such lands so acquired as have been heretofore assigned by the board of estimate to the use of the department of ports and trade, may be sold by the city in the manner prescribed by subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="384" destination-id="0-0-0-0">three hundred eighty-four</LINK> of the charter. The proceeds of such sale shall be paid into the real property fund.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39224" number="50441" version="1705">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1989/014" destination-id="0-0-0-27008">L.L. 1989/014</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-221621" number="50442" version="1705">
											<HEADING>§ 22-134 Construction. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9901" name="22-134"/>§ 22-134 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39225" number="50443" version="3">
												<PARA>The board of estimate may direct the commissioner to build or cause to be built the whole or any part of terminal ways, including foundations, abutments and bridges required therefor, terminal stations and equipment thereof, provided for by such plans for terminal facilities, and generally to execute such plans.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39226" number="50444" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-135 Operation. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9903" name="22-135"/>§ 22-135 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Operation. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39227" number="50445" version="3">
												<PARA>The board of estimate may direct the commissioner to operate or to permit the use of terminal facilities upon such terms and subject to such regulations as such board from time to time may establish; and to carry into effect the provisions of this subchapter, the commissioner may purchase or lease or obtain in the best manner obtainable for the interests of the city, and according to law, power, light, heat and fixtures for the use thereof and other necessities and conveniences for such operation, provided that nothing contained in this subchapter shall be deemed to include the right or privilege to grant a franchise to carry on the business of generating, selling or distributing electric light, heat or power.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39228" number="50446" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-136 Use of private facilities. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9905" name="22-136"/>§ 22-136 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Use of private facilities. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39229" number="50447" version="3">
												<PARA>The board of estimate may hire or contract for use by the city in supplement or extension of its terminal facilities such ways, stations, basins, plant or service as, being owned or controlled by others than the city, shall be needed or proper to that end, but not for a longer period than twenty-five years, except as provided for by option to the city.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39230" number="50448" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-137 Acquisition of private facilities. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9907" name="22-137"/>§ 22-137 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Acquisition of private facilities. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39231" number="50449" version="3">
												<PARA>In case any terminal facilities shall be provided, or agreed to be provided by the city as a substitute, in whole or in part, for any existing tracks, or other transportation or terminal facilities which the owner thereof may agree to surrender in consideration of the right to use such terminal facilities so provided in substitution, or agreed to be provided in substitution, the city may for such a time, and on such terms and conditions as may be agreed upon, lease, permit or agree in respect to such substituted use or operation.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39232" number="50450" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-138 Liability of city limited. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9909" name="22-138"/>§ 22-138 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Liability of city limited. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39233" number="50451" version="3">
												<PARA>Neither in any such operation of any such way, station or store, nor in any such transport as it shall undertake, shall the city be or undertake to be liable as a common carrier.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39234" number="50452" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-139 Private operation. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9911" name="22-139"/>§ 22-139 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Private operation. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39235" number="50453" version="1784">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the board of estimate shall determine that municipal operation of any terminal facilities is inexpedient, it shall advertise for proposals for the privilege of constructing, equipping and operating the same, or for equipping and operating after construction by the city, or for operating after construction and equipment by the city, by a notice to be printed once a week for two successive weeks in not less than two daily newspapers, and may require security from bidders for the execution of their bids, if accepted. Such notice shall describe such terminal facilities in such terms as the board of estimate shall deem proper, and shall state the time and place at which proposals will be received and opened. All proposals shall undertake to equip such facilities, unless equipment shall have been provided by the city, and to maintain and operate such terminal facilities for a period not exceeding twenty-five years, with the privilege, however, of renewing such contract for a further period not exceeding twenty-five years upon terms to be readjusted as provided in such contract. Such proposals may offer to pay to the city for the use of such terminal facilities either (1) a fixed annual sum; or (2) a share of gross receipts; or (3) a share of net receipts. The board of estimate, or a duly appointed committee thereof, shall attend at the time and place specified in such public notice, and shall publicly open all proposals which shall have been received, but such board shall not be bound to accept any proposals so received, and may reject all such proposals and re-advertise for proposals in the manner hereinbefore provided, or may accept any of such proposals as will, in the judgment of such board, best promote the public interest, and award a contract accordingly.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39236" number="50454" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any contract for private operation of terminal facilities shall contain a provision whereby the city, at any time after ten years, may terminate the same so far as it relates to the maintenance and operation of terminal ways, and terminal stations, and the equipment thereof, upon terms to be fixed in such contract, upon giving one year&apos;s written notice of its intention so to do. Upon termination by the city, pursuant to the privilege so reserved, the city shall purchase the equipment actually used in the operation of such terminal facilities at an amount agreed upon between the owner thereof and the city; or, in the event of failure to agree, at an amount to be fixed by appraisal, each party to name an impartial appraiser, and the two so named to select the third. In the event of failure to agree upon a third appraiser, he or she shall be named by the presiding justice of the appellate division of the supreme court, first department; provided, however, that the contract for the operation of such terminal facilities may provide for the amortization of all or a part of the operator&apos;s investment out of earnings, in which event the portion so amortized shall become the property of the city at the termination of the contract without further payment to the operator.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39237" number="50455" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any contract for private operation may provide for the construction of warehouses, factories or other buildings on land owned by the city, which warehouses, factories or buildings shall, during construction and at all times thereafter, be the property of the city. The contract may provide for the amortization of the cost of such warehouses, factories or buildings out of receipts from their operation, or out of receipts from the operation of all the terminal facilities included in such contract during the term thereof, and may provide for the payment by the city of any unamortized portion of the actual cost plus a reasonable contractor&apos;s profit, not to exceed fifteen per centum at the termination of the contract, or on the exercise of an option to recapture reserved in the contract. The contract may provide for the payment to the city for the privilege of operating such warehouses, factories, or other buildings so constructed, either (1) a fixed annual sum; or (2) a share of the gross receipts; or (3) a share in the net profits.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39238" number="50456" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such contract may contain any other provision not inconsistent with this section which the board of estimate may deem necessary or desirable for the protection of the interests of the city.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39239" number="50457" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the provisions of any general or special law, a railroad corporation may, with the consent of the board of estimate, purchase, acquire or hold any stocks or any bonds or other evidences of indebtedness of a corporation which, pursuant to this section, enters into a contract with the city for the operation of terminal facilities in the boroughs of Brooklyn and Queens, or either of them, and which contract provides for the handling over such terminal road of freight moved by water, or partly by rail and partly by water, and freight moved wholly by rail, without discrimination as between such freight moved by water, or partly by rail and partly by water, and freight moved wholly by rail. The consent of such board shall be granted only upon such notice and after such hearing as may be prescribed under rules and regulations which such board is hereby authorized to adopt.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39240" number="50458" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-140 Construction clause. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9913" name="22-140"/>§ 22-140 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction clause. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39241" number="50459" version="3">
												<PARA>Nothing contained in this subchapter shall be construed as in any way limiting the present or future jurisdiction of the public service commission of the state of New York, and nothing contained in this subchapter shall be construed as limiting or repealing any of the provisions of the railroad law of the state of New York. Provided, however, that it shall not be necessary before constructing a railroad as part of terminal facilities to obtain a certificate of convenience and necessity from the public service commission.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-39242" number="50460" version="804">
					<HEADING>Subchapter 3: Transfer of Barge Canal Terminals to City</HEADING>
					<PARA>Subchapter 3: Transfer of Barge Canal Terminals to City</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39243" number="50461" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-141 Definitions. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9915" name="22-141"/>§ 22-141 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39244" number="50462" version="3">
												<PARA>Unless expressly otherwise provided, whenever used in this subchapter, the following terms shall mean and include: </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39245" number="50463" version="3">
												<PARA>&quot;Pier properties&quot;. The properties described in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-142" destination-id="0-0-0-9917">22-142</LINK> of this subchapter and improvements thereon. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39246" number="50464" version="3">
												<PARA>&quot;Rehabilitation&quot;. Repair, reconstruction, renovation, improvement or betterment of pier properties in order to place such property in good condition for pier and terminal purposes and the acquisition of real and personal property for use in connection therewith. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39247" number="50465" version="3">
												<PARA>&quot;Pier and terminal purposes&quot;. Operation and maintenance of facilities for docking, loading and unloading of vessels and the handling, storage, processing and interchange of cargoes. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39248" number="50466" version="3">
												<PARA>&quot;Vessels&quot;. Commercial ships and barges of every description.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39249" number="50467" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-142 Legislative finding. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9917" name="22-142"/>§ 22-142 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Legislative finding. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39250" number="50468" version="3">
												<PARA>It is hereby found and determined that the pier properties, heretofore constituting barge canal terminals and barge canal lands, in this section hereinafter generally described, are no longer necessary or useful for canal or terminal purposes or as an aid to navigation thereon: The Greenpoint terminal, being all that tract, piece or parcel of land, situate, lying and being in the borough (formerly city) of Brooklyn, county of Kings, city and state of New York, bounded and described as follows (all bearings being referred to the true meridian): Beginning at a point formed by the intersection of the center line of Commercial street as established at the time of the acquisition of the property herein described by the state of New York between Franklin and West streets and the center line of West street, as established at the time of the acquisition of the property herein described by the state of New York between Dupont and Eagle streets; thence from said point of beginning, southerly and south-easterly along the aforesaid center line of West street, one hundred eighteen and fifty-six hundredths feet to a point formed by the intersection of said center line of West street and a line parallel to the southerly side of Dupont street as laid out west of West street and distant ninety-five feet southerly therefrom; thence along said line eight hundred fifty-five and seventy-five hundredths feet to a point in the pierhead line as established at the time of the acquisition of the property herein described by the state of New York by law; thence northerly, northeasterly and easterly along said pierhead line, one thousand sixty-nine and thirty-two hundredths feet more or less to a point where the center line of Blue street as established at the time of the acquisition of the property herein described by the state of New York, if extended, would intersect the aforesaid pierhead line; thence southerly and southeasterly along said center line of Blue street two hundred thirty-seven and twelve hundredths feet to a point in the westerly line of lands conveyed by the state of New York to the city of New York by letters-patent dated February thirteen, nineteen hundred forty-two; thence south thirty-seven degrees, four minutes, seventeen seconds west, along said westerly line of lands conveyed as aforesaid, one hundred fifty-three and thirty-two hundredths feet; thence continuing along said line of lands conveyed as aforesaid, the following several courses to said center line of Commercial street aforesaid, south seven degrees, eight minutes, forty-three seconds east, thirty-two and thirty-seven hundredths feet; thence north eighty-two degrees, fifty-one minutes, seventeen seconds east, forty-three feet; thence south seven degrees, eight minutes, forty-three seconds east, seventy feet; thence south eighty-two degrees, fifty-one minutes, seventeen seconds west, forty-three feet; thence south seven degrees, eight minutes, forty-three seconds east, seventy-seven feet; thence south fifty degrees, thirteen minutes, forty-eight seconds east, seventy-three and four hundredths feet; thence north eighty-two degrees, fifty-one minutes, seventeen seconds east, seventy-three and fifty-three hundredths feet to a point in said center line of Commercial street as aforesaid; thence south fifty-four degrees, twenty-five minutes, forty-seven seconds west, along said center line of Commercial street, seventy-five and seventy-eight hundredths feet to the point of beginning. Being the same premises appropriated by the state for the barge canal terminal at Greenpoint, in the borough of Brooklyn, county of Kings, city of New York, pursuant to the provisions of chapter seven hundred forty-six of the laws of nineteen hundred eleven, as shown on map of parcel number T-8, terminal contract number nineteen, approved by the canal board on June eight, nineteen hundred twelve and on file in the department of transportation of the state of New York, excepting so much thereof as was conveyed by the state of New York to the city of New York by letters-patent dated February thirteen, nineteen hundred forty-two. The Hallet&apos;s cove terminal being all that tract or parcel of land, situate, lying and being near the foot of Camelia street, Hallet&apos;s cove, East River, borough and county of Queens, city and state of New York, bounded and described as follows (all bearings being referred to the true meridian): Beginning at the point of intersection of the northerly side of Broadway and the pierhead and bulkhead line established by the harbor commission in eighteen hundred fifty-seven; thence running along said pierhead and bulkhead line north seventy degrees, nine minutes east two hundred seventy-six and twenty-five hundredths feet; thence still along said line north sixty-six degrees, fourteen minutes east one hundred seventy-two and eighty hundredths feet to a point in the southerly boundary line of lands owned or claimed by John W. Scott; thence along said southerly boundary line south fifty degrees east one hundred ninety-five feet to a point in the westerly side of the boulevard; thence south twelve degrees, twenty-eight minutes west three hundred forty-seven and sixty hundredths feet to a point in the northwesterly boundary line of lands owned or claimed by Peter McKernan; thence along said northwesterly boundary line south seventy-four degrees twenty-three minutes west sixty-four and forty-two hundredths feet to the lands owned or claimed by T. W. Stevens; thence still south seventy-four degrees, twenty-three minutes west seventy-one and eleven hundredths feet along the northwesterly line of the last mentioned lands to a point in the northerly side of Broadway; thence along the said northerly side of Broadway north forty-six degrees, fifty-eight minutes west four hundred ninety-four and ninety hundredths feet more or less to the point of beginning, Being the same premises appropriated by the state for the barge canal terminal at Hallet&apos;s cove, East river, borough of Queens, county of Queens, city of New York, pursuant to the provisions of chapter seven hundred forty-six of the laws of New York, nineteen hundred eleven, as amended, as shown on parcel number T-99, terminal contract number forty-five, approved by the canal board on December twenty-one, nineteen hundred fourteen, and on file in the department of transportation of the state of New York. The east 138th street terminal, being all those three tracts or parcels of land situate, lying and being in the 23rd Ward of the borough and county of the Bronx, city and state of New York, and being a part of section nine, block 2339, hereinafter bounded and described as follows (all bearings being referred to the easterly side of tenth avenue as the meridian, the bearing of which referred to true north is twenty-eight degrees, fifty-nine minutes, twenty-seven and thirty-three hundredths seconds east):</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39251" number="50469" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning at the point of intersection of the westerly line of Exterior street as at present laid out and the northerly line of the lands of the New York and Harlem railroad company distant six hundred eighty-three and six hundredths feet from the southwest corner of Exterior street and east 138th street as at present laid out, thence running along the said northerly boundary line the following bearings and courses south forty-seven degrees, eight minutes, thirty-nine seconds west thirteen and thirteen hundredths feet; thence south forty-eight degrees, fifty-four minutes, thirty-two seconds west fifty-two and three hundredths feet; thence south fifty degrees, forty-three minutes, fifty-two seconds west fifty-three and sixteen hundredths feet; thence south fifty-two degrees, fifty-four minutes, thirty-two seconds west eight and sixty-one hundredths feet to a point in the pierhead and bulkhead line of the Harlem river approved by the secretary of war in eighteen hundred ninety; thence along the pierhead and bulkhead line north twenty-two degrees, twenty-six minutes, thirty-five seconds east, seventy-six and fifty hundredths feet to a point; thence along said line north twenty-three degrees, twenty-four minutes, three seconds west two hundred thirty-four and sixty-two hundredths feet to a point in the southerly boundary line of lands owned or claimed by the Harlem river lumber and woodworking company; thence north sixty-three degrees, fifty-five minutes, eleven seconds east, one hundred seventy-four and fifteen hundredths feet along said southerly boundary line to a point in the westerly side of Exterior street as at present laid out; thence south twelve degrees, thirty-seven minutes, ten seconds east, two hundred eighty-seven and fifty-eight hundredths feet along the said westerly side of Exterior street to the point of beginning, Being the same premises appropriated by the state for the barge canal terminal at East 138th street, Harlem river, in the borough and county of Bronx, city of New York, pursuant to the provisions of chapter seven hundred forty-six of the laws of New York nineteen hundred eleven, as amended, as shown on map of parcel number T-100, terminal contract number forty-four, approved by the canal board on December eighteen, nineteen hundred fourteen, and on file in the department of transportation of the state of New York.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39252" number="50470" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning at a point in the westerly side of Exterior street as at present laid out and distant three hundred twenty-one and ninety-one hundredths feet from the southwest corner of Exterior street and east 138th street as at present laid out; thence along the said westerly side of Exterior street south twelve degrees, thirty-seven minutes, ten seconds east, seventy-three and fifty-seven hundredths feet to a point in the northerly boundary line of lands owned or claimed by Bradley L. Eaton and Vashti G. his wife; thence along said northerly boundary line south sixty-three degrees, fifty-five minutes, eleven seconds west one hundred seventy-four and fifteen hundredths feet to a point in the pierhead and bulkhead line approved by the secretary of war in eighteen hundred ninety; thence along the said pierhead and bulkhead line north twenty-three degrees, twenty-four minutes, three seconds west, sixty-one and forty-eight hundredths feet more or less; thence north twenty-four degrees, fifty-five minutes, fifty seconds west, forty-three and fifty-two hundredths feet more or less along said pierhead line to a point in the southerly boundary line of lands owned or claimed by John J. Bell; thence north seventy-four degrees, twelve minutes, seventeen seconds east, one hundred ninety and sixty-two hundredths feet to the point of beginning, Being the same premises appropriated by the state for the barge canal terminal at east 138th street, Harlem river, borough of Bronx, county of Bronx, city of New York, pursuant to the provisions of chapter seven hundred forty-six of the laws of New York, nineteen hundred eleven, as amended, as shown on parcel number T-101, terminal contract number forty-four, approved by the canal board on December eighteen, nineteen hundred fourteen, and on file in the department of transportation of the state of New York.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39253" number="50471" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beginning at a point in the westerly side of Exterior street as at present laid out and distant one hundred thirty-four and sixty-nine hundredths feet southerly from the intersection of the said westerly side of Exterior street with the southerly side of east 138th street as at present laid out; thence running south twelve degrees, thirty-seven minutes, ten seconds east, one hundred eighty-seven and twenty-two hundredths feet more or less along said westerly line of Exterior street to a point in the northerly line of lands owned or claimed by the Harlem river lumber and woodworking company, thence along said boundary line south seventy-four degrees, twelve minutes, seventeen seconds west, one hundred ninety and sixty-two hundredths feet to a point in the pierhead and bulkhead line of the Harlem river approved by the secretary of war in eighteen hundred ninety; thence running north twenty-four degrees, fifty-five minutes, fifty seconds west, two hundred fifty-one and fifty-six hundredths feet more or less to a point in said line; thence north twenty-six degrees, no minutes, twenty-eight seconds west, thirteen and three hundredths feet more or less to the intersection of the southerly boundary line of land owned or claimed by long dock mill and elevator with said pierhead and bulkhead line; thence running along said southerly boundary line south eighty-nine degrees, nine minutes, ten seconds east, one hundred thirty-five and fifty hundredths feet more or less; thence south eighty-nine degrees, fifty-five minutes, ten seconds east, twenty-two and fifty hundredths feet more or less; thence south eighty-eight degrees, five minutes, ten seconds east, ninety-six and thirty-four hundredths feet more or less to the point of beginning, Being the same premises appropriated by the state for the barge canal terminal at east 138th street, Harlem river, borough of Bronx, county of Bronx, city of New York, pursuant to the provisions of chapter seven hundred forty-six of the laws of New York, nineteen hundred eleven, as amended, as shown on parcel number T-102, terminal contract number forty-four, approved by the canal board on December eighteen, nineteen hundred fourteen, and on file in the department of transportation of the state of New York. The Coenties Slip terminal, being all that tract or parcel of land, situate, lying and being in the borough of Manhattan, city of New York, state of New York, bounded and described as follows (all bearings being referred to the meridian of bureau of design and surveys, New York): Beginning at a point distant one hundred twenty-seven and seventy-six hundredths feet and south seventy-three degrees, no minutes, fifty-five seconds east from the point of intersection of the northerly building line of South street with the westerly building line of (westerly) Coenties Slip, which building lines were determined by the bureau of design and surveys, Manhattan and shown on their map dated November fifteen, nineteen hundred fifteen; thence north thirty degrees, forty-seven minutes, nineteen seconds east, two hundred ten and sixty-three hundredths feet to a point in a line approximately in the center of the slip between piers six and seven, said line intersecting the bulkhead line at a point fifty-two and twenty-six hundredths feet easterly from the easterly side of pier six, and intersecting the pierhead line at a point ninety-one and ninety-one hundredths feet easterly from the easterly side of pier six; thence along said line south sixty-two degrees, twenty-nine minutes, thirty-eight seconds east, to a point in the exterior boundary line of lands under water granted to the city of New York by the state of New York September twenty-eight, eighteen hundred seventy-one; thence southwesterly along said exterior boundary line to a point in a line approximately in the center of the slip between piers four and five, said line intersecting the pierhead line at a point one hundred eleven and thirty-eight hundredths feet westerly from the westerly side of pier five and intersecting the bulkhead at a point eighty-four and eighty-one hundredths feet westerly from the westerly side of pier five; thence along said line north forty-seven degrees, fifty-eight minutes, nineteen seconds west to a point in a line parallel to and distant ten feet from the existing bulkhead line between Broad street and (westerly) Coenties Slip, thence along said parallel line north forty-two degrees, forty-eight minutes, twenty-six seconds east, one hundred eighty-eight and fifty-seven hundredths feet to the point of beginning, Being the same premises appropriated by the state of New York for the barge canal terminal in the East river at the foot of Coenties Slip, in the borough of Manhattan, city and county of New York, pursuant to the provisions of chapter seven hundred forty-six of the laws of New York, nineteen hundred eleven, as amended, as shown on parcel number T-129, terminal contract number fifty-two, approved by the canal board on April twenty-four, nineteen hundred sixteen, and on file in the department of transportation of the state of New York. The Pier ninety-three at west fifty-third street, being all that tract, piece or parcel of land situate, lying and being in the borough of Manhattan, city of New York, state of New York, bounded and described as follows: Beginning at a point 239.5 feet westerly from the easterly side of Twelfth Avenue, said point being 107.92 feet northerly from the northerly side of West 53rd Street produced; thence southerly from said point of beginning parallel to the easterly side of Twelfth Avenue 275.83 feet; thence westerly and parallel to the southerly side of West 53rd Street produced 760.5 feet, more or less, to a point in the exterior line of land under water granted to the city of New York by the state of New York in eighteen hundred seventy-one; thence northerly along said exterior line 275.83 feet, more or less, to a point in a line parallel to and distant 107.92 feet from the northerly side of West 53rd Street produced; thence easterly along said parallel line 760.5 feet, more or less, to the point of beginning, containing 209,771 square feet, more or less, as shown upon a certain map made by the state engineer of the state of New York, marked &quot;T-130&quot;. Being the same premises that were conveyed to the people of the state of New York by the city of New York by deed dated February sixteen, nineteen hundred seventeen, and recorded, together with the said map marked &quot;T-130&quot;, in the New York County Register&apos;s office on April seven, nineteen hundred seventeen, in liber three thousand two of deeds at page two hundred fifty-four.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39254" number="50472" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-143 Transfer. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9919" name="22-143"/>§ 22-143 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Transfer. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39255" number="50473" version="680">
												<PARA>Upon the adoption of a resolution by the board of estimate, pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-c" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred ninety-seven-c</LINK> of the charter, signifying acceptance of such pier properties and subject to the following conditions, and upon the delivery of a certified copy of such resolution to the secretary of state of the state of New York, all right, title and interest of the state of New York in and to such pier properties and appurtenances thereto and in to the equipment, chattels and other tangible property thereat and used in the operation thereof, and in and to the rents and revenues thereof which shall accrue from and after vesting of title as herein provided, shall thereby vest in the city: </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39256" number="50474" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>That the city shall rehabilitate such pier properties.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39257" number="50475" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>That the city shall not use or permit the use of such pier properties for any purpose which will materially and substantially interfere with their use for pier and terminal purposes.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39258" number="50476" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>That the city shall not grant or convey title to such pier properties to any person or legal entity other than the state.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39259" number="50477" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-144 Executory contracts. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9921" name="22-144"/>§ 22-144 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Executory contracts. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39260" number="50478" version="3">
												<PARA>Upon the vesting in the city of the right, title and interest of the state in and to such pier properties and as an incident thereto, there shall also vest in the city all the right, title and interest of the state in and to and in connection with any and all executory contracts and agreements in connection with such pier properties except as to moneys and rights accrued thereunder at the time of vesting of title as herein provided.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39261" number="50479" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-145 Violation of conditions. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9923" name="22-145"/>§ 22-145 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Violation of conditions. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39262" number="50480" version="3">
												<PARA>If the city shall violate any of the conditions set forth in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-143" destination-id="0-0-0-9919">22-143</LINK> of this subchapter, then at the option of the state the particular pier property or pier properties with respect to which or out of the operation of which such violation arises shall revert to the state; provided, that the state shall within a reasonable time after the discovery of such violation serve written notice upon the city requesting that such violation be remedied, and provided further, that the city shall fail to remedy such violation within a reasonable time thereafter; provided further, however, that the commissioner of general services is hereby authorized to grant and convey to the city of New York the remaining right, title and interest of the state of New York in a particular pier property or all such properties, free of the conditions and restrictions contained in sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-143" destination-id="0-0-0-9919">22-143</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-144" destination-id="0-0-0-9921">22-144</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-146" destination-id="0-0-0-9925">22-146</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-147" destination-id="0-0-0-9927">22-147</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-148" destination-id="0-0-0-9929">22-148</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-149" destination-id="0-0-0-9931">22-149</LINK> of this subchapter, upon such other terms and conditions, including consideration, as he or she may fix and determine and such property may be used for any and all purposes permitted by law.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39263" number="50481" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-146 State lands in case of reverter. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9925" name="22-146"/>§ 22-146 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">State lands in case of reverter. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39264" number="50482" version="3">
												<PARA>The pier properties, if any, which revert to the state pursuant to this subchapter shall be and shall be deemed to be unappropriated state lands.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39265" number="50483" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-147 Rehabilitation of pier properties. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9927" name="22-147"/>§ 22-147 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rehabilitation of pier properties. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39266" number="50484" version="3">
												<PARA>The city of New York shall proceed with the rehabilitation of such pier properties as and when in its opinion it is practicable so to do. No failure on its part to rehabilitate any pier property or properties and no delay in the rehabilitation thereof, because of the non-availability of materials or any other reason for which the city is not responsible or over which it has no control, shall constitute a violation of condition (a) of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="22-143" destination-id="0-0-0-9919">22-143</LINK> of this subchapter.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39267" number="50485" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-148 Intent. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9929" name="22-148"/>§ 22-148 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Intent. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39268" number="50486" version="3">
												<PARA>It is the intent of this subchapter that the rehabilitation, maintenance and operation of such pier properties shall be in all respects for the benefit of the people of the state of New York and to provide needed transportation and terminal facilities so that their commerce and prosperity may be increased and their health and living conditions improved. The city is hereby declared to be and shall be regarded as performing an essential governmental function in rehabilitating, maintaining and operating such pier properties.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-39269" number="50487" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 22-149 Tax exemption. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-9931" name="22-149"/>§ 22-149 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Tax exemption. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-39270" number="50488" version="3">
												<PARA>No taxes shall be payable or required to be paid upon any of such pier properties or upon any interest therein or upon any other property, real or personal, acquired or used in connection therewith.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>