<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-209435" number="60663" version="1467">
			<HEADING>Chapter 10: Housing Development Project Reporting Requirements</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11669" name="T26C010"/>Chapter 10: Housing Development Project Reporting Requirements</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47720" number="60664" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-901 Definitions. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11671" name="26-901"/>§ 26-901 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47721" number="60665" version="3">
											<PARA>For the purposes of this chapter only, the following terms shall be defined as follows: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47722" number="60666" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;City financial assistance&quot; includes any loans, grants, tax credits, tax exemptions, tax abatements, subsidies, mortgages, debt forgiveness, land conveyances for less than appraised value, land value or other thing of value allocated, conveyed or expended by the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47723" number="60667" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Construction condition&quot; means:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47724" number="60668" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a violation of the New York city construction codes issued to a housing development project, a developer or a covered contractor of such housing development project, during the project work or within a five-year period following the completion of such project;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47725" number="60669" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a complaint related to the construction quality of a housing development project received by the department during the project work or within a five-year period following the completion of such project;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47726" number="60670" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a determination by the department, during the project work or within a five-year period following completion of such project, that the construction quality of a housing development project does not comply with applicable law or does not conform to customary standards for construction in the city of New York.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47727" number="60671" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Contractor&quot; means an individual, sole proprietorship, partnership, joint venture, corporation or other entity that enters into a contract or other agreement with or is otherwise engaged by a developer or the department to perform project work.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47728" number="60672" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Covered contractor&quot; means a contractor or subcontractor whose annual gross revenue for the immediately preceding tax year is not less than two million five hundred thousand dollars, calculated in accordance with 29 CFR § 779.266; provided, however that where an entity is a principal owner of, serves as principal officer of, conducts or participates directly or indirectly in the conduct of the affairs of such contractor or subcontractor and any other contractor or subcontractor, the annual gross revenue for the immediately preceding tax year for each such contractor or subcontractor shall be aggregated and, if such aggregated value is not less than two million five hundred thousand dollars, each such contractor or subcontractor shall be a covered contractor.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47729" number="60673" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Department&quot; means the department of housing preservation and development.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47730" number="60674" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Developer&quot; means an individual, sole proprietorship, partnership, joint venture, corporation or other entity that receives city financial assistance for a housing development project.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47731" number="60675" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f-1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>“Disposition project” means the construction of any residential building, residential facility, or residential structure that: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229840" number="60676" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>requires the sale, lease, exchange, or other disposition of real property of the city that is, or will be, under the jurisdiction of the department on the date of such sale, lease, exchange, or other disposition; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229839" number="60677" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>creates at least 1 dwelling unit; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229838" number="60678" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>is funded in whole or in part by loans, grants, tax credits, subsidies, mortgages, debt forgiveness, or other thing of value allocated, conveyed, or expended by the city, other than tax exemptions, tax abatements, land conveyances for less than appraised value, as-of-right assistance or benefits, or any assistance or benefits for which the amount is based on an evaluation of as-of-right assistance or benefits for which such project would have been eligible. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229837" number="60679" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Disqualified list&quot; means a list that identifies entities that are precluded by the department from being selected as developers where &quot;disqualified&quot; shall mean debarred, suspended or otherwise prohibited for any length of time. Such term shall also include a list of entities that are ineligible to be included on a list of prequalified contractors or subcontractors.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47732" number="60680" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Housing development project&quot; means construction, rehabilitation or alteration of any residential building, residential facility or residential structure by a developer (1) which creates or preserves at least one dwelling unit; (2) which is funded in whole or in part by city financial assistance other than non-discretionary tax abatements or benefits approved or administered in accordance with sections 421-a or 489 of the New York state real property tax law or other similar programs and (3) where the developer of such project was not selected more than five years prior to the effective date of this chapter. The term &quot;housing development project&quot; shall not include emergency repairs performed by or on behalf of the department pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="27-2125" destination-id="0-0-0-11673">27-2125</LINK> of this code, work performed by or on behalf of the department pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="27-2153" destination-id="0-0-0-3127">27-2153</LINK> of this code, demolition work performed by or on behalf of the department pursuant to articles two hundred fifteen or two hundred sixteen of chapter two of title twenty-eight of this code, or work funded by the department pursuant to article seven-a of the New York state real property actions and proceedings law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47733" number="60681" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;List identifier&quot; means a description of the purpose for which a disqualified list or prequalified list is used by the department that shall include the types of housing development projects for which the list is used.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47734" number="60682" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>j.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Prequalified list&quot; means a list that identifies entities that are prequalified to be selected as developers and that was compiled, modified or used by the department to select developers within the immediately preceding five-year period; provided, however that the term &quot;prequalified list&quot; shall also include a list of entities that the department compiles and makes available to developers to assist in the selection of contractors and subcontractors to perform project work.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47735" number="60683" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>k.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Principal officer&quot; means an individual who serves as or performs the functions of chief executive officer, chief financial officer or chief operating officer of an entity.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47736" number="60684" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>l.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Principal owner&quot; means an individual, partnership, joint venture, corporation or other entity which holds a ten percent or greater ownership interest in an entity or holds an ownership interest as a general partner, managing partner or other position conducting or participating directly in the conduct of the affairs of an entity. The term &quot;principal owner&quot; shall not include a limited partner of a limited partnership or an equity investor in a limited liability company or a limited liability partnership where such equity investor does not conduct or participate directly in the conduct of the affairs of the limited liability company or limited liability partnership.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47737" number="60685" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>m.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Project identifier&quot; means a description of a housing development project sufficient to identify such project.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47738" number="60686" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>n.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Project work&quot; means construction, rehabilitation, alteration or demolition work performed in connection with a housing development project. Such term shall not include professional services including architectural, engineering, legal or accounting services or administrative, clerical or other similar office support services, or individuals solely engaged in managing, directing or supervising project work.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47739" number="60687" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>n-1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>“Sponsor” means a person or combination of persons designated by the department to develop a disposition project. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229841" number="60688" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>o.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Subcontractor&quot; means an individual, sole proprietorship, partnership, joint venture, corporation or other entity that enters into a contract or other agreement with or is otherwise engaged by a contractor, the department or other entity to perform project work.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229836" number="60689" version="2128">
											<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2024/125, 12/18/2024, eff. 12/18/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47740" number="60690" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-902 Reporting on prequalified lists and disqualified lists. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11675" name="26-902"/>§ 26-902 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Reporting on prequalified lists and disqualified lists. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47741" number="60691" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each prequalified list, the department shall make available on its website the list identifier and the criteria used by the department to determine whether an entity qualifies for such list.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47742" number="60692" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each disqualified list, the department shall make available on its website the list identifier, the name and address of each entity on such list and the name and title of each principal officer and principal owner of such entity and the criteria used by the department to determine whether an entity is disqualified.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47743" number="60693" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-903 Reporting on housing development projects. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11677" name="26-903"/>§ 26-903 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Reporting on housing development projects. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47744" number="60694" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each housing development project, the developer shall provide to the department, and the department shall make available on its website the following information in a non-proprietary format that permits automated processing: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47745" number="60695" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the project identifier;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47746" number="60696" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the program name as identified by the department and the list identifiers of all prequalified lists used in connection with such program;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47747" number="60697" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the address; block; lot number; stories; square footage of the building at its base; the number of proposed dwelling units including the number of bedrooms, disaggregated by income limits and all initial legal and actual rents; and the number of proposed commercial units;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47748" number="60698" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the source, type and value of all city financial assistance and other financial assistance provided by the city, disaggregated by source and type;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47749" number="60699" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the anticipated completion date of such project;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47750" number="60700" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>for the developer, contractors and subcontractors for such project:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47751" number="60701" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the name and address;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47752" number="60702" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the name and title of each principal officer and principal owner of such developer, contractor or subcontractor and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47753" number="60703" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>when applicable, whether the wage information described by subdivision a of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-904" destination-id="0-0-0-11679">26-904</LINK> of this chapter has been provided to the department for such developer, contractor or subcontractor;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47754" number="60704" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the developer was prequalified at the time of selection;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47755" number="60705" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the method used to select the developer including, but not limited to, direct negotiation, request for proposals, competitive bidding, public bidding, auction, selection by entities other than the department, and application;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47756" number="60706" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the criteria used to evaluate potential developers and to select the developer;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47757" number="60707" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(10)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the developer or contractor executed any legal documents subjecting any of the project work to section 220 of the New York state labor law;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47758" number="60708" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(11)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the developer or contractor executed any legal documents subjecting any of the project work to subchapter IV of chapter thirty-one of part A of subtitle II of Title 40 of the United States Code or any applicable regulations or rules;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47759" number="60709" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(12)<TAB tab-count="1"/>To the extent known to the department, based on information reported to the department by the developer that the department reasonably believes to be correct and complete, a description of the final outcome of any judicial actions or proceedings, including any final judgment rendered or settlement, with respect to section 220 of the New York state labor law or subchapter IV of chapter thirty-one of part A of subtitle II of Title 40 of the United States Code or any applicable regulations or rules, within the five-year period immediately preceding developer selection by the department, against the developer, the current principal owner or principal officer thereof, or the former principal owner or principal officer thereof if such person held such position or status within the five-year period immediately preceding developer selection by the department;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47760" number="60710" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(13)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the completion date of the project; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47761" number="60711" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(14)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the total number of construction conditions and for each such condition, the nature of the condition and a description of any remedial actions taken, ordered or requested with respect to such condition.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47762" number="60712" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For housing development projects where the developer was selected after the effective date of this chapter, the department shall update the information required by subdivision a of this section every six months until completion of such project except that the information required by paragraph fourteen shall be updated every six months until five years after completion of such project.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47763" number="60713" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For housing development projects where the developer was selected prior to the effective date of this chapter, the department shall make available the information required by subdivision a of this section no later than January 1, 2014 and shall update such information every six months thereafter until completion of such project except that:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47764" number="60714" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the information required by paragraph six for subcontractors shall be limited to subcontractors that entered into a contract or other agreement with or were otherwise engaged by a contractor or the department; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47765" number="60715" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the information required by paragraph fourteen shall be updated every six months until five years after completion of such project.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47766" number="60716" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than October 31, 2018, and by October 31 in each year thereafter, the department shall submit to the mayor and, by electronic mail, the council, and shall publish online, a report on housing development projects. Such report shall include, at a minimum, the following information for each housing development project; provided that such report need not include any housing development project that was completed more than five years before the date of such report or where the developer was selected before the effective date of the local law that added this subdivision: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47767" number="60717" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the project identifier; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47768" number="60718" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the address; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47769" number="60719" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the anticipated completion date or the actual completion date for completed projects; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47770" number="60720" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the name of the developer and each contractor; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47771" number="60721" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the information required by paragraph four of subdivision a of this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47772" number="60722" version="3">
											<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2017/202, 11/17/2017, eff. 5/18/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-025]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47773" number="60723" version="2128">
										<HEADING>§ 26-903.1 Reporting on disposition projects.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-27924" name="26-903.1"/>§ 26-903.1 Reporting on disposition projects.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229854" number="60724" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than January 31, 2026, and every 6 months thereafter, the department shall submit to the council and publish online a report containing the following information about each disposition project: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229853" number="60725" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The project identifier; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229852" number="60726" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The borough, block, and lot numbers; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229851" number="60727" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The date that the sponsor was designated by the department; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229850" number="60728" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The date of approval of the sale, lease, exchange, or other disposition of real property, pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-c" destination-id="0-0-0-0">197-c</LINK> or section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-d" destination-id="0-0-0-0">197-d</LINK> of the charter, or the date of waiver of the requirements set forth in sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-c" destination-id="0-0-0-0">197-c</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-d" destination-id="0-0-0-0">197-d</LINK> of the charter, pursuant to section 694 of the general municipal law, to such sale, lease, exchange, or other disposition; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229849" number="60729" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whether the disposition project includes privately-owned parcels; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229848" number="60730" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the sale, lease, exchange, or other disposition of real property has not occurred, the 6-month period during which such sale, lease, exchange, or other disposition is expected to occur; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229847" number="60731" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the sale, lease, exchange, or other disposition of real property has occurred, the date of such sale, lease, exchange, or other disposition of such real property and the amount of city financial assistance received by the sponsor of such disposition project. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229846" number="60732" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The report due on January 31, 2026 shall include disposition projects where the date of approval of the sale, lease, exchange, or other disposition of real property, pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-c" destination-id="0-0-0-0">197-c</LINK> or section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-d" destination-id="0-0-0-0">197-d</LINK> of the charter, or the date of waiver of the requirements set forth in sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-c" destination-id="0-0-0-0">197-c</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-d" destination-id="0-0-0-0">197-d</LINK> of the charter, pursuant to section 694 of the general municipal law, to such sale, lease, exchange, or other disposition, is after July 1, 2016 and before January 1, 2026. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229845" number="60733" version="2128">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each report due after January 31, 2026 shall include disposition projects where the date of approval of the sale, lease, exchange, or other disposition of real property, pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-c" destination-id="0-0-0-0">197-c</LINK> or section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-d" destination-id="0-0-0-0">197-d</LINK> of the charter, or the date of waiver of the requirements set forth in sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-c" destination-id="0-0-0-0">197-c</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-d" destination-id="0-0-0-0">197-d</LINK> of the charter, pursuant to section 694 of the general municipal law, to such sale, lease, exchange, or other disposition is after July 1, 2016, and, for the report due on July 31 of each year, before the preceding July 1, and for the report due on January 31 of each year, before the preceding January 1. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-229843" number="60734" version="2128">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2024/125, 12/18/2024, eff. 12/18/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-229842" number="60735" version="2128">
										<HEADING>§ 26-904 Wage information reporting. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11679" name="26-904"/>§ 26-904 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Wage information reporting. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47774" number="60736" version="3">
											<PARA>For all housing development projects where the developer of such project was selected after the effective date of this chapter, each such developer shall report to the department the information listed below at least quarterly:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47775" number="60737" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>for each individual employed or otherwise engaged to perform project work by the developer or any covered contractor:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47776" number="60738" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the individual&apos;s job title, position, or a description of the type of work performed by such person;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47777" number="60739" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the information described by subdivision three of section 195 of the New York state labor law which includes the name of the individual; the name of the employer; the address and phone number of the employer; the rate or rates of pay and basis thereof, whether paid by the hour, shift, day, week, salary, piece, commission, or otherwise; gross wages; deductions; allowances, if any, claimed as part of the minimum wage and net wages;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47778" number="60740" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>for each contractor or subcontractor that is not a covered contractor, a written certification under oath by a principal officer of such contractor or subcontractor that such contractor or subcontractor is not a covered contractor.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-47779" number="60741" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 26-905 Ineligibility for inclusion on prequalified lists. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11681" name="26-905"/>§ 26-905 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Ineligibility for inclusion on prequalified lists. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47780" number="60742" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to any other penalty provided by law, any contractor or subcontractor who fails to provide wage reporting information in accordance with section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="26-904" destination-id="0-0-0-11679">26-904</LINK> of this chapter shall be ineligible to be included on a prequalified list of contractors and subcontractors.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-47781" number="60743" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to any other penalty provided by law, any contractor or subcontractor with a history of construction conditions, as determined by the department, shall be ineligible to be included on a prequalified list of contractors and subcontractors.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>