<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-15474" number="18753" version="802">
			<HEADING>Chapter 25: Tax on Occupancy of Hotel Rooms</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2771" name="T11C025"/>Chapter 25: Tax on Occupancy of Hotel Rooms</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15475" number="18754" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2501 Definitions. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4393" name="11-2501"/>§ 11-2501 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15476" number="18755" version="3">
											<PARA>When used in this chapter the following terms shall mean or include:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15477" number="18756" version="1772">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Person.&quot; An individual, partnership, society, association, joint stock company, corporation, estate, receiver, trustee, assignee, referee, or any other person acting in a fiduciary or representative capacity, whether appointed by a court or otherwise and any combination of individuals or of the foregoing.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15478" number="18757" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Operator.&quot; Any person operating a hotel in the city of New York, including, but not limited to, the owner or proprietor of such premises, lessee, sublessee, mortgagee in possession, licensee or any other person otherwise operating such hotel.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15479" number="18758" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Occupant.&quot; A person who, for a consideration, uses, possesses, or has the right to use or possess, any room or rooms in a hotel under any lease, concession, permit, right of access, license to use or other agreement, or otherwise. &quot;Right to use or possess&quot; includes the rights of a room remarketer as described in subdivision twelve of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15480" number="18759" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Occupancy.&quot; The use or possession, or the right to the use or possession of any room or rooms in a hotel, or the right to the use or possession of the furnishings or to the services and accommodations accompanying the use and possession of the room or rooms. &quot;Right to the use or possession&quot; includes the rights of a room remarketer as described in subdivision twelve of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15481" number="18760" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Hotel.&quot; A building or portion of it which is regularly used and kept open as such for the lodging of guests. The term &quot;hotel&quot; includes an apartment hotel, a motel, boarding house or club, whether or not meals are served.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15482" number="18761" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Room.&quot; Any room of any kind, other than a bathroom or lavatory, in any part or portion of a hotel which is available for, or let out for, use or possession for any purpose other than a place of assembly as defined in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="27-232" destination-id="0-0-0-2487">27-232</LINK> of the code.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15483" number="18762" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Rent.&quot; The consideration received for occupancy valued in money, whether received in money or otherwise, including all receipts, cash, credits, and property or services of any kind or nature, including any service or other charge or amount required to be paid as a condition for occupancy, and also any amount for which credit is allowed by the operator or room remarketer to the occupant, without any deduction therefrom whatsoever, whether received by the operator or a room remarketer or another person on behalf of either of them.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15484" number="18763" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Permanent resident.&quot; Any occupant of any room or rooms in a hotel for at least one hundred eighty consecutive days shall be considered a permanent resident with regard to the period of such occupancy.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15485" number="18764" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Commissioner of finance.&quot; The commissioner of finance of the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15486" number="18765" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>10.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Comptroller.&quot; The comptroller of the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15487" number="18766" version="679">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>11.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Tax appeals tribunal.&quot; The tax appeals tribunal established by section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="168" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred sixty-eight</LINK> of the charter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15488" number="18767" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>12.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Room remarketer.&quot; A person who reserves, arranges for, conveys, or furnishes occupancy, whether directly or indirectly, to an occupant for rent in an amount determined by such room remarketer, directly or indirectly, whether pursuant to a written or other agreement. Such person&apos;s ability or authority to reserve, arrange for, convey, or furnish occupancy, directly or indirectly, and to determine rent therefor, shall be the &quot;rights of a room remarketer&quot;. A room remarketer is not a permanent resident with respect to a room for which such person has the rights of a room remarketer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15489" number="18768" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>13.<TAB tab-count="1"/>[Repealed.]</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15490" number="18769" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>14.<TAB tab-count="1"/>[Repealed.]</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-206064" number="18770" version="1400">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/043" destination-id="0-0-0-24910">L.L. 2009/043</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-083]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-206065" number="18771" version="1400">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2502 Imposition of tax. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4395" name="11-2502"/>§ 11-2502 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Imposition of tax. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15492" number="18772" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>On and after July first, nineteen hundred seventy until and including August thirty-first, nineteen hundred eighty, there is hereby imposed and there shall be paid a tax for every occupancy of each room in a hotel in the city of New York at the rates set forth in, and determined in accordance with the following table:<LINEBRK/>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15493" number="18773" version="1810">
											<PARA>
												<TABLE>
													<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2" left-border-space="43" left-border-width="15" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="43" right-border-width="15" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="43" top-border-width="15" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="43" bottom-border-width="15" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="43" horizontal-border-width="15" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="43" vertical-border-width="15" vertical-border-color="#000000">
														<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="20" percentage="yes"/>
														<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="20" percentage="yes"/>
													</TABLEFORMAT>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>If the rent per day for the room is:</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>The tax is:</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>Less than $10</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$.25 per day</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$10 or more, but less than $15</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$.50 per day</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$15 or more, but less than $20</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$.75 per day</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$20 or more</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$1.00 per day</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
												</TABLE>
											</PARA>
											<PARA>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15494" number="18774" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>On and after September first, nineteen hundred eighty, there is hereby imposed and there shall be paid a tax for every occupancy of each room in a hotel in the city of New York at the rates set forth in, and determined in accordance with, the following table:<LINEBRK/>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15495" number="18775" version="1810">
											<PARA>
												<TABLE>
													<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2" left-border-space="43" left-border-width="15" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="43" right-border-width="15" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="43" top-border-width="15" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="43" bottom-border-width="15" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="43" horizontal-border-width="15" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="43" vertical-border-width="15" vertical-border-color="#000000">
														<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="20" percentage="yes"/>
														<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="20" percentage="yes"/>
													</TABLEFORMAT>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>If the rent per day for the room is:</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>The tax is:</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$10 or more, but less than $20</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$.50 per day</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$20 or more, but less than $30</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$1.00 per day</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$30 or more, but less than $40</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$1.50 per day</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
													<ROW>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$40 or more</PARA>
														</COL>
														<COL>
															<PARA>$2.00 per day</PARA>
														</COL>
													</ROW>
												</TABLE>
											</PARA>
											<PARA>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15496" number="18776" version="3">
											<PARA>Where a person occupies a room for less than a full day and pays less than the rent for a full day, the tax shall nevertheless be the same amount as would be due had such person occupied the room for a full day at the rent for a full day. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15497" number="18777" version="1949">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to the tax imposed by paragraph two of this subdivision, there is hereby imposed and there shall be paid a tax for every occupancy of each room in a hotel in the city of New York (A) at the rate of five percent of the rent or charge per day for each such room up to and including August thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety, (B) at the rate of six percent of the rent or charge per day for each such room on and after September first, nineteen hundred ninety and before December first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, (C) at the rate of five percent of the rent or charge per day for each such room on and after December first, nineteen hundred ninety-four and before March first, two thousand nine, (D) at the rate of five and seven-eighths percent of the rent or charge per day for each such room on and after March first, two thousand nine and before December first, two thousand thirteen, (E) at the rate of five percent of the rent or charge per day for each such room on and after December first, two thousand thirteen and before December twentieth, two thousand thirteen, (F) at the rate of five and seven-eighths percent of the rent or charge per day for each such room on and after December twentieth, two thousand thirteen and before December first, two thousand twenty-seven, and (G) at the rate of five percent of the rent or charge per day for each such room on and after December first, two thousand twenty-seven. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-091]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15498" number="18778" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When occupancy is provided, for a single consideration, with property, services, amusement charges, or any other items, the separate sale of which is not subject to tax under this chapter, the entire consideration shall be treated as rent subject to tax under paragraph one of this subdivision; provided, however, that where the amount of the rent for occupancy is stated separately from the price of such property, services, amusement charges or other items on any sales slip, invoice, receipt, or other statement given the occupant and such rent is reasonable in relation to the value of such property, services, amusement charges, or other items, only such separately stated rent will be subject to tax under this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15499" number="18779" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In regard to the collection of tax on occupancies by remarketers, when occupancy is provided, for a single consideration, with property, services, amusement charges, or any other items, whether or not such other items are taxable, the rent portion of the consideration for such sale shall be computed as follows: the total consideration for the sale multiplied by a fraction, the numerator of which shall be the consideration paid to the hotel for the occupancy and the denominator of which shall be the consideration paid to the hotel for the occupancy plus the consideration paid to the providers of the other items being sold, or by any other reasonable method pursuant to which the rent portion of consideration would be no less than the computation of rent portion of consideration under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph. Nothing herein shall be construed to subject to tax or exempt from tax any service or property or amusement charge or other items otherwise subject to tax or exempt from tax under this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15500" number="18780" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A room remarketer shall be allowed a refund or credit against the taxes collected and required to be remitted pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2505" destination-id="0-0-0-4397">11-2505</LINK> of this chapter in the amount of the tax it paid to the operator of the hotel or another room remarketer under this subdivision. Provided, however, that in order to qualify for a refund or credit under this paragraph with respect to any quarterly period, as described in subdivision a of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2504" destination-id="0-0-0-4399">11-2504</LINK> of this chapter, the room remarketer must, with respect to such quarter, (i) be registered for hotel room occupancy tax purposes under section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2514" destination-id="0-0-0-4401">11-2514</LINK> of this chapter, and (ii) collect the taxes imposed by paragraphs two and three of this subdivision. Subject to the conditions and limitations of this paragraph, the provisions of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2507" destination-id="0-0-0-4403">11-2507</LINK> of this chapter shall apply to refunds or credits under this paragraph.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15501" number="18781" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where the rent is paid or charged or billed, or falls due on either a weekly, monthly or other term basis, the daily rent upon which the tax is determined shall be the result obtained by dividing the rent for such term by the number of days in such term. Where the rent is for more than one room, including but not limited to a suite of rooms, the daily rent per room upon which tax is determined shall be calculated by multiplying the daily rent for the group of rooms by a fraction, the numerator of which shall be the daily rent for the particular room, or a similar room, when such room is rented alone with similar bath facilities, and the denominator of which shall be the total of the daily rent for the individual rooms in the group of rooms, or similar rooms, when such rooms are rented alone with similar bath facilities. In any case in which it is not possible to determine the daily rent per room in the foregoing manner, the commissioner of finance shall prescribe methods for making such determination. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15502" number="18782" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No tax shall be imposed hereunder upon a permanent resident.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15503" number="18783" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of this subdivision, an occupant who is eligible to request and has requested a lease pursuant to the provisions of paragraph two of subdivision (a) of section 2522.5 of the rent stabilization regulations promulgated by the division of housing and community renewal of the state of New York (title nine, subtitle S, chapter VIII of the official compilation of codes, rules and regulations of the state of New York), shall tentatively be accorded the status of permanent resident as of the date of such request, notwithstanding that such occupant has not met the one hundred eighty-consecutive-day requirement contained in subdivision eight of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2501" destination-id="0-0-0-4393">11-2501</LINK> of this chapter as of such date. In the case of such an occupant, the operator or room remarketer shall not collect the taxes imposed by this chapter for any day, commencing with the date such lease is requested, which falls within a period of continuous occupancy by such occupant of a room or rooms in the hotel. Provided, however, if such occupant ceases to occupy a room or rooms in the hotel prior to the completion of one hundred eighty consecutive days of occupancy, any taxes not collected theretofore by reason of the provisions of this paragraph shall become immediately due and payable on the date of cessation of occupancy and shall be collected by the operator or room remarketer from such occupant. In the event, however, that the operator or room remarketer is unable to collect such taxes from the occupant, the operator or room remarketer shall not be liable to the city for such taxes. The provisions of this paragraph shall apply with respect to leases requested on or after September first, nineteen hundred ninety.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15504" number="18784" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No tax shall be imposed hereunder upon any organization described in subdivision (a) of section eleven hundred sixteen of the tax law to the extent such organization is not subject to the tax imposed under subdivision (e) of section eleven hundred five of the tax law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15505" number="18785" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No tax shall be imposed hereunder upon any person occupying any room or rooms in a hotel solely and directly as a result of such person&apos;s involuntary displacement from premises by the attack on the World Trade Center on September eleventh, two thousand one, provided such premises were not subject to the tax imposed by this section or the tax imposed under section eleven hundred seven of the tax law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15506" number="18786" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where an occupant claims exemption from the tax under the provisions of paragraph one of this subdivision, the rent shall be deemed taxable hereunder unless the operator shall receive from the occupant claiming such exemption a signed written statement describing the specific circumstances providing the basis for such claim and containing such other information as the commissioner of finance may require. The operator shall retain such statement and provide it to the commissioner of finance upon request.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15507" number="18787" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where any corporation, or association, or trust, or community chest, fund or foundation, organized and operated exclusively for religious, charitable, or educational purposes, or for the prevention of cruelty to children or animals, and no part of the net earnings of which inures to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual and no substantial part of the activities of which is carrying on propaganda, or otherwise attempting to influence legislation, carries on its activities in furtherance of any of the purposes for which it was organized, in premises in which, as part of said activities, it operates a hotel, occupancy of rooms in said premises and rents therefrom received by such corporation or association shall not be subject to tax hereunder. Nothing in this subdivision shall be deemed to include an organization operated for the primary purpose of carrying on a trade or business for profit, whether or not all of its profits are payable to one or more organizations described in this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15508" number="18788" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The tax to be collected shall be stated separately from the rent on a sales slip, invoice, receipt, or other statement of the price (&quot;invoice&quot;) given to the occupant prior to the occupant&apos;s completion of his or her occupancy and be verifiable from the books and records of an operator or room remarketer responsible for collecting and remitting the tax.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15509" number="18789" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where an occupant rents a room directly from an operator, the tax shall be paid by the occupant to the operator as trustee for and on account of the city, and the operator shall be liable for the collection of the tax on the rent and for the payment of the tax on the rent.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15510" number="18790" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The operator or room remarketer and any officer of any corporate operator or room remarketer shall be personally liable for the portion of the tax collected or required to be collected under this chapter, and the operator shall have the same right in respect to collecting the tax from the occupant, or in respect to nonpayment of the tax by the occupant as if the tax were a part of the rent for the occupancy payable at the time such tax shall become due and owing, including all rights of eviction, dispossession, repossession and enforcement of any innkeeper&apos;s lien that he or she may have in the event of nonpayment of rent by the occupant; provided however, that the commissioner of finance shall be joined as a party in any action or proceeding brought by the operator to collect or enforce collection of the tax.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15511" number="18791" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where the occupant has failed to pay and the operator or room marketer has failed to collect a tax as imposed by this chapter, then in addition to all other rights, obligations and remedies provided, such tax shall be payable by the occupant directly to the commissioner of finance, and it shall be the duty of the occupant to file a return thereof with the commissioner of finance and to pay the tax imposed therein to the commissioner of finance within fifteen days after such tax was due.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15512" number="18792" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of finance may, wherever he or she deems it necessary for the proper enforcement of this chapter, provide by regulation that the occupant shall file returns and pay directly to the commissioner of finance the tax herein imposed, at such times as returns are required to be filed and payment over made by the operator or room remarketer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15513" number="18793" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid upon any occupancy on and after July first, nineteen hundred seventy, although such occupancy is had pursuant to a contract, lease or other arrangement made prior to such effective date. Where rent is paid, or charged or billed, or falls due on either a weekly, monthly, or other term basis, the rent so paid, charged, billed or falling due shall be subject to the tax herein imposed to the extent that it covers any portion of the period on and after July first, nineteen hundred seventy, and such payment, bill, charge or rent due shall be apportioned on the basis of the ratio of the number of days falling within said period, to the total number of days covered thereby. Where any tax has been paid hereunder upon any rent which has been ascertained to be worthless, the commissioner of finance may by regulation provide for credit and/or refund of the amount of such tax upon application therefor as provided in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2507" destination-id="0-0-0-4403">11-2507</LINK> of this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15514" number="18794" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>j.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the purpose of the proper administration of this chapter and to prevent evasion of the tax hereby imposed, it shall be presumed that all rents are subject to tax until the contrary is established, and the burden of proving that a rent for occupancy is not taxable hereunder shall be upon the operator, the room remarketer, or the occupant. Where an occupant claims exemption from the tax under the provisions of subdivision c of this section, the rent shall be deemed taxable hereunder unless the operator or room remarketer shall receive from the occupant claiming such exemption a copy of the exempt organization certificate that is necessary to obtain exemption from the tax imposed under subdivision (e) of section eleven hundred five of the tax law, together with a certificate duly executed by the organization named in such certificate certifying that the occupant is its agent, representative or employee and that his or her occupancy is paid or to be paid by, and is necessary or required in the course of or in connection with the affairs of said organization.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15515" number="18795" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>k.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No operator or room remarketer shall advertise or hold out to the public in any manner, directly or indirectly, that the tax imposed by this chapter is not considered as a mandatory addition to the rent charged to the occupant.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15516" number="18796" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>l.<TAB tab-count="1"/>An occupancy that an operator conveys or furnishes to a room remarketer that the room remarketer intends to convey or furnish, directly or indirectly, to an occupant for rent shall be exempt from the taxes imposed by this section, provided that such room remarketer furnishes the operator with a certificate in such form and containing such information as may be prescribed by the commissioner of finance. The operator shall retain such statement and provide it to the commissioner of finance upon request. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-012]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15518" number="18797" version="1949">
											<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2015/112, 11/30/2015, eff. 11/30/2015; Am. 2016 N.Y. Laws Ch. 60, 4/13/2016, eff. 4/13/2016; Am. L.L. 2019/207, 11/27/2019, eff. 11/27/2019; Am. L.L. 2023/153, 11/17/2023, eff. 11/17/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-091]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226234" number="18798" version="1949">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1986/069" destination-id="0-0-0-27232">L.L. 1986/069</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/043" destination-id="0-0-0-24910">L.L. 2009/043</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-206066" number="18799" version="1400">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2503 Records to be kept. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4405" name="11-2503"/>§ 11-2503 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Records to be kept. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15519" number="18800" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every operator and every room remarketer shall keep records of every occupancy and of all rent paid, charged or due thereon and of the tax payable thereon, in such form as the commissioner of finance may by regulation require. Such records shall be available for inspection and examination at any time upon demand by the commissioner of finance or his or her duly authorized agent or employee and shall be preserved for a period of three years, except that the commissioner of finance may consent to their destruction within that period or may require that they be kept longer. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15520" number="18801" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the provisions of section three hundred five and three hundred nine of the state technology law or any other law, the commissioner may require any person who has elected to maintain in an electronic format any portion of the records required to be maintained by that person under this chapter, to make the electronic records available and accessible to the commissioner, notwithstanding that the records are also maintained in a hard copy format. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15521" number="18802" version="1400">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/043" destination-id="0-0-0-24910">L.L. 2009/043</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-083]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-206067" number="18803" version="1400">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2504 Returns. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4399" name="11-2504"/>§ 11-2504 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Returns. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15522" number="18804" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every operator and every room remarketer shall file with the commissioner of finance a return of occupancy and of rents, and of the taxes payable thereon, for the quarterly periods ending on the last day of February, May, August and November of each year. Such returns shall be filed within twenty days after the end of the quarterly period covered thereby. The commissioner of finance may permit or require returns to be made by other periods and upon such dates as he or she may specify. If the commissioner of finance deems it necessary in order to insure the payment of the tax imposed by this chapter, he or she may require returns to be made for shorter periods than those prescribed pursuant to the foregoing provisions of this subdivision and upon such dates as he or she may specify. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15523" number="18805" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The forms of returns shall be prescribed by the commissioner of finance and shall contain such information as he or she may deem necessary for the proper administration of this chapter. The commissioner of finance may require amended returns to be filed within twenty days after notice and to contain the information specified in the notice.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15524" number="18806" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If a return required by this chapter is not filed or if a return when filed is incorrect or insufficient on its face the commissioner of finance shall take the necessary steps to enforce the filing of such a return or a corrected return. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15525" number="18807" version="1400">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/043" destination-id="0-0-0-24910">L.L. 2009/043</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-083]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-206068" number="18808" version="1400">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2505 Payment of tax. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4397" name="11-2505"/>§ 11-2505 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Payment of tax. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15526" number="18809" version="3">
											<PARA>At the time of filing a return of occupancy and of rents each operator and room remarketer shall pay to the commissioner of finance the taxes imposed by this chapter upon the rents required to be included in such return, as well as all other moneys collected by the operator or room remarketer acting or purporting to act under the provisions of this chapter, even though it be judicially determined that the tax collected is invalidly imposed. All the taxes for the period for which a return is required to be filed shall be due from the operator or room remarketer and payable to the commissioner of finance on the date limited for the filing of the return for such period, without regard to whether a return is filed or whether the return which is filed correctly shows the amount of rents and the taxes due thereon. Where the commissioner of finance in his or her discretion deems it necessary to protect revenues to be obtained under this chapter he or she may require any operator or room remarketer required to collect the tax imposed by this chapter to file with him or her a bond, issued by a surety company authorized to transact business in this state and approved by the superintendent of insurance of this state as to solvency and responsibility, in such amount as the commissioner of finance may fix, to secure the payment of any tax and/or penalties and interest due or which may become due from such operator or room remarketer. In the event that the commissioner of finance determines that an operator or room remarketer is to file such bond he or she shall give notice to such operator or room remarketer to that effect specifying the amount of the bond required. The operator or room remarketer shall file such bond within five days after the giving of such notice unless within such five days the operator or room remarketer shall request in writing a hearing before the commissioner of finance at which the necessity, propriety and amount of the bond shall be determined by the commissioner of finance. Such determination shall be final and shall be complied with within fifteen days after the giving of notice thereof. In lieu of such bond, securities approved by the commissioner of finance or cash in such amount as he or she may prescribe, may be deposited which shall be kept in the custody of the commissioner of finance who may at any time without notice to the depositor apply them to any tax and/or interest or penalties due, and for that purpose the securities may be sold by him or her at public or private sale without notice to the depositor thereof.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15527" number="18810" version="1400">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/043" destination-id="0-0-0-24910">L.L. 2009/043</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-083]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-206069" number="18811" version="1400">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2506 Determination of tax. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4407" name="11-2506"/>§ 11-2506 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Determination of tax. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15528" number="18812" version="679">
											<PARA>If a return required by this chapter is not filed, or if a return when filed is incorrect or insufficient, the amount of tax due shall be determined by the commissioner of finance from such information as may be obtainable and, if necessary, the tax may be estimated on the basis of external indices, such as number of rooms, location, scale of rents, comparable rents, type of accommodations and service, number of employees and/or other factors. Notice of such determination shall be given to the person liable for the collection and/or payment of the tax. Such determination shall finally and irrevocably fix the tax unless the person against whom it is assessed, within ninety days after giving of notice of such determination, or, if the commissioner of finance has established a conciliation procedure pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-124" destination-id="0-0-0-2745">11-124</LINK> of the code and the taxpayer has requested a conciliation conference in accordance therewith, within ninety days from the mailing of a conciliation decision or the date of the commissioner&apos;s confirmation of the discontinuance of the conciliation proceeding, both (1) serves a petition upon the commissioner of finance and (2) files a petition with the tax appeals tribunal for a hearing, or unless the commissioner of finance of his or her own motion shall redetermine the same. Such hearing and any appeal to the tax appeals tribunal sitting en banc from the decision rendered in such hearing shall be conducted in the manner and subject to the requirements prescribed by the tax appeals tribunal pursuant to sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="168" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred sixty-eight</LINK> through <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="172" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred seventy-two</LINK> of the charter. After such hearing the tax appeals tribunal shall give notice of its decision to the person against whom the tax is assessed. A decision of the tax appeals tribunal sitting en banc shall be reviewable for error, illegality or unconstitutionality or any other reason whatsoever by a proceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules if application therefor is made to the supreme court by the person against whom the tax was assessed, within four months after the giving of the notice of such tax appeals tribunal decision. A proceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules shall not be instituted by a person liable for the tax unless: (a) the amount of any tax sought to be reviewed, with penalties and interest thereon, if any, shall be first deposited with the commissioner of finance and there shall be filed with the commissioner of finance an undertaking, issued by a surety company authorized to transact business in this state and approved by the superintendent of insurance of this state as to solvency and responsibility, in such amount as a justice of the supreme court shall approve, to the effect that if such proceeding be dismissed or the tax confirmed, such person will pay all costs and charges which may accrue in the prosecution of the proceeding; or (b) at the option of such person such undertaking filed with the commissioner of finance may be in a sum sufficient to cover the taxes, penalties and interest thereon stated in such decision plus the costs and charges which may accrue against it in the prosecution of the proceeding, in which event such person shall not be required to deposit such taxes, penalties and interest as a condition precedent to the application. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15529" number="18813" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2507 Refunds. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4403" name="11-2507"/>§ 11-2507 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Refunds. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15530" number="18814" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the manner provided in this section the commissioner of finance shall refund or credit, without interest, any tax, penalty or interest erroneously, illegally or unconstitutionally collected or paid if written application to the commissioner of finance for such refund shall be made within one year from the payment thereof. Whenever a refund or credit is made or denied by the commissioner of finance, he or she shall state his or her reasons therefor and give notice thereof to the taxpayer in writing. Such application may be made by the occupant, operator, room remarketer or other person who has actually paid the tax to the commissioner of finance. Such application may also be made by an operator or room remarketer who has collected and paid over such tax to the commissioner of finance provided that the application is made within one year of the payment by the occupant to the operator or room remarketer, but no actual refund of moneys shall be made to such operator or room remarketer until he or she shall first establish to the satisfaction of the commissioner of finance, under such regulations as the commissioner of finance may prescribe, that he or she has repaid to the occupant the amount for which the application for refund is made. The commissioner of finance may, in lieu of any refund required to be made, allow credit therefor on payments due from the applicant.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15531" number="18815" version="679">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any determination of the commissioner of finance denying a refund or credit pursuant to subdivision a of this section shall be final and irrevocable unless the applicant for such refund or credit, within ninety days from the mailing of notice of such determination, or, if the commissioner of finance, has established a conciliation procedure pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-124" destination-id="0-0-0-2745">11-124</LINK> and the applicant has requested a conciliation conference in accordance therewith, within ninety days from the mailing of a conciliation decision or the date of the commissioner&apos;s confirmation of the discontinuance of the conciliation proceeding, both (1) serves a petition upon the commissioner of finance and (2) files a petition with the tax appeals tribunal for a hearing. Such petition for a refund or credit, made as herein provided, shall be deemed an application for a revision of any tax, penalty or interest complained of. Such hearing and any appeal to the tax appeals tribunal sitting en banc from the decision rendered in such hearing shall be conducted in the manner and subject to the requirements prescribed by the tax appeals tribunal pursuant to sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="168" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred sixty-eight</LINK> through <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="172" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred seventy-two</LINK> of the charter. After such hearing, the tax appeals tribunal shall give notice of its decision to the applicant and to the commissioner of finance. The applicant shall be entitled to review such decision of the tax appeals tribunal sitting en banc by a proceeding pursuant to article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules, provided such proceeding is instituted within four months after the giving of the notice of such decision, and provided, in the case of an application by a person liable for the tax, that a final determination of tax was not previously made. Such a proceeding shall not be instituted by a person liable for the tax unless an undertaking is filed with the commissioner of finance in such amount and with such sureties as a justice of the supreme court shall approve to the effect that if such proceeding be dismissed or the tax confirmed, such person will pay all costs and charges which may accrue in the prosecution of such proceeding.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15532" number="18816" version="1772">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A person shall not be entitled to a revision, refund or credit under this section of a tax, interest or penalty which had been determined to be due pursuant to the provisions of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2506" destination-id="0-0-0-4407">11-2506</LINK> of this chapter where he or she has had a hearing or an opportunity for a hearing, as provided in said section, or has failed to avail himself or herself of the remedies therein provided. No refund or credit shall be made of a tax, interest or penalty paid after a determination by the commissioner of finance made pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2506" destination-id="0-0-0-4407">11-2506</LINK> of this chapter unless it be found that such determination was erroneous, illegal or unconstitutional or otherwise improper, by the tax appeals tribunal after a hearing or of the commissioner of finance&apos;s own motion, or, if such tax appeals tribunal affirms in whole or in part the determination of the commissioner of finance, in a proceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules, pursuant to the provision of said section, in which event refund or credit without interest shall be made of the tax, interest or penalty found to have been overpaid. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15533" number="18817" version="1400">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/043" destination-id="0-0-0-24910">L.L. 2009/043</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-083]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-206070" number="18818" version="1400">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2508 Reserves. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4409" name="11-2508"/>§ 11-2508 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Reserves. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15534" number="18819" version="3">
											<PARA>In cases where the occupant, operator or room remarketer has applied for a refund and has instituted a proceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules to review a determination adverse to such occupant, operator or room remarketer on his or her application for refund, the comptroller shall set up appropriate reserves to meet any decision adverse to the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15535" number="18820" version="1400">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/043" destination-id="0-0-0-24910">L.L. 2009/043</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-083]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-206071" number="18821" version="1400">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2509 Remedies exclusive. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4411" name="11-2509"/>§ 11-2509 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Remedies exclusive. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15536" number="18822" version="3">
											<PARA>The remedies provided by sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2506" destination-id="0-0-0-4407">11-2506</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2507" destination-id="0-0-0-4403">11-2507</LINK> of this chapter shall be the exclusive remedies available to any person for the review of tax liability imposed by this chapter; and no determination or proposed determination of tax or determination on any application for refund by the commissioner of finance, nor any decision by the tax appeals tribunal or any of its administrative law judges, shall be enjoined or reviewed by an action for declaratory judgment, and action for money had and received or by any action or proceeding other than, in the case of a decision by the tax appeals tribunal sitting en banc, a proceeding in the nature of a certiorari proceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules; provided, however, that a taxpayer may proceed by declaratory judgment if he or she institutes suit within thirty days after a deficiency assessment is made and pays the amount of the deficiency assessment to the commissioner of finance prior to the institution of such suit and posts a bond for costs as provided in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2506" destination-id="0-0-0-4407">11-2506</LINK> of this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15537" number="18823" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2510 Proceedings to recover tax. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4413" name="11-2510"/>§ 11-2510 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Proceedings to recover tax. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15538" number="18824" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever any operator or room remarketer, or any officer of a corporate operator or room remarketer, or any occupant or other person shall fail to collect and pay over any tax and/or to pay any tax, penalty or interest imposed by this chapter as therein provided, the corporation counsel shall, upon the request of the commissioner of finance bring or cause to be brought an action to enforce the payment of the same on behalf of the city of New York in any court of the state of New York or of any other state or of the United States. If, however, the commissioner of finance in his or her discretion believes that any such operator, or room remarketer, officer, occupant or other person is about to cease business, leave the state or remove or dissipate the assets out of which the tax, penalties or interest might be satisfied, and that any such tax, penalty or interest will not be paid when due, he or she may declare such tax, penalty or interest to be immediately due and payable and may issue a warrant immediately. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15539" number="18825" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>As an additional or alternate remedy, the commissioner of finance may issue a warrant, directed to the city sheriff commanding him or her to levy upon and sell the real and personal property of the operator or room remarketer or officer of a corporate operator or room remarketer or of the occupant or other person liable for the tax, which may be found within the city for the payment of the amount thereof, with any penalties and interest, and the cost of executing the warrant, and to return such warrant to the commissioner of finance and to pay to him or her the money collected by virtue thereof within sixty days after the receipt of such warrant. The city sheriff shall within five days after the receipt of the warrant file with the county clerk a copy thereof, and thereupon such clerk shall enter in the judgment docket the name of the person mentioned in the warrant and the amount of the tax, penalties and interest for which the warrant is issued and the date when such copy is filed. Thereupon the amount of such warrant so docketed shall become a lien upon the title to and interest in real and personal property of the person against whom the warrant is issued. The city sheriff shall then proceed upon the warrant, in the same manner, and with like effect, as that provided by law in respect to executions issued against property upon judgments of a court of record, and for services in executing the warrant such sheriff shall be entitled to the same fees, which he or she may collect in the same manner. In the discretion of the commissioner of finance a warrant of like terms, force and effect may be issued and directed to any officer or employee of the department of finance, and in the execution thereof such officer or employee shall have all the powers conferred by law upon sheriffs, but shall be entitled to no fee or compensation in excess of the actual expenses paid in the performance of such duty. If a warrant is returned not satisfied in full, the commissioner of finance may from time to time issue new warrants and shall also have the same remedies to enforce the amount due thereunder as if the city had recovered judgment therefor and execution thereon had been returned unsatisfied.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15540" number="18826" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever an operator shall make a sale, transfer, or assignment in bulk of any part or the whole of such operator&apos;s hotel or of his or her lease, license or other agreement or right to possess or operate such hotel, or of the equipment, furnishings, fixtures, supplies or stock of merchandise, or of the said premises or lease, license or other agreement or right to possess or operate such hotel and the equipment, furnishings, fixtures, supplies and stock of merchandise pertaining to the conduct or operation of said hotel, other- wise than in the ordinary and regular prosecution of business, the purchaser, transferee or assignee shall at least ten days before taking possession of the subject of said sale, transfer or assignment, or paying therefor, notify the commissioner of finance by registered mail of the proposed sale and of the price, terms and conditions thereof whether or not the seller, transferor or assignor, has represented to, or informed the purchaser, transferee or assignee that it owes any tax pursuant to this chapter, and whether or not the purchaser, transferee or assignee has knowledge that such taxes are owing, and whether any such taxes are in fact owing. Whenever the purchaser, transferee or assignee shall fail to give notice to the commissioner of finance as required by the preceding paragraph, or whenever the commissioner of finance shall inform the purchaser, transferee or assignee that a possible claim for such tax or taxes exists, any sums of money, property or choses in action, or other consideration, which the purchaser, transferee or assignee is required to transfer over to the seller, transferor or assignor shall be subject to a first priority right and lien for any such taxes theretofore or thereafter determined to be due from the seller, transferor or assignor to the city, and the purchaser, transferee or assignee is forbidden to transfer to the seller, transferor or assignor any such sums of money, property or choses in action to the extent of the amount of the city&apos;s claim. For failure to comply with the provisions of this subdivision, the purchaser, transferee or assignee, in addition to being subject to the liabilities and remedies imposed under the provisions of article six of the uniform commercial code, shall be personally liable for the payment to the city of any such taxes theretofore or thereafter determined to be due to the city from the seller, transferor or assignor, and such liability may be assessed and enforced in the same manner as the liability for tax under this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15541" number="18827" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of finance, if he or she finds that the interests of the city will not thereby be jeopardized, and upon such conditions as the commissioner of finance may require, may release any property from the lien of any warrant or vacate such warrant for unpaid taxes, additions to tax, penalties and interest filed pursuant to subdivision b of this section, and such release or vacating of the warrant may be recorded in the office of any recording officer in which such warrant has been filed. The clerk shall thereupon cancel and discharge as of the original date of docketing the vacated warrant. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15542" number="18828" version="1400">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/043" destination-id="0-0-0-24910">L.L. 2009/043</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-083]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-206072" number="18829" version="1400">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2511 General powers of the commissioner of finance. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4415" name="11-2511"/>§ 11-2511 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">General powers of the commissioner of finance. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15543" number="18830" version="3">
											<PARA>In addition to the powers granted to the commissioner of finance in this chapter, he or she is hereby authorized and empowered:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15544" number="18831" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To make, adopt and amend rules and regulations appropriate to the carrying out of this chapter and the purposes thereof;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15545" number="18832" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To extend, for cause shown, the time for filing any return for a period not exceeding thirty days; and to compromise disputed claims in connection with the taxes hereby imposed;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15546" number="18833" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To request information from the tax commission of the state of New York or the treasury department of the United States relative to any person; and to afford information to such tax commission or such treasury department relative to any person, any other provision of this chapter to the contrary notwithstanding;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15547" number="18834" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To delegate his or her functions hereunder to a commissioner or deputy commissioner in the department of finance or to any employee or employees of the department of finance;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15548" number="18835" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To prescribe methods for determining the rents for occupancy and to determine the taxable and non-taxable rents;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15549" number="18836" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To require any operator within the city to keep detailed records of the nature and type of hotel maintained and the nature and type of service rendered, and to require any operator or room remarketer to keep detailed records of the rooms available and rooms occupied daily, leases or occupancy contracts or arrangements, rents received, charged and accrued, the names and addresses of the occupants, whether or not any occupancy is claimed to be subject to the tax imposed by this chapter, and to furnish such information upon request to the commissioner of finance;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15550" number="18837" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To assess, determine, revise and readjust the taxes imposed under this chapter. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15551" number="18838" version="1400">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/043" destination-id="0-0-0-24910">L.L. 2009/043</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-083]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-206073" number="18839" version="1400">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2512 Administration of oaths and compelling testimony. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4417" name="11-2512"/>§ 11-2512 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Administration of oaths and compelling testimony. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15552" number="18840" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of finance, his or her employees or agents duly designated and authorized by him or her, the tax appeals tribunal and any of its duly designated and authorized employees or agents shall have power to administer oaths and take affidavits in relation to any matter or proceeding in the exercise of their powers and duties under this chapter. The commissioner of finance and the tax appeals tribunal shall have power to subpoena and require the attendance of witnesses and the production of books, papers and documents to secure information pertinent to the performance of the duties of the commissioner or the tax appeals tribunal hereunder and of the enforcement of this chapter and to examine them in relation thereto, and to issue commissions for the examination of witnesses who are out of the state of unable to attend before such commissioner or tax appeals tribunal or excused from attendance. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15553" number="18841" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A justice of the supreme court either in court or at chambers shall have power summarily to enforce by proper proceedings the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production and examination of books, papers and documents called for by the subpoena of the commissioner of finance or the tax appeals tribunal under this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15554" number="18842" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cross-reference; criminal penalties.</CHARFORMAT> For failure to obey subpoenas or for testifying falsely, see section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-4007" destination-id="0-0-0-3599">11-4007</LINK> of this title; for supplying false or fraudulent information, see section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-4009" destination-id="0-0-0-3647">11-4009</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15555" number="18843" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The officers who serve the summons or subpoena of the commissioner of finance or the tax appeals tribunal and witnesses attending in response thereto shall be entitled to the same fees as are allowed to officers and witnesses in civil cases in courts of record, except as herein otherwise provided. Such officers shall be the city sheriff and his or her duly appointed deputies or any officers or employees of the department of finance or the tax appeals tribunal, designated to serve such process. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15556" number="18844" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2513 Reference to tax. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4419" name="11-2513"/>§ 11-2513 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Reference to tax. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15557" number="18845" version="3">
											<PARA>Whenever reference is made in placards or advertisements or in any other publication to this tax, such reference shall be substantially in the following form: &quot;city tax on occupancy of hotel rooms&quot;, except that in any bill, receipt, statement or other evidence or memorandum of occupancy or rent charge issued or employed by the operator the words &quot;city tax&quot; will suffice.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15558" number="18846" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2514 Registration. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4401" name="11-2514"/>§ 11-2514 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Registration. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15559" number="18847" version="3">
											<PARA>By June thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy, or in the case of operators or room remarketers commencing business or opening new hotels after such date, within three days after such commencement or opening, or in the case of room remarketers doing business on the effective date of the local law that added this phrase, within three days of such effective date, every operator or room remarketer shall file with the commissioner of finance a certificate of registration in a form prescribed by the commissioner of finance. The commissioner of finance shall within five days after such registration issue without charge to each operator or room remarketer a certificate of authority empowering such operator or room remarketer to collect the tax from the occupant and duplicate thereof for each additional hotel or room remarketer of such operator. Each certificate or duplicate shall state the hotel or room remarketer to which it is applicable. Such certificates of authority shall be prominently displayed by the operator or room remarketer in such manner that it may be seen and come to the notice of all occupants and persons seeking occupancy. Such certificates shall be non-assignable and nontransferable and shall be surrendered immediately to the commissioner of finance upon the cessation of business at the hotel named, upon its sale or transfer, or upon cessation of business of the named room remarketer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15560" number="18848" version="1400">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/043" destination-id="0-0-0-24910">L.L. 2009/043</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-083]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-206074" number="18849" version="1400">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2515 Interest and penalties. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4421" name="11-2515"/>§ 11-2515 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Interest and penalties. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15561" number="18850" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Interest on underpayments. </CHARFORMAT>If any amount of tax is not paid or paid over on or before the last date prescribed for payment (without regard to any extension of time granted for payment), interest on such amount at the rate set by the commissioner of finance pursuant to subdivision (g) of this section, or, if no rate is set, at the rate of seven and one-half percent per annum, shall be paid for the period from such last date to the date of payment. In computing the amount of interest to be paid, such interest shall be compounded daily. Interest under this subdivision shall not be paid if the amount thereof is less than one dollar. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15562" number="18851" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Failure to file return. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15563" number="18852" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In case of failure to file a return under this chapter on or before the prescribed date (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not due to willful neglect, there shall be added to the amount required to be shown as tax on such return five percent of the amount of such tax if the failure is for not more than one month, with an additional five percent for each additional month or fraction thereof during which such failure continues, not exceeding twenty-five percent in the aggregate.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15564" number="18853" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of a failure to file a return of tax within sixty days of the date prescribed for filing of such return (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not due to willful neglect, the addition to tax under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall not be less than the lesser of one hundred dollars or one hundred percent of the amount required to be shown as tax on such return.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15565" number="18854" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of this paragraph, the amount of tax required to be shown on the return shall be reduced by the amount of any part of the tax which is paid on or before the date prescribed for payment of the tax and by the amount of any credit against the tax which may be claimed upon the return.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15566" number="18855" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Failure to pay tax shown on return.</CHARFORMAT> In case of failure to pay the amount shown as tax on a return required to be filed under this chapter on or before the prescribed date (determined with regard to any extension of time for payment), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not due to willful neglect, there shall be added to the amount shown as tax on such return one-half of one percent of the amount of such tax if the failure is not for more than one month, with an additional one-half of one percent for each additional month or fraction thereof during which such failure continues, not exceeding twenty-five percent in the aggregate. For the purpose of computing the addition for any month the amount of tax shown on the return shall be reduced by the amount of any part of the tax which is paid on or before the beginning of such month and by the amount of any credit against the tax which may be claimed upon the return. If the amount of tax required to be shown on a return is less than the amount shown as tax on such return, this paragraph shall be applied by substituting such lower amount.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15567" number="18856" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Failure to pay tax required to be shown on return.</CHARFORMAT> In case of failure to pay any amount in respect of any tax required to be shown on a return required to be filed under this chapter which is not so shown (including a determination made pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2506" destination-id="0-0-0-4407">11-2506</LINK> of this chapter) within ten days of the date of a notice and demand therefor, unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not due to willful neglect, there shall be added to the amount of tax stated in such notice and demand one-half of one percent of such tax if the failure is not for more than one month, with an additional one-half of one percent for each additional month or fraction thereof during which such failure continues, not exceeding twenty-five percent in the aggregate. For the purpose of computing the addition for any month, the amount of tax stated in the notice and demand shall be reduced by the amount of any part of the tax which is paid before the beginning of such month.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15568" number="18857" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Limitations on additions.</CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15569" number="18858" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to any return, the amount of the addition under paragraph one of this subdivision shall be reduced by the amount of the addition under paragraph two of this subdivision for any month to which an addition applies under both paragraphs one and two. In any case described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) of this subdivision, the amount of the addition under such paragraph (1) shall not be reduced below the amount provided in such paragraph.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15570" number="18859" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to any return, the maximum amount of the addition permitted under paragraph three of this subdivision shall be reduced by the amount of the addition under paragraph (1) of this subdivision (determined without regard to subparagraph (B) of such paragraph (1)) which is attributable to the tax for which the notice and demand is made and which is not paid within ten days of such notice and demand.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15571" number="18860" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Underpayment due to negligence.</CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15572" number="18861" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any part of an underpayment of tax is due to negligence or intentional disregard of this chapter or any rules or regulations hereunder (but without intent to defraud), there shall be added to the tax a penalty equal to five percent of the underpayment.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15573" number="18862" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be added to the tax (in addition to the amount determined under paragraph (1) of this subdivision) an amount equal to fifty percent of the interest payable under subdivision (a) of this section with respect to the portion of the underpayment described in such paragraph (1) which is attributable to the negligence or intentional disregard referred to in such paragraph (1), for the period beginning on the last date prescribed by law for payment of such underpayment (determined without regard to any extension) and ending on the date of the assessment of the tax (or, if earlier, the date of the payment of the tax).</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15574" number="18863" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Underpayment due to fraud.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15575" number="18864" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any part of an underpayment of tax is due to fraud, there shall be added to the tax a penalty equal to two times the underpayment.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15576" number="18865" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>[Repealed.]</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15577" number="18866" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The penalty under this subdivision shall be in lieu of any other addition to tax imposed by subdivision (b) or (c) of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15578" number="18867" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Additional penalty.</CHARFORMAT> Any person who, with fraudulent intent, shall fail to pay any tax imposed by this chapter, or to make, render, sign or certify any return, or to supply any information within the time required by or under this chapter, shall be liable for a penalty of not more than one thousand dollars, in addition to any other amounts required under this chapter to be imposed, assessed and collected by the commissioner of finance. The commissioner of finance shall have the power, in his or her discretion, to waive, reduce or compromise any penalty under this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15579" number="18868" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The interest and penalties imposed by this section shall be paid and disposed of in the same manner as other revenues from this chapter. Unpaid interest and penalties may be enforced in the same manner as the tax imposed by this chapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15580" number="18869" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Authority to set interest rates.</CHARFORMAT> The commissioner of finance shall set the rate of interest to be paid pursuant to subdivision (a) of this section, but if no such rate of interest is set, such rate shall be deemed to be set at seven and one-half percent per annum. Such rate shall be the rate prescribed in paragraph two of this subdivision but shall not be less than seven and one-half percent per annum. Any such rate set by the commissioner of finance shall apply to taxes, or any portion thereof, which remain or become due on or after the date on which such rate becomes effective and shall apply only with respect to interest computed or computable for periods or portions of periods occurring in the period in which such rate is in effect.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15581" number="18870" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">General rule.</CHARFORMAT> The rate of interest set under this subdivision shall be the sum of (i) the federal short-term rate as provided under paragraph three of this subdivision, plus (ii) seven percentage points.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15582" number="18871" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Federal short-term rate.</CHARFORMAT> For purposes of this subdivision:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15583" number="18872" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The federal short-term rate for any month shall be the federal short-term rate determined by the United States secretary of the treasury during such month in accordance with subsection (d) of section twelve hundred seventy-four of the internal revenue code for use in connection with section six thousand six hundred twenty-one of the internal revenue code. Any such rate shall be rounded to the nearest full percent (or, if a multiple of one-half of one percent, such rate shall be increased to the next highest full percent).</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15584" number="18873" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Period during which rate applies.</CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15585" number="18874" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">In general.</CHARFORMAT> Except as provided in clause (ii) of this subparagraph, the federal short-term rate for the first month in each calendar quarter shall apply during the first calendar quarter beginning after such month.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15586" number="18875" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Special rule for the month of September, nineteen hundred eighty-nine.</CHARFORMAT> The federal short-term rate for the month of April, nineteen hundred eighty-nine shall apply with respect to setting the rate of interest for the month of September, nineteen hundred eighty-nine.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15587" number="18876" version="679">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Publication of interest rate. The commissioner of finance shall cause to be published in the city record, and give other appropriate general notice of, the interest rate to be set under this subdivision no later than twenty days preceding the first day of the calendar quarter during which such interest rate applies. The setting and publication of such interest rate shall not be included within paragraph (a) of subdivision five of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="1041" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one thousand forty-one</LINK> of the city charter relating to the definition of a rule.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15588" number="18877" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Miscellaneous. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15589" number="18878" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Officers of a corporate operator or room remarketer and partners in a partnership which is an operator or room remarketer shall be personally liable for the tax collected or required to be collected by such corporation or partnership under this chapter, and subject to the penalties and interest imposed by this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15590" number="18879" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The certificate of the commissioner of finance to the effect that a tax has not been paid, that a return, bond or registration certificate has not been filed, or that information has not been supplied pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, shall be presumptive evidence thereof.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15591" number="18880" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cross-reference:</CHARFORMAT> For criminal penalties, see chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T11C040" destination-id="0-0-0-2809">forty</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15592" number="18881" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person required to make or maintain records under this chapter who fails to make or maintain or make available to the commissioner these records is subject to a penalty not to exceed one thousand dollars for the first quarterly period or part thereof for which the failure occurs and not to exceed five thousand dollars for each additional quarterly period or part thereof for which the failure occurs. This penalty is in addition to any other penalty provided for in this chapter but may not be imposed and collected more than once for failures for the same quarterly period or part thereof. If the commissioner determines that a failure to make or maintain or make available records in any quarterly period was entirely due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, the commissioner must remit the penalty imposed for that quarterly period. These penalties will be paid and disposed of in the same manner as other revenues from this chapter. These penalties will be determined, assessed, collected, paid and enforced in the same manner as the tax imposed by this chapter, and all the provisions of this chapter relating to tax will be deemed also to apply to the penalties imposed by this subdivision. For purposes of the penalty imposed by this subdivision, a person will be considered to have failed to make or maintain the required records when the commissioner of finance determines that the records made or maintained by that person for a quarterly period do not enable the commissioner to verify occupancy or the amounts received for such occupancy or the taxability of that occupancy and to conduct a complete audit.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15593" number="18882" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person required to make or maintain records under this chapter who fails to present and make available these records in an auditable form is subject to a penalty not to exceed one thousand dollars for each quarterly period or part thereof for which records maintained by that person are not presented and made available by that person in auditable form, even if these records are adequate to verify credits, receipts, and the taxability thereof and to perform a complete audit. This penalty is in addition to any other penalty provided for in this chapter, but will not be imposed and collected more than once for these failures for the same quarterly period or part thereof. If the commissioner determines that any failure described in this subdivision for a quarterly period was entirely due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, the commissioner must remit the penalty imposed for that quarter. The penalties imposed by this subdivision will be paid and disposed of in the same manner as other revenues from this chapter. These penalties will be determined, assessed, collected, paid and enforced in the same manner as the tax imposed by this chapter, and all the provisions of this chapter relating to tax will be deemed also to apply to the penalties imposed by this subdivision. For purposes of the penalty imposed by this subdivision, a person will be considered to have failed to present and make records available in auditable form when the records presented by that person for that quarter lack sufficient organization, such as by date, invoice number, sales receipts, or sequential numbering, or are otherwise inadequate (without reorganizing, reordering or otherwise rearranging the records into an auditable form) to permit direct reconciliation of the receipts, invoices or other source documents with the entries for the quarterly period in the books and records and on the returns of that person.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15594" number="18883" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who, having elected to maintain in an electronic format any portion or all of the records he or she is required to make and maintain by this chapter, fails to present and make these records available and accessible to the commissioner in electronic format, is subject to a penalty not to exceed five thousand dollars for each quarterly period or part thereof for which these electronic records are not presented and made available and accessible upon request, notwithstanding that the records may also be maintained and available in hard copy format. This penalty is in addition to any other penalty provided for in this chapter, but may not be imposed and collected more than once for a failure for the same quarterly period or part thereof. Provided, however, nothing in this subdivision will prevent the separate imposition, if applicable, of any penalty imposed by subdivision (i) or (j) of this section for the same quarterly period or part thereof. If the commissioner determines that the failure to present and make electronically maintained records available and accessible for a quarterly period was entirely due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, the commissioner must remit the penalty imposed for that quarter. These penalties will be paid and disposed of in the same manner as other revenues from this chapter. These penalties will be determined, assessed, collected, paid and enforced in the same manner as the tax imposed by this chapter, and all the provisions of this chapter relating to tax will be deemed also to apply to the penalty imposed by this subdivision. For purposes of the penalty imposed by this subdivision, a failure to present and make available and accessible a record maintained in electronic format includes not only the denial of access to the requested records that were maintained electronically, but also the failure to make available to the commissioner the information, knowledge, or means necessary to access and otherwise use the electronically maintained records in the inspection and examination of these records.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15595" number="18884" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(l)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Aiding or assisting in the giving of fraudulent returns, reports, statements or other documents.</CHARFORMAT> Any person who, with the intent that tax be evaded, for a fee or other compensation or as an incident to the performance of other services for which that person receives compensation, aids or assists in, or procures, counsels, or advises the preparation or presentation under this chapter, or in connection with any matter arising under this chapter, of any return, report, declaration, statement or other document that is fraudulent or false as to any material matter, or supplies any false or fraudulent information, whether or not such falsity or fraud is with the knowledge or consent of the person authorized or required to present that return, report, declaration, statement or other document, will pay a penalty not exceeding five thousand dollars. The definitions in subsection (l) of section one thousand eighty-five of the tax law apply for the purposes of this penalty.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15596" number="18885" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(m)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">False or fraudulent document penalty.</CHARFORMAT> Any taxpayer that submits a false or fraudulent document to the department will be subject to a penalty of one hundred dollars per document submitted, or five hundred dollars per tax return submitted. This penalty will be in addition to any other penalty provided by law. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15597" number="18886" version="1400">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/043" destination-id="0-0-0-24910">L.L. 2009/043</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-083]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-206075" number="18887" version="1400">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2516 Returns to be secret. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2787" name="11-2516"/>§ 11-2516 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Returns to be secret. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15598" number="18888" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except in accordance with proper judicial order, or as otherwise provided by law, it shall be unlawful for the commissioner of finance, any officer or employee of the department of finance, any person engaged or retained on an independent contract basis, the tax appeals tribunal, any commissioner or employee of such tribunal, or any person who, pursuant to this section, is permitted to inspect any return or to whom a copy, an abstract or a portion of any return is furnished, or to whom any information contained in any return is furnished, to divulge or make known in any manner the rents or other information relating to the business of a taxpayer contained in any return required under this chapter. The officers charged with the custody of such returns shall not be required to produce any of them or evidence of anything contained in them in any action or proceeding in any court, except on behalf of the commissioner of finance in an action or proceeding under the provisions of this chapter or on behalf of any party to any action or proceeding under the provisions of this chapter when the returns or facts shown thereby are directly involved in such action or proceeding, in either of which events the court may require the production of, and may admit in evidence, so much of said returns or of the facts shown thereby, as are pertinent to the action or proceeding and no more. Nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit the delivery to a taxpayer or his or her duly authorized representative of a certified copy of any return filed in connection with his or her tax; nor to prohibit the delivery of such a certified copy of such return or of any information contained in or relating thereto, to the United States of America or any department thereof, to the state of New York or any department thereof, or to any agency or department of the city of New York, provided the same is requested for official business; nor to prohibit the inspection for official business of such returns by the corporation counsel or other legal representatives of the city or by the district attorney of any county within the city; nor to prohibit the publication of statistics so classified as to prevent the identification of particular returns and the items thereof. Returns shall be preserved for three years and thereafter until the commissioner of finance permits them to be destroyed. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15599" number="18889" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any officer or employee of the city who willfully violates the provisions of subdivision a of this section shall be dismissed from office and be incapable of holding any public office for a period of five years thereafter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15600" number="18890" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cross-reference:</CHARFORMAT> For criminal penalties, see chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T11C040" destination-id="0-0-0-2809">forty</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15601" number="18891" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section shall be deemed a state statute for purposes of paragraph (a) of subdivision two of section eighty-seven of the public officers law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15602" number="18892" version="679">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding anything in subdivision a of this section to the contrary, if a taxpayer has petitioned the tax appeals tribunal for administrative review as provided in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="170" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred seventy</LINK> of the charter, the commissioner of finance shall be authorized to present to the tribunal any report or return of such taxpayer, or any information contained therein or relating thereto, which may be material or relevant to the proceeding before the tribunal. The tax appeals tribunal shall be authorized to publish a copy or a summary of any decision rendered pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="171" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one hundred seventy-one</LINK> of the charter. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15603" number="18893" version="1714">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1988/062" destination-id="0-0-0-27058">L.L. 1988/062</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-221915" number="18894" version="1714">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2517 Notices and limitations of time. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4423" name="11-2517"/>§ 11-2517 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Notices and limitations of time. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15604" number="18895" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any notice authorized or required under the provisions of this chapter may be given by mailing the same to the person for whom it is intended in a postpaid envelope addressed to such person at the address given in the last return filed by him or her pursuant to the provisions of this chapter or in any application made by him or her or, if no return has been filed or application made, then to such address as may be obtainable. The mailing of such notice shall be presumptive evidence of the receipt of the same by the person to whom addressed. Any period of time which is determined according to the provisions of this chapter by the giving of notice shall commence to run from the date of mailing of such notice. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15605" number="18896" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of the civil practice law and rules or any other law relative to limitations of time for the enforcement of a civil remedy shall not apply to any proceeding or action taken by the city to levy, appraise, assess, determine or enforce the collection of any tax or penalty provided by this chapter. However, except in the case of a wilfully false or fraudulent return with intent to evade the tax, no assessment of additional tax shall be made after the expiration of more than three years from the date of the filing of a return; provided, however, that where no return has been filed as provided by law the tax may be assessed at any time.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15606" number="18897" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where, before the expiration of the period prescribed herein for the assessment of an additional tax, a taxpayer has consented in writing that such period be extended, the amount of such additional tax due may be determined at any time within such extended period. The period so extended may be further extended by subsequent consents in writing made before the expiration of the extended period.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15607" number="18898" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any return, claim, statement, notice, application, or other document required to be filed, or any payment required to be made, within a prescribed period or on or before a prescribed date under authority of any provision of this chapter is, after such period or such date, delivered by United States mail to the commissioner of finance, the tax appeals tribunal, bureau, office, officer or person with which or with whom such document is required to be filed, or to which or to whom such payment is required to be made, the date of the United States postmark stamped on the envelope shall be deemed to be the date of delivery. This subdivision shall apply only if the postmark date falls within the prescribed period or on or before the prescribed date for the filing of such document, or for making the payment, including any extension granted for such filing or payment, and only if such document or payment was deposited in the mail, postage prepaid, properly addressed to the commissioner of finance, the tax appeals tribunal, bureau, office, officer or person with which or with whom the document is required to be filed or to which or to whom such payment is required to be made. If any document is sent by United States registered mail, such registration shall be prima facie evidence that such document was delivered to the commissioner of finance, the tax appeals tribunal, bureau, office, officer or person to which or to whom addressed, and the date of registration shall be deemed the postmark date. The commissioner of finance and, where relevant, the tax appeals tribunal are authorized to provide by regulation the extent to which the provisions of the preceding sentence with respect to prima facie evidence of delivery and the postmark date shall apply to certified mail. Except as provided in subdivision f of this section, this subdivision shall apply in the case of postmarks not made by the United States postal service only if and to the extent provided by regulation of the commissioner of finance or, where relevant, the tax appeals tribunal.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15608" number="18899" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the last day prescribed under authority of this chapter (including any extension of time) for performing any act falls on a Saturday, Sunday or legal holiday in the state, the performance of such act shall be considered timely if it is performed on the next succeeding day which is not a Saturday, Sunday or legal holiday.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15609" number="18900" version="1812">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any reference in subdivision d of this section to the United States mail shall be treated as including a reference to any delivery service designated by the secretary of the treasury of the United States pursuant to section seventy-five hundred two of the internal revenue code and any reference in subdivision d of this section to a United States postmark shall be treated as including a reference to any date recorded or marked in the manner described in section seventy-five hundred two of the internal revenue code by a designated delivery service. If the commissioner of finance finds that any delivery service designated by such secretary is inadequate for the needs of the city, the commissioner of finance may withdraw such designation for purposes of this title. The commissioner of finance may also designate additional delivery services meeting the criteria of section seventy-five hundred two of the internal revenue code for purposes of this title, or may withdraw any such designation if the commissioner of finance finds that a delivery service so designated is inadequate for the needs of the city. Any reference in subdivision d of this section to the United States mail shall be treated as including a reference to any delivery service designated by the commissioner of finance and any reference in subdivision d of this section to a United States postmark shall be treated as including a reference to any date recorded or marked in the manner described in section seventy-five hundred two of the internal revenue code by a delivery service designated by the commissioner of finance. Notwithstanding the foregoing, any withdrawal of designation or additional designation by the commissioner of finance shall not be effective for purposes of service upon the tax appeals tribunal, unless and until such withdrawal of designation or additional designation is ratified by the president of the tax appeals tribunal.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15610" number="18901" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any equivalent of registered or certified mail designated by the United States secretary of the treasury, or as may be designated by the commissioner of finance pursuant to the same criteria used by such secretary for such designations pursuant to section seventy-five hundred two of the internal revenue code, shall be included within the meaning of registered or certified mail as used in subdivision d of this section. If the commissioner of finance finds that any equivalent of registered or certified mail designated by such secretary or the commissioner of finance is inadequate for the needs of the city, the commissioner of finance may withdraw such designation for purposes of this title. Notwithstanding the foregoing, any withdrawal of designation or additional designation by the commissioner of finance shall not be effective for purposes of service upon the tax appeals tribunal, unless and until such withdrawal of designation or additional designation is ratified by the president of the tax appeals tribunal. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15611" number="18902" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2518 Construction and enforcement. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4425" name="11-2518"/>§ 11-2518 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction and enforcement. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15612" number="18903" version="3">
											<PARA>This chapter shall be construed and enforced in conformity with chapter one hundred sixty-one of the laws of nineteen hundred seventy, as amended, pursuant to which it is enacted.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-15613" number="18904" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 11-2519 Tourism and convention fund. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4427" name="11-2519"/>§ 11-2519 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Tourism and convention fund. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15614" number="18905" version="3">
											<PARA>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, with respect to the additional tax imposed at the rate of six percent on and after September first, nineteen hundred ninety and before December first, nineteen hundred ninety-four pursuant to subparagraph (B) of paragraph three of subdivision a of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-2502" destination-id="0-0-0-4395">11-2502</LINK> of this chapter, four and one-sixth percent of the total revenues resulting from the imposition of such tax, including four and one-sixth percent of any interest or penalties thereon, shall be credited to and deposited in a special tourism and convention fund, which shall be used solely for the purpose of promoting tourism and conventions in the city. Seven-eighths of the moneys in such fund shall be made available to the New York Convention and Visitor&apos;s Bureau, Inc. pursuant to an annual contract with the city which may specify, among other things, the services which shall be provided by such bureau with such moneys and the content and number of reports which will have to be provided by such bureau to the city concerning the expenditure of such moneys, and provided that the annual budget and business plan of such bureau is approved by the mayor of the city or his or her designee. The remaining one-eighth of the fund shall be spent for promoting tourism and conventions which may include, at the mayor&apos;s discretion, moneys spent in connection with additional contracts made with the New York Convention and Visitor&apos;s Bureau, Inc. For purposes of this section, the term &quot;promoting tourism and conventions&quot; shall mean developing, placing, and purchasing advertising promoting the city, and engaging in such other efforts as are designed to attract tourists and conventions to the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>