<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-129769" number="56728" version="580">
			<HEADING>Chapter 3: Water Supply</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10659" name="T24C003"/>Chapter 3: Water Supply</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-44573" number="56729" version="804">
				<HEADING>Subchapter 1: Water Supply to the City of New York</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter 1: Water Supply to the City of New York</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44574" number="56730" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-301 Assessment of city property used for water purposes. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-755" name="24-301"/>§ 24-301 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Assessment of city property used for water purposes. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44575" number="56731" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The lands taken, or to be taken, for storage, reservoirs, or for other constructions necessary for the introduction and maintenance of a sufficient supply of water in the city, or for the purpose of preventing contamination or pollution, shall be assessed and taxed in the counties in which they are or may be located, in the manner prescribed by law, exclusive of the aqueducts.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44576" number="56732" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section shall not be construed to prevent the assessors in the county of Nassau from assessing for taxation the pumping stations and buildings located in such county.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44577" number="56733" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-302 Commissioner of environmental protection; duty in regard to sources of water supply and property of department. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10661" name="24-302"/>§ 24-302 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commissioner of environmental protection; duty in regard to sources of water supply and property of department. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44578" number="56734" version="3">
											<PARA>It shall be the duty of the commissioner to preserve the purity of all waters from which any part of the city water supply is drawn, and to protect such supply and the lands adjacent thereto from injury or nuisance. He or she shall maintain, preserve and repair all structures and all other property connected with the water supply.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44579" number="56735" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-303 Protection of water supply; certain acts misdemeanors. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10663" name="24-303"/>§ 24-303 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Protection of water supply; certain acts misdemeanors. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44580" number="56736" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any person to throw or deposit, or cause to be thrown or deposited any dead animal or other offensive matter or anything whatever in either of the reservoirs or in any lake, pond or stream, or in any aqueduct or pipe from or through which the water supply of the city shall be drawn.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44581" number="56737" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person violating the provisions of this section shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine or imprisonment, or both, in the discretion of the court. Such fine shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars, and such imprisonment shall not exceed a period of three months. Such imprisonment shall be in the jail of the county in which the offense shall have been committed.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44582" number="56738" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-303.1 Protection of water supply. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10665" name="24-303.1"/>§ 24-303.1 Protection of water supply. </PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44583" number="56739" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in this section, the term &quot;oil or natural gas waste&quot; means (i) waste that is generated as a result of natural gas extraction activities, which may consist of water, chemical additives, or naturally occurring radioactive materials and heavy metals and (ii) brine that is generated as a result of oil or natural gas production, extraction or storage. The term &quot;oil or natural gas waste&quot; includes, but is not limited to, leachate from solid wastes associated with natural gas extraction activities, or any natural gas waste byproduct, but excludes the byproducts of natural gas from anaerobic decomposition processes at digesters and landfills in the city. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-005]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44584" number="56740" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Prohibitions. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">
													</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</CHARFORMAT>
												<HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-005]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44585" number="56741" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful to discharge or cause to be discharged any oil or natural gas waste to any surface water bodies located within the city or to any wastewater treatment plant located within the city. Officers and employees of the department of environmental protection and officers of the department of sanitation may issue summonses, appearance tickets and notices of violation for violations of this paragraph. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-005]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44586" number="56742" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful to apply or cause to be applied any oil or natural gas waste on any road, real property or landfill located within the city. Officers and employees of the department of environmental protection may issue summonses, appearance tickets and notices of violation for violations of this paragraph. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-005]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44587" number="56743" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Contracting. </CHARFORMAT>All city bids or contracts for the construction or maintenance of a city road shall include a provision stating that no materials containing or manufactured from oil or natural gas waste shall be utilized in providing such a service. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-005]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44588" number="56744" version="3">
											<PARA>(L.L 2016/095, 8/31/2016, eff. 11/29/2016) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-005]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44589" number="56745" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-304 Injury to water supply property. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10667" name="24-304"/>§ 24-304 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Injury to water supply property. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44590" number="56746" version="3">
											<PARA>If any unauthorized person shall willfully do or cause to be done any act by which any work, materials or property, including manhole covers, now or hereafter erected or used within the city or elsewhere by such city, or any person acting under their authority, for the purpose of procuring or keeping a supply of water shall in any manner be injured or removed, or shall erect or place any nuisance on the banks of any river, lake or stream from which the water supply of such city shall be drawn, such person on conviction thereof, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44591" number="56747" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-305 Pollution of or interference with water supply. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10669" name="24-305"/>§ 24-305 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Pollution of or interference with water supply. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44592" number="56748" version="3">
											<PARA>It shall be unlawful, within the city, to bathe in or go into the water of any water supply reservoir or any part of a city aqueduct, or to throw stones, chips or dirt or any other material or substance whatever into any gatehouse, ventilator, fountain or basin. It shall also be unlawful to injure or disfigure any part of the water works system of the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44593" number="56749" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-306 Trespass on water supply property. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10671" name="24-306"/>§ 24-306 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Trespass on water supply property. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44594" number="56750" version="3">
											<PARA>It shall be unlawful to enter or remain on any part of the embankment of a water supply reservoir within the city without the permission of the commissioner of environmental protection, or to fail or refuse to comply with the rules and regulations of the commissioner as to when citizens shall leave such embankment, or the grounds or buildings attached thereto.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44595" number="56751" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-307 Hydrants to be kept closed. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10673" name="24-307"/>§ 24-307 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hydrants to be kept closed. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44596" number="56752" version="3">
											<PARA>The commissioner of environmental protection shall cause all water supply hydrants within the city to be kept closed. Except in case of fire and for the purpose of extinguishing the same, or when otherwise authorized by law, it shall be unlawful to take or use the water from any such hydrant.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44597" number="56753" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-308 Opening, tampering with or operating valves or fire hydrants. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10675" name="24-308"/>§ 24-308 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Opening, tampering with or operating valves or fire hydrants. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44598" number="56754" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any person other than an employee of the department of environmental protection, or the fire department to open, use, operate, or tamper with a fire hydrant or high pressure hydrant, in the city, or a valve in the water supply system of the city, without a permit in writing from the commissioner of environmental protection. It shall also be unlawful to leave such a hydrant open for a longer period than shall be limited in the permit, or use water for other purposes than shall have been authorized by such commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44599" number="56755" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner may grant a permit to a person, other than an employee of the department of environmental protection or of the fire department, to open, use or operate a fire hydrant in the city, upon such terms and conditions as may be prescribed by the commissioner and upon payment by such permittee of a fee of five dollars for each day for which such permit is granted. A permittee shall be required, at the time of making application for such permit, to pay to the department a sum sufficient to cover the total fee for the entire period for which such permit is granted. If the work for which such permit is granted is completed on a date prior to the termination date of such permit, the permittee shall be entitled to a refund of the fee paid for each day subsequent to such completion date. The commissioner may grant a permit pursuant to this section to any agency or to a non-profit organization for the purpose of providing street showers for children, without payment of the fee required by this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44600" number="56756" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner shall have the power, subject to the approval of the board of estimate, to increase the amount of the fee prescribed by subdivision b hereof, to an amount sufficient to cover the cost to the city of the supervision and inspection of hydrants in connection with the granting of permits under the provisions of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44601" number="56757" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every permittee shall open, use or operate such hydrant in accordance with such rules and regulations and such terms and conditions as may be prescribed by the commissioner for the purpose of protecting and maintaining the hydrant in a continuously accessible and usable condition. A permit granted pursuant to this section may be revoked by the commissioner for the failure by the permittee to comply with any of the terms and conditions of the permit or any applicable provision of law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44602" number="56758" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The opening, use or operation of a fire hydrant, under a permit issued pursuant to this section, shall be subject to inspection by an employee or employees of the department of environmental protection, duly appointed in accordance with the provisions of the civil service law, and assigned to such duties in accordance with the provisions of section eleven hundred three of the charter. The compensation of any such employee or employees shall be paid by the city in accordance with the provisions of section one hundred twenty-three of the charter. No permittee shall be required to pay the compensation of any employee, or any part thereof, as a condition to the granting of a permit for the opening, use or operation of a fire hydrant.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44603" number="56759" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-309 Connections. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10677" name="24-309"/>§ 24-309 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Connections. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44604" number="56760" version="3">
											<PARA>It shall be unlawful, within the city, to open any street, bore any pipe, or make connection with any main or pipe for water supply purposes, except under the direction of the commissioner of environmental protection.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-111708" number="56761" version="43">
										<HEADING>§ 24-309.1 Tracking lead water service lines; online interactive map.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-18963" name="24-309.1"/>§ 24-309.1 Tracking lead water service lines; online interactive map.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111725" number="56762" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than June 1, 2019, the department of environmental protection shall make information about known lead water service lines available on the city&apos;s website in the form of an online interactive map, pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="23-803" destination-id="0-0-0-18961">23-803</LINK>. The department of environmental protection, or individuals authorized by such department, shall make best efforts to identify all lead water service lines, including privately owned service lines, by consulting relevant city or public records or by any other relevant means. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111724" number="56763" version="43">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such online interactive map shall: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111723" number="56764" version="43">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Be searchable by address or borough, block and lot number; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111722" number="56765" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identify, to the best of the department of environmental protection&apos;s ability, through a color scheme or other identification method, lead water service lines, and, if the composition is unknown, mark it as such until such department can determine its composition; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111721" number="56766" version="43">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Indicate which lead water service lines are owned by the city; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111720" number="56767" version="43">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Provide relevant information to users, including information about lead contamination prevention, lead water test kits and any other relevant resources. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111719" number="56768" version="43">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If a property is serviced by a lead water service line, the department of environmental protection shall: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111718" number="56769" version="43">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If applicable, provide information to relevant property owners about the process and permissions required in making a connection to a pipe for the purposes of replacing lead water service lines; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111717" number="56770" version="43">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Replace any known lead water service lines that are owned by the city as soon as practicable but no later than December 31, 2025. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111716" number="56771" version="43">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than June 1, 2019 and every June 1 thereafter, the department of environmental protection shall provide to the council and the mayor an annual report containing information on the following: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111715" number="56772" version="43">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Locations of all known lead water service lines; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111714" number="56773" version="43">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Efforts underway to replace lead water supply mains and service lines; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111713" number="56774" version="43">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The status of public outreach and education efforts on the prevention of lead contamination. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111712" number="56775" version="43">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department of environmental protection may include with any such report a recommendation to the mayor and the council about whether continued reporting on such topic is necessary and appropriate. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111710" number="56776" version="711">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2019/065, 4/14/2019, eff. 4/14/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-036]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44605" number="56777" version="43">
										<HEADING>§ 24-310 Closing of taps before building is demolished. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10679" name="24-310"/>§ 24-310 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Closing of taps before building is demolished. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44606" number="56778" version="3">
											<PARA>It shall be unlawful to demolish any building in the city without first having obtained a permit from the department of environmental protection, providing for the withdrawal of existing taps supplying the premises, in the manner specified in the permit.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44607" number="56779" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-311 Obstruction of stop-cocks. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10681" name="24-311"/>§ 24-311 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Obstruction of stop-cocks. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44608" number="56780" version="3">
											<PARA>It shall be unlawful for any person to obstruct access to a stop-cock connected with a water pipe in the city, or to permit any person in his or her employ to do so.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44609" number="56781" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-312 Public wells. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10683" name="24-312"/>§ 24-312 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Public wells. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44610" number="56782" version="3">
											<PARA>It shall be unlawful to dig a well in any street or public place in the city, and the commissioner of transportation shall cause it to be filled in, in all cases.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44611" number="56783" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-313 No royalty for use of patented apparatus. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10685" name="24-313"/>§ 24-313 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">No royalty for use of patented apparatus. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44612" number="56784" version="3">
											<PARA>No patented hydrant, valve or stop-cock shall be used by the department of environmental protection unless the patentee or owner of the patent shall allow its use without royalty.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44613" number="56785" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-314 Right of entry on lands dedicated for highway or park purposes. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10687" name="24-314"/>§ 24-314 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Right of entry on lands dedicated for highway or park purposes. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44614" number="56786" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department of environmental protection shall at all times have the unqualified right to enter upon all lands transferred or dedicated under the provisions of chapter six hundred sixty of the laws of nineteen hundred twenty-one, for highway or park purposes, to make repairs, replacements, additions, alterations or extensions to its water mains, pipes or works and for any other use of the property necessary to the purposes for which it was originally acquired, without applying for or obtaining the consent of any other authority. The department of environmental protection shall rebuild and replace any part of the road bed thus destroyed or torn up for water supply or incidental purposes, and restore it to a condition satisfactory to the authority having jurisdiction there- over.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44615" number="56787" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All owners of property adjacent to such strip dedicated for highway purposes shall have a right of way over every part of such land so dedicated.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44616" number="56788" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-315 Permits; issuance; revocation. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10689" name="24-315"/>§ 24-315 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Permits; issuance; revocation. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44617" number="56789" version="3">
											<PARA>The commissioner of environmental protection is authorized and empowered to issue or renew temporary permits for the use or occupation of any city property, under his or her jurisdiction. Such issuance or renewal shall be for a term not to exceed five years, for such consideration and upon such terms and conditions as the commissioner may deem necessary for the adequate protection and utilization of such property. The permit or renewal thereof shall be non-transferable; shall specifically provide that it may be cancelled by the commissioner upon thirty days&apos; notice in writing and shall not confer any right, easement or interest in, to, over, under or across such property.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44618" number="56790" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-316 Leaking tap or service pipe to be repaired. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10691" name="24-316"/>§ 24-316 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Leaking tap or service pipe to be repaired. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44619" number="56791" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>As used in this section:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44620" number="56792" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;tap&quot; means a connection made between a city-owned pipe or main supplying water and a service pipe.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44621" number="56793" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;service pipe&quot; means a pipe used to carry water from a tap to a house control valve, a building or other enclosure or a point at which the water supply is fully metered.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44622" number="56794" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When a test made by the department of environmental protection indicates that there is a leak at a tap or in a service pipe, if conditions permit, a notice shall be served by a representative of such department upon the owner or occupant of the premises being supplied by such tap or service pipe. The notice shall direct that all necessary repairs be made to stop the leak.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44623" number="56795" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the event that a tap is shut off by the department because of a leak, the owner or occupant of the affected premises shall be notified that the tap has been closed and that a licensed plumber should be engaged to make the necessary repair and take charge of the street excavation. If the owner or occupant fails within three days after notice, excepting emergencies as determined by the commissioner to engage a licensed plumber, the tap shall remain closed and the department of environmental protection shall backfill the excavation.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44624" number="56796" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-317 Lien on premises. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2733" name="24-317"/>§ 24-317 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Lien on premises. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44625" number="56797" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be filed in the office of the department of environmental protection a record of all work caused to be performed by or on behalf of the department which relates to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-316" destination-id="0-0-0-10691">24-316</LINK> of this code. Such records shall be kept on a building by building basis and shall be accessible to the public during business hours. Within thirty days after the issuance of an order to shut off a tap, or backfill an excavation, or both, entry of such order shall be made on the records of the department of environmental protection. Such entry shall constitute notice to all parties.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44626" number="56798" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All expenses incurred by or on behalf of the department for services performed pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-316" destination-id="0-0-0-10691">24-316</LINK> of this code shall constitute a lien upon the land and buildings upon or in respect to which, or either of which, the work required by such order has been done, or expenses incurred, when the amount thereof shall have been definitely computed as a statement of account by the department and such department shall cause to be filed in the office of the city collector an entry of the account stated in the book in which such charges against the premises are to be entered. Such lien shall have a priority over all other liens and encumbrances except for the lien of taxes and assessments. However, no lien created pursuant to this section shall be enforced against a subsequent purchaser in good faith or mortgagee in good faith unless the requirements of subdivision a of this section are satisfied; this limitation shall only apply to transactions occurring after the date such record should have been entered pursuant to subdivision a and the date such entry was made.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44627" number="56799" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A notice thereof, stating the amount due and the nature of the charge, shall be mailed by the city collector, within five days after such entry, to the last known address of the person whose name appears on the records in the office of the city collector as being the owner or agent or as the person designated by the owner to receive tax bills or, where no name appears, to the premises, addressed to either the owner or the agent.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44628" number="56800" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If such charge is not paid within thirty days from the date of entry, it shall be the duty of the city collector to receive interest thereon at the rate of interest applicable to such property for a delinquent tax on real property, to be calculated to the date of payment from the date of entry.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44629" number="56801" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such charge and the interest thereon shall continue to be, until paid, a lien on the premises. Such lien shall be a tax lien within the meaning of sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-319" destination-id="0-0-0-2799">11-319</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-401" destination-id="0-0-0-2801">11-401</LINK> of the code and may be sold, enforced or foreclosed in the manner provided in chapters three and four of title eleven of such code or may be satisfied in accordance with the provisions of section thirteen hundred fifty-four of the real property actions and proceedings law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44630" number="56802" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such notice mailed by the city collector pursuant to this section shall have stamped or printed thereon a reference to this section of the code.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44631" number="56803" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-318 Validity of lien; grounds for challenge. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10693" name="24-318"/>§ 24-318 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Validity of lien; grounds for challenge. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44632" number="56804" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In any proceedings to enforce or discharge a lien created pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-317" destination-id="0-0-0-2733">24-317</LINK> of this subchapter, the validity of the lien shall not be subject to challenge based on: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44633" number="56805" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The lawfulness of the work done; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44634" number="56806" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The propriety and accuracy of the items of expenses for which a lien is claimed, except as provided in this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44635" number="56807" version="1786">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No such challenge may be made except by (1) the owner of the property, or (2) a mortgagee or lienor whose mortgage or lien would, but for the provisions of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-317" destination-id="0-0-0-2733">24-317</LINK> of this subchapter, have priority over the department&apos;s lien.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44636" number="56808" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-320 City authorized to use ground under streets and highways. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10695" name="24-320"/>§ 24-320 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">City authorized to use ground under streets and highways. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44637" number="56809" version="3">
											<PARA>All persons acting under the authority of the city shall have the right to use the ground or soil under any street, highway, or road within this state to introduce water into the city, on condition that they shall cause the surface of such street, highway, or road to be restored, and all damages done thereto to be repaired.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44638" number="56810" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-321 Restriction on power to contract. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10697" name="24-321"/>§ 24-321 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Restriction on power to contract. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44639" number="56811" version="3">
											<PARA>It shall be unlawful for the commissioner of environmental protection to enter into any contract with any person engaged in the business of supplying or selling water for private or public use and consumption, without the prior approval of the board of estimate. The separate written consent and approval of the proposed contract in all its details, shall be given by both the mayor and comptroller. It shall be unlawful for the city or any of its agencies to make any contract in relation to the water supply with any person, except in accordance with the provisions and requirements of the charter and this code. Such provisions and requirements are hereby declared to establish the exclusive rule for the making of such contracts. All proceedings relating to the making or approval of any such contract may be reviewed by the appellate division of the supreme court in the first or second department on the application of any resident taxpayer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44640" number="56812" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-322 Special water service for fire, sanitary and other purposes. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10699" name="24-322"/>§ 24-322 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Special water service for fire, sanitary and other purposes. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44641" number="56813" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The board of estimate may make and enter into contracts and agreements for a term of years with any corporation duly organized under the laws of this state, for the furnishing of a special water service for fire, sanitary and other purposes, and for supplying water suitable therefor from any source with a pressure equal to a head of three hundred feet above tide water. Such contracts and agreements shall contain such conditions, provisions and stipulations as such board may consider necessary and proper in the interests of the city, and shall be upon such terms as it deems best. Such board, by such contract, may authorize such corporation to lay down pipes and erect hydrants in the streets of the city, under such restrictions and conditions as may be prescribed by such board.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44642" number="56814" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such contracts or agreements may also provide for the purchase by the city of all the rights and property secured by such corporation and the works constructed by them for furnishing water for such special purposes, when such board of estimate shall deem such purchase to be for the interest of the city. Such purchase, however, must be determined upon by such board at the expiration of five years from the date of the contract. The cost of such purchase shall be determined by arbitrators appointed by the supreme court.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44643" number="56815" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section and all contracts or agreements executed under its provisions, shall be construed so as not to interfere with, hinder or delay the construction and use of any works now or hereafter authorized by law, relating to procuring an increased supply of water from the Croton aqueduct system of the city. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44644" number="56816" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-323 Construction of highways and bridges in connection with reservoirs. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10701" name="24-323"/>§ 24-323 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction of highways and bridges in connection with reservoirs. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44645" number="56817" version="3">
											<PARA>The city is required to build such highways and bridges as may be made necessary by the construction of any reservoir, and to forever repair and maintain such bridges.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44646" number="56818" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-324 Construction of highways around middle branch reservoir. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10703" name="24-324"/>§ 24-324 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction of highways around middle branch reservoir. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44647" number="56819" version="3">
											<PARA>The city is required to repair and maintain the highways built or in process of construction by the city around the new reservoir, on the middle branch of the Croton river, in the town of South East.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44648" number="56820" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-325 City to erect and maintain fences to protect certain water works. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10705" name="24-325"/>§ 24-325 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">City to erect and maintain fences to protect certain water works. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44649" number="56821" version="3">
											<PARA>The city, at its own expense, shall erect and maintain all fences needed to protect the works upon the lands taken by the city in the county of Westchester for water supply purposes by virtue of chapter two hundred fifty-six of the laws of eighteen hundred thirty-four. It shall also erect and maintain, at its own expense, convenient passes under or across the Croton aqueduct, for farming and other uses of individually owned lands in such county intersected by such aqueduct.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44650" number="56822" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-326 Regulation of use of lakes and reservoirs used for city water supply. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10707" name="24-326"/>§ 24-326 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Regulation of use of lakes and reservoirs used for city water supply. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44651" number="56823" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any natural lake or any reservoir used or built by the city for water supply purposes may be used by the public for boating, cutting ice and fishing. The city and its representatives shall not prohibit such use, and they are required to afford access to such lakes or reservoirs, except that the city may prohibit such use in the event of a declaration of an emergency by the governor as hereinafter provided and except in the event of the declaration of war by or against the United States of America. The city may grant permits to boat owners for the use of boats on such lakes and reservoirs, and may prescribe rules and regulations for their proper use.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44652" number="56824" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any emergency shall have been declared to exist by the governor in the manner hereinafter provided in subdivision c of this section or in the event of a declaration of war by or against the United States of America, the mayor, for the duration of such emergency or of such war, may revoke, in whole or in part, the privileges set forth in subdivision a hereof and prohibit the use by the public of the lakes and reservoirs of the city. The commissioner may make reasonable rules and regulations as to the use of such reservoirs during such emergency or war period. Any such order of revocation shall define the terms and extent of revocation, and shall state the date on which it shall become effective. Any rules and regulations promulgated by the commissioner of environmental protection during such emergency shall be published once in a newspaper circulating in each of the counties in which the water supply property to be affected thereby shall be located.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44653" number="56825" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The governor is hereby empowered to declare the existence of an emergency affecting the city&apos;s water supply sources upon application of the commissioner of environmental protection and subject to the following conditions:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44654" number="56826" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notice of the application by the commissioner to have such emergency declared and of the date and place of the public hearing to be had thereon shall be published at least twice in a newspaper published in each county in which are located the sources of water supply as to which it is claimed the emergency exists and in addition written notice of such application and of the date and place of the hearing thereon shall be served on the clerk of the board of supervisors of each such county at least eight days before such hearing.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44655" number="56827" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>After such public hearing, at which all persons interested shall have an opportunity to be heard, the governor, may, if he or she deems such emergency to exist, declare the existence of such emergency affecting the city&apos;s water supply sources and fix the period for which the emergency shall be deemed to exist. The duration of such period of emergency may be extended after the giving of similar notice and after holding of a similar public hearing.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44656" number="56828" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the requirements of paragraphs one and two of subdivision c of this section, the governor shall have the power to declare the existence of an emergency affecting the city&apos;s water supply sources or any part thereof upon application of the commissioner without notice, and without a public hearing for a period not exceeding thirty days. Where such emergency is so declared, however, it shall not be extended or renewed except after notice and public hearing as provided in such paragraphs one and two.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44657" number="56829" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the event of the declaration of an emergency by the governor or of the declaration of war by or against the United States of America, duly designated employees of the department of environmental protection are empowered and authorized to act as peace officers in any county in which any water supply property of the city is located for the purpose of enforcing the rules and regulations promulgated by the commissioner for the period of the emergency. The department of environmental protection shall file in the office of the sheriff of each such county a certificate of appointment of each such designated employee, and shall attach to each such certificate a complete copy of the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant to subdivisions a and b of this section. Copies of all amendments of such rules and regulations shall be filed by the commissioner with each such sheriff. The sheriff of any such county may cancel any such certificate for cause, and forthwith shall mail written notice of such cancellation to the department of environmental protection, specifying the cause of such revocation. Immediately upon any such cancellation, the employee whose certificate shall have been cancelled, shall have no further authority to act as a peace officer. Each employee so appointed at all times when on duty, shall have in his or her possession a shield or other suitable badge of authority which he or she shall exhibit at once to any person upon request.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44658" number="56830" version="1786">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be the special duty of the employees so appointed to prevent breaches of the peace and unlawful depredations and to arrest and bring before the proper judicial officer any person guilty of violating any of such rules and regulations.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44659" number="56831" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person convicted of violating any of the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant to subdivision a of this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than ten dollars for the first offense, twenty dollars or ten days imprisonment, or both, for the second offense, or fifty dollars or fifty days imprisonment, or both, for the third or any subsequent offense.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44660" number="56832" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-327 Regulation of use of Putnam county lakes and reservoirs used for city water supply. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10709" name="24-327"/>§ 24-327 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Regulation of use of Putnam county lakes and reservoirs used for city water supply. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44661" number="56833" version="3">
											<PARA>Whenever the waters of natural lakes in Putnam county have been or are acquired by the city, or reservoirs have been or are constructed, the residents of such county shall have the right of boating, fishing and taking ice from such lakes and reservoirs, subject to such regulations as the commissioner of environmental protection may make from time to time to preserve the purity of the water and to prevent nuisances, and subject, however, to the right of the city to prohibit such use in the event of the declaration of an emergency as provided in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-326" destination-id="0-0-0-10707">24-326</LINK> of this code.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44662" number="56834" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-328 Lake Mahopac; level of water not reduced. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10711" name="24-328"/>§ 24-328 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Lake Mahopac; level of water not reduced. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44663" number="56835" version="3">
											<PARA>Nothing in this chapter contained shall authorize, empower or permit any water in excess of its ordinary flow to be drawn from Lake Mahopac, in the town of Carmel, Putnam county, between the first days of March and September in any year.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44664" number="56836" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-329 Interments near reservoir prohibited. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10713" name="24-329"/>§ 24-329 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Interments near reservoir prohibited. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44665" number="56837" version="3">
											<PARA>It shall be unlawful to establish any cemetery or place of burial, or burial vaults, or other place for the reception or burial of dead bodies, or to bury, or deposit in vaults, any dead body, within a distance of half a mile of any reservoir, or any ponds used for the supply of the borough of Brooklyn with water. In the county of Nassau, however, it shall be lawful to do so with the written consent of the state department of health and the commissioner of environmental protection upon such terms and conditions as may be prescribed by such commissioner. This section shall not, however, be construed to prevent burials in any cemetery already established, or grounds now held by any religious corporation or society organized under the laws of this state.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44666" number="56838" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-330 Watering horses. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10715" name="24-330"/>§ 24-330 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Watering horses. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44667" number="56839" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within the city, all publicly owned watering troughs, and those erected or maintained by the American Society for the prevention of cruelty to animals, shall be provided with the necessary piping and fixtures to enable the filling of pails with water therefrom, or otherwise modified in construction so as to meet the requirements of the board of health. The supply of water for such troughs shall be furnished by the department of environmental protection. All other horse-watering troughs on streets and public places in the city shall likewise be provided with the piping and fixtures necessary to enable the filling of pails with water, and the use of the water for that purpose shall be paid for. All horse-watering stations in streets and public places hereafter constructed or operated, shall conform to the provisions of this section. It shall be unlawful to draw water from such fixtures except to water horses or other animals. It shall be unlawful to tamper with such fixtures.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44668" number="56840" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every commercial vehicle to which a horse is attached, while on the public thoroughfares of the city, must be provided with a watering pail, which shall be used for the purpose of watering or feeding the horse or horses attached to the vehicle.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44669" number="56841" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of this section shall not prevent the establishment of temporary relief stations for watering horses in conformity with such requirements as may be imposed by the board of health, with the consent of the commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44670" number="56842" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-331 Sale of water; license. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10717" name="24-331"/>§ 24-331 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Sale of water; license. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44671" number="56843" version="3">
											<PARA>It shall be unlawful for any person, except when licensed by the commissioner, to take water from any hydrant or water connection erected, or to be erected in the city, and attached to the water pipes, to be used on any boat, vessel, barge or piledriver, or to be sold or offered for sale to the owner of any boat, vessel, barge, or pile-driver.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44672" number="56844" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-332 Use of water through hose. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10719" name="24-332"/>§ 24-332 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Use of water through hose. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44673" number="56845" version="3">
											<PARA>It shall be unlawful for any person to wash any street, sidewalk, areaway, steps, building or other place in the city by means of a hose or piping, or to use water through a hose or sprinkler for watering lawns or gardens, or to operate any outside shower where the water runs upon a street, sidewalk, or other public place between the first day of November and the last day of March following.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44674" number="56846" version="1448">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2006/039" destination-id="0-0-0-25064">L.L. 2006/039</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-208284" number="56847" version="1448">
										<HEADING>§ 24-334 Water meters; when to be placed. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-8729" name="24-334"/>§ 24-334 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Water meters; when to be placed. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44675" number="56848" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner is authorized to install or cause to be installed water meters, the pattern and maximum price of which shall be approved by the board of estimate in any or all stores, workshops, hotels, lodging houses, factories, office buildings, and public edifices, at wharves, ferry houses, and stables, and in all places in which water is furnished for business consumption and in any or all new or substantially improved or altered dwellings. When authorized thereto by resolution of the board of estimate or by local law, the commissioner may install such meters in any or all other multiple dwellings, and he or she shall install such meter or meters or cause them to be installed upon written demand of the owner of any lot or premises to which such water is supplied. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44676" number="56849" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of this subdivision an improvement or alteration is a physical change in an existing structure, other than painting, ordinary repairs and normal replacement of maintenance items. A structure shall be deemed to have been substantially improved or altered where:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44677" number="56850" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the cost of improvement or alteration exceeds the sum of one hundred fifty thousand dollars; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44678" number="56851" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>fifty percent or more of the dwelling units or square feet of the structure in multiple dwellings are improved or altered and the cost of such improvement or alteration exceeds the sum of fifteen thousand dollars per dwelling unit; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44679" number="56852" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>there has been a conversion in the use of the structure.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44680" number="56853" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Thereafter, as shall be determined by the commissioner, the department shall make out all charges for water furnished by such department to such premises in ratable proportion to the water furnished, as ascertained by meter, subject to such minimum and service charges as may be established. All expense and cost of meters, and their connections, and of their setting, repair and maintenance, unless with the approval of the board of estimate such expense and cost be borne by the department, shall be a charge and lien upon the premises.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44681" number="56854" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section shall not, however, be construed so as to remit or prevent the due collection of arrearages or charges for water consumption heretofore incurred, nor interfere with the proper liens therefor, nor of charges, or rates, or liens hereafter to be incurred for water consumption in any building or place which may not contain one of the meters aforesaid. The moneys collected for service charges and for expense and cost of meters and their connections, and for setting, repairing, maintaining and replacing the same, may be applied by the commissioner to the payment of expenses incurred in procuring meters and their connections and in their setting, repair, maintenance and replacement.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44682" number="56855" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-335 Charges where supply is metered. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10721" name="24-335"/>§ 24-335 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Charges where supply is metered. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44683" number="56856" version="682">
											<PARA>No charge for the supply of water other than a meter charge, minimum charge or annual service charge shall be made against any houses or lots or any portion or portions thereof where a water meter may have been or shall be placed. In all cases where a water meter may have been or shall be placed, the charge for supply of water shall be determined only by the quantity of water actually used, as shown by such meters, except for a minimum charge or an annual service charge and except as provided by subdivision four of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="734" destination-id="0-0-0-0">seven hundred thirty-four</LINK> of the charter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44684" number="56857" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-336 Acquisition of water meters. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10723" name="24-336"/>§ 24-336 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Acquisition of water meters. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44685" number="56858" version="3">
											<PARA>The commissioner may acquire any water meters installed upon premises connected with the public water supply, from private owners, with the approval of the mayor, upon such terms and subject to such rules and regulations as the mayor may approve.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44686" number="56859" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-337 Waste of water prohibited; remedies. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10725" name="24-337"/>§ 24-337 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Waste of water prohibited; remedies. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44687" number="56860" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for water to be wasted, whether owing to leak or wasteful condition, regardless of fault, from any water pipe, valve, faucet, conduit, equipment, facility or device connected to the city water system or which utilizes city water. It shall be the duty of an owner, lessee, agent, manager, operator and of any other person in charge of or who has control over any premises, plant, equipment, facility, device or operation to make frequent regular inspections so as to minimize the likelihood of leak or waste and within a reasonable time after the discovery or notification of any leak or wasteful condition to effect repairs or take other appropriate corrective action within the power of such person. The commissioner of environmental protection shall promulgate such reasonable rules and regulations as the commissioner may from time to time deem appropriate for the prevention of the waste of water.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44688" number="56861" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to enforcement pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-346" destination-id="0-0-0-10727">24-346</LINK> the commissioner may serve a leak and waste notice upon any person having a duty to repair or correct a leak or wasteful condition or upon any person in violation of the rules and regulations for the prevention of the waste of water. Such notice shall specify the repair or correction to be made and shall fix a reasonable time for compliance. Where such notice has been served and water continues to be wasted after the time for correction has expired, the commissioner may, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing before the commissioner or his or her designee, turn off the water supply to the premises or impose a penalty not to exceed fifty dollars per day for each day that water continues to be wasted after the expiration date contained in the notice, or both. Any penalty imposed pursuant to this section may be added to the water rents; except that no such penalty may be imposed against any property unless both the leak and waste notice and notice of the proceeding to impose the penalty was served upon the owner by mailing copies thereof to the person whose name appears on the records in the office of the city collector as being the owner or agent or as the person designated by the owner to receive tax bills at the address on file for such purpose or where no name appears to the property addressed to &quot;owner&quot; or &quot;agent&quot; and such person has had an opportunity to be heard. The provisions of this subdivision shall not be construed to limit the commissioner&apos;s power to shut off water supply without notice, or with such notice as the commissioner may deem practicable, where a leak exists; or where emergency action is otherwise deemed essential.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44689" number="56862" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall establish or reestablish a permanent committee on water conservation (the &quot;committee&quot;) within six months of the effective date of this section consisting of outside experts, representatives of public interest, environmental and professional groups and interested citizens, two of whom shall be appointed by the city council and the rest shall be appointed by the commissioner. The members of the committee shall serve without compensation for a term of three years. The commissioner shall be the chairman.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44690" number="56863" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within one year after the effective date of this section, and annually thereafter, the committee shall submit to the city council a report evaluating the effectiveness of paragraphs a through e, of subdivision P.104.2 of section P.104.0 of RS 16 describing the latest available water-conserving fixtures, and including written recommendations. The department shall make available to the committee any and all information useful and necessary for the committee to prepare and complete the report for submission to the city council. To prepare such report the committee shall utilize any information and/or materials determined to be pertinent that have been published, distributed or in any other manner made available from state agencies, public and private research groups, multistate agencies such as the Delaware River Basin Commission, and other similar public or private agencies or groups with expertise with respect to water-conserving plumbing fixtures. The report shall include, but not be limited to:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44691" number="56864" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a review of compliance with paragraphs a through e, of subdivision P.104.2 of section P.104.0 of reference standard RS 16 of the appendix to chapter one of title twenty-seven of this code, the impact of such compliance, and the relationship of the standards set forth herein to current technology;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44692" number="56865" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>recommendations as to the feasibility of requiring more stringent water-saving performance standards than provided in paragraphs a through e of subdivision P.104.2 of section P.104.0 of reference standard RS 16.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44693" number="56866" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall establish a city-wide comprehensive public information campaign focusing on water-conserving fixtures, the benefits of good water-saving equipment, and the opportunity for rapid pay-back and long-term money savings, especially in energy costs, for home owners and landlords. Within six months after the effective date of this section, a proposal for the public information campaign shall be submitted to the city council for review and commentary. The department shall report annually to the city council on the status of the public information campaign.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44694" number="56867" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-338 Meters to be installed where water is wasted. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10729" name="24-338"/>§ 24-338 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Meters to be installed where water is wasted. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44695" number="56868" version="3">
											<PARA>The commissioner is authorized to install or cause to be installed a meter or meters in any premises where repeated violation notices to prevent waste of water are necessary, or where the owner fails to comply with waste of water violation notices.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44696" number="56869" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-339 Water saving plumbing fixtures. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10731" name="24-339"/>§ 24-339 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Water saving plumbing fixtures. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44697" number="56870" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any person to distribute, sell, offer for sale, import or install any plumbing fixture which does not meet the standards of subdivision P.104.2 of section P.104.0 of reference standard RS sixteen.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44698" number="56871" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>An owner who has installed a shower head in a class A dwelling unit which meets the standards of subdivision P.104.2 of section P.104.0 of reference standard RS sixteen shall not be required to replace any such device which is stolen, removed, missing or rendered inoperable during the occupancy of such dwelling unit but shall replace such device prior to the commencement of a new occupancy of such dwelling unit. Notwithstanding the provisions of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="27-2005" destination-id="0-0-0-10733">27-2005</LINK>, it shall be the sole duty of the occupant of each dwelling unit in a class A multiple dwelling in which such a shower head has been provided and installed by the owner to replace such devices which are either stolen, removed, missing or rendered inoperable during the occupancy of such dwelling unit. The meaning of terms used in this subdivision shall be as defined in chapter two of title twenty-seven of this code.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44699" number="56872" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-341 Charges not to be affected. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10735" name="24-341"/>§ 24-341 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Charges not to be affected. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44700" number="56873" version="3">
											<PARA>Nothing contained in sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-335" destination-id="0-0-0-10721">24-335</LINK> through <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-337" destination-id="0-0-0-10725">24-337</LINK> of the code shall be construed to prevent the imposition of charges in accordance with schedules, rules or regulations heretofore adopted or the performance of any act required or authorized under such schedules, rules or regulations or under the provisions of sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-335" destination-id="0-0-0-10721">24-335</LINK> through <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-337" destination-id="0-0-0-10725">24-337</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-301" destination-id="0-0-0-3093">11-301</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-312" destination-id="0-0-0-2725">11-312</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="11-314" destination-id="0-0-0-3115">11-314</LINK> of the code, nor to affect or invalidate charges heretofore imposed, or hereafter to be imposed as herein provided, nor to prevent the due collection of such charges or interfere with the liens thereof.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44701" number="56874" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-342 Connection charges. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10737" name="24-342"/>§ 24-342 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Connection charges. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44702" number="56875" version="3">
											<PARA>All persons contracting for a supply of water within the city, shall pay the cost of the materials and labor used and expended in the streets, necessary to make the connection with the conduit pipes, as required by the rules and regulations of the commissioner of environmental protection.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44703" number="56876" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-343 Transfer of house service pipe connection to new water main. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10739" name="24-343"/>§ 24-343 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Transfer of house service pipe connection to new water main. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44704" number="56877" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In instances where the city has laid a water main in a street where surface grades have been established but where the surface has not been improved to the established grade and when a new water main is installed by the city because it is required by the grading of such street to the established grade, the commissioner of environmental protection shall issue an order directing the owner of each house which was directly connected with the main as previously laid, to transfer the house service pipe connection to the new main, at the expense of such owner when required in accordance with the rules and regulations of the commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44705" number="56878" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When a new water main is installed by the city to replace a private main, the commissioner shall issue an order directing the owner of each house fronting on the city main and receiving water from such private main to transfer the house service pipe connection to the city main, at the expense of such owner and in accordance with the rules and regulations of the commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44706" number="56879" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>An order issued pursuant to this section shall be served upon the owner of the premises, by registered mail sent to the address registered by such owner in the bureau of city collections in the department of finance, or if no address is registered in such bureau, by registered mail sent to the last known address of such owner, or to the address of such owner as shown on the records in the office where conveyances of real property are recorded pursuant to law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44707" number="56880" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the transfer is not made within ten days after the mailing of such order, the department of environmental protection may make such transfer through its officers, agents or contractors. The owner shall be personally liable for the expenses and disbursements incurred by the department in making such transfer. The amount of such expenses and disbursements shall be due and payable when definitely fixed by the commissioner of environmental protection and entered upon the records in the office of the city collector. A notice stating the amount due and the nature of the charge shall be mailed by the city collector within five days after such entry to the address registered by such owner in the bureau of city collections in the department of finance, or if no address is registered in such bureau, to the last known address of the owner of such property or to the address of such owner as shown on the records in the office where conveyances of real property are recorded pursuant to law. If such amount is not paid on or before the last day of the month following the month of entry, it shall be the duty of the city collector to charge, collect and receive interest thereon at the rate of seven per cent per annum to be calculated to the date of payment from the date of entry. The amount of such expenses and disbursements and the interest thereon shall be a lien upon the premises for which the transfer of the house service pipe connection was made, and shall be enforced and collected in the manner provided in chapter three of title eleven of this code for the enforcement and collection of water rents and the lien thereof.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44708" number="56881" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-343.1 Backflow prevention device reporting. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10741" name="24-343.1"/>§ 24-343.1 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Backflow prevention device reporting. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44709" number="56882" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of this section the following terms shall have the following meanings: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44710" number="56883" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Backflow&quot; shall mean a flow condition, induced by a differential in pressure, that causes the flow of water or other liquids and/or gases into the distribution of pipes of a city water main, private water main, or to an internal water main from any source other than its intended source.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44711" number="56884" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Backsiphonage&quot; shall mean the backflow of contaminated or polluted water, or water of questionable quality from a plumbing fixture or other source, into a city water main, private water main, or to an internal water main due to a temporary negative or sub-atmospheric pressure within the public water supply system.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44712" number="56885" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Backflow prevention device&quot; shall mean an approved air gap, reduced pressure zone device or double check valve assembly used to contain potential contamination within a facility.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44713" number="56886" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Cross connection&quot; shall mean a physical connection or arrangement between two separate piping systems where one system contains potable water and the other contains steam, gas, a chemical, or water of questionable safety, and there may be a flow from one system to the other.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44714" number="56887" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Hazardous facility&quot; shall mean a facility in which substances may be present that may endanger the health of other water users if introduced into the public water system, including but not limited to, laboratories, sewage treatment plants, chemical plants, hospitals and mortuaries.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44715" number="56888" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the department or the owner or operator of a building or structure has determined that there is a cross connection and no backflow prevention device, or a defective or unapproved device, such that there is a possibility of backflow or backsiphonage from such building or structure into a city water main, private water main, or to an internal water main, the owner or operator of such building or structure shall be under a duty to correct such potential or actual backflow or backsiphonage and provide the proper documentation to certify to the department that a backflow prevention device has been installed and where appropriate, that a backflow prevention device has been replaced. Where removal of a cross-connection or installation or replacement of a backflow prevention device has been performed as part of a project for which a licensed professional engineer or registered architect has submitted plans that have been approved by the department, such licensed professional engineer or registered architect shall inspect and submit to the department a certification that the cross-connection has been removed or a backflow prevention device installed or replaced in conformity with plans approved by the department or the department of buildings.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44716" number="56889" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall send out a mailing to or shall otherwise notify owners or operators of facilities identified by the department as potentially requiring backflow prevention devices informing them of the potential need for such a device and of the process for installation of backflow prevention devices under the auspices of the cross connection control program. The materials contained in such mailing shall be translated into such languages provided for in section 8-1002* of this code.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44717" number="56890" version="3">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">* Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> Repealed. For current provisions, see <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T21C001S01" destination-id="0-0-0-2169">Title 21, Chapter 1, Subchapter 1</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-032]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44718" number="56891" version="26">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>On or before February 15, 2020, and on or before every February 15 thereafter, the department shall submit a report to the mayor and the speaker of the council setting forth the following information: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-035]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111637" number="56892" version="26">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of all facilities that the department estimates requires the installation of one or more backflow prevention devices; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-035]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111636" number="56893" version="26">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of such facilities that the department has determined to be hazardous facilities; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-035]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111635" number="56894" version="26">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of all facilities in which backflow prevention devices were installed in the preceding calendar year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-035]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111634" number="56895" version="26">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of hazardous facilities in which backflow prevention devices were installed in the preceding calendar year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-035]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111633" number="56896" version="26">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of annual backflow prevention device test reports filed with the department in the preceding calendar year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-035]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111632" number="56897" version="26">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of violations issued in the preceding calendar year for failure to install a backflow prevention device; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-035]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111631" number="56898" version="26">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of violations issued in the preceding calendar year for failure to file an annual backflow prevention device test report with the department. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-035]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-111628" number="56899" version="711">
											<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2019/058, 3/31/2019, eff. 3/31/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-035]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44719" number="56900" version="1396">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/076" destination-id="0-0-0-24880">L.L. 2009/076</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-083]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-205751" number="56901" version="1396">
										<HEADING>§ 24-344 Report of receipts by clerk in bureau of water register. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10743" name="24-344"/>§ 24-344 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Report of receipts by clerk in bureau of water register. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44720" number="56902" version="3">
											<PARA>The clerk of the bureau of water register assigned to collecting, on each day, except Sunday of each week, shall render to the comptroller an account, under oath, of all moneys received by him or her, showing the amounts received from all classes of revenue and shall, thereupon, pay over the amounts so received to the commissioner of finance, furnishing to the comptroller a receipt showing the payment of such sums into the city treasury.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44721" number="56903" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-345 Pay-as-you-go financing for certain water pollution control projects. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10745" name="24-345"/>§ 24-345 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Pay-as-you-go financing for certain water pollution control projects. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44722" number="56904" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Subject to the provisions of subdivision c and subdivision d of this section, for the fiscal year commencing July first, nineteen hundred seventy-seven and for each succeeding fiscal year, a direct mandatory budget appropriation shall be made for the city&apos;s per centum share of the costs of the north river water pollution control project, the oakwood beach water pollution control project and the red hook water pollution control project payable during such fiscal year.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44723" number="56905" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The budgetary appropriations made to pay part of the annual costs of such projects shall be in amounts consistent with the requirements of any final judgment, decree or order of any federal court which sets forth a schedule for the completion of such projects.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44724" number="56906" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the fiscal year commencing July first, nineteen hundred seventy-seven, such appropriation shall not exceed the sum of eight million dollars.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44725" number="56907" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The aggregate amount of such annual appropriations shall not exceed the sum of seventy-nine million dollars.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44726" number="56908" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-346 Enforcement and penalties. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10727" name="24-346"/>§ 24-346 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Enforcement and penalties. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44727" number="56909" version="682">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the commissioner of environmental protection and the environmental control board shall enforce the provisions of this chapter and chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T24C004" destination-id="0-0-0-10747">four</LINK> of this title and the regulations promulgated pursuant thereto or pursuant to section<LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="1403" destination-id="0-0-0-0"> fourteen hundred three</LINK> of the New York city charter as hereinafter provided. Such commissioner and board shall have the power to issue such orders as may be provided for herein and such additional orders as may be necessary for the enforcement of such provisions.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44728" number="56910" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who violates or fails to comply with any of the provisions of this chapter and chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T24C004" destination-id="0-0-0-10747">four</LINK> of this title or any order, rule or regulation issued by the board or commissioner or with the conditions of any permit issued by the commissioner within the city of New York shall be liable for a civil penalty of not less than fifty nor more than one thousand dollars for each violation, except that the civil penalty for violating section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-303.1" destination-id="0-0-0-10665">24-303.1</LINK> shall be not less than two thousand five hundred dollars nor more than twenty-five thousand dollars and the civil penalty for the removal of a manhole cover in violation of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-304" destination-id="0-0-0-10667">24-304</LINK> shall be not less than two thousand five hundred dollars nor more than ten thousand dollars. In the case of a continuing violation each day&apos;s continuance shall be a separate and distinct offense. The environmental control board shall have the power to impose such civil penalties. A proceeding to impose such penalties shall be commenced by the service of a notice of violation returnable to such board. Such board, after a hearing as provided by the rules and regulations of the board, shall have the power to enforce its final decisions and orders imposing such civil penalties as if they were money judgments pursuant to subdivision d of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="1049-a" destination-id="0-0-0-0">one thousand forty-nine-a</LINK> of the New York city charter. A civil penalty imposed by the board may also be collected in an action brought in the name of the city in any court of competent jurisdiction. The board, in its discretion, may, within the limits set forth in this subdivision, establish a schedule of civil penalties indicating the minimum and maximum penalty for each separate offense. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-007]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44729" number="56911" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to the civil penalties set forth in subdivision b of this section and except as otherwise specifically provided, any person who knowingly violates or fails to comply with any provision of this chapter and chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T24C004" destination-id="0-0-0-10747">four</LINK> of this title or any order, rule or regulation issued by the commissioner or board or with the conditions of any permit issued by the commissioner shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction thereof, shall be punished by a fine of not less than two hundred fifty nor more than one thousand dollars, or by imprisonment not exceeding thirty days, or both for each violation, except that the punishment for the removal of a manhole cover in violation of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-304" destination-id="0-0-0-10667">24-304</LINK> shall be a fine of not less than five hundred dollars nor more than ten thousand dollars, or imprisonment not exceeding thirty days, or both for each violation. In the case of a continuing violation each day&apos;s continuance shall be a separate and distinct offense.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44730" number="56912" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of any continued or knowing violation of any of the provisions of this chapter and chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T24C004" destination-id="0-0-0-10747">four</LINK> of this title or any order, rule or regulation issued by the board or commissioner or of the conditions of any permit issued by the commissioner within the city of New York or where the board finds that the violation of any of such provisions or of the conditions of any such permit presents or may present a danger to the water supply or the water supply system, the board after notice and the opportunity for a hearing in accordance with the rules and regulations of the board, may issue a cease and desist order requiring any person who owns, leases, operates, controls or supervises any building, structure, facility, device, equipment, installation or operation to cease and desist from any activity or process which causes or is conducted so as to cause such violation within the time specified in such order.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44731" number="56913" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such order may provide that if the order is not complied with or so far complied with as the commissioner of environmental protection may regard as reasonable within the time specified therein, the commissioner may take such action as shall be specified therein, including but not limited to:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44732" number="56914" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>sealing, blocking or inactivating any equipment, facility or device; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44733" number="56915" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>terminating the water supply. For such purpose the commissioner or his or her deputies or such other officers or employees as are designated by the commissioner may enter on any public or private property.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44734" number="56916" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever the commissioner has reasonable cause to believe that a violation of the provisions of this chapter and chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T24C004" destination-id="0-0-0-10747">four</LINK> of this title or any order, rule or regulation issued by the board or commissioner or in violation of the conditions of any permit issued by the commissioner within the city of New York creates or may create an imminent danger to the water supply or to the water supply system or to the public health or to the life or safety of persons, the commissioner may issue a cease and desist order requiring any person who owns, leases, operates, controls or supervises any building, structure, facility, device, equipment, installation or operation to take such action as may be necessary to halt or prevent such violation.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44735" number="56917" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If service of the order cannot be made personally because such person cannot be located at such time then service may be made by delivering a copy to a person of suitable age and discretion at the residence or place of business of the person sought to be served. If service cannot be made personally or by such delivery to a person of suitable age and discretion because of inability to locate or to obtain the name or address of such person at such time, service may be made by conspicuously posting a copy of such order upon the property to which it relates. The posting of such order shall be sufficient notice of such order to all persons having a duty in relation thereto under the provisions of this subdivision.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44736" number="56918" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the order is not complied with or so far complied with as the commissioner may regard as reasonable, within the time specified therein the commissioner may act to halt or prevent such violation by:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44737" number="56919" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>sealing, blocking or otherwise inactivating any equipment, facility or device;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44738" number="56920" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>terminating the water supply; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44739" number="56921" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>any other means or method that is reasonable under the circumstances. For such purpose the commissioner or his or her deputies or such other officers or employees as are designated by the commissioner may enter on any public or private property.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44740" number="56922" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person affected by such an order may make written application to the environmental control board for a hearing. Such hearing shall be provided, pursuant to the rules and regulations of the board, and shall be held within forty-eight hours after the receipt of such application. The board may suspend, modify or terminate such order.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44741" number="56923" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the respondent fails to comply with any order issued by the board or commissioner or with the conditions of any permit, or the board or commissioner otherwise deems it necessary, the corporation counsel, acting in the name of the city, may maintain an action or proceeding in a court of competent jurisdiction to compel compliance with or restrain by injunction the violation of any order or permit issued by the board or commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44742" number="56924" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who violates or fails to comply with any of the provisions of this chapter and chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T24C004" destination-id="0-0-0-10747">four</LINK> of this title or any order, rule or regulation or with the conditions of any permit issued by the commissioner shall be liable to the city for any expense, loss or damage suffered by the city by reason of such violation.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44743" number="56925" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Unless otherwise specifically provided, service of any notice or order may be made either personally or by mail addressed to the last known address of the person to be served.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44744" number="56926" version="3">
											<PARA>(L.L 2016/095, 8/31/2016, eff. 11/29/2016) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-007]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44745" number="56927" version="1425">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
													<BOOKMARK id="0-0-0-24542" name=""/>Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2008/035" destination-id="0-0-0-24982">L.L. 2008/035</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-207269" number="56928" version="1425">
				<HEADING>Subchapter 2: Water Supply Sources Outside the City of New York</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter 2: Water Supply Sources Outside the City of New York</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44746" number="56929" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-347 Commissioner of environmental protection to submit forms of contracts and specifications for approval of corporation counsel. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-757" name="24-347"/>§ 24-347 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commissioner of environmental protection to submit forms of contracts and specifications for approval of corporation counsel. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44747" number="56930" version="3">
											<PARA>Upon the filing of the oath of the commissioners of appraisal in the manner hereinbefore provided, the commissioner of environmental protection shall, from time to time, as the commissioner may determine, prepare and submit to the corporation counsel, forms of contracts and specifications for the doing of the work and the furnishing of the material required to be done and furnished by such approved plan, or for the doing of such parts of such work and the furnishing of such parts of the materials as the commissioner may from time to time determine. The forms of contracts, specifications and bonds for the faithful performance shall be subject to approval as to form by the corporation counsel, which approval shall be endorsed thereon or attached thereto. The commissioner is hereby given the exclusive authority to determine what provisions shall be embodied in such contracts.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44748" number="56931" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-348 Advertisement for sealed bids or proposals for work or materials; publication. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10749" name="24-348"/>§ 24-348 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Advertisement for sealed bids or proposals for work or materials; publication. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44749" number="56932" version="1786">
											<PARA>When the form of any contract with its specifications and the form of bond for the performance thereof shall have been approved as provided for in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-347" destination-id="0-0-0-757">24-347</LINK>, the commissioner shall advertise for sealed bids or for proposals for the doing of the work or the furnishing of the materials called for in such approved form of contract. Such advertisement shall be published in the City Record and in two daily newspapers published in the city, to be designated by the commissioner, for at least fifteen days consecutively before the time fixed for the closing of the bid box.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44750" number="56933" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-349 Receipt of sealed bids; deposit required. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10751" name="24-349"/>§ 24-349 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Receipt of sealed bids; deposit required. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44751" number="56934" version="3">
											<PARA>All bids or proposals which may be sent in answer to the invitation of such advertisement shall be enclosed in a sealed envelope and delivered to the commissioner or to such person as may be designated by the commissioner to receive the same, who shall, upon receipt thereof, forthwith and in the presence of the person offering such bid, deposit it in a box provided for the receipt thereof. But no bid or proposal shall be so received or deposited unless at the time of such presentation there shall be deposited with the person as aforesaid designated a certified check upon a national or state bank, drawn to the order of the comptroller, to an amount not less than five percent of the amount of the bond or security required by such approved form for the faithful performance of the work or furnishing of the materials required to be done or furnished. Such amount need not, however, in any case, exceed one hundred thousand dollars.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44752" number="56935" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-350 Public opening of bids, acceptance; rejection; readvertisement. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10753" name="24-350"/>§ 24-350 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Public opening of bids, acceptance; rejection; readvertisement. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44753" number="56936" version="3">
											<PARA>After the expiration of the time limited in the advertisement, such bids or proposals shall be publicly opened by the commissioner and he or she may select the bid or proposal, the acceptance of which will, in the commissioner&apos;s judgment, best secure the efficient performance of the work, or the commissioner may reject any or all of such bids. In case of the rejection of all bids, the commissioner shall readvertise such contract, and shall receive and dispose of the bids tendered under such advertisement in the manner hereinbefore provided. In case any work shall be abandoned by any contractor, or the contractor&apos;s contract terminated pursuant to the provisions thereof, it shall be readvertised and relet in the manner provided for in this subchapter for the original letting of such work, except that in such a case, the board of estimate by a two-thirds vote may order otherwise, and may authorize, upon the recommendation of the commissioner, the completion of the work in such manner and by such means as the commissioner deems appropriate.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44754" number="56937" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-351 Return or forfeiture of deposits. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10755" name="24-351"/>§ 24-351 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Return or forfeiture of deposits. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44755" number="56938" version="3">
											<PARA>Within three days after the decision as to who shall receive the contract, the comptroller shall return all the deposits made to the persons making the same, except the deposit made by the bidder to whom the contract shall be awarded; and if the bidder to whom the contract is awarded shall refuse or neglect, within ten days after due notice that the contract has been awarded, to execute the same, and furnish the security required, the amount of deposit made by the bidder shall be forfeited to and be retained by the city as liquidated damages for such neglect or refusal and shall be paid into the general fund, but if such bidder shall execute the contract, and furnish the security within such time, the amount of the bidder&apos;s deposit shall be returned to the bidder.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44756" number="56939" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-352 Execution and filing of contracts; supervision and inspection of work and materials; employer&apos;s bond. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-759" name="24-352"/>§ 24-352 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Execution and filing of contracts; supervision and inspection of work and materials; employer&apos;s bond. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44757" number="56940" version="3">
											<PARA>The contracts, when so awarded, shall be executed in triplicate by the contractor or contractors on the one part and the commissioner acting for the city, on the other part. One of such originals shall be delivered to the contractor, and the other two shall be filed, one in the finance department and the other with the commissioner. The work and materials called for by such contract shall be done and furnished under the direction and supervision, and subject to the inspection of the commissioner, the commissioner&apos;s engineers, supervisors and inspectors. No contract shall take effect until the commissioner shall certify thereon in writing that the commissioner&apos;s acceptance will, in the commissioner&apos;s judgment, best secure the public interest and the efficient performance of the work therein mentioned.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44758" number="56941" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-353 Obligations for capital projects; proceeds for operating expenses. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10757" name="24-353"/>§ 24-353 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Obligations for capital projects; proceeds for operating expenses. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44759" number="56942" version="3">
											<PARA>Expenditures made or incurred by the commissioner of environmental protection shall not be considered operating expenses but shall be deemed to be part of the acquisition, construction or addition to a water supply or distribution system and may be financed in the same manner as the acquisition, construction or addition to a water supply or distribution system.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44760" number="56943" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-354 Work and materials to be procured by contract; exceptions; certificate of public interest. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-761" name="24-354"/>§ 24-354 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Work and materials to be procured by contract; exceptions; certificate of public interest. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44761" number="56944" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All work hereby authorized to be done and all materials hereby authorized to be furnished involving an expenditure of over one thousand dollars, shall be procured by contract made in the manner required by and pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter. The commissioner of environmental protection, however, may without contract cause such surveys to be made and such maps, plans and estimates to be prepared, as shall, in his or her opinion, be necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter, and may appoint and fix the compensation of suitable engineers and other persons to supervise and inspect all work hereby authorized to be done. The commissioner of environmental protection may procure any work to be done without contract, not involving an expenditure of over five thousand dollars, if the commissioner certifies that in his or her opinion, it is for the public interest that such work be done; and in such certificate the commissioner shall state his or her reasons therefor.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44762" number="56945" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any inconsistent provisions of this subchapter or of any general or special law, the commissioner of environmental protection, during the existence of a state of war between the United States of America and the governments of Germany, Japan and Italy, or any of them, and for six months immediately following the termination thereof, may procure or contract for, without public letting, any equipment or materials necessary for the completion of the Delaware aqueduct and appurtenant structures and for any work to be done in connection with the installation of such equipment or materials if the commissioner certifies that in his or her opinion, it is in the public interest that any such equipment or material be procured or contracted for or any such work be done, without public letting, and any such certificate of the commissioner shall state his or her reasons therefor. Any such certificate shall be filed in the office of the comptroller of the city of New York.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44763" number="56946" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-355 Police protection to inhabitants of construction areas; appointment and dismissal of police; powers and duties. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10759" name="24-355"/>§ 24-355 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Police protection to inhabitants of construction areas; appointment and dismissal of police; powers and duties. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44764" number="56947" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be the duty of the commissioner of environmental protection to provide proper police protection to the inhabitants of the localities in which any work may be constructed under the authority of this subchapter during the period of construction, against the acts or omissions of persons employed on such works or found in their neighborhood. To that end the commissioner is authorized and required to appoint a sufficient number of persons to adequately police such localities for such periods. The commissioner shall also have power to remove such persons and to fix or change their compensation in his or her discretion, which compensation shall be paid by the city upon a certificate of the commissioner, as part of the expense authorized to be incurred by this subchapter.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44765" number="56948" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of environmental protection shall give to each person so appointed a certificate of appointment and certified copies thereof, one of which shall be filed in the office of the sheriff of each county in which any work shall be in process of construction under this subchapter and in which such person shall be authorized to perform that person&apos;s duties. Each person so appointed shall be and have all the powers of a peace officer in the county where any work is being constructed under the authority of this subchapter. Such person shall at all times when on duty wear upon his or her clothing or have in his or her possession a shield or other suitable badge of authority which such person shall at once exhibit to any person asking therefor.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44766" number="56949" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be the special duty of the persons so appointed to prevent breaches of the peace and unlawful depredations and to arrest and bring before the proper magistrates persons employed on such works or found in the vicinity thereof, who are guilty of offenses against the law punishable by death, imprisonment or fines, or persons whom they may have reasonable cause to believe to be guilty of such offenses.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44767" number="56950" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The sheriff of a county wherein a certificate of appointment of any such person as a peace officer is filed may cancel such certificate for cause, and shall immediately give notice in writing of such cancellation to the commissioner of environmental protection, specifying the cause of such revocation. Such notice may be given by mail. On such cancellation the authority of such person as a peace officer shall immediately cease.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44768" number="56951" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any expense necessarily incurred by a county, town or city in a criminal action or proceeding against any person employed on any works constructed or in process of construction under this subchapter, or in the suppression of riots among persons employed on such work, or in the prevention of the commission of crime by such person, after being duly audited, as required by law, shall constitute a claim in favor of such county, town or city against the city of New York and an action may be maintained on such audit as for money paid to the use of the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44769" number="56952" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-356 Construction and repair of highways and bridges; rules and regulations to prevent improper use. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10761" name="24-356"/>§ 24-356 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction and repair of highways and bridges; rules and regulations to prevent improper use. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44770" number="56953" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The city is hereby required to build and construct such highways and bridges as may be made necessary by the construction of any reservoir under this subchapter, and to repair and forever maintain such additional highways and bridges and to remove the snow and to sand the highway surfaces whenever necessary, except such as shall be part of any state route; and in case any bridge or highway thus constructed shall cross any railroad, it shall do so above or below such railroad and not upon the same level. The plans and specifications for any highways required to be constructed under the provisions of this section shall be approved by the state department of transportation.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44771" number="56954" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of environmental protection shall make such reasonable rules and regulations, not in conflict with the highway law, as may be necessary to prevent improper and destructive use of highways and bridges constructed under the provisions of the water supply laws of the city of New York. Provided, however, that the commissioner of environmental protection shall have no greater authority in respect thereto than is now, or may hereafter be, vested by the highway law of the state of New York in the town, county or state authorities in relation to the construction and regulation of town, county and state highways. Any individual or corporation failing to observe such rules and regulations shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, in addition, shall be liable for actual damages to such highways and bridges, to be recovered by the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44772" number="56955" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The state commissioner of transportation, in his or her discretion, shall have the power to perform, at the request of the commissioner of environmental protection and at the expense of the city, any work of original construction of substituting routes required to be performed by the city pursuant to this section. Whenever the state commissioner of transportation shall grant such a request of the commissioner of environmental protection, he or she shall prepare and submit to such commissioner of environmental protection for his or her approval an estimate of the cost of performing such work. Such estimate of cost shall be an estimate of the cost of performing such work of construction pursuant to plans, designs and specifications prepared by the commissioner of environmental protection and approved by the state commissioner of transportation, and shall include all costs in connection with performing such work, including the costs of engineering, auditing and administration. Upon approval of such estimate by the commissioner of environmental protection, the city shall thereupon deposit with the state comptroller, who is authorized to receive and accept the same, for the purpose of this subdivision, a sum of money equal to such estimate, which shall be subject to the draft or requisition of the state commissioner of transportation and a copy of the resolution of such commissioner of environmental protection authorizing such deposit shall be filed with the state commissioner of transportation and with the state comptroller. If, at any time prior to the award of a contract for the performance of such work or prior to the state commissioner of transportation becoming obligated to award such a contract, it appears to such commissioner of environmental protection that the state commissioner of transportation, for any reason, will be unable to award a contract for the performance of such work or that it is undesirable that such a contract be awarded, any sum or sums so deposited by the city, less the amount of cost which the state commissioner of transportation has already incurred, if any, shall be refunded to the city by the state comptroller upon demand of such commissioner of environmental protection made to the state comptroller and to the state commissioner of transportation. The performance of any such work of construction shall be by contract, to be let, so far as practicable, in the manner provided by section thirty-eight of the highway law, which section shall, so far as practicable, apply to contracts hereunder and payments thereon. Such contract shall be subject to and in conformity with such plans, designs and specifications of the commissioner of environmental protection. No contract shall be executed for any such work until satisfactory proof has been furnished to the state commissioner of transportation that the city has made available any real property required and any easements deemed necessary. When work performed by the state commissioner of transportation hereunder has been completed and the cost thereof paid, the state commissioner of transportation shall render to the commissioner of environmental protection an itemized statement showing in full (a) the amount of money which has been deposited by the city with the state comptroller in connection with such work, and (b) all disbursements made by the state commissioner of transportation in connection with the performance of such work. Any surplus money shall be paid to the city upon the warrant of the state comptroller upon vouchers therefor approved by the state commissioner of transportation.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44773" number="56956" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-357 Report to comptroller of expenses and liabilities. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10763" name="24-357"/>§ 24-357 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Report to comptroller of expenses and liabilities. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44774" number="56957" version="3">
											<PARA>The commissioner of environmental protection shall in every calendar month file in the office of the comptroller an account of any expenses made by the commissioner, or under the commissioner&apos;s authority, and of all liabilities incurred by the commissioner during the preceding month and an abstract of each such account shall be published in the City Record.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44775" number="56958" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-358 Removal of buildings to prevent contamination of the water supply. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10765" name="24-358"/>§ 24-358 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Removal of buildings to prevent contamination of the water supply. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44776" number="56959" version="3">
											<PARA>The city or its representatives shall not enter upon any lands not taken in pursuance of subchapter three-A of chapter three of title five for the purpose of preserving streams or watercourses from pollution or contamination, or of moving or causing to be moved any buildings, improvements or edifices on the ground that the same may contaminate the water supply, without making a provision for just compensation to the owner of such buildings or improvements for the removal or destruction thereof.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44777" number="56960" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-359 Rights of fishing and ice cutting in lakes and reservoirs preserved; regulation. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10767" name="24-359"/>§ 24-359 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rights of fishing and ice cutting in lakes and reservoirs preserved; regulation. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44778" number="56961" version="3">
											<PARA>Nothing herein contained shall authorize or empower the city to prohibit the public from using such lakes or reservoirs that may be constructed under the provisions of this subchapter, for the purpose of ice-cutting or fishing; and the city, or its representatives, shall not hereafter prohibit the public from using such lakes or reservoirs which are now under the care or supervision of the city for the purposes of ice-cutting or fishing, subject, however, to reasonable rules and regulations, and subject however, to the right of the city to prohibit such use in the event of the declaration of an emergency as provided in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="24-326" destination-id="0-0-0-10707">24-326</LINK> of this code.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-44779" number="56962" version="804">
				<HEADING>Subchapter 3: Water Supply to Other Municipalities</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter 3: Water Supply to Other Municipalities</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44780" number="56963" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-360 Water supply to municipalities other than New York city; connections; charges; regulations; quantity to be taken. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10769" name="24-360"/>§ 24-360 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Water supply to municipalities other than New York city; connections; charges; regulations; quantity to be taken. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44781" number="56964" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be lawful for any of the municipal corporations or water districts in the counties of Ulster, Greene, Delaware, Schoharie, Sullivan, Orange, Westchester and Putnam, and for the village of Deposit in the counties of Delaware and Broome, to take and receive from any of the reservoirs, aqueducts, conduits, streams or pipes of the city a supply of water for the uses and purposes of such municipal corporations or water districts or village and to that end such municipal corporations or water districts are, and each of them is, and such village also is, authorized and empowered to lay the necessary mains, pipes, valves, hydrants, supply pipes and other necessary appurtenances for the use of such water, without the consent of any board, officer, bureau, or department of the state or any subdivision thereof.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44782" number="56965" version="1787">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The connections with such reservoirs, aqueducts, conduits, streams or pipes shall be made at the expense of such municipalities or water districts. They shall pay to the city such fair and reasonable water charges or rates as may be agreed upon between the commissioner of environmental protection and the authorities of such municipal corporations or water districts or as from time to time upon the application of either party shall be fixed by the New York state department of environmental conservation, which department is hereby given power to fix such fair and reasonable charges or rates after hearing all parties interested. The expenses of any such hearing and decision by the New York state department of environmental conservation shall be paid by the applicant. Bills for such expenses shall be certified by such department to the applicant and paid by the applicant directly to the claimant within thirty days of the date of such certification.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44783" number="56966" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such charges or rates shall not, however, exceed the charges or rates now charged by the city to persons using water in that city. Such fair and reasonable charges or rates shall be determined on the basis of the actual total cost of the water to the city after deducting from the total cost all construction costs and expenses of operation, maintenance and carrying charges incurred within the corporate limits of the city in connection with the distribution and delivery of the water within such limits. Such charges or rates fixed by the New York state department of environmental conservation shall be subject to review by the supreme court.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44784" number="56967" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any such municipal corporation or water district desiring to take and receive water under the provisions of this section shall make application to the commissioner of environmental protection in writing, showing the place and manner in which it is proposed to make such connections. Such commissioner shall have exclusive jurisdiction in the premises, to the exclusion of any other board, officer, bureau or department of the state or any subdivision thereof. It shall be the duty of the commissioner to grant a permit or authorization for such connections, under reasonable rules and regulations, including the installation of proper meters or other devices for ascertaining the quantity of water thus taken.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44785" number="56968" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The daily quantity of water which may be taken and received by any municipal corporation or water district under the provisions of this section shall not exceed the quantity calculated by multiplying the number of its inhabitants as shown by the last preceding census of the United States or the last state or official municipal census by the daily per capita consumption in the city of New York.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44786" number="56969" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-361 Change in sanitary sewers in city of Kingston, before water taken from Esopus creek, Ulster county. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10771" name="24-361"/>§ 24-361 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Change in sanitary sewers in city of Kingston, before water taken from Esopus creek, Ulster county. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44787" number="56970" version="3">
											<PARA>In case any water shall be taken under the provisions of this subchapter from the Esopus creek in the county of Ulster, then and in that event and before any water shall be diverted from such Esopus creek, the city of New York shall, at the expense, cost and charge of the city and under a plan to be approved of by the common council and the city engineer of the city of Kingston, build, construct, reconstruct, alter or change the sanitary sewers of such city of Kingston known as the first and eighth ward sewers, the trunk sewer of which follows the general line of the Tannery brook in such city of Kingston and which now discharges or flows into the Esopus creek, so that the same shall discharge into the Hudson river or into the Rondout creek. The city of New York shall be liable for all damages of every name and nature which may result from the building, construction, reconstruction, alteration or changing of such sewers, and shall also at the expense, cost and charge of the city of New York, but in the name of the city of Kingston, acquire by purchase or by the condemnation proceedings provided for by this subchapter, all rights in and over private lands in the city of Kingston, which it may be necessary to acquire in order to build, construct, reconstruct, alter or change such sewers. The city of New York in executing such plan, may use for such purposes the public streets of the city of Kingston or any right of way or easement that the city of Kingston now has for the purpose of constructing or maintaining sewers.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44788" number="56971" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-362 Disposal of the sewage of the city of Port Jervis. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10773" name="24-362"/>§ 24-362 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Disposal of the sewage of the city of Port Jervis. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44789" number="56972" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The city of New York, through the commissioner of environmental protection, is hereby authorized and empowered to enter into a contract or agreement, subject to the approval of the board of estimate, with the municipal authorities of the city of Port Jervis, New York, to provide for the treatment and disposition of the sewage of the city of Port Jervis in such manner as may be provided for in said agreement and the said municipal authorities of the city of Port Jervis are likewise authorized and empowered hereby to enter into the agreement aforesaid.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44790" number="56973" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The city of New York, through the commissioner of environmental protection, subject to the approval of the board of estimate, is hereby authorized and empowered to acquire by purchase, or by condemnation pursuant to this subchapter, such real estate in the city of Port Jervis or the county of Orange as may be necessary to carry into effect any agreed plan for the treatment and disposition of the sewage of the city of Port Jervis, and to convey any such real estate so acquired to the city of Port Jervis, any special or general law to the contrary, notwithstanding.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44791" number="56974" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Before proceeding with the construction, the plans and specifications therefor shall be submitted to the state department of health for approval and a permit obtained from the state department of health pursuant to the provisions of the public health law applicable thereto.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44792" number="56975" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-363 Sewage disposal in Ulster, Delaware and Sullivan counties. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10775" name="24-363"/>§ 24-363 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Sewage disposal in Ulster, Delaware and Sullivan counties. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44793" number="56976" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The city of New York, through the commissioner of environmental protection, is hereby authorized and empowered, subject to the approval of the board of estimate, the state department of health, and the authorities of the town or village affected, or in the alternative the supreme court in the judicial district in which the proposed sewers and disposal works are to be located, to construct, maintain and operate systems and plants for the collection, treatment and disposal of sewage in any town or incorporated village in the Rondout creek and Delaware river watersheds in the counties of Ulster, Delaware and Sullivan.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44794" number="56977" version="1787">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The city of New York, through the commissioner of environmental protection, is hereby authorized and empowered, subject to the approval of the board of estimate, to enter into contracts or agreements, where practicable, with the municipal authorities of any towns or incorporated villages within the Rondout creek and Delaware river watersheds, in the counties of Ulster, Delaware and Sullivan, to provide, maintain and operate systems and plants for the collection, treatment and disposal of sewage in any such town or village, and the municipal authorities of any such village or the town board of any such town are likewise authorized and empowered to enter into such agreements with the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44795" number="56978" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If it be deemed by the commissioner of environmental protection to be impracticable to proceed in the manner provided in subdivision b of this section, then the city may present a petition to the supreme court in the judicial district in which such sewers or disposal works are to be located, stating the proposed location of such sewers or disposal plants, that the plans therefor have been approved by the state department of health, and such other facts as may be proper in the circumstances, together with a prayer for an order authorizing the construction of such sewers or disposal works in accordance with such plans. Notice of the time and place of presentation of such petition shall be served on the authorities of the town or village where the sewers or disposal works are to be constructed and on the state department of health and posted in such town or village in at least ten conspicuous public places at least ten days before the hearing on such petition. Upon the presentation of such petition the court shall hear the parties to such proceedings and also such other residents of such towns or villages as desire to be heard. Such court may approve, modify or reject the whole or any part of said plan, upon good and sufficient cause therefor being shown and the order thereon shall be final.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44796" number="56979" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The city, through the commissioner of environmental protection subject to the approval of the board of estimate, is hereby authorized and empowered to acquire by purchase or condemnation pursuant to this subchapter, such real estate in the counties of Ulster, Delaware and Sullivan as may be necessary to carry into effect any plan approved pursuant to the provisions of this section for the collection, treatment and disposal of the sewage of any village or town in said watersheds, and to convey any such real estate so acquired to the village or town in which it is located, any general, special or local law to the contrary, notwithstanding.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44797" number="56980" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When a sewerage system shall have been constructed, the city shall lay and thereafter maintain such pipes as may be necessary from such sewerage system to the outside of the foundation walls of buildings in the area affected by the plans approved. The cost of such pipes shall be paid by the city and in all cases where such pipes are so laid the owner shall make no claim for damage for such entry on his or her property unless the city shall have failed to replace and leave the surface and all improvements in the same condition as they were before the laying of such pipes.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44798" number="56981" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the city shall have constructed a sewerage system and shall have laid the necessary pipes from such system to the outside of the foundation wall of any such building, the owner of such building shall cause the drainage and sewerage of such building to be connected with and discharged into such pipes.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44799" number="56982" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All persons acting under the authority of the city shall have the right to use the ground or soil under any street, highway or road within the counties of Ulster, Delaware and Sullivan, to construct, maintain and operate such sewers and disposal works, on the condition that they shall cause the surface of such street, highway or road to be restored, and all damages done thereto repaired.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-44800" number="56983" version="3">
				<HEADING>Subchapter 4: Water Supply; Miscellaneous</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter 4: Water Supply; Miscellaneous</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44801" number="56984" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-364 Utilization of water to generate electric current. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10777" name="24-364"/>§ 24-364 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Utilization of water to generate electric current. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44802" number="56985" version="3">
											<PARA>The commissioner of environmental protection may, subject to the approval of the board of estimate, utilize such water as the department of environmental protection now owns or as it may hereafter acquire, for the purpose of generating electric current for the use of the municipality, or may permit the utilization of such water for the generation and sale of electric current by an electric corporation which was the owner of a developed or undeveloped water power site or sites affected, acquired or damaged by the execution of a plan or project of the city for an additional water supply, and the commissioner of environmental protection, with the approval of the board of estimate, in connection with the settlement of a resultant claim for damage made by such electric corporation, may grant or lease to such electric corporation for periods not to exceed fifty years, rights in, or to use, the lands and waters of the city for the generation of electric current as herein provided, for such consideration and on such terms and conditions as are, in the opinion of the commissioner, in the best interests of the city of New York, including but not limited to a general release of such claim, provided that such grant or lease may be made at the time of settlement of the claim as above provided but the period of use under the terms of the lease or grant, not to exceed fifty years, may commence when generation of electric current thereunder shall begin, provided that no additional water shall be used for such purpose than would otherwise be required by the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44803" number="56986" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-365 Cemetery and burial grounds. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-763" name="24-365"/>§ 24-365 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cemetery and burial grounds. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44804" number="56987" version="3">
											<PARA>Whenever for the purposes of this subchapter it shall be necessary to use any land or premises, or any portion thereof, now occupied by graves, burial places, cemeteries or other places of interment of human remains, such graves, burial places, cemeteries or other places of interment of human remains and the human remains located therein, shall be removed and disposed of in the following manner: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44805" number="56988" version="1763">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The city having acquired title to the land where burial places are situated shall cause a notice to be published once in each week for four successive weeks in two newspapers published in the county where such burial place or places are situated, which such notice shall be substantially as follows: &quot;Please take notice that the undersigned hereby intends to make application relating to the removal of all the remains, all the monuments and all other distinguishing marks from the cemetery or burial place located in the town of __________________ county of ____________ known as ____________ not less than sixty days after (the last publication date of this notice) for an order pursuant to subchapter four of chapter three of title twenty-four of the administrative code of the city of New York; Please take further notice that any and all person or persons legally entitled to direct as to the disposition of the above may remove the same to any other cemetery or burial place within the same or an adjoining county within sixty days after (the last publication date of this notice) if they so elect upon informing the commissioner of environmental protection in writing of the cemetery or burial place in which said remains are to be reinterred and to which the monuments and other distinguishing marks are to be moved.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44806" number="56989" version="3">
											<PARA>______________________________________</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44807" number="56990" version="3">
											<PARA>Corporation counsel of the city of New York.&quot; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44808" number="56991" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Not less than sixty days after the last publication date of said notice, the corporation counsel shall make an application to a special term of the supreme court in the same judicial district in which the cemetery or burial place is located for an order authorizing such removal of said remains, monuments and all other distinguishing marks to a cemetery or burial place in the same or an adjoining county from that in which said cemetery or burial place is located. Such order shall be made upon due proof of not less than ten days&apos; notice to interested parties who have appeared by attorney, or who have filed appearances in writing with the corporation counsel, and of proof of publication of notice of such application once in each week for four weeks in each of two newspapers published in the county where such cemetery or burial place is situated, immediately prior to application to the supreme court. Such notice shall briefly set forth the time and place of the making of such application and a designation of the cemetery or burial place to which said remains, monuments and distinguishing marks are sought to be removed. All removals and transportation of such human remains shall be done in accordance with the provisions of the public health law and the local rules or ordinances of any town, city or village wherein such cemetery or burial place is located, or wherein any of such remains may be interred. The commissioner of environmental protection on behalf of the city may acquire by purchase such other lands as may be necessary within the county where such cemetery or burial place is located, or in an adjoining county, for the purpose of properly interring such removed remains, which lands shall be acquired with the approval of the supreme court in the same judicial district as that in which the condemnation proceedings were originally instituted. In the acquisition of such lands no cemetery or burial place shall be divided and the acreage acquired must be at least substantially equal to the acreage taken. The commissioner of environmental protection on behalf of the city may also acquire other lands within the county wherein such cemetery or burial place is located, or in an adjoining county, for the purpose of properly interring and removing such remains, in the same manner as provided by this subchapter for the acquisition of water supply and other lands but such acquisition of such lands shall be subject to approval of the supreme court. No lands shall be acquired within the corporate limits of a village or city except within the bounds of an existing cemetery unless by consent of the board of trustees of the village or common council of the city or other authorities within such village or city occupying similar positions as trustees or aldermen, respectively. The supreme court, upon application for the confirmation of the report of the commissioners, shall make inquiry as to the rights of individual lot owners in cemeteries and provide for the protection of such rights as justice shall require. All the bodies removed by said commissioner of environmental protection shall, when distinguishable, be encased each in a separate box or coffin, and each monument, head stone, foot stone, slab, board or other designating or distinguishing mark shall be properly removed and reset at the grave of each body at the time of such reinterment. Members of the same family shall be reinterred in contiguous graves. Whenever any person or persons, legally entitled to direct as to the disposition of any human remains now interred in a cemetery or burial place, shall request, in writing, within the sixty day period aforesaid, the burial of such remains in a cemetery in the same or an adjoining county, the commissioner shall cause such remains to be reinterred where requested within the same county or in adjoining county, and shall carefully and properly remove such remains to such burial plot and properly reinter the same, and in the event that any human remains be removed to, and reinterred in any other place other than that acquired as herein provided, no portion of the expense for the acquisition of any other grave, graves, or other place or places of burial shall be borne by the city, but in such event the city shall bear only the expense of removal and transportation of such remains. Whenever there is no request to remove remains within the sixty day period as hereinbefore provided, the corporation counsel shall apply for an order authorizing such removal in the manner herein provided. Whenever any person or persons legally entitled to direct as to the disposition of any human remains exhumed or to be exhumed from any cemetery or burial place as herein provided, elect to remove the same for reinterment to any burial plot or cemetery not within the same county from which such remains were exhumed, or in an adjoining county, such person or persons so entitled to designate such other burial place or plot shall be permitted to remove such exhumed remains from such county, subject to the provisions of the public health law, and the local rules or ordinances of any town, city or village wherein such cemetery or burial place shall be located, or wherein such human remains may be reinterred, but no portion of the expense of such transportation or burial shall be borne by the commissioner of environmental protection. When any lands acquired for the purposes of reinterment of human remains as herein provided, to which shall have been removed all remains exhumed from a cemetery or burial place belonging to an individual or individuals, or to a corporation organized under the religious corporations law, the not-for-profit corporation law or by special act, or belonging to a town, village or city, the board of estimate of the city of New York shall, after reinterment, execute and deliver, without expense to the prior owner, if an individual, or if such prior owner be a corporation, to the trustees or other governing body of such corporation, by whatsoever name or title they may hold office, or to the board of trustees, if any, of a town burial ground, and to their successors in office, a quit claim deed covering the lands so acquired, together with all structures erected thereon, and where lands have been acquired for the purpose of reinterment of human remains exhumed from a public or private cemetery or burial place which shall have been used by the inhabitants of any town in this state as a cemetery or burial place for the space of fourteen years and not having a board of trustees pursuant to the provisions of the town law, the board of estimate of the city of New York shall, after reinterment, execute and deliver, and without expense to the grantee therefor a quit claim deed or other proper release to such town wherein such lands so acquired as provided by this section may be situated, and such cemetery or burial place shall from and after the execution and delivery thereof be deemed to be vested in such town, and shall be subject, in the same manner as other corporate property of towns, to the government and direction of directors in town meeting, excepting, however, that where such lands so acquired for the purposes set forth in this section are situated within the limits of a village or city, such quit claim deed or release herein provided for shall be executed and delivered to such village or city and thereafter be and become property of such village or city and subject to the laws governing such village or city. From and after the execution and delivery by the board of estimate as by this section provided, of the quit claim deed or release, the city of New York shall be divested of all right and title to said lands so quit claimed or released and shall not thereafter be liable for the care, custody, maintenance and control thereof. This section does not limit any existing right of burial or removal of remains under other provisions of law applicable thereto. Nothing herein contained shall impose any duty whatsoever upon the city of New York for the care, custody, maintenance and control of any burial grounds, cemeteries or other places of interment for human remains.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44809" number="56992" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 24-366 Assessment of electric generation viability. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10779" name="24-366"/>§ 24-366 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Assessment of electric generation viability. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44810" number="56993" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall undertake a resource assessment of the city&apos;s potable water supply and wastewater treatment systems and the natural bodies of water within the city&apos;s jurisdiction to determine the potential of such systems and bodies of water for generating electricity. In performing such assessment the department shall include an examination of the potential to construct and operate energy generating facilities within such systems and natural bodies of water; the means for transmitting the electricity generated; the need to construct and operate generation-related infrastructure; grid-connection issues; generation system installation and maintenance costs; and risks to the operation of water supply and wastewater treatment systems and natural bodies of water posed by energy-generating facilities.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44811" number="56994" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall conduct a technological review of in-conduit and free-flow hydropower technologies that are appropriate for the pressure and water flow rates for each site identified in the resource assessment.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44812" number="56995" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>With information gathered during the resource assessment and technological review, the department shall conduct an economic analysis to determine the economic viability of generating electricity for each site identified in the resource assessment.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44813" number="56996" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The resource assessment, technological review and economic analysis shall be completed within eighteen months of the effective date of the local law that added this section and shall be submitted to the mayor and the speaker of the council.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44814" number="56997" version="1367">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2012/024" destination-id="0-0-0-24772">L.L. 2012/024</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-204457" number="56998" version="1367">
										<HEADING>§ 24-367 Soil and foundation work; notification and permit required.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10781" name="24-367"/>§ 24-367 Soil and foundation work; notification and permit required.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44815" number="56999" version="1256">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever soil or foundation work, as defined in <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="BC Ch. 33" destination-id="0-0-0-16523">chapter 33</LINK> of the New York city building code, for any purpose, is proposed to a depth greater than 50 feet in the borough of the Bronx or on or north of 135th Street in the borough of Manhattan, or greater than 100 feet in the borough of Brooklyn, Queens, or Staten Island or south of 135th Street in the borough of Manhattan, the owner of the premises, engineer, architect or contractor shall notify the department of environmental protection of the location of such activity at least 30 business days prior to commencement of such activity. Within 10 business days of receiving such notification, the department shall determine whether the location of such activity is in close proximity to critical infrastructure, as defined in rules promulgated by the department, and notify the owner of the premises, engineer, architect or contractor of such determination. If the department determines that the location of such activity is in close proximity to critical infrastructure, the owner of the premises, engineer, architect or contractor shall obtain a permit from the department prior to commencement of such activity. The issuance of any permit or approval by any agency of the city other than the department for such activity shall not relieve the owner of the premises, engineer, architect or contractor of the obligation to comply with the notification and permitting requirements of this section. The department may promulgate a rule waiving or amending the notification and permitting requirements of this section where the department determines that such activity must be performed on an emergency basis. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44816" number="57000" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department may issue a stop work order whenever the department finds that any soil or foundation work in violation of this section or any rules promulgated thereunder creates a danger to critical infrastructure. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44817" number="57001" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such order shall be posted at the site of the soil or foundation work and served personally on or mailed to the owner or developer or to the person executing the work at the site or the agent of any of them. When there is an immediate danger to critical infrastructure, a verbal order to stop work may be given followed promptly by a written order in accordance with this subdivision. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44818" number="57002" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon issuance of a stop work order, work specified in the order shall immediately cease, except work authorized or required by the commissioner to make the site safe. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44819" number="57003" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No person shall, with knowledge or notice of a stop work order, allow, authorize, promote, continue or cause to be continued any work covered by the stop work order, except work authorized or required by the commissioner to make the site safe. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44820" number="57004" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon application in accordance with the rules of the department, the commissioner shall rescind the stop work order where the commissioner finds (i) that the condition that gave rise to its issuance has been corrected and either all civil penalties or criminal fines assessed for any violation of such order have been paid or, where a violation is pending, security for the payment of such penalties or fines has been posted or, (ii) where the stop work order was issued in error or conditions are such that the order should not have been issued. The commissioner may by rule require the payment of a fee in the amount of the expense of additional inspection and administrative expense related to such stop work order. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44821" number="57005" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful to tamper with, remove or deface a written posted stop work order from the location where it was affixed unless and until such stop work order has been rescinded by the commissioner. The owner or other person in control of the location shall ensure that the stop work order remains posted until rescinded by the commissioner. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-44822" number="57006" version="3">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2018/065, 1/19/2018, eff. 1/19/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-021]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-44823" number="57007" version="1069">
										<HEADING>§ 24-368 Database of water accounts.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-21380" name="24-368"/>§ 24-368 Database of water accounts.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135862" number="57008" version="1762">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any contrary provision of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T23C005" destination-id="0-0-0-10147">chapter 5 of title 23</LINK>, the commissioner of environmental protection shall create and maintain a searchable online database through which members of the public who register and pay a periodic subscription fee, as established by the department, may access information about a water account in any commercial, residential and industrial property, however such database shall be subject to the exceptions provided in subdivision b. Such database shall be available on or through the city&apos;s website, in a non-proprietary format that permits automated processing, have the ability to produce reports by query, be accessible through an application programming interface and include all non-confidential information maintained in connection with such water account, including, but not necessarily limited to, the following: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135861" number="57009" version="1069">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Water meter number, as designated by the 8-digit serial number on such meter; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135860" number="57010" version="1069">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Date and copy of the bill of every bill issued for such water account, including metered billing and flat rate accounts and accounts billed attributed consumption charges, to the extent such bill is available to the customer for such water account on the portal provided to such customer; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135859" number="57011" version="1069">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Reading of such water meter, as recorded by the department, to the extent such reading is available to the department; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135858" number="57012" version="1069">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Total amount of water used pursuant to the reading described in paragraph 3 of this subdivision; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135857" number="57013" version="1069">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Current account balance for such water account, including open late payment charges; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135856" number="57014" version="1069">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Payment history dating back at least 5 years; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135855" number="57015" version="1069">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Date such water meter was installed and date such water meter was sealed, to the extent such dates are available; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135854" number="57016" version="1069">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Size of such water meter, in cubic feet; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135853" number="57017" version="1069">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Cumulative denial-of-access fees; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135852" number="57018" version="1069">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>10.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Cumulative theft-of-service fees. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135851" number="57019" version="1069">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such database shall not provide access to properties in tax class one with three or fewer dwelling units, to any person other than the owner of such property, a party or entity authorized by the property owner, a party appearing on the deed of such property, or any lender with an unpaid mortgage encumbering the property, provided that such property owners shall not be required to pay to register to access information in such database concerning said properties. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135850" number="57020" version="1069">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The database shall maintain the information required by subdivision a for any water meter that has been replaced. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135849" number="57021" version="1069">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The database shall include the information required by subdivision a starting from January 1, 1996 or the date the water meter was installed, whichever is later. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135848" number="57022" version="1069">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2021/145, 12/11/2021, eff. 4/10/2022) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-135847" number="57023" version="1069">
										<HEADING>§ 24-369 Notice to certain property owners.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-21378" name="24-369"/>§ 24-369 Notice to certain property owners.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135846" number="57024" version="1069">
											<PARA>Notice shall be provided once every three months to an owner of a one, two or three family residential real property in class one with outstanding water and sewer charges.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135845" number="57025" version="1069">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2021/145, 12/11/2021, eff. 4/10/2022) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>