<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-129390" number="5311" version="550">
			<HEADING>Chapter 2: Actions Against New York City</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1813" name="T07C002"/>Chapter 2: Actions Against New York City</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-4130" number="5312" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 7-201 Actions against the city. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1815" name="7-201"/>§ 7-201 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Actions against the city. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4131" number="5313" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In every action or special proceeding prosecuted or maintained against the city, the complaint or necessary moving papers shall contain an allegation that at least thirty days have elapsed since the demand, claim or claims, upon which such action or special proceeding is founded, were presented to the comptroller for adjustment, and that the comptroller has neglected or refused to make an adjustment or payment thereof for thirty days after such presentment, except that in every action or special proceeding in relation to excise or non-property taxes, such complaint or necessary moving papers shall contain an allegation that such demand, claim or claims upon which the action or special proceeding is founded, were presented to the commissioner of finance for adjustment and that the commissioner has neglected or refused to make an adjustment or payment thereof for thirty days after such presentment.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4132" number="5314" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>An action against the city, for damages for injuries to real or personal property, or for the destruction thereof, alleged to have been sustained by reason of the negligence of, or by the creation or maintenance of a nuisance by the city, or any agency thereof, shall be commenced within one year after the cause of action therefor shall have accrued, provided that a notice of the intention to commence such action and of the time when and place where the damages were incurred or sustained, together with a verified statement showing in detail the property alleged to have been damaged or destroyed, and the value thereof, shall have been filed with the comptroller within six months after such cause of action shall have accrued.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4133" number="5315" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>As used in this subdivision:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4134" number="5316" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;street&quot; shall include the curbstone, an avenue, underpass, road, alley, lane, boulevard, concourse, parkway, road or path within a park, park approach, driveway, thoroughfare, public way, public square, public place, and public parking area.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4135" number="5317" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;sidewalk&quot; shall include a boardwalk, underpass, pedestrian walk or path, step and stairway.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4136" number="5318" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;bridge&quot; shall include a viaduct and an overpass.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4137" number="5319" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No civil action shall be maintained against the city for damage to property or injury to person or death sustained in consequence of any street, highway, bridge, wharf, culvert, sidewalk or crosswalk, or any part or portion of any of the foregoing including any encumbrances thereon or attachments thereto, being out of repair, unsafe, dangerous or obstructed, unless it appears that written notice of the defective, unsafe, dangerous or obstructed condition, was actually given to the commissioner of transportation or any person or department authorized by the commissioner to receive such notice, or where there was previous injury to person or property as a result of the existence of the defective, unsafe, dangerous or obstructed condition, and written notice thereof was given to a city agency, or there was written acknowledgement from the city of the defective, unsafe, dangerous or obstructed condition, and there was a failure or neglect within fifteen days after the receipt of such notice to repair or remove the defect, danger or obstruction complained of, or the place otherwise made reasonably safe.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4138" number="5320" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of transportation shall keep an indexed record in a separate book of all written notices which the city receives and acknowledgement of which the city gives of the existence of such defective, unsafe, dangerous or obstructed conditions, which record shall state the date of receipt of each such notice, the nature and location of the condition stated to exist and the name and address of the person from whom the notice is received. This record shall be a public record. The record of each notice shall be maintained in the department of transportation for a period of three years after the date on which it is received and shall be preserved in the municipal archives for a period of not less than ten years.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4139" number="5321" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Written acknowledgement shall be given by the department of transportation of all notices received by it. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-4140" number="5322" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 7-202 Power of comptroller to extend the time for commencement of suit upon claims. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1817" name="7-202"/>§ 7-202 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Power of comptroller to extend the time for commencement of suit upon claims. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4141" number="5323" version="3">
											<PARA>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the comptroller may, by stipulation in writing, agree with a claimant against the city, the board of education or any community college of the city university of New York, to extend the time of such claimant to commence suit upon a claim, the settlement of which is then pending before the comptroller, provided that such stipulation shall not extend the time within which such suit may be brought for a period or periods aggregating more than six months after the expiration of the time otherwise limited by law for the commencement of a suit upon such claim.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-4142" number="5324" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 7-203 Settlement of claims. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1819" name="7-203"/>§ 7-203 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Settlement of claims. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4143" number="5325" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The comptroller may require any person presenting for settlement an account or claim, except a claim with regard to excise and non-property taxes, for any cause against the city or the board of education, to be sworn before the comptroller, any of the deputy comptrollers, or any officer or employee of the comptroller&apos;s office or of the law department designated in a written instrument by the comptroller and filed in the comptroller&apos;s office, touching such account or claim, and when so sworn, to answer orally as to any facts relative to the justness of such account or claim. Wilful false swearing before the comptroller, deputy comptroller or officer or employee designated to conduct such oral examination is perjury and punishable as such. In adjusting and settling such claims, the comptroller, as far as practicable, shall be governed by the rules of law and principles of equity which prevail in courts of justice. Claims against the city or against any of the counties contained within its territorial limits, or payable in the first instance from moneys in the city treasury for services rendered or work done or materials or supplies furnished, except:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4144" number="5326" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>claims reduced to judgment, or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4145" number="5327" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>awards, costs, charges and expenses duly taxed or ordered paid in judicial proceedings, or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4146" number="5328" version="675">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>claims arising under the provisions of contracts made at public letting in the manner provided by <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="Chapter 13" destination-id="0-0-0-0">chapter thirteen</LINK> of the charter and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T06C001" destination-id="0-0-0-1615">chapter one of title six</LINK> of the code, or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4147" number="5329" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>claims settled and adjusted by the comptroller, pursuant to the authority of this section, shall not be paid unless an auditor of accounts shall certify that the charges therefor are just and reasonable.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4148" number="5330" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except as hereinbefore otherwise provided, all contracts with the city or any of such counties or with any public officer acting in its or their behalf, shall be subject to audit by the comptroller. The power hereby given to settle and adjust such claims shall not be construed to authorize the comptroller to dispute the amount of any salary established by or under the authority of any officer or department authorized to establish the same, nor to question the due performance of duties by such officer, except when necessary to prevent fraud. If in any action at law against the city to recover upon a claim not embraced within the exceptions specified in subdivision a the amount claimed by the plaintiff is in excess of the amount so audited and settled by the comptroller, the plaintiff must establish a claim by competent evidence of value, and no testimony shall be admitted to show a promise or agreement by any officer or employee of the city or of any of the counties contained within its territorial limits to pay any larger sum than the amount so audited or allowed by the comptroller. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-4149" number="5331" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 7-204 Settlement of claims. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1821" name="7-204"/>§ 7-204 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Settlement of claims. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4150" number="5332" version="3">
											<PARA>The commissioner of finance may require any person presenting for settlement a claim in relation to excise and non-property taxes against the city to be sworn before the commissioner of finance, any of the deputy commissioners of finance, or any officer or employee of the department of finance or of the law department designated in a written instrument by the commissioner of finance and filed in the office of the commissioner, touching such claim, and when so sworn, to answer orally as to any facts relative to the justness of such claim. Wilful false swearing before the commissioner of finance, any deputy commissioner or officer or employee designated to conduct such oral examination is perjury and punishable as such. In adjusting and settling such claims, the commissioner of finance, as far as practicable, shall be governed by the rules of law and principles of equity which prevail in courts of justice.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-4151" number="5333" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 7-205 Comptroller to audit charges against city for costs, etc. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1823" name="7-205"/>§ 7-205 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Comptroller to audit charges against city for costs, etc. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4152" number="5334" version="3">
											<PARA>The comptroller, with the approval of the mayor, is authorized to audit and allow, as charges against the city, the reasonable costs, counsel fees and expenses paid or incurred, or which shall hereafter be paid or incurred by any commissioner or any judge of the civil or criminal courts of the city of New York who shall have been a successful party in any proceeding or trial to remove him or her from office, or who shall bring or defend any action or proceeding, in which the question of his or her title to office is in any way presented or involved, or in which it is sought to convict him or her, or to review or prohibit any such removal or to obtain possession of his or her office, or by any commissioner for the proper presentation and justification of his or her official conduct before any body or tribunal lawfully investigating the same, and not officially recommending his or her removal from office. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-4153" number="5335" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 7-206 Illegal claims; power of board of estimate to pay or compromise on equitable grounds. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1825" name="7-206"/>§ 7-206 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Illegal claims; power of board of estimate to pay or compromise on equitable grounds. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4154" number="5336" version="3">
											<PARA>The board of estimate may inquire into, hear and determine any claim against the city or any agency when the comptroller, or in the case of a claim against the board of education, the comptroller and the board of education, certifies in writing that such claim is illegal or invalid, but that it is equitable and proper that such claim be paid in whole or in part. If, upon such inquiry, the board of estimate, by a unanimous vote, determines that benefits have been received by the city or any agency and that public interests will best be served by payment or compromise thereof, it may authorize payment of such claim, and such claim shall thereupon be paid in such amount as the board shall determine to be just, in full satisfaction thereof, provided that the claimant shall execute a release, upon any such payment, in such form as shall be approved by the corporation counsel. The provisions of this section shall not authorize the audit or payment of any claim barred by the statute of limitations, nor any claim for services performed under an appointment in violation of any provision of the civil service law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-4155" number="5337" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 7-207 Payment of bonds upon which suit is barred by lapse of time. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1827" name="7-207"/>§ 7-207 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Payment of bonds upon which suit is barred by lapse of time. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4156" number="5338" version="3">
											<PARA>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the comptroller shall pay the principal and interest upon bonds or other evidences of indebtedness issued by the city within twenty years after a cause of action has accrued on said bonds or other evidences of indebtedness issued by the city or interest thereon, suit upon which may be barred by the statute of limitations. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-4157" number="5339" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 7-208 Claims for injuries caused by police while executing legal process or sustained by persons injured while assisting in the apprehension of a criminal. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1829" name="7-208"/>§ 7-208 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Claims for injuries caused by police while executing legal process or sustained by persons injured while assisting in the apprehension of a criminal. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4158" number="5340" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The board of estimate may inquire into, hear and determine any claim against the city wherein compensation is sought for the death of or injury to any person or persons:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4159" number="5341" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>which shall have been caused by a police officer of the city, while such officer is engaged in arresting or endeavoring to arrest any person or in retaking any person who has escaped from legal custody, or in executing any legal process, or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4160" number="5342" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>which shall have been caused by any person who is engaged in or who is in the act of leaving the scene of the commission of a felony or who is endeavoring to escape from a police officer or from legal custody, if such death was caused or injury received in assisting a police officer in the performance of the officer&apos;s duties.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4161" number="5343" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The board, by a unanimous vote, as a matter of grace and not as a matter of right, may award an amount recommended by the comptroller to be paid to the person or persons injured, or in the case of death to the person or persons who would be entitled to distribution under the provisions of EPTL 5-4.4 or any amendments thereto. As a condition precedent, however, to consideration by the board, such claim must be certified in writing to the board by the comptroller as an illegal or invalid claim against the city, but which in the comptroller&apos;s judgment it is equitable and proper to pay in the amount certified by the comptroller; and provided, further, that a written petition stating all the essential facts in relation to such injury or death, signed by the injured person or persons, or in case of death by a person or persons entitled to receive the award or any part thereof, or by the personal representatives of a decedent, shall be filed with the comptroller within six months of the date of the occurrence which resulted in such injury or death. The provisions of this section shall not authorize the audit or payment of any claim barred by the statute of limitations. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-4162" number="5344" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 7-209 Issuance of execution. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1831" name="7-209"/>§ 7-209 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Issuance of execution. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4163" number="5345" version="3">
											<PARA>Before execution may be issued upon any judgment recovered against the city ten days&apos; notice in writing of the recovery of such judgment shall be given to the comptroller.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-4164" number="5346" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 7-210 Liability of real property owner for failure to maintain sidewalk in a reasonably safe condition. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1833" name="7-210"/>§ 7-210 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Liability of real property owner for failure to maintain sidewalk in a reasonably safe condition. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4165" number="5347" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be the duty of the owner of real property abutting any sidewalk, including, but not limited to, the intersection quadrant for corner property, to maintain such sidewalk in a reasonably safe condition.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4166" number="5348" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the owner of real property abutting any sidewalk, including, but not limited to, the intersection quadrant for corner property, shall be liable for any injury to property or personal injury, including death, proximately caused by the failure of such owner to maintain such sidewalk in a reasonably safe condition. Failure to maintain such sidewalk in a reasonably safe condition shall include, but not be limited to, the negligent failure to install, construct, reconstruct, repave, repair or replace defective sidewalk flags and the negligent failure to remove snow, ice, dirt or other material from the sidewalk. This subdivision shall not apply to one-, two- or three-family residential real property that is (i) in whole or in part, owner occupied, and (ii) used exclusively for residential purposes.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4167" number="5349" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the city shall not be liable for any injury to property or personal injury, including death, proximately caused by the failure to maintain sidewalks (other than sidewalks abutting one-, two- or three-family residential real property that is (i) in whole or in part, owner occupied, and (ii) used exclusively for residential purposes) in a reasonably safe condition. This subdivision shall not be construed to apply to the liability of the city as a property owner pursuant to subdivision b of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4168" number="5350" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing in this section shall in any way affect the provisions of this chapter or of any other law or rule governing the manner in which an action or proceeding against the city is commenced, including any provisions requiring prior notice to the city of defective conditions. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4169" number="5351" version="1493">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2003/049" destination-id="0-0-0-25334">L.L. 2003/049</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-211255" number="5352" version="1493">
										<HEADING>§ 7-211 Personal injury and property damage liability insurance. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1835" name="7-211"/>§ 7-211 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Personal injury and property damage liability insurance. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4170" number="5353" version="3">
											<PARA>An owner of real property, other than a public corporation as defined in section sixty-six of the general construction law or a state or federal agency or instrumentality, to which subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="7-210" destination-id="0-0-0-1833">7-210</LINK> of this code applies, shall be required to have a policy of personal injury and property damage liability insurance for such property for liability for any injury to property or personal injury, including death, proximately caused by the failure of such owner to maintain the sidewalk abutting such property in a reasonably safe condition. The city shall not be liable for any injury to property or personal injury, including death, as a result of the failure of an owner to comply with this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4171" number="5354" version="1492">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2003/054" destination-id="0-0-0-25330">L.L. 2003/054</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-211224" number="5355" version="1492">
										<HEADING>§ 7-212 Authority to make payments for personal injury, including death, where abutting property owner liable pursuant to section 7-210 is uninsured. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1837" name="7-212"/>§ 7-212 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Authority to make payments for personal injury, including death, where abutting property owner liable pursuant to section 7-210 is uninsured. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4172" number="5356" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where a judgment for personal injury, including death, obtained against an abutting property owner pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="7-210" destination-id="0-0-0-1833">7-210</LINK> of this code is unsatisfied for a period of at least one year following entry of such judgment in the office of the county clerk of the county in which such property is situated and the judgment debtor has been determined by the comptroller after investigation to have no policy of liability insurance or other assets to satisfy such judgment, the comptroller, after consultation with the corporation counsel, is hereby authorized and empowered to make a payment for such personal injury, including death.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4173" number="5357" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any such payment shall be made in the discretion of the comptroller and shall not be made as a matter of right. The amount of such payment shall not exceed uncompensated medical expenses. Payment may be in a single payment, or may be made in periodic payments. No such payment or periodic payments shall exceed fifty thousand dollars in total with respect to any unsatisfied judgment and the total of all such payments for all judgments in any fiscal year shall not exceed four million dollars.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4174" number="5358" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Petitions for a payment under this section shall be presented to the comptroller not less than one or more than three years following entry of such judgment in the office of the county clerk of the county in which such property is located. Each petition shall include evidence demonstrating (i) that efforts to collect the judgment have been pursued, and (ii) that the judgment debtor has no policy of liability insurance or other assets to satisfy the judgment.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4175" number="5359" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Before the comptroller shall make such payment, he or she shall require the petitioner to execute an assignment of the judgment to the city. After assignment the city shall be entitled to enforce the judgment. To the extent that the city collects money on the judgment in excess of the payment or payments made to a petitioner pursuant to this section, such excess amount shall be paid to the petitioner after deducting the city&apos;s expenses.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4176" number="5360" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No payment shall be made under this section if it is determined that the unsatisfied judgment was obtained by fraud, or by collusion of the plaintiff and of any defendant in the action.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4177" number="5361" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The comptroller shall, by rule, establish procedures for the presentation of petitions for payment pursuant to the provisions of subdivision c of this section, for the review of such petitions by that office and with respect to such other matters as are necessary to implement the provisions of this section. </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-4178" number="5362" version="1492">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2003/054" destination-id="0-0-0-25330">L.L. 2003/054</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>