<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-128171" number="39835" version="475">
			<HEADING>Chapter 1: License Enforcement</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7925" name="T20C001"/>Chapter 1: License Enforcement</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-32485" number="39836" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 20-101 Legislative intent. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7927" name="20-101"/>§ 20-101 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Legislative intent. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32486" number="39837" version="421">
											<PARA>The council finds that for the protection and relief of the public from deceptive, unfair and unconscionable practices, for the maintenance of standards of integrity, honesty and fair dealing among persons and organizations engaging in licensed activities, for the protection of the health and safety of the people of New York city and for other purposes requisite to promoting the general welfare, licensing by the department of consumer and worker protection is a necessary and proper mode of regulation with respect to certain trades, businesses and industries. The council finds further that, in order to secure the above-mentioned purposes, and generally to carry out responsibilities for supervising and regulating licensed activities, trades, businesses and industries, the commissioner of consumer and worker protection requires powers, remedies and sanctions which are equitable, flexible and efficient. Finally, the council finds that sanctions and penalties applied by the commissioner and by the courts for the violation of laws and regulations by individuals and organizations engaging in various licensed activities, trades, businesses and industries, must be sufficient to achieve these above-mentioned purposes of licensing. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-052]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32487" number="39838" version="708">
											<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2020/080, 8/28/2020, eff. 8/28/2020) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-052]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-124507" number="39839" version="476">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2020/080" destination-id="0-0-0-20343">L.L. 2020/080</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-053]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-128172" number="39840" version="475">
										<HEADING>§ 20-102 Definitions. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7929" name="20-102"/>§ 20-102 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32488" number="39841" version="3">
											<PARA>Wherever used in this title: </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32489" number="39842" version="421">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Commissioner&quot; shall mean the commissioner of consumer and worker protection. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-052]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32490" number="39843" version="421">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Department&quot; shall mean the department of consumer and worker protection. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-052]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32491" number="39844" version="421">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;License&quot; shall mean an authorization by the department of consumer and worker protection to carry on various activities within its jurisdiction, which may take the form of a license, permit, registration, certification or such other form as is designated under law, regulation or rule. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-052]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32492" number="39845" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Organization&quot; shall mean a business entity, including but not limited to a corporation, trust, estate, partnership, cooperative, association, firm, club or society.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32493" number="39846" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Person&quot; shall mean a natural person or an organization.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32494" number="39847" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Trade name&quot; shall mean that name under which an organization or person solicits, engages in, conducts or transacts a business or activity.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32495" number="39848" version="708">
											<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2020/080, 8/28/2020, eff. 8/28/2020) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-052]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-124508" number="39849" version="476">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2020/080" destination-id="0-0-0-20343">L.L. 2020/080</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-053]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-128173" number="39850" version="475">
										<HEADING>§ 20-103 Construction of this chapter and chapter two of this title. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7931" name="20-103"/>§ 20-103 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction of this chapter and chapter two of this title. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32496" number="39851" version="3">
											<PARA>The provisions of this chapter and chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T20C002" destination-id="0-0-0-2521">two</LINK> of this title shall be liberally construed in accordance with the legislative declaration of the city council set forth in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="20-101" destination-id="0-0-0-7927">20-101</LINK>.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-32497" number="39852" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 20-104 Powers of the commissioner with respect to licensing. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7145" name="20-104"/>§ 20-104 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Powers of the commissioner with respect to licensing. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32498" number="39853" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner shall have cognizance and control of the granting, issuance, transferring, renewal, denial, revocation, suspension and cancellation of all licenses issued under chapter two and under all other laws conferring such powers upon him or her. The commissioner or the commissioner&apos;s designee shall collect all fees for all such licenses and permits and shall otherwise enforce the provisions of chapter two.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32499" number="39854" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner shall, as he or she determines necessary and appropriate, promulgate, amend and rescind regulations and rules:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32500" number="39855" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>to carry out the powers and duties of the department;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32501" number="39856" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>to prevent and remedy fraud, misrepresentation, deceit and unconscionable dealing, and to promote fair trade practices by those engaging in licensed activities;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32502" number="39857" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>to require adequate disclosure by those engaging in licensed activities of both the terms and conditions under which they perform licensed activities, adequate disclosure of the true names or true corporate names of licensees, and adequate disclosure of applicable local, state and federal law pertinent to consumers&apos; interests regarding the conduct of activities licensed under chapter two; </PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32503" number="39858" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>to require that licensees keep such records as he or she may determine are necessary or useful for carrying out the purposes of chapter two and, except as specifically set forth in chapter two, retain them for three years;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32504" number="39859" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>to ensure that all persons and organizations licensed under this title have made appropriate financial disclosure, and that the premises complies with all legal requirements necessary to engage in the licensed activity;</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32505" number="39860" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>with respect to licensed activities, to protect the health, safety, convenience and welfare of the general public; and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32506" number="39861" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>to ensure that those engaging in licensed activities do not discriminate against any person on the basis of age, sex, race, color, national origin, creed or religion in violation of city, state or federal laws.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32507" number="39862" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner shall compile all regulations and rules promulgated by the department and maintain a copy thereof, available for public inspection at his or her principal office at such times as that office shall be open for business. A record of each license issued indicating its kind and class, the license number, the fee received therefor and such other records as the commissioner may require shall be kept by the department.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32508" number="39863" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner or the commissioner&apos;s designee shall be authorized to conduct investigations, to issue subpoenas, to receive evidence, to hear complaints regarding activities for which a license is or may be required, to take depositions on due notice, to serve interrogatories, to hold public and private hearings upon due notice, to take testimony and to promulgate, amend and modify procedures and practices governing such proceedings.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32509" number="39864" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner shall be authorized, upon due notice and hearing, to suspend, revoke or cancel any license issued by him or her in accordance with the provisions of chapter two and to impose or institute fines or civil penalties for the violation of (i) any of the provisions of chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T20C002" destination-id="0-0-0-2521">two</LINK> of this title and regulations and rules promulgated under chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T20C002" destination-id="0-0-0-2521">two</LINK> of this title and (ii) any of the provisions of any other law, rule or regulation, the enforcement of which is within the jurisdiction of the department including but not limited to subchapter one of chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T20C005" destination-id="0-0-0-7933">five</LINK> of this title (the consumer protection law) subchapter two of chapter five (the truth in-pricing-law); provided that such violation is committed in the course of and is related to the conduct of the business, trade or occupation which is required to be licensed pursuant to chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T20C002" destination-id="0-0-0-2521">two</LINK> of this title. Except to the extent that dollar limits are otherwise specifically provided such fines or civil penalties shall not exceed five hundred dollars for each violation.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32510" number="39865" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner may arrange for the redress of injuries caused by such violations, and may otherwise provide for compliance with the provisions and purposes of chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T20C002" destination-id="0-0-0-2521">two</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32511" number="39866" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner or the commissioner&apos;s designee shall be authorized to suspend the license of any person pending payment of such fine or civil penalty or pending compliance with any other lawful order of the department.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32512" number="39867" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner shall be authorized to impose a fine or civil penalty or to suspend a license or both for a failure to appear at a hearing at the department after due notice of such hearing. If a license has been suspended, it shall be returned to the department forthwith upon receipt of the order of suspension. Failure to surrender the license shall be grounds for a fine or civil penalty or revocation of the license.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32513" number="39868" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any of the remedies provided for in this section shall be in addition to any other remedies provided under any other provision of law.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32514" number="39869" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner, upon due notice and hearing, may require that persons licensed under chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T20C002" destination-id="0-0-0-2521">two</LINK> of this title who have committed repeated, multiple or persistent violations of chapter two or any other law, rule or regulation the enforcement of which is within the jurisdiction of the department, conspicuously display at their place of business and in advertisements a notice (of a form, content and size to be specified by the commissioner), which shall describe the person&apos;s record of such violations; provided that, for each time such display is required, the commissioner may require that such notice be displayed for not less than ten nor more than one hundred days.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32515" number="39870" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner may refuse to issue or renew any license issued in accordance with the provisions of chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T20C002" destination-id="0-0-0-2521">two</LINK> of this title and may suspend or revoke any such license, after due notice and opportunity to be heard, upon the occurrence of any one or more of the following conditions:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32516" number="39871" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Two or more judgments within a two-year period against the applicant or licensee for theft of identity as defined in section three hundred eighty-s of the general business law; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32517" number="39872" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>One criminal conviction against the applicant or licensee for acts of identity theft or unlawful possession of personal identification information as defined in article one hundred ninety of the penal law; or</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32518" number="39873" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Two or more criminal convictions within a two-year period of any employees or associates of the applicant or licensee for acts of identity theft or unlawful possession of personal identification information as defined in article one hundred ninety of the penal law that are committed with the use of the applicant&apos;s or licensee&apos;s equipment, data, technology, or other similar resource. It shall be an affirmative defense that a applicant or licensee did not have reasonable grounds to believe the proscribed acts were taking place with the use of the licensee&apos;s equipment, data, technology, or other similar resource or that the proscribed acts were not taking place with the use of the applicant&apos;s or licensee&apos;s equipment, data, technology, or other similar resource.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32519" number="39874" version="1472">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2005/044" destination-id="0-0-0-25202">L.L. 2005/044</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-209718" number="39875" version="1472">
										<HEADING>§ 20-105 Additional powers of the commissioner with respect to unlicensed activities. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2405" name="20-105"/>§ 20-105 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Additional powers of the commissioner with respect to unlicensed activities. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32520" number="39876" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be unlawful for any person required to be licensed pursuant to the provisions of chapter two or pursuant to provisions of state law enforced by the department to engage in any trade, business or activity for which a license is required without such license.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32521" number="39877" version="422">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to the enforcement procedures set forth in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="20-106" destination-id="0-0-0-7935">20-106</LINK> of this chapter and chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T20C002" destination-id="0-0-0-2521">two</LINK> of this title the commissioner upon due notice and hearing shall be authorized: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-052]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32522" number="39878" version="422">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>to impose fines upon any person in violation of subdivision a of this section of one hundred dollars per violation per day for each and every day during which such person violates such subdivision, with each day constituting a distinct and independent violation. Except as otherwise expressly provided in chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T20C002" destination-id="0-0-0-2521">two</LINK> of this title, fines imposed pursuant to this paragraph shall be in addition to, and shall not be offset or modified by, any fines or civil penalties prescribed by chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T20C002" destination-id="0-0-0-2521">two</LINK> of this title. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-052]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32523" number="39879" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>to order any person in violation of subdivision a of this section immediately to discontinue such activity at the premises on which such activity is occurring.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32524" number="39880" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>to order that such premises on which such activity is occurring be sealed, provided that such premises are primarily used for such activity.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32525" number="39881" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>to order that any devices, items or goods sold, offered for sale available for public use or utilized in the operation of a business and relating to such activity for which a license is required but has not been obtained pursuant to the provisions of chapter two shall be removed, sealed or otherwise made inoperable.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32526" number="39882" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Orders of the commissioner issued pursuant to this subdivision shall be posted at the premises on which unlicensed activity occurs in violation of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32527" number="39883" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Orders of the commissioner issued pursuant to paragraph two, three or four of subdivision b of this section shall be stayed with respect to any person who, prior to service of the notice provided in subdivision b of this section, had submitted a full and complete application in proper form and accompanied by the requisite fee for a license or the renewal of a license while such application is pending.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32528" number="39884" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Ten days after the posting of an order issued pursuant to paragraph two, three or four of subdivision b of this section and upon the written directive of the commissioner, officers and employees of the department and officers of the New York city police department are authorized to act upon and enforce such orders.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32529" number="39885" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any devices, items or goods removed pursuant to the provisions of subdivision b of this section shall be stored in a garage, pound or other place of safety and the owner or other person lawfully entitled to the possession of such devices, items, or goods may be charged with reasonable costs for removal and storage payable prior to the release of such devices, items or goods to such owner or such other person.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32530" number="39886" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner shall order that any premises which are sealed pursuant to this section shall be unsealed and that any devices, items or goods removed, sealed or otherwise made inoperable pursuant to this section shall be released, unsealed or made operable upon:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32531" number="39887" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>payment of all outstanding fines and all reasonable costs for removal and storage, and</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32532" number="39888" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>presentation of proof that a license has been obtained for such activity or, if such person or premises are for any reason ineligible to obtain a license, proof satisfactory to the commissioner that such premises, devices, items or goods will not be used in violation of this section.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32533" number="39889" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be a misdemeanor for any person to remove the seal on any premises or remove the seal or make operable any devices, items or goods sealed or otherwise made inoperable in accordance with an order of the commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32534" number="39890" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner or other person lawfully entitled to reclaim the devices, items or goods removed pursuant to this section shall reclaim such devices, items or goods. If such owner or such other person does not reclaim such devices, items or goods within ninety days of their removal, such devices, items or goods shall be subject to forfeiture upon notice and judicial determination in accordance with provisions of law. Upon forfeiture the department shall, upon a public notice of at least five days, sell such forfeited devices, items or goods at public sale. The net proceeds of such sale, after deduction of the lawful expenses incurred, shall be paid into the general fund of the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32535" number="39891" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>j.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the event that any removal made pursuant to this section shall include any perishable items, goods or food products which cannot be retained in custody without such items, goods or food products becoming unwholesome, putrid, decomposed or unfit in any way, they may be delivered to the commissioner of health for disposition pursuant to the provisions of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="17-323" destination-id="0-0-0-6809">17-323</LINK> of this code.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32536" number="39892" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>k.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of this section shall not be construed to apply to general vendors required to be licensed pursuant to subchapter twenty-seven of chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T20C002" destination-id="0-0-0-2521">two</LINK> of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32537" number="39893" version="708">
											<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2020/080, 8/28/2020, eff. 8/28/2020) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-052]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-124509" number="39894" version="476">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2020/080" destination-id="0-0-0-20343">L.L. 2020/080</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-053]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-128174" number="39895" version="475">
										<HEADING>§ 20-106 Judicial enforcement. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7935" name="20-106"/>§ 20-106 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Judicial enforcement. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32538" number="39896" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except as otherwise specifically provided in chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T20C002" destination-id="0-0-0-2521">two</LINK> of this title, or in subdivision b of this section, any person, whether or not he or she holds a license issued under chapter two, who violates any provision of chapter two or any regulation or rule promulgated under it shall, upon conviction thereof, be punished for each violation by a fine of not less than twenty-five dollars nor more than five hundred dollars, or by imprisonment not exceeding fifteen days, or both; and any such person shall be subject also to a civil penalty in the sum of one hundred dollars for each violation, to be recovered in a civil action.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32539" number="39897" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who engages without a license therefor in an activity for which a license is required by any provision of chapter two, shall, upon conviction thereof, be subject to the following sanctions:</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32540" number="39898" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If he or she has never held a license for such activity, he or she shall be subject to a fine of not less than twenty-five dollars, nor more than five hundred dollars, or by imprisonment not exceeding fifteen days, or both; and any such person shall be subject also to the payment of a civil penalty in the sum of the greater of twice the applicable license fee or one hundred dollars, to be recovered in a civil action.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32541" number="39899" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If he or she has never held a license for such activity, and has been convicted once previously for engaging in such activity without a license, or if he or she has held such license and his or her license has lapsed prior to such person&apos;s perfecting an application for a renewal, he or she shall be subject to a fine of not less than one hundred dollars nor more than one thousand dollars, or by imprisonment not exceeding thirty days, or both; and he or she shall be subject also to civil penalty in the sum of one thousand dollars, to be recovered in a civil action.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32542" number="39900" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If such person has held such a license, but his or her license has been suspended or revoked, or he or she has twice previously been convicted of engaging in such activity without a license, he or she shall be subject to a fine of not less than two hundred dollars nor more than two thousand dollars, or by imprisonment not exceeding sixty days, or both; and he or she shall be subject also to a civil penalty in the sum of two thousand dollars, to be recovered in a civil action.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32543" number="39901" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every manager or proprietor of a business required to be licensed under chapter two who consents to, causes or allows that business to operate without a license and every person aiding such unlicensed business and every owner or lessee of any building, part of building, grounds, room or place, who leases or lets the premises for the operation of any unlicensed business or assents that the premises be used for any such purpose, is in violation of this title and shall be subject to a penalty of one hundred dollars per day for every day during which the unlicensed business operates. This penalty shall be prosecuted, sued for and recovered in the name of the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32544" number="39902" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The corporation counsel is authorized to bring an injunction proceeding to restrain or enjoin any violation of this title.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-32545" number="39903" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 20-107 Application; filing fee; license fee. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7937" name="20-107"/>§ 20-107 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application; filing fee; license fee. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32546" number="39904" version="2276">
											<PARA style-name="EdNote" style-name-escaped="EdNote" style-id="0-0-0-17">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note: </CHARFORMAT>this section has been amended by <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-24" type="Web" url="https://legistar.council.nyc.gov/LegislationDetail.aspx?ID=7423870&amp;GUID=936312B5-EB50-4C5B-845B-A63BB2AF3365&amp;Options=ID|Text|&amp;Search=">L.L. 2025/183, 12/12/2025, eff. 9/8/2026</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-116]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-235650" number="39905" version="2276">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All applications for licenses shall be made to the commissioner or the commissioner&apos;s designee in such form and detail as shall be prescribed.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32547" number="39906" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every application for a license or the renewal of an existing license shall provide an opportunity for the applicant to indicate the language in which he or she would prefer that inspections in connection with such license be conducted. Nothing in this subdivision nor any failure to comply with such preference shall be construed so as to create a cause of action or constitute a defense in any legal, administrative, or other proceeding.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32548" number="39907" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except as specifically provided in chapter two, every application shall include the license fee for the full license term. If the license is not issued, the lesser of fifty dollars or one-half of the amount of the annual license fee shall be retained by the department as a non-returnable filing fee. In the event a license is issued for less than the full license term, the applicable fee shall be decreased proportionately to the nearest half year, except that in no case shall the fee be less than the fee for one-half year. Where a two year license is surrendered for a reason other than suspension or revocation and less than one year of the license term has expired, the licensee may apply for a refund of an amount equal to one year&apos;s license fee. Except as otherwise specifically provided for in chapter two, reference to fees, license fees or any other word of similar import shall be deemed to be the license fee for one year. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this section, whenever the commissioner increases or decreases the term of a type of license pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="20-108" destination-id="0-0-0-7939">20-108</LINK> of this chapter, the fee for such license shall be increased or decreased proportionately and the amount of refund due upon surrender of such license before the expiration of the term for a reason other than suspension or revocation shall be prorated to the unexpired term.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32549" number="39908" version="2276">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1989/084" destination-id="0-0-0-26918">L.L. 1989/084</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2025/183" destination-id="0-0-0-28500">L.L. 2025/183</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-116]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-221114" number="39909" version="1696">
										<HEADING>§ 20-108 License terms. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7939" name="20-108"/>§ 20-108 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">License terms. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32550" number="39910" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner shall establish by regulation the expiration date of licenses issued pursuant to chapter two.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32551" number="39911" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Licenses issued pursuant to chapter two shall be for a two-year term unless otherwise specifically provided for in chapter two; provided, however, that whenever the commissioner changes the expiration date of a type of license pursuant to subdivision a of this section, he or she may also increase or decrease the term of such type of license by rule to the extent necessary to effectuate the change.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32552" number="39912" version="1696">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1989/084" destination-id="0-0-0-26918">L.L. 1989/084</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-221115" number="39913" version="1696">
										<HEADING>§ 20-109 Transferability. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7941" name="20-109"/>§ 20-109 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Transferability. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32553" number="39914" version="3">
											<PARA>No license issued under chapter two shall be assignable or transferable unless otherwise specifically provided by law or regulation or rule issued by the commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-32554" number="39915" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 20-110 Change of corporate ownership. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7943" name="20-110"/>§ 20-110 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Change of corporate ownership. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32555" number="39916" version="3">
											<PARA>Where any person or organization becomes the beneficial owner of ten percent or more of the stock of an organization to which a license has been granted pursuant to chapter two, if such person or organization previously did not hold at least a ten percent interest, such license shall immediately become void unless prior written approval of the commissioner or the commissioner&apos;s designee is obtained.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-32556" number="39917" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 20-111 Change in a partnership. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7945" name="20-111"/>§ 20-111 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Change in a partnership. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32557" number="39918" version="3">
											<PARA>Any license issued under chapter two shall immediately become void upon the addition or termination of any general partner or upon the dissolution of a partnership unless prior written approval of the commissioner or the commissioner&apos;s designee is obtained.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-32558" number="39919" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 20-112 Address of licensed activity. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7947" name="20-112"/>§ 20-112 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Address of licensed activity. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32559" number="39920" version="3">
											<PARA>Except as specifically provided in chapter two, a license shall be valid only for the location designated upon the application therefor, except in the case of licenses issued for activities which in their nature are carried out at large and not at a fixed place of business. No license shall be issued for more than one location. Licensees shall, at least ten days prior thereto, notify the commissioner or the commissioner&apos;s designee by registered or certified mail, or personal service, of any change of address of the licensed premises or of the residence of the licensee.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-32560" number="39921" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 20-113 Trade name. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7949" name="20-113"/>§ 20-113 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Trade name. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32561" number="39922" version="3">
											<PARA>A license issued under chapter two shall be valid only for activities conducted under the name of the person or organization to whom such license was issued or under the trade name stated in the application therefor; if a licensed activity is to be conducted under a trade name, the application must state that trade name. No license shall be issued for more than one trade name, and no licensed activity may be carried out under more than one such name; provided, however, that if a person or organization was engaged in bona fide licensed activities under more than one such trade name or was issued a license to conduct licensed activities under more than one trade name prior to June fifth, nineteen hundred seventy-three, a single license shall be issued for such trade names. Licensees shall notify the commissioner or the commissioner&apos;s designee of any change of trade name at least ten days before such change becomes effective, and no such change may take place without the prior written approval of the commissioner or the commissioner&apos;s designee.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-32562" number="39923" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 20-114 Inspection; display of license. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7951" name="20-114"/>§ 20-114 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Inspection; display of license. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32563" number="39924" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All licensed vehicles or places of business shall be regularly inspected, and reports thereof shall be made to the commissioner.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32564" number="39925" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All licensees shall conspicuously post on their premises, licenses issued under chapter two and said licenses shall be accessible at all times for inspection by any interested person. Licensees having no fixed place of business shall exhibit their licenses upon the request of any interested person.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-32565" number="39926" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 20-115 Bonds. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7953" name="20-115"/>§ 20-115 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Bonds. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32566" number="39927" version="3">
											<PARA>Except as specifically provided in chapter two, a bond may be required for any licensed activity in a form and amount approved by the commissioner for the due observance of the provisions of chapter two and the laws, regulations and rules governing the conduct of licensed activities. The amount of the bond shall be established by the commissioner after a public hearing, five-day notice of which shall be published in the City Record.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-32567" number="39928" version="3">
										<HEADING>§ 20-116 Advertising. </HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7955" name="20-116"/>§ 20-116 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Advertising. </CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32568" number="39929" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person required to be licensed under chapter two or pursuant to provisions of state law enforced by the department to carry on a trade, occupation or business activity, who is not so licensed may not advertise the availability of goods and services related to the carrying on of such trade, occupation or business activity in any print publication or broadcast media having a circulation or audience within the city.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32569" number="39930" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner after notice and hearing shall be authorized to impose civil penalties upon any person found to have violated subdivision a of this section. Such penalties shall be levied for each broadcast of such advertisement and shall be not less than fifty dollars nor more than two hundred fifty dollars for each violation. Such penalties for printed advertisements shall be determined based on the period of time the publication in which the advertisement appears remains current. The current period shall be determined as that time when a publication is initially offered for sale until the period when the next dated publication is offered for sale. In no case shall this period be less than twenty-four hours. If the current period is: daily, such penalty shall be not less than fifty dollars nor more than one hundred dollars per day; weekly, such penalty shall be not less than two hundred fifty dollars nor more than three hundred fifty dollars per week; greater than one week and not more than one month, such penalty shall be not less than three hundred fifty dollars nor more than five hundred dollars; greater than one month, such penalty shall be not less than five hundred dollars nor more than one thousand dollars. Such civil penalties may be recovered in a civil action before any court having jurisdiction of such actions.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32570" number="39931" version="3">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner shall promulgate regulations requiring that any person required to be licensed under this title or pursuant to provisions of state law enforced by the department shall state in all print advertising with respect to such licensed activity the license number, and that the activity is licensed by the department.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-32571" number="39932" version="1073">
										<HEADING>§ 20-117 Licensee disclosure of breach of security, notification requirements.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7957" name="20-117"/>§ 20-117 Licensee disclosure of breach of security, notification requirements<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">.</CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32585" number="39933" version="1073">
											<PARA>Any person who is required to be licensed pursuant to <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T20C002" destination-id="0-0-0-2521">chapter two of this title</LINK> or pursuant to provisions of state law enforced by the department, and who is also required to make a notification pursuant to subdivision 2 or 3 of section 899-aa of the general business law, shall promptly submit a copy of such notification to the department. Such notice shall be made without delaying notice to any individual whose private information was, or is reasonably believed to have been, accessed, acquired, disclosed, or used by an unauthorized person. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-136015" number="39934" version="1073">
											<PARA>(Repealed L.L. 2021/080, 7/18/2021, eff. 11/15/2021; Added L.L. 2021/151, 12/11/2021, eff. 4/10/2022) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-068]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135341" number="39935" version="1472">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2005/046" destination-id="0-0-0-25198">L.L. 2005/046</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2021/080" destination-id="0-0-0-21122">L.L. 2021/080</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-135342" number="39936" version="1030">
										<HEADING>§ 20-118 Notifications regarding identity theft. [Repealed]</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7959" name="20-118"/>§ 20-118 Notifications regarding identity theft. [Repealed]</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135346" number="39937" version="1030">
											<PARA>(Repealed L.L. 2021/080, 7/18/2021, eff. 11/15/2021) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135339" number="39938" version="1472">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2005/044" destination-id="0-0-0-25202">L.L. 2005/044</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2021/080" destination-id="0-0-0-21122">L.L. 2021/080</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
								<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-135340" number="39939" version="1030">
										<HEADING>§ 20-119 Penalties.</HEADING>
										<PARA>
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7961" name="20-119"/>§ 20-119 Penalties.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-134645" number="39940" version="1037">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except as otherwise provided in this section and this chapter, any person who violates any provision of this chapter or any rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter shall be subject to a civil penalty of: (i) one hundred seventy-five dollars for the first violation; (ii) three hundred dollars for the second violation committed; and (iii) five hundred dollars for the third and any subsequent violation committed. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-135588" number="39941" version="1811">
											<PARA>
												<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who violates section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="381572687-333571626-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Rules.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T06C001_1-21" destination-id="0-0-0-0">1-21 of title 6</LINK> of the rules of the city of New York, or any successor to such provision, shall be subject to a civil penalty of five hundred dollars. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32589" number="39942" version="1037">
											<PARA>(L.L. 2015/069, 6/29/2015, eff. 6/29/2015; L.L. 2021/080, 7/18/2021, eff. 11/15/2021; Am. L.L. 2021/098, 9/26/2021, eff. 11/15/2021) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-32591" number="39943" version="2278">
											<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
												<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2015/069" destination-id="0-0-0-20617">L.L. 2015/069</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2021/080" destination-id="0-0-0-21122">L.L. 2021/080</LINK>, and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2021/098" destination-id="0-0-0-21262">L.L. 2021/098</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-067]</HIGHLIGHTER>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>