<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Admin" content-collection-id="NYCadmin" source-infobase-title="New York City Administrative Code" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\NYCadmin.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCadmin_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCadmin\output\QYOUGRVBABWOEQAB\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCadmin_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Title" style-name-escaped="Title" style-id="0-0-0-682" level-depth="1" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-129337" number="19357" version="547">
			<HEADING>Title 12: Personnel and Labor</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4549" name="T12"/>Title 12: Personnel and Labor</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-685" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-15945" number="19358" version="3">
				<HEADING>Chapter 1: Officers and Employees</HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4551" name="T12C001"/>Chapter 1: Officers and Employees</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-688" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Appendix" style-name-escaped="Appendix" style-id="0-0-0-691" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-694" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Article" style-name-escaped="Article" style-id="0-0-0-697" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle" style-name-escaped="Subarticle" style-id="0-0-0-700" level-depth="7" toc-section="false">
								<LEVEL style-name="Subarticle - Part" style-name-escaped="Subarticle---Part" style-id="0-0-0-29474" level-depth="8" toc-section="false">
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15946" number="19359" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-101 Salaries; retroactive increases forbidden. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4553" name="12-101"/>§ 12-101 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Salaries; retroactive increases forbidden. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15947" number="19360" version="3">
												<PARA>Any action taken by the head of an agency or by the mayor to increase the salary of any officer or person whose salary is paid out of the city treasury, to take effect prior to the date of such action is void.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15948" number="19361" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-102 Salaries; increases after fixation in budget permitted. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4555" name="12-102"/>§ 12-102 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Salaries; increases after fixation in budget permitted. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15949" number="19362" version="3">
												<PARA>The head of an agency subject to the provisions of section one hundred twenty-four of the charter, or the mayor shall have the power to increase, during any fiscal year, the salary of any officer or person paid from the city treasury even after such salary shall have been fixed in the budget for such fiscal year.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15950" number="19363" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-103 Salaries; of county officials. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4557" name="12-103"/>§ 12-103 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Salaries; of county officials. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15951" number="19364" version="3">
												<PARA>The salaries of all county officers in counties within the city, unless otherwise provided by law, shall be fixed by the mayor.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15952" number="19365" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-104 Payment of claims of certain employees authorized. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4559" name="12-104"/>§ 12-104 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Payment of claims of certain employees authorized. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15953" number="19366" version="1772">
												<PARA>The mayor is hereby authorized to inquire into, hear and determine any claim heretofore or hereafter filed against the city, or any agency, or the board of education, by a duly appointed employee or his or her estate, where it is shown that such employee failed and neglected to cash the check paid to such employee for services rendered, notwithstanding a bar to the payment of any such claim by limitation of time or otherwise. The mayor may, after due consideration, authorize payment of such claim, and such claim shall thereupon be paid in such amount as the mayor shall determine to be just, in full satisfaction thereof, provided that the claimant or his or her estate, shall execute and deliver a release upon receipt of such payment, in such form as shall be approved by the corporation counsel. The allowance in payment of such claim shall be without any interest whatsoever. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15954" number="19367" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-105 Heads of agencies; power to make deductions from salaries of subordinates. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4561" name="12-105"/>§ 12-105 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Heads of agencies; power to make deductions from salaries of subordinates. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15955" number="19368" version="3">
												<PARA>Except as otherwise provided by law, every head of an agency is empowered:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15956" number="19369" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To make ratable deductions from the salaries and wages of subordinates, on account of absences from duty without leave.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15957" number="19370" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In his or her discretion, to cause deductions to be made from the salaries, compensation or wages of subordinates of such agency, not exceeding thirty days&apos; pay, as a fine for delinquency or misconduct.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15958" number="19371" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In his or her discretion, to suspend for not more than one month without pay, any subordinate pending the hearing and determination of charges against such subordinate, or the making of any explanation, as the case may be. If the subordinate so suspended be removed, such subordinate shall not be entitled to salary or compensation after suspension. If he or she be not so removed, such subordinate shall be entitled to full salary or compensation from the date of suspension to the date of reinstatement, less such deduction or fine as may be imposed. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15959" number="19372" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-106 Heads of agencies other than the police and fire commissioner, may rehear charges against and reinstate persons dismissed. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4563" name="12-106"/>§ 12-106 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Heads of agencies other than the police and fire commissioner, may rehear charges against and reinstate persons dismissed. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15960" number="19373" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The head of any agency, upon written application by any person who has been dismissed from service, setting forth the reasons for demanding an opportunity of making a further explanation, shall have the power, in his or her discretion, to rehear the explanation and any new matter offered in further reply to the charges or complaint upon which such person was dismissed from service. Such person shall be required to waive, in writing, all claims against the city for back pay. Such application for another opportunity to explain shall only be presented to and granted by the officer who made the removal or such officer&apos;s immediate successor, when the applicant for the further explanation shall make it appear, by affidavit:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15961" number="19374" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>That on a further opportunity to explain, he or she can produce such evidence as would probably have changed the decision if it had been presented theretofore; and</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15962" number="19375" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If such evidence has been discovered since the previous explanation, that it is not cumulative; and</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15963" number="19376" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>That the failure to produce it at the first explanation was not owing to want of diligence.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15964" number="19377" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If upon the further explanation, the head of such agency shall determine that such person has been illegally or unjustly dismissed, the head of such agency may, in his or her discretion, and with the approval in writing of the commissioner of citywide administrative services, cause such person to be reinstated.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15965" number="19378" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The consent of the mayor shall be required when reinstatement of an applicant is made by the immediate successor of the removing official. It shall be unlawful, however, for the immediate successor of the removing official to reinstate an applicant who has been removed for more than two years.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15966" number="19379" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section shall not apply to members of the uniformed forces under the jurisdiction of the police commissioner and the fire commissioner. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15967" number="19380" version="1582">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1996/059" destination-id="0-0-0-26052">L.L. 1996/059</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-216114" number="19381" version="1582">
											<HEADING>§ 12-107 Publication of notice of appointments, removals, and changes of salaries. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4565" name="12-107"/>§ 12-107 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Publication of notice of appointments, removals, and changes of salaries. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15968" number="19382" version="3">
												<PARA>Notice of all appointments and removals from office, and all changes of salaries except those resulting from collective bargaining or original jurisdiction adjustments, shall be transmitted within one week after they are made, by the appointing agency or department head, to and published within thirty days in the City Record, indicating the name, title and salary of each individual appointed, promoted, demoted, removed from office or whose services have otherwise terminated, and whether an appointment is a &quot;provisional appointment.&quot;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15969" number="19383" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-108 Overtime work by officers or employees and additional compensation therefor. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4567" name="12-108"/>§ 12-108 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Overtime work by officers or employees and additional compensation therefor. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15970" number="19384" version="3">
												<PARA>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other statute, general, special or local, the mayor may authorize the head of any agency to require any officer or employee in such agency or any class or group of officers or employees in such agency to work in excess of the maximum number of hours of employment prescribed for such officer or employee or class or group of officers or employees by any statute, general, special or local, provided that each such officer or employee shall be paid overtime compensation for such work at not less than his or her regular basic pay rate. The amounts received as overtime compensation pursuant to the provisions of this section shall be regarded as salary or compensation for the purposes of any pension or retirement system of which the employee receiving such overtime compensation is a member. Such overtime compensation shall not be regarded as salary or compensation for the purpose of determining the right to any increase of salary or any salary increment on account of length of service or otherwise, nor shall the payment of such overtime compensation be construed to constitute a promotion. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15971" number="19385" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-109 Activities of mayor and other officers of the city or of any agency as officers or members of an educational corporation chartered by the board of regents of the University of the state of New York to carry out programs to encourage scholastic achievement by pupils within the city. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4569" name="12-109"/>§ 12-109 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Activities of mayor and other officers of the city or of any agency as officers or members of an educational corporation chartered by the board of regents of the University of the state of New York to carry out programs to encourage scholastic achievement by pupils within the city. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15972" number="19386" version="679">
												<PARA>The provisions of sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="1100" destination-id="0-0-0-0">eleven hundred</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="2604" destination-id="0-0-0-0">two thousand six hundred four</LINK> of the charter, section three of the general city law and any other similar provision of law, general, special or local, or rule or regulation or rule of law shall not apply to the mayor, the head of any city department or of any agency, or any other officer of the city or of any agency in respect to his or her activities as an officer or member of an educational corporation chartered by the board of regents of the University of the state of New York to carry out award, citation, scholarship and other programs in cooperation with participating colleges and universities designed to encourage scholastic achievement on the part of pupils attending public, private and parochial schools within the city of New York or to foster interest in the humanities and the arts and to encourage participation in cultural programs. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, general, special or local, the mayor, the head of any department of the city or of any agency or any other officer of the city or any agency may, during his or her term of office, serve as an officer or member of such a corporation.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-15973" number="19387" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-110 Annual disclosure. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1119" name="12-110"/>§ 12-110 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Annual disclosure. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15974" number="19388" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in this section:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15975" number="19389" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;affiliated&quot; shall mean a firm that is a subsidiary of another firm, or two firms that have a parent in common, or two firms with a stockholder in common who owns at least twenty-five per cent of the shares of each such firm.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15976" number="19390" version="679">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;agency&quot; or &quot;city agency&quot; shall mean a city, county, borough or other office, position, administration, department, division, bureau, board, commission, authority, corporation, committee or other agency of government, the expenses of which are paid in whole or in part from the city treasury, and shall include but not be limited to the council, the offices of each elected city official, the board of education, community boards, the health and hospitals corporation, the New York city industrial development agency, the offices of the district attorneys of the counties of Bronx, Kings, New York, Queens and Richmond, and of the special narcotics prosecutor, the New York city housing authority, and the New York city housing development corporation, but shall not include any court or any corporation or institution maintaining or operating a public library, museum, botanical garden, arboretum, tomb, memorial building, aquarium, zoological garden or similar facility or any advisory committee as that term is defined in subdivision one of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="2601" destination-id="0-0-0-0">twenty-six hundred one</LINK> of the charter.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15977" number="19391" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;business dealings&quot; shall mean any transaction involving the sale, purchase, rental, disposition or exchange of any goods, services, or property, any license, permit, grant or benefit, and any performance of or litigation with respect to any of the foregoing, but shall not include any transaction involving a public servant&apos;s residence or any ministerial matter.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15978" number="19392" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;city&quot; shall mean the city of New York and shall include an agency of the city.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15979" number="19393" version="679">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;conflicts of interest board&quot; or &quot;board&quot; shall mean the conflicts of interest board appointed pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="2602" destination-id="0-0-0-0">twenty-six hundred two</LINK> of the New York city charter.;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15980" number="19394" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;domestic partners&quot; shall mean persons who have a registered domestic partnership, which shall include any partnership registered pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="3-240" destination-id="0-0-0-767">3-240</LINK> of the administrative code of the city of New York.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15981" number="19395" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;gift&quot; shall mean anything of value for which a person pays nothing or less than fair market value and may be in the form of money, services, reduced interest on a loan, travel, travel reimbursement, entertainment, hospitality, thing, promise, or in any other form. &quot;Gift&quot; shall not include reimbursements.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15982" number="19396" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;income&quot; shall include, but not be limited to, salary from government employment, income from other compensated employment whether public or private, directorships and other fiduciary or advisory positions, contractual arrangements, teaching income, partnership income, lecture fees, consultant fees, bank and bond interest, dividends, income derived from a trust, real estate rents, and recognized gains from the sale or exchange of real or other property.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15983" number="19397" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;independent body&quot; shall mean any organization or group of voters which nominates a candidate or candidates for office to be voted for at an election, and which is not a political party as defined in paragraph twelve* of this subdivision.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15984" number="19398" version="3">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">* <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> should be &quot;thirteen&quot;. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-026]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15985" number="19399" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>10.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The terms &quot;local authority,&quot; &quot;local public authority&quot; or &quot;city public authority&quot; shall be given the same meaning as the term &quot;local authority&quot; is given in subdivision two of section two of the public authorities law and shall include only such entities that have their primary office in the city of New York.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15986" number="19400" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>11.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;local political party official&quot; shall mean:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15987" number="19401" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>any chair of a county committee elected pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="2-112" destination-id="0-0-0-4571">2-112</LINK> of the election law, or his or her successor in office, who received compensation or expenses, or both, from constituted committee or political committee funds, or both, during the reporting period aggregating thirty thousand dollars or more;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15988" number="19402" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>that person (usually designated by the rules of a county committee as the &quot;county leader&quot; or &quot;chair of the executive committee&quot;) by whatever title designated, who pursuant to the rules of a county committee or in actual practice, possesses or performs any or all of the following duties or roles, provided that such person received compensation or expenses, or both, from constituted committee or political committee funds, or both, during the reporting period aggregating thirty thousand dollars or more:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15989" number="19403" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the principal political, executive and administrative officer of the county committee;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15990" number="19404" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the power of general management over the affairs of the county committee;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15991" number="19405" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the power to exercise the powers of the chair of the county committee as provided for in the rules of the county committee;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15992" number="19406" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the power to preside at all meetings of the county executive committee if such a committee is created by the rules of the county committee or exists de facto, or any other committee or subcommittee of the county committee vested by such rules with or having de facto the power of general management over the affairs of the county committee at times when the county committee is not in actual session;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15993" number="19407" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the power to call a meeting of the county committee or of any committee or subcommittee vested with the rights, powers, duties or privileges of the county committee pursuant to the rules of the county committee, for the purpose of filling an office at a special election in accordance with section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="6-114" destination-id="0-0-0-1657">6-114</LINK> of the election law, for the purpose of filling a vacancy in accordance with section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="6-116" destination-id="0-0-0-1665">6-116</LINK> of such law or for the purpose of filling a vacancy or vacancies in the county committee which exist by reason of an increase in the number of election districts within the county occasioned by a change of the boundaries of one or more election districts, taking effect after the election of its members, or for the purpose of determining the districts that the elected members shall represent until the next election at which such members of such committee are elected; provided, however, that in no event shall such power encompass the power of a chair of an assembly district committee or other district committee smaller than a county and created by the rules of the county committee, to call a meeting of such district committee for such purpose;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15994" number="19408" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the power to direct the treasurer of the party to expend funds of the county committee; or</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15995" number="19409" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the power to procure from one or more bank accounts of the county committee the necessary funds to defray the expenses of the county committee. The terms &quot;constituted committee&quot; and &quot;political committee&quot; as used in this subparagraph shall have the same meanings as those contained in section 14-100 of the election law.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15996" number="19410" version="679">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>12.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;policymaking position&quot; shall mean the position held by a person charged with &quot;substantial policy discretion&quot; as referenced in paragraphs twelve and fifteen of subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="2604" destination-id="0-0-0-0">twenty-six hundred four</LINK> of the New York city charter and as defined by rule of the conflicts of interest board.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15997" number="19411" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>13.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;political party&quot; shall mean any political organization which at the last preceding election for governor polled at least fifty thousand votes for its candidate for governor.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15998" number="19412" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>14.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;political organization&quot; shall mean any political party as defined in paragraph thirteen of this subdivision, or independent body, as defined in paragraph nine of this subdivision, or any organization that is affiliated with or a subsidiary of a party or independent body.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-15999" number="19413" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>15.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;reimbursements&quot; shall mean any travel-related expenses provided by non-governmental sources, whether directly or as repayment, for activities related to the reporting person&apos;s official duties, such as speaking engagements, conferences, or fact-finding events, but shall not include gifts.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16000" number="19414" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>16.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;relative&quot; shall mean the spouse, domestic partner, child, stepchild, brother, sister, parent, or stepparent of the person reporting, or any person whom the person reporting claimed as a dependent on his or her most recently filed personal income tax return, and each such relative&apos;s spouse or domestic partner.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16001" number="19415" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>17.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;securities&quot; shall mean bonds, mortgages, notes, obligations, warrants and stocks of any class, investment interests in limited or general partnerships and such other evidences of indebtedness and certificates of interest as are usually referred to as securities.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16002" number="19416" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>18.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The terms &quot;state agency&quot; and &quot;local agency&quot; shall be given the same meanings as such terms are given in section eight hundred ten of the general municipal law.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16003" number="19417" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>19.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;unemancipated child&quot; shall mean any son, daughter, stepson or stepdaughter who is under age eighteen, unmarried and living in the household of the person reporting at the time the person files his or her annual disclosure report, and shall also include any son or daughter of the spouse or domestic partner of such person who is under age eighteen, unmarried and living in the household of the person reporting at the time the person files his or her annual disclosure report.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16004" number="19418" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Persons required to file an annual disclosure report.</CHARFORMAT> The following persons shall file with the conflicts of interest board an annual disclosure report, in such form as the board shall determine, disclosing certain financial interests as hereinafter provided. Reports shall, except as otherwise provided by the board, be filed electronically, in such form as the board may determine.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16005" number="19419" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Elected and political party officials.</CHARFORMAT>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16006" number="19420" version="679">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each elected officer described in sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="4" destination-id="0-0-0-0">four</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24" destination-id="0-0-0-0">twenty-four</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="25" destination-id="0-0-0-0">twenty-five</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="81" destination-id="0-0-0-0">eighty-one</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="91" destination-id="0-0-0-0">ninety-one</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="1125" destination-id="0-0-0-0">eleven hundred twenty-five</LINK> of the New York city charter, and each local political party official described in paragraph eleven of subdivision a of this section, shall file such report not later than such date designated by the conflicts of interest board each year.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16007" number="19421" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A local political party official required to file a report pursuant to subparagraph (a) of this paragraph who is also subject to the financial disclosure filing requirements of subdivision two of section seventy-three-a of the public officers law may satisfy the requirements of paragraph one by filing with the conflicts of interest board a copy of the statement filed pursuant to section seventy-three-a of the public officers law, on or before the filing deadline provided in such section seventy-three-a, notwithstanding the filing deadline otherwise imposed by paragraph one of this subdivision.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16008" number="19422" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Candidates for public office.</CHARFORMAT>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16009" number="19423" version="146">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each person, other than any person described in paragraph one, who has declared his or her intention to seek a designation or nomination for election to an office described in paragraph one of this subdivision and who has filed papers or petitions for a designation or nomination for election, or on whose behalf a certification of nomination or designating or independent nominating petition has been filed which has not been declined, for an office described in paragraph one shall file such report within 25 days after the last day for filing his or her designating or independent nominating petitions pursuant to the election law, provided that the board shall establish by rule the dates, not to exceed 31 days prior to the relevant payment date, by which a person who intends to seek payment on the payment dates of February 15, March 15, or April 15 shall file such report, and further provided that a person who has declared his or her intention to seek a designation or nomination for election to an office described in paragraph one of this subdivision and who intends to seek a payment of public funds on December 15 in the year preceding a covered election or January 15 in the year of a covered election, pursuant to subdivision 4 of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="3-705" destination-id="0-0-0-1113">3-705</LINK>, shall file a report no later than November 1 of the year preceding such covered election, with such report covering a period of the first nine months of the calendar year preceding such covered election. Any person filing a report covering the first nine months of a year preceding a covered election shall file a report for the entire calendar year preceding a covered election by January 30 in the year of such covered election. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-039]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16010" number="19424" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each person, other than any person described in paragraph one, who was a write-in candidate at the primary election for an office described in paragraph one of subdivision b of this section and whose name is thereafter entered in the nomination book at the board of elections, shall file such report within 25 days after such primary election. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-019]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16011" number="19425" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each person, other than any person described in paragraph one, who has been designated to fill a vacancy in a designation or nomination for an office described in paragraph one of subdivision b of this section shall file such report within 20 days after a certificate designating such person to fill such vacancy is filed with the board of elections, or within five days before the election for which the certificate is filed, whichever is earlier. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-019]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16012" number="19426" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The conflicts of interest board shall obtain from the board of elections lists of all candidates for the elected positions set forth in paragraph one of subdivision b of this section, and from such lists, shall determine and publish lists of those candidates who have not, within ten days after the required date for filing such reports, filed the reports required by this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-019]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16013" number="19427" version="1812">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The following categories of persons who had such status during the preceding calendar year or up until the date of filing their annual disclosure report shall be required to file a report not later than the date designated by the conflicts of interest board each year:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16014" number="19428" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each agency head, deputy agency head, assistant agency head, and member of any board or commission who on the date designated by the board for filing holds a policymaking position, as defined by rule of the board and as annually determined by the head of his or her agency, subject to review by the board;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16015" number="19429" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each officer or employee of the city in the mayor&apos;s office, the city council, a district attorney&apos;s office, the office of the special narcotics prosecutor, or any other agency that does not employ M-level mayor&apos;s management plan indicators for its managers, whose responsibilities on the date designated by the board for filing involve the independent exercise of managerial or policymaking functions or who holds a policymaking position on such date, as defined by rule of the board and as annually determined by the appointing authority of his or her agency, subject to review by the board;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16016" number="19430" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each officer or employee of the city, other than an officer or employee of the city in the mayor&apos;s office, the city council, a district attorney&apos;s office or the special narcotics prosecutor&apos;s office, who, on the date designated by the board for filing, is paid in accordance with the mayor&apos;s management pay plan at level M4 or higher, or who holds a policymaking position on such date, as defined by rule of the board and as annually determined by the head of his or her agency, subject to review by the board;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16017" number="19431" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each officer or employee of the city whose duties at any time during the preceding calendar year involved the negotiation, authorization or approval of contracts, leases, franchises, revocable consents, concessions and applications for zoning changes, variances and special permits, as defined by rule of the board and as annually determined by his or her agency head, subject to review by the board.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16018" number="19432" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each assessor required to file a report solely by reason of section three hundred thirty-six of the real property tax law.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16019" number="19433" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each of the following members, officers and employees of city public authorities:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16020" number="19434" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each member of the authority;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16021" number="19435" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each head, deputy head or assistant head of the authority;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16022" number="19436" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each officer and employee of the authority who on the date designated by the board for filing holds a policymaking position, as defined by rule of the board and as annually determined by the head of his or her authority, subject to review by the board; and</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16023" number="19437" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each officer or employee of the authority whose duties at any time during the preceding calendar year involved the negotiation, authorization or approval of contracts, leases, franchises, revocable consents, concessions and applications for zoning changes, variances and special permits, as defined by rule of the conflicts of interest board and as annually determined by the head of his or her authority, subject to review by the board.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16024" number="19438" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person required by New York state law to file an annual disclosure report with the conflicts of interest board.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16025" number="19439" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Separation from service:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16026" number="19440" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each person described in this paragraph shall, following separation from service, file such report for the portion of the last calendar year in which he or she served in his or her position within sixty days of his or her separation from service or on or before the date designated by the conflicts of interest board for filing pursuant to subparagraph (a) of this paragraph, whichever is earlier, if such person met the criteria of this subparagraph on his or her last day of service. Each such person who leaves service prior to the date designated by the board for filing pursuant to subparagraph (a) of this paragraph shall also file a report for the previous calendar year within sixty days of his or her separation from service or on or before such date designated by the board, whichever is earlier.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16027" number="19441" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each such person who is terminating or separating from service shall not receive his or her final paycheck, and/or any lump sum payment to which he or she may be entitled, until such person has complied with the requirements of this section.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16028" number="19442" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each elected officer and each local political party official described in paragraph eleven of subdivision a of this section shall, after leaving office, file such report for the previous calendar year, if such officer or local political party official has not previously filed such report, and shall file such report for the portion of the last calendar year in which he or she served in office, within sixty days of his or her last day in office or on or before the date designated by the board for filing pursuant to subparagraph (a) of paragraph one of this subdivision, whichever is earlier.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16029" number="19443" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Procedures involving the filing of annual disclosure reports.</CHARFORMAT>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16030" number="19444" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each agency head or head of a city public authority shall file with the conflicts of interest board, prior to the date required for the filing of reports, a list of persons obligated to report pursuant to this section.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16031" number="19445" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each agency head or head of a city public authority shall determine, subject to review by the conflicts of interest board, which persons within the agency or city public authority occupy positions that are described in clauses three and four of subparagraph (a) of paragraph three of subdivision b of this section, and shall, prior to the date on which the filing of the report is required, inform such employees of their obligation to report. The conflicts of interest board shall promulgate rules establishing procedures whereby any employee may seek review of the agency&apos;s or city public authority&apos;s determination that he or she is required to report.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16032" number="19446" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The speaker of the council, each district attorney and the special narcotics prosecutor shall determine, subject to review by the conflicts of interest board, which persons on their staff occupy positions that are described in clause two of subparagraph (a) of paragraph three of subdivision b of this section, and shall, prior to the date required for the filing of the reports, inform such employees of their obligation to report.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16033" number="19447" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The conflicts of interest board shall promulgate rules establishing procedures whereby a person required to file an annual disclosure report may request an additional period of time within which to file such report, due to justifiable cause or undue hardship. Such rules shall include, but not be limited to, the establishment of a date beyond which in all cases of justifiable cause or undue hardship no further extension of time will be granted.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16034" number="19448" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any amendments and changes to an annual disclosure report made after its filing shall be made on a form to be prescribed by the conflicts of interest board. Amendments shall be made only by the person who originally filed such report.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16035" number="19449" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Information to be reported.</CHARFORMAT>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16036" number="19450" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Officers and employees of the city; members of city boards and commissions entitled to compensation; candidates for public office; elected and political party officials.</CHARFORMAT> The report filed by officers and employees of the city, members of city boards and commissions entitled to compensation, candidates for public office, elected officials, political party officials, and any other person required by state law to file a report other than a person described by paragraph three or four of this subdivision, shall contain the information required by this paragraph on such form as the board shall prescribe. For purposes of filing an annual disclosure report, members of the New York city housing development corporation shall be deemed to be members of a city board or commission entitled to compensation.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16037" number="19451" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>List the name of the person reporting; his or her title or position; the entity by which he or she is employed or from which he or she receives compensation; his or her office address and telephone number; list the marital status of the person reporting, and if married, list the spouse&apos;s full name including maiden name where applicable; indicate whether the person is a member of a domestic partnership, and if so, list the partner&apos;s full name; list the names of all unemancipated children.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16038" number="19452" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>List any office, trusteeship, directorship, partnership, or position of any nature including honorary positions, whether compensated or not, held by the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child with any firm, corporation, association, partnership, or other organization other than the state of New York. Do not list membership positions. If the listed entity was licensed or regulated by any state or local agency, or engaged in business dealings with, or had matters other than ministerial matters before, any state or local agency, list the name of such agency.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16039" number="19453" version="1812">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>List the name, address and description of any occupation, trade, business, profession or employment, other than the employment listed pursuant to paragraph one of this subdivision, engaged in by the person reporting. If such employer or business was licensed or regulated by any state or local agency, or engaged in business dealings with, or matters other than ministerial matters before, any state or local agency, list the name of any such agency.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16040" number="19454" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the spouse, domestic partner or unemancipated child of the person reporting was engaged in any occupation, employment, trade, business or profession which activity was licensed or regulated by any state or local agency, or engaged in business dealings with, or had matters other than ministerial matters before, any state or local agency, list the name, address and description of such occupation, employment, trade, business or profession and the name of any such agency.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16041" number="19455" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>List any positions the person reporting held as an officer of any political party or political organization, as a member of any political party committee, or as a political party district leader.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16042" number="19456" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the person reporting practices law, is licensed by the department of state as a real estate broker or agent or practices a profession licensed by the state department of education, give a general description of the principal subject areas of matters undertaken by such person. If the person reporting practices with a firm or corporation of which he or she is a partner or shareholder, give a general description of principal subject areas of matters undertaken by such firm or corporation. Do not list the name of the individual clients, customers or patients.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16043" number="19457" version="1812">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Describe the terms of, and the parties to, any agreement providing for future payments or benefits to the person reporting by a prior or current employer other than the city of New York. Such description of an agreement shall include interests in or contributions to a pension fund, profit-sharing plan, life or health insurance, buy-out agreements or severance payments, etc.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16044" number="19458" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Describe the terms of, and the parties to, any contract, promise or agreement between the person reporting and any person, firm or corporation with respect to the future employment of such reporting person.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16045" number="19459" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>List the nature and amount of any income of one thousand dollars or more from each source derived during the preceding calendar year, to the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner. Income from a business or profession and real estate rents shall be reported with the source identified by the building address in the case of real estate rents and otherwise by the name of the entity and not by the name of the individual customers, clients or tenants, with the aggregate net income before taxes for each building address or entity. The receipt of maintenance received in connection with a matrimonial action, alimony and child support payments shall not be listed.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16046" number="19460" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>List the source of each of the following items received or accrued during the preceding calendar year by the person reporting: </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16047" number="19461" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any deferred income to be paid following the close of the calendar year for which this disclosure statement is filed, other than any source of income otherwise disclosed pursuant to subparagraph (a) of paragraph nine* of this subdivision, of one thousand dollars or more from each source. Deferred income derived from the practice of a profession shall be listed in the aggregate and shall be identified as to the source, including the name of the firm, corporation, partnership or association through which the income was derived, but shall not include individual clients&apos; identities.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16048" number="19462" version="3">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">* <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> should be &quot;subparagraph (1) of paragraph (i)&quot;. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-026]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16049" number="19463" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Reimbursement to the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner, for expenditures, excluding campaign expenditures and expenditures in connection with official duties reimbursed by the city, of one thousand dollars or more in each instance.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16050" number="19464" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Honoraria received by the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner from a single source in the aggregate amount of one thousand dollars or more.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16051" number="19465" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any gift, its value and nature, from any single source received by the person reporting, his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child, during the preceding calendar year, excluding gifts from a relative, except as otherwise provided under the election law covering campaign contributions. Gifts in the aggregate amount or value of less than one thousand dollars from any single source shall not be reported where, from the beginning of the reporting period until the date the report is filed, the donor engaged in no business dealings with the city. Gifts in the aggregate amount or value of less than fifty dollars from any single source shall not be reported. The value of separate gifts from the same or affiliated donors during the reporting period shall be aggregated.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16052" number="19466" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>List the identity and value, if reasonably ascertainable, of each interest in a trust, estate or beneficial interest held by the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner, including but not limited to (1) retirement plans (other than retirement plans of the state of New York or city of New York) and (2) deferred compensation plans established in accordance with the internal revenue code, where the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner held a beneficial interest of one thousand dollars or more during the preceding calendar year. Do not report interests in an estate of a relative or interests in a trust or other beneficial interest established by or for a relative or by or for the estate of a relative.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16053" number="19467" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>List each assignment of income of one thousand dollars or more, and each transfer other than to a relative during the preceding calendar year for less than fair consideration of an interest of one thousand dollars or more, in a trust, estate, or other beneficial interest, securities or real property, by the person reporting, which would otherwise be required to be reported herein and is not or has not been reported.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16054" number="19468" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>List any interest of one thousand dollars or more, excluding bonds and notes, held by the person reporting, his or her spouse or domestic partner or the reporting person&apos;s unemancipated child, or partnership of which any such person is a member, or corporation, ten per centum or more of the stock of which is owned or controlled by any such person, whether vested or contingent, in any contract made or executed by a state or local agency. Include the name of the entity which holds such interest and the relationship of the person reporting, or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child, to such entity and the interest in such contract. Do not list any interest in any such contract on which final payment has been made and all obligations under the contract, except for guarantees and warranties, have been performed, provided, however, that such an interest shall be listed if there has been an ongoing dispute during the calendar year for which this statement is filed with respect to any such guarantees or warranties. Do not list any interest in a contract made or executed by a state agency after public notice and pursuant to a process for competitive bidding or a process for competitive requests for proposals.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16055" number="19469" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>List the name, principal address and general description or the nature of the business activity of any entity in which the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child had an investment of one thousand dollars or more, excluding investments in securities and interests in real property.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16056" number="19470" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(l)<TAB tab-count="1"/>List the type and market value of securities held by the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child from each issuing entity, valued at one thousand dollars or more at the close of the preceding calendar year, including the name of the issuing entity, exclusive of securities held by the person reporting issued by a professional corporation. Whenever an interest in securities exists through a beneficial interest in a trust, the securities held in such trust shall be listed only if the person reporting has knowledge thereof, except where the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner has transferred assets to such trust for his or her benefit; in that event the securities shall be listed unless they are not ascertainable by the person reporting because the trustee is under an obligation or has been instructed in writing not to disclose the contents of the trust to the person reporting. Securities of which the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner is the owner of record but in which he or she has no beneficial interest shall not be listed. Where the person or his or her spouse or domestic partner holds more than five per centum of the stock of a publicly held corporation or more than ten per centum of a privately held corporation, percentage of ownership shall be listed. List any securities owned for investment purposes by a corporation more than fifty per centum of the stock of which is owned or controlled by the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner. The market value for such securities shall be reported only if reasonably ascertainable and shall not be reported if the security is an interest in a general partnership that was listed in subparagraph e of this subdivision or if the security is corporate stock, not publicly traded, in a trade or business of the reporting person or his or her spouse or domestic partner.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16057" number="19471" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(m)<TAB tab-count="1"/>List the location, size, general nature, acquisition date, market value and percentage of ownership of any real property in which any vested or contingent interest of one thousand dollars or more was held by the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child during the preceding calendar year. List real property owned for investment purposes by a corporation more than fifty per centum of the stock of which is owned or controlled by the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner. Do not list any real property which is the primary or secondary personal residence of the reporting person or his or her spouse or domestic partner, except where there is a co-owner who is other than a relative.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16058" number="19472" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(n)<TAB tab-count="1"/>List the identity of each note or account receivable or other outstanding loan in the amount of one thousand dollars or more held by the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner during the preceding calendar year, including debts secured by a mortgage, and other secured and unsecured debts. List the name of the debtor, type of obligation, date due and the nature of the collateral, if any, securing payment for each such debt. Debts, notes and accounts receivable owed to the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner by a relative shall not be reported.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16059" number="19473" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(o)<TAB tab-count="1"/>List each creditor to whom the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner was indebted, for a period of ninety consecutive days or more during the preceding calendar year, and each such creditor to whom any debt was owed on the date of filing, in an amount of five thousand dollars or more. Debts to be listed include real estate mortgages and other secured and unsecured loans. If any reportable liability has been guaranteed by any third person, list the name of such guarantor. Do not list liabilities incurred by, or guarantees made by, the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner or by any proprietorship, partnership or corporation in which such person has an interest, when incurred or made in the ordinary course of trade, business or professional practice of such person. Include the name of the creditor and any collateral pledged by such individual to secure payment of any such liability. Do not list any liability to a relative or any obligation to pay maintenance in connection with a matrimonial action, alimony or child support payments. Revolving charge account information shall only be set forth if the liability thereon is in excess of five thousand dollars for a period of ninety consecutive days or more during the preceding calendar year, or if the liability thereon is in excess of five thousand dollars as of the time of filing. Any loan issued in the ordinary course of business by a financial institution to finance educational costs, the cost of home purchase or improvements for a primary or secondary residence, or purchase of a personally owned motor vehicle, household furniture or appliances shall be excluded.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16060" number="19474" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(p)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name, title, and position of any relative of the person reporting who holds a position, whether paid or unpaid, with the city; the city agency with which such position is held; and the relationship between such relative and the person reporting.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16061" number="19475" version="679">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(q)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever a &quot;value&quot; or &quot;amount&quot; is required to be reported pursuant to this section, such value or amount shall be reported as being within one of the following categories: (a) at least one thousand dollars but less than five thousand dollars; (b) at least five thousand dollars but less than thirty-two thousand dollars, or such other amount as the conflicts of interest board shall set pursuant to subdivision sixteen of section twenty-six hundred one and subdivision a of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="2603" destination-id="0-0-0-0">twenty-six hundred three</LINK> of the charter; (c) at least thirty-two thousand dollars, or such other amount as the conflicts of interest board shall set pursuant to subdivision sixteen of section twenty-six hundred one and subdivision a of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="2603" destination-id="0-0-0-0">twenty-six hundred three</LINK> of the charter, but less than sixty thousand dollars; (d) at least sixty thousand dollars but less than one hundred thousand dollars; (e) at least one hundred thousand dollars but less than two hundred fifty thousand dollars; (f) at least two hundred fifty thousand dollars but less than five hundred thousand dollars; and (g) five hundred thousand dollars or more.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16062" number="19476" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Uncompensated members of boards and commissions of the city.</CHARFORMAT> The report required to be filed by a person who is a member of a city board or commission and is not entitled to compensation for such service shall contain the information required by this paragraph on such form as the board shall prescribe. For purposes of filing an annual disclosure report, members of the New York city housing development corporation shall be deemed to be compensated members of a city board or commission who are required to file an annual disclosure report in accordance with paragraph one of subdivision d of this section.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16063" number="19477" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name of the person reporting; each of his or her city board, commission or agency titles and positions; his or her city employee identification number, if any; his or her office address, email address, if any, and telephone number; his or her home address, personal email address, if any, and home telephone number; whether he or she has a spouse or domestic partner and, if so, the full name of such spouse or domestic partner; and the names of all unemancipated children.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16064" number="19478" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The location, size, and general nature of any residential, commercial, retail or industrial real property that is owned by, rented to or rented by the person reporting, or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child. Only real property that is within the city of New York shall be reported. Residential property in which the person reporting or a relative resides shall not be reported. For other residential property, only the borough, city (if outside New York city), town, or village shall be reported.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16065" number="19479" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name of each employer or business, other than the city of New York, from which the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child received, during the reporting period, compensation for services performed or for goods sold or produced or as a member, officer, director, or employee. The name of individual clients, customers or patients shall not be reported, nor shall any business in which the reporting person or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child was an investor only. The nature of the business shall also be identified, as well as the relationship between the reporting person or his or her spouse, domestic partner, or unemancipated child and the employer or business (owner, partner, officer, director, member, employee, and/or shareholder). An employer or business shall not be reported where, from the beginning of the reporting period until the date the report is filed, the employer or business engaged in no business dealings with the agency of which the person reporting is a board or commission member.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16066" number="19480" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name of any entity in which the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child has an interest that exceeds five percent of the firm or an investment of ten thousand dollars, whichever is less. The nature of the business and the type of business shall also be identified. An entity shall not be reported where, from the beginning of the reporting period until the date the report is filed, the entity engaged in no business dealings with the agency of which the person reporting is a board or commission member.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16067" number="19481" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Gifts having a value of fifty dollars or more received by the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child during the reporting period, including the recipient of the gift, the donor of the gift, the relationship between the recipient and the donor, and the nature of the gift. The value of separate gifts from the same or affiliated donors during the reporting period shall be aggregated. A gift shall not be reported where (i) the gift is from a relative; or (ii) from the beginning of the reporting period until the date the report is filed, the donor engaged in no business dealings with the agency of which the person reporting is a board or commission member; or (iii) the gift consists of attendance, including meals and refreshments, at a meeting, public affair, function, or occasion and complies with the rules of the board governing the acceptance of such attendance, meals, or refreshments.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16068" number="19482" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Members, officers and employees of city public authorities.</CHARFORMAT> The report required to be filed by a person pursuant to subdivision three of section twenty-eight hundred twenty-five of the public authorities law shall contain the following information:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16069" number="19483" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name of the person reporting; the name of the city public authority of which the person reporting is a board member, officer or employee; his or her title and position with such entity; any city title and position that he or she holds; any city agency of which the person reporting is a member, officer or employee; his or her city employee identification number, if any; his or her office address, email address, if any, and telephone number; his or her home address, personal email address, if any, and home telephone number; whether he or she has a spouse or domestic partner and, if so, the full name of such spouse or domestic partner; and the names of all unemancipated children.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16070" number="19484" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The location, size, and general nature of any residential, commercial, retail or industrial real property that is owned by, rented to or rented by the person reporting, or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child. Only real property that is within the city of New York shall be reported. Residential property in which the person reporting or a relative resides shall not be reported. For other residential property, only the borough, city (if outside New York city), town, or village shall be reported.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16071" number="19485" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name of each employer or business, other than the city of New York, from which the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child received, during the reporting period, compensation for services performed or for goods sold or produced or as a member, officer, director, or employee. The name of individual clients, customers or patients shall not be reported, nor shall any business in which the reporting person or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child was an investor only. The nature of the business shall also be identified, as well as the relationship between the reporting person or his or her spouse, domestic partner, or unemancipated child and the employer or business (owner, partner, officer, director, member, employee, and/or shareholder). An employer or business shall not be reported where, from the beginning of the reporting period until the date the report is filed, the employer or business engaged in no business dealings with the local public authority of which the person reporting is a board member, officer or employee.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16072" number="19486" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name of any entity in which the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child has an interest that exceeds five percent of the firm or an investment of ten thousand dollars, whichever is less. The nature of the business and the type of business shall also be identified. An entity shall not be reported where, from the beginning of the reporting period until the date the report is filed, the entity engaged in no business dealings with the local public authority of which the person reporting is a board member, officer or employee.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16073" number="19487" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Gifts having a value of fifty dollars or more received by the person reporting or his or her spouse or domestic partner or unemancipated child during the reporting period, including the recipient of the gift, the donor of the gift, the relationship between the recipient and the donor, and the nature of the gift. The value of separate gifts from the same or affiliated donors during the reporting period shall be aggregated.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16074" number="19488" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>A gift shall not be reported where (i) the gift is from a relative; or (ii) from the beginning of the reporting period until the date the report is filed, the donor engaged in no business dealings with the local public authority of which the person reporting is a board member, officer or employee; or (iii) the gift consists of attendance, including meals and refreshments, at a meeting, public affair, function, or occasion and complies with the rules of the board governing the acceptance of such attendance, meals, or refreshments.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16075" number="19489" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Tax assessors.</CHARFORMAT> The report required to be filed by a person pursuant to section three hundred thirty-six of the real property tax law shall be on the form prescribed by such law.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16076" number="19490" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Filers in multiple filing categories.</CHARFORMAT> If a person is required to file an annual disclosure report by more than one paragraph of subdivision b of this section, he or she shall file the most comprehensive report of those required by paragraphs one through four of this subdivision. The most comprehensive report shall be deemed to be the report required by paragraph one of this subdivision; the second most comprehensive report shall be deemed to be the report required by paragraph four of this subdivision; and the third most comprehensive report shall be deemed to be the report required by paragraphs two and three of this subdivision.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16077" number="19491" version="679">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Information filed in reports required by this section shall be maintained by the conflicts of interest board and shall be made available for public inspection, upon written request on such form as the board shall prescribe, except that information filed in reports required by this section by each elected officer described in sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="4" destination-id="0-0-0-0">four</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24" destination-id="0-0-0-0">twenty-four</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="25" destination-id="0-0-0-0">twenty-five</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="81" destination-id="0-0-0-0">eighty-one</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="91" destination-id="0-0-0-0">ninety-one</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="1125" destination-id="0-0-0-0">eleven hundred twenty-five</LINK> of the New York city charter shall be made available for public inspection on the board&apos;s website without written request. The availability of forms for public inspection pursuant to this subdivision is subject to the following provisions: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16078" number="19492" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Privacy, safety and security requests.</CHARFORMAT>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16079" number="19493" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person required to file a report pursuant to this section may, at the time the report is filed or at any time thereafter, except when a request for inspection is pending, submit a request to the conflicts of interest board, in such form as the board shall require, to withhold any item disclosed therein from public inspection on the ground that the inspection of such item by the public would constitute an unwarranted invasion of his or her privacy or a risk to the safety or security of any person. Such request shall be in writing and shall be in such form as the conflicts of interest board shall prescribe and shall set forth the reason such person believes the item should not be disclosed. During the time for evaluation of such a request, such report shall not be available for public inspection. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16080" number="19494" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The conflicts of interest board shall evaluate such request and any such item shall be withheld from public inspection upon a finding by the board that the inspection of such item by the public would constitute an unwarranted invasion of privacy or a risk to the safety or security of any person. In making this determination, the board shall consider the following factors:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16081" number="19495" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the item is of a highly personal nature;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16082" number="19496" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the item in any way relates to the duties of the positions held by such person, including whether there are security or safety issues relating to such duties;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16083" number="19497" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the disclosure poses a risk to the security or safety of the reporting person or any other individual;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16084" number="19498" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the item involves an actual or potential conflict of interest.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16085" number="19499" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The conflicts of interest board shall provide a written notification of the board&apos;s determination to the person who requested that information be withheld from public inspection and shall not release the information subject to the request until at least ten days after mailing of the notification. Such notification shall advise the person of his or her right to seek review of such determination by the supreme court of the state of New York and that the conflicts of interest board will not release the information subject to the request until ten days after the mailing of the notification.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16086" number="19500" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any information regarding any financial interests of the spouse, domestic partner or an unemancipated child of a person filing in which the person filing has no financial interest shall be withheld from public inspection, except the information disclosed pursuant to subparagraph (p) of paragraph one of subdivision d of this section, as an unwarranted invasion of privacy unless the conflicts of interest board determines that such information involves an actual or potential conflict of interest on the part of the person filing, subject to the factors set forth in subparagraph (b) of paragraph one of this subdivision.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16087" number="19501" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whether or not a person required to file a report pursuant to this section has submitted a request for privacy, the conflicts of interest board may upon its own initiative grant privacy as to any information contained in such person&apos;s report upon a finding by the board that the release of such information would constitute a risk to the safety or security of any person.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16088" number="19502" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where a person required to file a report pursuant to this section files an amendment to a previously submitted report, both the original submission and the amendment shall be available for public inspection, subject to the provisions of this subdivision.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16089" number="19503" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The conflicts of interest board shall establish procedures governing the withholding of information on the ground of privacy. Such procedures shall include provision for the person who filed the information to appear in person to set forth, or submit a written statement setting forth, the reasons why the information should be withheld from public inspection.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16090" number="19504" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Requests to examine reports.</CHARFORMAT> Whenever pursuant to this section the conflicts of interest board produces a report for public inspection, the board shall notify the person who filed the report of the production and of the identity of the person to whom such report was produced, except that no such notification shall be required if the report is made available for public inspection on the board&apos;s website without written request or if the request to examine the report is made by the department of investigation or any governmental unit, or component thereof, which performs as one of its principal functions any activity pertaining to the enforcement of criminal laws, provided that such report is requested solely for a law enforcement function. Nothing in this section shall preclude the conflicts of interest board from disclosing any and all information in an annual disclosure report to the department of investigation or any other governmental unit, or component thereof, which performs as one of its principal functions any activity pertaining to the enforcement of criminal laws, provided that such report is requested solely for a law enforcement function. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-001]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16091" number="19505" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Retention of reports.</CHARFORMAT> Reports filed pursuant to this section shall be retained by the conflicts of interest board for a period of two years following the termination of the public employment or service of the person who filed the report. In the case of candidates for office who have filed reports pursuant to this section and who were not elected, the reports shall be retained by the board for a period of two years following the day of an election on which the candidates were defeated. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the board, in consultation with the department of records and information services and the department of investigation, may establish by rule a different period or periods of retention of annual disclosure reports which takes into account the need for efficient records management and the need to retain such reports for a reasonable period for investigatory and other purposes. Such reports shall thereafter be destroyed by the board unless a request for public disclosure of an item contained in such report is pending. In lieu of the destruction of such reports, the board, in its discretion, may establish procedures providing for their return to the persons who filed them.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16092" number="19506" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Penalties.</CHARFORMAT>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16093" number="19507" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person required to file a report pursuant to this section who has not so filed at the end of one week after the date required for filing shall be subject to a fine of not less than two hundred fifty dollars or more than ten thousand dollars. Factors to be considered by the conflicts of interest board in determining the amount of the fine shall include but not be limited to the person&apos;s failure in prior years to file a report in a timely manner, and the length of the delay in filing. In addition, within two months after the date required for filing, the conflicts of interest board shall inform the appropriate agency and the commissioner of investigation of the failure to file of any such person.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16094" number="19508" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any intentional violation of the provisions of this section, including but not limited to failure to file, failure to include assets or liabilities, and misstatement of assets or liabilities, shall constitute a misdemeanor punishable by imprisonment for not more than one year or by a fine not to exceed one thousand dollars, or by both, and shall constitute grounds for imposition of disciplinary penalties, including removal from office in the manner provided by law. In addition, any intentional violation of the provisions of this section may subject the person reporting to assessment by the conflicts of interest board of a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed ten thousand dollars.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16095" number="19509" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any intentional and willful unlawful disclosure of confidential information that is contained in a report filed in accordance with this section, by a city officer or employee or by any other person who has obtained access to such a report or confidential information contained therein, shall constitute a misdemeanor punishable by imprisonment for not more than one year or a fine not to exceed one thousand dollars, or by both, and shall constitute grounds for imposition of disciplinary penalties, including removal from office or position in the manner provided by law.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16096" number="19510" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The conflicts of interest board shall establish procedures governing the receipt of complaints alleging a violation of this section. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16097" number="19511" version="705">
												<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2016/021, 2/19/2016, eff. 2/19/2016; Am. L.L. 2017/211, 11/17/2017, eff. 11/17/2017; Am. L.L. 2019/128, 7/14/2019, eff. 7/14/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-039]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16098" number="19512" version="2278">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1986/016" destination-id="0-0-0-27308">L.L. 1986/016</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1990/084" destination-id="0-0-0-26760">L.L. 1990/084</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1998/027" destination-id="0-0-0-25818">L.L. 1998/027</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2003/043" destination-id="0-0-0-25336">L.L. 2003/043</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2006/014" destination-id="0-0-0-25090">L.L. 2006/014</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2012/058" destination-id="0-0-0-24742">L.L. 2012/058</LINK>, and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2016/021" destination-id="0-0-0-20521">L.L. 2016/021</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-129613" number="19513" version="568">
											<HEADING>§ 12-112 Council; violations of law by members of. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4573" name="12-112"/>§ 12-112 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Council; violations of law by members of. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16099" number="19514" version="3">
												<PARA>Any member of the council, who shall vote for any appropriation unauthorized by law or in excess of the amount authorized by law, or for any illegal or injurious disposition of corporate property or rights, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and liable to the punishment and penalties prescribed therefor; and every member voting in favor thereof shall be individually liable to refund the amounts to the city at the suit of any citizen and taxpayer.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16100" number="19515" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-113 Protection of sources of information. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1707" name="12-113"/>§ 12-113 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Protection of sources of information. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-131367" number="19516" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> For purposes of this section:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16102" number="19517" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Adverse personnel action&quot; shall include dismissal, demotion, suspension, disciplinary action, negative performance evaluation, any action resulting in loss of staff, office space or equipment or other benefit, failure to appoint, failure to promote, or any transfer or assignment or failure to transfer or assign against the wishes of the affected officer or employee.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16103" number="19518" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Remedial action&quot; means an appropriate action to restore the officer or employee to his or her former status, which may include one or more of the following:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16104" number="19519" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>reinstatement of the officer or employee to a position the same as or comparable to the position the officer or employee held or would have held if not for the adverse personnel action, or, as appropriate, to an equivalent position;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16105" number="19520" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>reinstatement of full seniority rights;</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16106" number="19521" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>payment of lost compensation; and</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16107" number="19522" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>other measures necessary to address the effects of the adverse personnel action.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16108" number="19523" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Commissioner&quot; shall mean the commissioner of investigation.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16109" number="19524" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Child&quot; shall mean any person under the age of nineteen, or any person ages nineteen through twenty-one if such person receives instruction pursuant to an individualized education plan.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16110" number="19525" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Educational welfare&quot; shall mean any aspect of a child&apos;s education or educational environment that significantly impacts upon such child&apos;s ability to receive appropriate instruction, as mandated by any relevant law, rule, regulation or sound educational practice.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16111" number="19526" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Superior officer&quot; shall mean an agency head, deputy agency head or other person designated by the head of the agency to receive a report pursuant to this section, who is employed in the agency in which the conduct described in such report occurred.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16112" number="19527" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>7.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Contract&quot; shall mean any written agreement, purchase order or instrument having a value in excess of one hundred thousand dollars pursuant to which a contracting agency is committed to expend or does expend funds in return for work, labor, services, supplies, equipment, materials, or any combination of the foregoing, and shall include a subcontract between a covered contractor and a covered subcontractor. Such term shall not include contracts or subcontracts resulting from emergency procurements or that are government-to-government procurements.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16113" number="19528" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>8.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Contracting agency&quot; shall mean a city, county, borough, or other office, position, administration, department, division, bureau, board or commission, or a corporation, institution or agency of government, the expenses of which are paid in whole or in part from the city treasury.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16114" number="19529" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>9.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Covered contractor&quot; shall mean a person or business entity who is a party or a proposed party to a contract with a contracting agency valued in excess of one hundred thousand dollars, and &quot;covered subcontractor&quot; shall mean a person or entity who is a party or a proposed party to a contract with a covered contractor valued in excess of one hundred thousand dollars.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16115" number="19530" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>10.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Officers or employees of an agency of the city&quot; shall be deemed to include officers or employees of local development corporations or other not-for-profit corporations that are parties to contracts with contracting agencies and the governing boards of which include city officials acting in their official capacity or appointees of city officials. Such officers and employees shall not be deemed to be officers or employees of a covered contractor or covered subcontractor.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16116" number="19531" version="1765">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>11.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Special commissioner of investigation&quot; shall mean the position of deputy commissioner of investigation for the city school district of the city of New York, as established by mayoral executive order number 11 for the year 1990, as amended, or any successor to the duties of such officer. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16124" number="19532" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No officer or employee of an agency of the city shall take an adverse personnel action with respect to another officer or employee in retaliation for his or her making a report of information concerning conduct which he or she knows or reasonably believes to involve corruption, criminal activity, conflict of interest, gross mismanagement or abuse of authority by another city officer or employee, which concerns his or her office or employment, or by persons dealing with the city, which concerns their dealings with the city, to the commissioner, a council member, the public advocate, the comptroller, or the special commissioner of investigation. Such report shall be referred to the commissioner unless (i) such conduct is within the jurisdiction of the special commissioner of investigation, in which case such report shall be referred to such special commissioner, or (ii) such conduct is alleged to have been committed by the commissioner, the special commissioner of investigation or a deputy commissioner of investigation, in which case such report shall be referred to the corporation counsel. For the purposes of this subdivision, an agency of the city shall be deemed to include, but not be limited to, an agency the head or members of which are appointed by one or more city officers, and the offices of elected city officers. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133725" number="19533" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No officer or employee of a covered contractor or covered subcontractor shall take an adverse personnel action with respect to another officer or employee of such contractor or subcontractor in retaliation for such officer or employee making a report of information concerning conduct which such officer or employee knows or reasonably believes to involve corruption, criminal activity, conflict of interest, gross mismanagement or abuse of authority by any officer or employee of such contractor or subcontractor, which concerns a contract with a contracting agency, to the commissioner, a council member, the public advocate, the comptroller, the special commissioner of investigation, the chief procurement officer, the agency chief contracting officer, or the agency head or commissioner of the contracting agency. Such report shall be referred to the commissioner unless such conduct is within the jurisdiction of the special commissioner of investigation, in which case such report shall be referred to such special commissioner. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133724" number="19534" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every contract or subcontract in excess of one hundred thousand dollars shall contain a provision detailing the provisions of paragraph two of this subdivision and of paragraph two of subdivision e of this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133723" number="19535" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon request, the commissioner, council member, public advocate, comptroller, special commissioner of investigation or corporation counsel receiving the report of alleged adverse personnel action shall make reasonable efforts to protect the anonymity and confidentiality of the officer or employee making such report. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133722" number="19536" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No officer or employee of an agency of the city shall take an adverse personnel action with respect to another officer or employee in retaliation for his or her making a report of information concerning conduct which he or she knows or reasonably believes to present a substantial and specific risk of harm to the health, safety or educational welfare of a child by another city officer or employee, which concerns his or her office or employment, or by persons dealing with the city, which concerns their dealings with the city, to the commissioner, a council member, the public advocate, the comptroller, the mayor, the special commissioner of investigation or any superior officer. Such report shall be referred to the commissioner unless (i) such conduct is within the jurisdiction of the special commissioner of investigation, in which case such report shall be referred to such special commissioner, or (ii) such conduct is alleged to have been committed by the commissioner, the special commissioner of investigation or a deputy commissioner of investigation, in which case such report shall be referred to the corporation counsel. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133721" number="19537" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>An officer or employee of an agency of the city, or of a public agency or public entity subject to the jurisdiction of the commissioner pursuant to <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="Chapter 34" destination-id="0-0-0-0">chapter thirty-four</LINK> of the charter, who believes that another officer or employee has taken an adverse personnel action in violation of subdivision b of this section may report such action (i) to the commissioner, or (ii) to the special commissioner of investigation, if such alleged adverse personnel action is within the jurisdiction of such special commissioner, or (iii) to the corporation counsel, if such alleged adverse personnel action is alleged to have been committed by the commissioner, the special commissioner of investigation or a deputy commissioner of investigation. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133720" number="19538" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If such report concerns an alleged adverse personnel action that is within the jurisdiction of the special commissioner of investigation, such report shall be referred to such special commissioner, and if such report concerns an adverse personnel action that is alleged to have been committed by the commissioner, the special commissioner of investigation or a deputy commissioner of investigation, such report shall be referred to the corporation counsel. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133719" number="19539" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon receipt of a report made pursuant to subdivision c of this section, the commissioner, or the special commissioner of investigation or corporation counsel, as applicable, shall conduct an inquiry to determine whether retaliatory adverse personnel action has been taken. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133718" number="19540" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within fifteen days after receipt of an allegation pursuant to subdivision c of this section of a prohibited adverse personnel action, the commissioner, or the special commissioner of investigation or corporation counsel, as applicable, shall provide written notice to the officer or employee making the allegation that the allegation has been received by the commissioner, or the special commissioner of investigation or corporation counsel, as applicable. Such notice shall include the name of the person in the department of investigation, or in the offices of the special commissioner of investigation or the corporation counsel, as applicable, who shall serve as a contact with the officer or employee making the allegation. Thereafter, the commissioner, or the special commissioner of investigation or corporation counsel, as applicable, shall at least once in every 90-day period provide written notice of the status of such investigation to such officer or employee. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133717" number="19541" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon the completion of an investigation initiated under this subdivision, the commissioner, or the special commissioner of investigation or corporation counsel, as applicable, shall provide a written statement of the final determination to the officer or employee who complained of the retaliatory adverse personnel action. The statement shall include the recommendations, if any, of the commissioner, or the special commissioner of investigation or corporation counsel, as applicable, for remedial action, or shall state that the commissioner, or the special commissioner of investigation or corporation counsel, as applicable, has determined to dismiss the complaint and terminate the investigation. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16125" number="19542" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon a determination that a retaliatory adverse personnel action has been taken with respect to an officer or employee of an agency of the city in violation of paragraph one or five of subdivision b of this section, the commissioner, or the special commissioner of investigation or corporation counsel, as applicable, shall without undue delay report his or her findings and, if appropriate, recommendations to the head of the appropriate agency or entity, who shall determine whether to take remedial action and shall report such determination to the commissioner, or the special commissioner of investigation or corporation counsel, as applicable, in writing. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133729" number="19543" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon a determination that the agency or entity head has failed to take appropriate remedial action, the commissioner, or the special commissioner of investigation or corporation counsel, as applicable, shall consult with the agency or entity head and afford the agency or entity head reasonable opportunity to take such action. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133728" number="19544" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If such action is not taken, the commissioner, or the special commissioner of investigation or corporation counsel, as applicable, shall report his or her findings and the response of the agency or entity head to the complainant and if the complainant was employed by an agency the head or members of which are appointed by the mayor, to the mayor; if the complainant was employed by a non-mayoral agency of the city, to the city officer or officers who appointed the agency head; or if the complainant was employed by a public agency or other public entity not covered by the preceding categories but subject to the jurisdiction of the commissioner pursuant to <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="Chapter 34" destination-id="0-0-0-0">chapter thirty-four</LINK> of the charter, to the officer or officers who appointed the head of the public agency or public entity, who shall take such action as is deemed appropriate. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133727" number="19545" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If, within 60 days from the date of such report to the mayor or to the officer or officers who appointed the head of the agency or entity, such agency or entity has not taken either the remedial action recommended by, or other remedial action acceptable to, the commissioner, the special commissioner of investigation or the corporation counsel, as applicable, such agency or entity head shall provide a written explanation to the complainant and to the commissioner, or the special commissioner of investigation or corporation counsel, as applicable, of the specific reasons why such agency or entity did not take such remedial action. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133726" number="19546" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within one year after such written explanation is due to be provided to such complainant, the complainant may bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction against the complainant&apos;s employer to recover relief necessary to make the complainant whole; provided that the monetary value of such relief shall not exceed that of the remedial actions recommended by the commissioner, the special commissioner of investigation or the corporation counsel, as applicable, with respect to such complainant and that such relief shall otherwise be comparable to such recommended actions. If such complainant prevails in such action, such court shall award such complainant litigation costs and reasonable attorneys&apos; fees. A complainant who brings an action pursuant to this subparagraph shall provide notice of such action to the commissioner, the special commissioner of investigation or the corporation counsel, as applicable; provided, however, that failure to provide such notice shall not be a jurisdictional defect and shall not be a defense to an action brought pursuant to this subparagraph. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16126" number="19547" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any officer or employee of a covered contractor or covered subcontractor who believes that he or she has been the subject of an adverse personnel action in violation of paragraph two of subdivision b shall be entitled to bring a cause of action against such covered contractor or covered subcontractor to recover all relief necessary to make him or her whole. Such relief may include but shall not be limited to: (i) an injunction to restrain continued retaliation, (ii) reinstatement to the position such employee would have had but for the retaliation or to an equivalent position, (iii) reinstatement of full fringe benefits and seniority rights, (iv) payment of two times back pay, plus interest, and (v) compensation for any special damages sustained as a result of the retaliation, including litigation costs and reasonable attorneys&apos; fees. An officer or employee described in this paragraph may bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction for such relief. An officer or employee who brings a cause of action pursuant to this paragraph shall notify the agency chief contracting officer or agency head or commissioner of the contracting agency of such action; provided, however, that failure to provide such notice shall not be a jurisdictional defect, and shall not be a defense to an action brought pursuant to this paragraph. This paragraph shall not be deemed to create a right of action against the city, any public agency or other public entity, or local development corporations or not-for-profit corporations the governing boards of which include city officials acting in their official capacity or appointees of city officials, nor shall any such public agency, entity or corporation be made a party to an action brought pursuant to this subdivision.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16127" number="19548" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the rights of any officer or employee with regard to any administrative procedure or judicial review, nor shall anything in this section be construed to diminish or impair the rights of a public employee or employer under any law, rule, regulation or collective bargaining agreement or to prohibit any personnel action which otherwise would have been taken regardless of any report of information made pursuant to this section.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16128" number="19549" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Violation of this section may constitute cause for administrative penalties.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16129" number="19550" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner shall conduct ongoing public education efforts as necessary to inform employees and officers of covered agencies and contractors of their rights and responsibilities under this section.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16130" number="19551" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Not later than October thirty-first of each year, the commissioner, in consultation with the special commissioner of investigation and the corporation counsel, shall prepare and forward to the mayor and the council a report that shall include, but need not be limited to, the following information for the preceding fiscal year: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133742" number="19552" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of reports concerning conduct allegedly involving corruption, criminal activity, conflict of interest, gross mismanagement or abuse of authority, as described in paragraph 1 of subdivision b of this section, received by the commissioner, the special commissioner of investigation and the corporation counsel, whether directly or upon referral, in such fiscal year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133741" number="19553" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of reports concerning conduct allegedly involving corruption, criminal activity, conflict of interest, gross mismanagement or abuse of authority, as described in paragraph 2 of subdivision b of this section, received by the commissioner and the special commissioner of investigation, whether directly or upon referral, in such fiscal year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133740" number="19554" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of reports concerning conduct allegedly presenting a substantial and specific risk of harm to the health, safety or educational welfare of a child by another city officer or employee, as described in paragraph 5 of subdivision b of this section, received by the commissioner, the special commissioner of investigation and the corporation counsel, whether directly or upon referral, in such fiscal year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133739" number="19555" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of complaints made under subdivision c of this section that were received by the commissioner, the special commissioner of investigation and the corporation counsel, in such fiscal year, and the disposition of such complaints; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133738" number="19556" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to investigations conducted under subdivision d of this section: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133737" number="19557" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of investigations open at the end of such fiscal year and the median number of days that such investigations had been open at the end of such fiscal year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133736" number="19558" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of investigations open for 90 or more days, but fewer than 180 days, at the end of such fiscal year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133735" number="19559" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of investigations open for 180 or more days, but fewer than 365 days, at the end of such fiscal year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133734" number="19560" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of investigations open for 365 or more days, but fewer than 730 days, at the end of such fiscal year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133733" number="19561" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of investigations open for 730 or more days at the end of such fiscal year; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133732" number="19562" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>As of the end of such fiscal year, the number of full-time plus part-time personnel of the department of investigation, calculated based on full-time equivalency rates, whose duties include conducting investigations under subdivision d of this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133715" number="19563" version="951">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>j.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any referral to the special commissioner of investigation pursuant to subdivision b or c of this section shall not be construed to divest the commissioner of authority to investigate or participate in the investigation of the matter that has been referred. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-133730" number="19564" version="951">
												<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2021/009, 1/17/2021, eff. 7/16/2021) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16131" number="19565" version="1367">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2012/033" destination-id="0-0-0-24762">L.L. 2012/033</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-082]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-204382" number="19566" version="1367">
											<HEADING>§ 12-114 Fees paid to city. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-2217" name="12-114"/>§ 12-114 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Fees paid to city. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16132" number="19567" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every officer of the city government shall be paid a fixed salary and all fees, percentages or commissions or other money paid to such officer in his or her official capacity, shall be the property of the city. All sums so received, including sums received for licenses or permits, shall be paid over not later than the next succeeding business day after receipt thereof, except as otherwise provided by law, to the commissioner of finance without deduction. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16133" number="19568" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each such officer who shall receive any fees, perquisites, commissions or percentages, or money paid to such officer in his or her official capacity, or any other money which should be paid over to the city, shall make a detailed return to the comptroller, under oath, and in such form as the comptroller shall prescribe, showing the amount of all such fees, commissions, percentages, perquisites and money received by him or her since the last preceding statement and return, and showing when, from whom and for what reason such money was received.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16134" number="19569" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The comptroller may require any such officer to make such statement and return to him or her, if it has not been made as herein provided, and he or she shall order the commissioner of finance to withhold the salary of such officers until such return is produced, and upon the production of said return the comptroller shall immediately issue a release to the commissioner of finance for the salary so withheld.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16135" number="19570" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section shall not apply to city marshals. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16136" number="19571" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-115 Civil rights protected. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4575" name="12-115"/>§ 12-115 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Civil rights protected. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16137" number="19572" version="3">
												<PARA>Nothing in the code contained shall affect any rights given or secured by section fifteen of the civil rights law.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16138" number="19573" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-116 Certificates of appointment. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4577" name="12-116"/>§ 12-116 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Certificates of appointment. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16139" number="19574" version="3">
												<PARA>Every person who shall be appointed or elected to any office in any agency shall receive a certificate of appointment, designating the term for which such person has been appointed or elected. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16140" number="19575" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-117 Official oath. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4579" name="12-117"/>§ 12-117 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Official oath. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16141" number="19576" version="3">
												<PARA>Every person elected or appointed to any office in any agency of the city, shall within five days after notice of such election or appointment, take and subscribe, before the mayor, any judge of a court of record, the appointing officer or the city clerk, an oath or affirmation faithfully to perform the duties of his or her office. Such oath or affirmation shall be filed in the office of the city clerk. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16142" number="19577" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-118 Appropriations for contesting office to be made for prevailing party only. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4581" name="12-118"/>§ 12-118 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Appropriations for contesting office to be made for prevailing party only. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16143" number="19578" version="3">
												<PARA>An appropriation or payment for the contesting of the office of mayor or any seat in the council or office in any department, or the office of any officer whose salary is paid from the city treasury, shall be made only to the prevailing party. Such appropriations or payment shall be made to the prevailing party only upon the written certificate of the corporation counsel and of the presiding justice of the appellate division of the first department of the supreme court, certifying who is the prevailing party, and the value of the services rendered in the case.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16144" number="19579" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-119 Definitions. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4583" name="12-119"/>§ 12-119 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16145" number="19580" version="3">
												<PARA>As used in sections <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="12-120" destination-id="0-0-0-4585">12-120</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="12-121" destination-id="0-0-0-4587">12-121</LINK> of this subchapter: </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16146" number="19581" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The word &quot;residence&quot; means domicile and the word &quot;resident&quot; means domiciliary.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16147" number="19582" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;city service&quot; means service as an employee of the city or of any agency thereof other than service in a position which is exempted from municipal residence requirements pursuant to the public officers law or any other state law. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16148" number="19583" version="1740">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1986/040" destination-id="0-0-0-27280">L.L. 1986/040</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-223340" number="19584" version="1740">
											<HEADING>§ 12-120 Residency requirements. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4585" name="12-120"/>§ 12-120 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Residency requirements. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16149" number="19585" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except as otherwise provided in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="12-121" destination-id="0-0-0-4587">12-121</LINK>, any person who enters city service on or after September first nineteen hundred eighty-six (i) shall be a resident of the city on the date that he or she enters city service or shall establish city residence within ninety days after such date and (ii) shall thereafter maintain city residence as a condition of employment. Failure to establish or maintain city residence as required by this section shall constitute a forfeiture of employment; provided, however, that prior to dismissal for failure to establish or maintain city residence an employee shall be given notice of and the opportunity to contest the charge that his or her residence is outside the city. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16150" number="19586" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding subdivision a of this section, employees who have completed two years of city service shall be deemed to be in compliance with the residency requirements of this section if they are residents of Nassau, Westchester, Suffolk, Orange, Rockland or Putnam county; provided, however, that</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16151" number="19587" version="679">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the mayor may require deputy mayors, heads of mayoral agencies as defined in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="385" destination-id="0-0-0-0">385</LINK> of the charter, deputy commissioners, assistant commissioners and general counsels of such agencies to have completed more than two years of city service to be in compliance with the residency requirements of this section,</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16152" number="19588" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the speaker of the council may require the council&apos;s chief of staff, deputy chiefs of staff, general counsel and division directors to have completed more than two years of city service to be in compliance with the residency requirements of this section,</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16153" number="19589" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the comptroller may require the chief of staff, deputy comptrollers, assistant comptrollers and general counsel to have completed more than two years of city service to be in compliance with the residency requirements of this section,</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16154" number="19590" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the borough presidents may require their chiefs of staff, deputy borough presidents and general counsels to have completed more than two years of city service to be in compliance with the residency requirements of this section, and</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16155" number="19591" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the public advocate may require the chief of staff, deputy advocates and general counsel to have completed more than two years of city service to be in compliance with the residency requirements of this section. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16156" number="19592" version="2278">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1986/040" destination-id="0-0-0-27280">L.L. 1986/040</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/010" destination-id="0-0-0-24930">L.L. 2009/010</LINK>, and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/048" destination-id="0-0-0-24900">L.L. 2009/048</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-205899" number="19593" version="1399">
											<HEADING>§ 12-121 Exceptions to residence requirements. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4587" name="12-121"/>§ 12-121 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Exceptions to residence requirements. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16157" number="19594" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of citywide administrative services on his or her own initiative or upon application of the head of an agency may certify that there is difficulty in the recruitment of personnel for a position and that to restrict recruitment for such position to persons who meet the residency requirements of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="12-120" destination-id="0-0-0-4585">12-120</LINK> based on their residence or their willingness to establish residence consistent with such requirements would not be in the public interest. Persons appointed to positions so certified by the commissioner shall not be required to establish or maintain residence consistent with the requirements of such section as a condition of employment while in service in that position. Each agency head may make application to the commissioner, in such form as the commissioner shall prescribe, for the certification of positions within the agency head&apos;s jurisdiction. The commissioner may certify such positions subject to such limitations and conditions as the commissioner may deem appropriate. Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions, positions in the city council may be so certified by the speaker of the city council. Copies of all certifications of the commissioner and the speaker shall be filed with the city clerk and shall be subject to annual review by the commissioner and speaker. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16158" number="19595" version="1812">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Residence in the city or Nassau, Westchester, Suffolk, Orange, Rockland or Putnam county shall not be required as a condition of employment for:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16159" number="19596" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>persons appointed to the position of chaplain; or</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16160" number="19597" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>employees whose regular work site is outside the city; or</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16161" number="19598" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>employees who have performed functions at a regular work site outside the city, where the city has reduced or terminated, or is in the process of reducing or terminating, the direct performance by city employees of such functions at such site, and the city seeks to transfer, reassign, or appoint such employees to positions located within the city. This paragraph shall apply only where the commissioner of citywide administrative services finds that it is in the public interest to waive the residence requirement for reasons including, but not limited to, facilitating the operations of the affected agency or agencies or furthering the interests of employee relations.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16162" number="19599" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>City residence shall not be required as a condition of employment for campus peace officers level I, level II and level III, as defined by subdivision twenty-seven of section 2.10 of the criminal procedure law, employed by the city university of New York before the effective date of this subdivision. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16163" number="19600" version="2278">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1986/040" destination-id="0-0-0-27280">L.L. 1986/040</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1996/059" destination-id="0-0-0-26052">L.L. 1996/059</LINK>, and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2009/010" destination-id="0-0-0-24930">L.L. 2009/010</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-206294" number="19601" version="1403">
											<HEADING>§ 12-122 Temporary transfer of employees. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4589" name="12-122"/>§ 12-122 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Temporary transfer of employees. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16164" number="19602" version="3">
												<PARA>Whenever the mayor shall determine that there is such an accumulation of work in any agency, the performance of which work will impose upon the regular employees thereof unreasonable and unwarranted burden, the mayor, upon application by the head of such agency, and with the consent of the commissioner of citywide administrative services, may assign to it for temporary employment, employees from any other agency, with the consent of the head thereof. Such transfer shall be for a limited period to be stated in the order of the mayor and may be extended if the mayor shall so determine. Such transfer shall not in any way affect the civil service standing, continuity of service, right to pension, grade or compensation of an employee so transferred.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16165" number="19603" version="1582">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1996/059" destination-id="0-0-0-26052">L.L. 1996/059</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-216115" number="19604" version="1582">
											<HEADING>§ 12-123 Authorizing leaves of absence with pay, for employees of the city to attend conventions, encampments, or parades. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4591" name="12-123"/>§ 12-123 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Authorizing leaves of absence with pay, for employees of the city to attend conventions, encampments, or parades. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16166" number="19605" version="3">
												<PARA>The mayor is hereby empowered to authorize the head of any agency, in the mayor&apos;s discretion, to grant to an employee in any such agency, including per diem employees, a leave of absence with pay for the purpose of attending a convention, encampment or parade of any organization composed of veterans of the wars in which the United States has participated, or a convention of any firefighter&apos;s association or other organization composed of active or exempt volunteer firefighter, if such employee is a member of such organization or association, and does actually attend such convention, encampment or parade.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16167" number="19606" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-124 Payment of salaries; exceptions. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4593" name="12-124"/>§ 12-124 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Payment of salaries; exceptions. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16168" number="19607" version="3">
												<PARA>The salary of every officer or employee paid out of the city treasury who is unable to devote full time to the performance of such person&apos;s regular duties by reason of his or her attendance as a delegate at a constitutional convention shall be paid, notwithstanding such person&apos;s inability to devote full time to his or her regular duties.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16169" number="19608" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-124.1 Electronic pay stubs. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4595" name="12-124.1"/>§ 12-124.1 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Electronic pay stubs. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16170" number="19609" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The pay stub of each city employee receiving direct deposit shall be made available to such employee in electronic format which shall be printable by such employee. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16171" number="19610" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each such city employee shall have access to such electronic pay stub through a secure password-protected website, which can be accessed remotely from a computer terminal or kiosk with intranet and/or internet access in compliance with any local, state and federal laws, regulations and rules, including those dealing with privacy protection. Every city agency shall make reasonable accommodations to provide computer terminals and/or kiosks with intranet and/or internet access for city employees employed by such agency to access such employee&apos;s electronic pay stub and shall permit said employees to access such pay stub as an incidental use.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16172" number="19611" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any city employee who does not wish to receive an electronic pay stub pursuant to subdivision a of this section may request that a printed paper copy of such employee&apos;s pay stub be prepared and forwarded to such employee.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16173" number="19612" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than September 1, 2008, the executive director of payroll administration, in collaboration with the commissioner of citywide administrative services, or his or her respective designee, shall establish and report to the council a plan regarding staggered implementation cycles for all city agencies to comply with the provisions of this local law by December 31, 2009. Such plan shall include, but not be limited to, a phase-in period during which city employees receive their respective pay stubs in both electronic and printed paper copy format and have the opportunity to request such pay stubs in printed paper copy format pursuant to subdivision c of this section.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16174" number="19613" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any obligation to prepare an electronic version of a city employee&apos;s pay stub pursuant to subdivision a of this section shall not negate or diminish any other obligation to furnish such employee with a W-2 wage and tax statement in accordance with federal laws and regulations.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16175" number="19614" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the purposes of this section, the following terms shall have the following meanings:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16176" number="19615" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;city employee&quot; shall include elected officials of the city of New York and employees of such officials, including employees of mayoral agencies, provided that such employee&apos;s pay is processed by the office of payroll administration; and</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16177" number="19616" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;city agency&quot; shall include any agency of the city of New York that employs a city employee. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16178" number="19617" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-125 Retired employees; change of options. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4597" name="12-125"/>§ 12-125 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Retired employees; change of options. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16179" number="19618" version="3">
												<PARA>Notwithstanding any other law to the contrary, no beneficiary shall be permitted to change any optional selection after it has become effective, provided, however, that if: </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16180" number="19619" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a retired member nominates the spouse of such member as the survivor beneficiary under option two or three of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="13-177" destination-id="0-0-0-4599">13-177</LINK> of the code, or if a retired member nominates the spouse of such member under option four of such section to receive payment of an annual benefit as a survivor; and</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16181" number="19620" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>such person so nominated ceases by causes other than death to be his or her spouse or is separated from such spouse; then the board of trustees shall have authority to permit the change of the optional benefit to the maximum benefit that is the actuarial equivalent by and with the consent of all parties. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16182" number="19621" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-126 Health insurance coverage for city employees, persons retired from city employment, and dependents of such employees and retirees. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4601" name="12-126"/>§ 12-126 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Health insurance coverage for city employees, persons retired from city employment, and dependents of such employees and retirees. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16183" number="19622" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in this section, the following terms shall have the meaning hereinafter stated: </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16184" number="19623" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;City employee.&quot; A person: (1) who is employed by a department or agency of the city; and (2) is paid out of the city treasury; and (3) is employed under terms prescribing a work week regularly consisting of twenty or more hours during the fiscal year; and (4) is not employed by the board of education.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16185" number="19624" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;City retiree.&quot; A person who: (1) is receiving a retirement allowance, pension or other retirement benefit from a retirement or pension system either maintained by the city or to which the city has made contributions on behalf of such person pursuant to subdivision (g) of section 80-a of the retirement and social security law; and (2) immediately prior to such person&apos;s retirement as a member of such system, was a city employee, or was an employee of the board of education employed under terms prescribing a work week regularly consisting of twenty or more hours during the fiscal year; and (3) had at the time of retirement, at least five years of credited service as a member of such retirement or pension system, except that (A) such requirement of credited service shall not apply in cases of retirement for accident disability, (B) the requirement of credited service for vested retirement and service retirement shall be at least ten years for a person who was not an employee of the city or the board of education on or before the effective date of the local law that added this clause, and (C) notwithstanding the provisions of clause (B) of this subparagraph, the requirement of credited service for vested retirement and service retirement shall be at least fifteen years for a person who was not an employee of the city or the board of education on or before the effective date of the local law that added this clause, is receiving a retirement allowance from the New York city teachers&apos; retirement system or the New York city board of education retirement system, and held a position represented by the recognized teacher organization for collective bargaining purposes on such person&apos;s last day of paid service.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16186" number="19625" version="1812">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Dependent.&quot; The spouse of a city employee or city retiree or any child of a city employee or city retiree during the period of eligibility of such child for coverage under the insurance contract applicable to such employee or retiree; provided, however, that no spouse or child of any such employee or retiree shall be deemed a dependent after the death of such employee or retiree.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16187" number="19626" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Health insurance coverage.&quot; A program of hospital-surgical-medical benefits to be provided by health and hospitalization insurance contracts entered into between the city and companies providing such health and hospitalization insurance.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16188" number="19627" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Payment of health insurance costs. </CHARFORMAT>Except as otherwise provided in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="12-126.1" destination-id="0-0-0-3999">12-126.1</LINK> and section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="12-126.2" destination-id="0-0-0-4001">12-126.2</LINK> of this chapter, for city employees, city retirees and their dependents:</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16189" number="19628" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The city will pay the entire cost of health insurance coverage for city employees, city retirees, and their dependents, not to exceed one hundred percent of the full cost of H.I.P.-H.M.O. on a category basis. Where such health insurance coverage is predicated on the insured&apos;s enrollment in the hospital and medical program for the aged and disabled under the Social Security Act, the city will pay the amount set forth in such act under 1839(a) as added by title XVIII of the 1965 amendment to the Social Security Act; provided that such amount shall not exceed the sum of nineteen dollars and fifty-three cents per month per individual for the period beginning January first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight and ending December thirty-first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight, and provided further however that such amount shall not exceed the sum of twenty-seven dollars and ninety cents per month per individual for the period beginning January first, nineteen hundred eighty-nine and ending December thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-one, and provided further that such amount shall not exceed the sum of twenty-nine dollars per month per individual for the period beginning January first, nineteen hundred ninety-two and ending December thirty-first nineteen hundred ninety-five. Provided further, that such amount shall not exceed the sum of thirty-two dollars per month per individual effective January first, nineteen hundred ninety-six. Provided further, that such amount shall not exceed the sum of thirty eight dollars and seventy cents per month effective January first, two thousand and provided further that each year thereafter, the City shall reimburse covered employees in an amount equal to one hundred percent of the Medicare Part-B premium rate applicable to that year.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16190" number="19629" version="280">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Health insurance coverage for surviving spouses, domestic partners and children of certain city employees: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-046]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16192" number="19630" version="1765">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where the death of a city employee is or was the natural and proximate result of an accident or injury sustained while in the performance of duty, or where accidental death benefits have been awarded in connection with a qualifying World Trade Center condition as defined in paragraph (a) of subdivision 36 of section 2 of the retirement and social security law, the surviving spouse or domestic partner, until he or she dies, and the children under the age of nineteen years and any such child who is enrolled on a full-time basis in a program of undergraduate study in an accredited degree-granting institution of higher education until such child completes his or her educational program or reaches the age of twenty-six years, whichever comes first, shall be afforded the right to health insurance coverage, and health insurance coverage which is predicated on the insured&apos;s enrollment in the hospital and medical program for the aged and disabled under the social security act, as is provided for city employees, city retirees and their dependents as set forth in paragraph one of this subdivision. Provided, however, and notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, and solely for the purposes of this subparagraph, a member otherwise covered by this subparagraph shall be deemed to have died as the natural and proximate result of an accident or injury sustained while in the performance of duty upon which his or her membership is based, provided that such member was in active service upon which his or her membership is based at the time that such member was ordered to active duty pursuant to Title 10 of the United States Code, with the armed forces of the United States or to service in the uniformed services pursuant to 38 U.S.C. Chapter 43, and such member died while on active duty or service in the uniformed services on or after June fourteenth, two thousand five while serving on such active military duty or in the uniformed services. For purposes of this subparagraph, &quot;city employee&quot; shall include employees of the board of education. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-046]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16193" number="19631" version="2123">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where an active or retired member of the fire department dies and is enrolled in a health insurance plan, the surviving spouse or domestic partner shall be afforded the right to such health insurance coverage and health insurance coverage which is predicated on the insured&apos;s enrollment in the hospital and medical program for the aged and disabled under the social security act as is provided for retirees and their dependents as set forth in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, provided such surviving spouse or domestic partner pays one hundred two percent of the group rate for such coverage, with two percent intended to cover administrative costs incurred, provided such spouse or domestic partner elects such health insurance coverage within one year of the death of his or her spouse or domestic partner. For purposes of this subparagraph, &quot;member of the fire department&quot; shall include persons who were employed by the fire department of the city of New York in a title whose duties are those of an emergency medical technician or advanced emergency medical technician (as those terms are defined in section three thousand one of the public health law), or whose duties required the direct supervision of employees whose duties are those of an emergency medical technician or advanced emergency medical technician (as those terms are defined in section three thousand one of the public health law), or whose duties are those of a fire protection inspector or associate fire protection inspector, or whose duties required the direct supervision of employees whose duties are those of a fire protection inspector or associate fire protection inspector. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16194" number="19632" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where a retired member of the police department, including premerger retirees who were police officers employed by the New York city housing authority or the New York city transit authority, dies and is enrolled in a health insurance plan, the surviving spouse shall be afforded the right to such health insurance coverage and health insurance coverage which is predicated on the insured&apos;s enrollment in the hospital and medical program for the aged and disabled under the social security act as is provided for retirees and their dependents as set forth in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, provided such surviving spouse pays one hundred two percent of the group rate for such coverage, with two percent intended to cover administrative costs incurred, provided such spouse elects such health insurance coverage within one year of the death of his or her spouse.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16195" number="19633" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where an active or retired member of the New York city department of correction or sanitation dies and is enrolled in a health insurance plan, the surviving spouse or domestic partner shall be afforded the right to such health insurance coverage and health insurance coverage which is predicated on the insured&apos;s enrollment in the hospital and medical program for the aged and disabled under the social security act as is provided for retirees and their dependents as set forth in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, provided such surviving spouse or domestic partner pays one hundred two percent of the group rate for such coverage, with two percent intended to cover administrative costs incurred, provided such spouse or domestic partner elects such health insurance coverage within one year of the death of his or her spouse or domestic partner.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16196" number="19634" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any amount paid by the city pursuant to subdivision b of this section shall not be deemed to be salary, wages or compensation within the meaning of any law relating to any retirement or pension system and shall not be considered or included for the purpose of computing or determining employee or city contributions or the rights, allowances and benefits to which a city employee or such employee&apos;s heirs or beneficiaries shall become entitled under any retirement or pension system; and shall not be construed as a change of grade or classification or as a promotion to higher grade or position.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16197" number="19635" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such health insurance coverage as is provided under this section shall be administered by office of labor relations. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16198" number="19636" version="2123">
												<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2015/094, 10/13/2015, retro. eff. 7/29/2015; Am. L.L. 2018/122, 6/23/2018, retro. eff. 4/4/2018; Am. L.L. 2020/024, 1/19/2020, retro. eff. 9/23/2019; Am. L.L. 2020/025, 1/19/2020, retro. eff. 10/22/2019; Am. L.L. 2020/032, 2/11/2020, eff. 2/11/2020; Am. 2023 N.Y. Laws Ch. 706, 12/8/2023, eff. 12/8/2023; Am. 2024 N.Y. Laws Ch. 584, 12/13/2024, eff. 12/13/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-104]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16199" number="19637" version="1582">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 1996/059" destination-id="0-0-0-26052">L.L. 1996/059</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2020/032" destination-id="0-0-0-20333">L.L. 2020/032</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-128010" number="19638" version="468">
											<HEADING>§ 12-126.1 Special provisions applicable to health insurance and welfare benefit fund coverage for certain members of city retirement systems. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3999" name="12-126.1"/>§ 12-126.1 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Special provisions applicable to health insurance and welfare benefit fund coverage for certain members of city retirement systems. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16200" number="19639" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions. </CHARFORMAT>The following terms, as used in this section, shall have the following meanings, unless a different meaning is plainly required by the context: </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16201" number="19640" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;NYCERS former fractional plan member&quot;. A member of the New York city employees&apos; retirement system who, pursuant to the provisions of subdivision m of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="13-162" destination-id="0-0-0-4603">13-162</LINK> of the code, is deemed to have elected to become a career pension plan member (as defined in subdivision forty-six of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="13-101" destination-id="0-0-0-4605">13-101</LINK> of the code), and who currently is such a career pension plan member or a fifty-five-year-increased-service-fraction member (as defined in subdivision fifty-one of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="13-101" destination-id="0-0-0-4605">13-101</LINK> of the code).</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16202" number="19641" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;BERS former fractional plan member&quot;. A member of the board of education retirement system of the city of New York who, pursuant to the provisions of paragraph (g) of subdivision eighteen of section twenty-five hundred seventy-five of the education law, is deemed to have elected to become a career pension plan member (as defined in paragraph twenty-eight of section two of the rules and regulations of such retirement system), and who currently is such a career pension plan member or a fifty-five-year-increased-service-fraction member (as defined in paragraph thirty-one of section two of such rules and regulations).</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16203" number="19642" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Health insurance and welfare benefits fund surcharge&quot;. An amount, expressed as a percentage of salary, specified in a collective bargaining agreement (or other similar instrument) between the city of New York (or the board of education of the city) and the employee organization or organizations representing NYCERS former fractional plan members or BERS former fractional plan members in which it is provided that such members shall absorb the additional health insurance and welfare benefit fund increases caused by the enactment of subdivision m of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="13-162" destination-id="0-0-0-4603">13-162</LINK> of the code and paragraph (g) of subdivision eighteen of section twenty-five hundred seventy-five of the education law.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16204" number="19643" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Commencing with the first full payroll period which begins after October first, nineteen hundred ninety-three, the salary of each NYCERS former fractional plan member and each BERS former fractional plan member shall be reduced by the amount of the health insurance and welfare benefits fund surcharge on each and every payroll of such member for each and every payroll period.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16205" number="19644" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of labor relations shall promulgate rules for the appropriate administration of this section.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16206" number="19645" version="1224">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any salary reduction effectuated pursuant to subdivision b of this section shall be considered part of such member&apos;s salary for the purpose of computing employer and employee pension contributions and all retirement benefits administered by the New York city employees&apos; retirement system or the board of education retirement system of the city of New York. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16207" number="19646" version="1224">
											<HEADING>§ 12-126.2 Special provisions applicable to health insurance and welfare benefit fund coverage for certain correction officers and sanitation workers. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4001" name="12-126.2"/>§ 12-126.2 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Special provisions applicable to health insurance and welfare benefit fund coverage for certain correction officers and sanitation workers. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16208" number="19647" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> The following terms, as used in this section shall have the following meanings, unless a different meaning is plainly required by the context: </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16209" number="19648" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;RSSL&quot;. The New York state retirement and social security law.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16210" number="19649" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Tier II member&quot;. A member of a retirement system or pension fund maintained by the city who is subject to the provisions of article eleven of the RSSL.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16211" number="19650" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Tier III member&quot;. A member of a retirement system or pension fund maintained by the city who is subject to the provisions of article fourteen of the RSSL.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16212" number="19651" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Tier IV member&quot;. A member of a retirement system or pension fund maintained by the city who is subject to the provisions of article fifteen of the RSSL.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16213" number="19652" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Tier II or tier III correction officer participant in a twenty year retirement program.&quot; A tier II or tier III member of the uniformed correction force who is a participant in the twenty-year retirement program established pursuant to (A) section four hundred forty-five-a of the RSSL or (B) section four hundred forty-five-c of the RSSL or (C) section five hundred four-a of the RSSL or (D) section five hundred four-b of the RSSL.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16214" number="19653" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Tier II or tier IV sanitation worker participant in a twenty-year retirement program.&quot; A tier II or tier IV member of the uniformed force of the New York city department of sanitation who is a participant in the twenty-year improved benefit retirement program established pursuant to section four hundred forty-five-b of the retirement and social security law or is a participant in the twenty-year retirement program established pursuant to section six hundred four-a of the retirement and social security law.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16215" number="19654" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Health insurance and welfare benefits fund surcharge.&quot; An amount, expressed as a percentage of salary, specified in a collective bargaining agreement (or other similar instrument) between the city of New York and the employee organization or organizations representing tier II and tier III correction officer participants in a twenty-year retirement program or tier II or tier IV sanitation worker participants in a twenty-year retirement program in which it is provided that such participants shall absorb the additional health insurance and welfare benefit fund increases caused by the enactment of section four hundred forty-five-a of the retirement and social security law, section four hundred forty-five-b of the retirement and social security law, section four hundred forty-five-c of the retirement and social security law, section five hundred four-a of the retirement and social security, section five hundred four-b of the retirement and social security law and section six hundred four-a of the retirement and social security law.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16216" number="19655" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Starting date.&quot; The first day of the first whole payroll period commencing after the date which is thirty days after the effective date of this section.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16217" number="19656" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Effective as of the starting date, the salary of any tier II or tier III correction officer participant in a twenty-year retirement program or any tier II or tier IV sanitation worker participant in a twenty-year retirement program shall be reduced by the amount of the health insurance and welfare benefits fund surcharge on each and every payroll of such member for each and every payroll period.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16218" number="19657" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of labor relations shall promulgate rules for the appropriate administration of this section.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16219" number="19658" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any salary reduction effectuated pursuant to subdivision b of this section shall be considered part of such participant&apos;s final average salary for the purpose of computing employer and employee pension contributions and all retirement benefits administered by any retirement system or plan to which the city of New York contributes on behalf of said such participant. However, this subdivision shall in no way be construed to supersede the provisions of sections four hundred thirty-one, five hundred twelve and six hundred eight of the retirement and social security law or any other similar provision of law which limits the salary base for computing retirement benefits payable by a public retirement system. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16220" number="19659" version="2148">
											<HEADING>§ 12-126.3 Health insurance coverage and welfare fund benefits of certain retirees and their dependents.</HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4607" name="12-126.3"/>§ 12-126.3 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Health insurance coverage and welfare fund benefits of certain retirees and their dependents.</CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16222" number="19660" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> The following terms, as used in this section, shall have the following meanings, unless a different meaning is plainly required by the context: </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16223" number="19661" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Pre-merger transit police retiree&quot;. A member of the uniformed force of the former transit police department of the New York city transit authority who retired as such a member prior to April thirtieth, nineteen hundred ninety-five or retired thereafter as such an employee as a result of an application to retire filed prior to such April thirtieth.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16224" number="19662" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Pre-merger civilian retiree of the transit police department&quot;. An employee of such former transit police department who was not a member of its uniformed force and who retired as such an employee prior to April thirtieth, nineteen hundred ninety-five or retired thereafter as such an employee as a result of an application to retire filed prior to such April thirtieth.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16225" number="19663" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Pre-merger housing police retiree&quot;. A member of the uniformed force of the former housing police department of the New York city housing authority who retired as such a member prior to April thirtieth, nineteen hundred ninety-five or retired thereafter as such an employee as a result of an application to retire filed prior to such April thirtieth.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16226" number="19664" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Pre-merger civilian retiree of the housing police department&quot;. An employee of such former housing police department who was not a member of its uniformed force and who retired as such an employee prior to April thirtieth, nineteen hundred ninety-five or retired as such an employee thereafter as a result of an application to retire filed prior to such April thirtieth.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16227" number="19665" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Health insurance coverage&quot;. The program of hospital-surgical-medical benefits provided to participants therein and their dependents at city cost pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="12-126" destination-id="0-0-0-4601">12-126</LINK> of this chapter and any supplements to such program (i) provided for by an applicable collective bargaining agreement (or other similar instrument) or (ii) provided by other action or practice of the city and/or an appropriate public employee organization representing employees of the city police department.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16228" number="19666" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Welfare fund benefits&quot;. The benefits provided to eligible participants and their dependents pursuant to (i) the provisions of a collective bargaining agreement (or other similar instrument) which denominates such benefits as welfare fund benefits or (ii) a welfare fund agreement executed pursuant to a collective bargaining agreement (or other similar instrument) and benefits provided as welfare fund benefits pursuant to other action or practice of the city and/or an appropriate employee organization representing employees of the city police department.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16229" number="19667" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Appropriate public employee organization representing employees of the city police department&quot;. The certified or recognized public employee organization under article fourteen of the civil service law and chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T12C003" destination-id="0-0-0-4609">three</LINK> of title twelve of the code which represents employees of the police department of the city who have a title and rank which are the same as or equivalent to the title and rank which a pre-merger retiree had at the time of the retirement of such pre-merger retiree.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16230" number="19668" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Pre-merger retiree&quot;. A retiree identified in any of paragraphs one, two, three and four of this subdivision.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16231" number="19669" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Similarly situated retiree of the city police department&quot;. A person (i) who retired as an employee of the police department of the city on a date the same as the retirement date of a pre-merger retiree and (ii) whose title and rank on the date of retirement were the same as or equivalent to the title and rank of such pre-merger retiree at the time of the retirement of such pre-merger retiree.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16232" number="19670" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Health insurance coverage and welfare fund benefits shall be provided pursuant to the provisions of this section to each pre-merger transit police retiree and each pre-merger housing police retiree, and the dependents of each such retiree, in the same manner and to the same extent as if such retiree, at the time of his or her retirement, was a similarly situated retiree of the city police department.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16233" number="19671" version="1812">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Subject to the provisions of paragraphs two and three of this subdivision, health insurance coverage and welfare fund benefits shall be provided pursuant to the provisions of this section to each pre-merger civilian retiree of the transit police department and each pre-merger civilian retiree of the housing police department, and the dependents of each such retiree, in the same manner and to the same extent as if such retiree, at the time of his or her retirement, was a similarly situated retiree of the city police department.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16234" number="19672" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where any civilian retiree referred to in paragraph one of this subdivision was not entitled, under the collective bargaining agreement (or other similar instrument) and/or employer-provided health insurance program applicable to such retiree immediately prior to his or her retirement, to reimbursement by his or her employer for the whole or any part of Medicare premiums paid, such retiree shall not be entitled to reimbursement under this section for the whole or any part of Medicare premiums paid.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16235" number="19673" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Subject to the provisions of paragraph two of this subdivision, all costs of providing health insurance coverage and welfare fund benefits to pre-merger civilian retirees of the housing police department shall be paid by the New York city housing authority.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16236" number="19674" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In relation to providing health insurance coverage and welfare fund benefits pursuant to the preceding provisions of this section to each pre-merger retiree, the respective powers and obligations of the city and the appropriate employee organization representing employees of the city police department (subject to the provisions of paragraphs two and three of subdivision c of this section) shall be the same as in the case of a similarly situated retiree of the city police department.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16237" number="19675" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Subject to the provisions of paragraphs two and three of subdivision c of this section, the costs of providing the health insurance coverage and welfare fund benefits prescribed by the preceding subdivisions of this section to each pre-merger retiree shall be paid by the city and/or paid by or shared with the appropriate public employee organization representing employees of the city police department in the same manner and to the same extent as the city and/or such public employee organization pay or share such costs with respect to a similarly situated retiree of the city police department.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16238" number="19676" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing contained in this section shall be construed as amending or altering any provision of article fourteen of the civil service law or chapter <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T12C003" destination-id="0-0-0-4609">three</LINK> of title twelve of the code. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16239" number="19677" version="2148">
											<HEADING>§ 12-126.4 Health insurance coverage for former mayors.</HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4611" name="12-126.4"/>§ 12-126.4 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Health insurance coverage for former mayors.</CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16241" number="19678" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any former mayor of the city of New York, upon attaining the age of sixty-two, shall be afforded the right to such health insurance coverage as is provided for city employees, city retirees, and their dependents as set forth in paragraph one of subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="12-126" destination-id="0-0-0-4601">12-126</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16242" number="19679" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any amount paid by the city pursuant to this section shall not be deemed to be salary, wages or compensation within the meaning of any law relating to any retirement or pension system and shall not be considered or included for the purpose of computing or determining employee or city contributions or the rights, allowances and benefits to which a city employee or such employee&apos;s heirs or beneficiaries shall become entitled under any retirement or pension system; and shall not be construed as a change of grade or classification or as a promotion to higher grade or position. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16243" number="19680" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such health insurance coverage as is provided under this section shall be administered by the office of labor relations. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230577" number="19681" version="2148">
												<PARA>(Renumbered L.L. 2025/003, 1/13/2025, eff. 3/14/2025) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-230578" number="19682" version="2148">
											<HEADING>§ 12-126.5 Continuation of city employee health insurance during agency transfer.</HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-28034" name="12-126.5"/>§ 12-126.5 Continuation of city employee health insurance during agency transfer.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230594" number="19683" version="2148">
												<PARA>Each agency shall make best efforts to expedite any administrative processes related to the provision of continuous city-administered health insurance coverage for an employee who transfers employment from one agency to a different agency. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230593" number="19684" version="2148">
												<PARA>(L.L. 2025/003, 1/13/2025, eff. 3/14/2025) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-230595" number="19685" version="2148">
											<HEADING>§ 12-126.6 Communication to city employees regarding enrollment in city-administered benefits.</HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-28036" name="12-126.6"/>§ 12-126.6 Communication to city employees regarding enrollment in city-administered benefits.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230592" number="19686" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in this section, the following term has the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230591" number="19687" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">City-administered benefits.</CHARFORMAT> The term “city-administered benefits” means employee benefits, including, but not limited to, health insurance; flexible spending accounts; commuter benefits; and other related supplemental benefits, such as life insurance, that are administered by the city for its employees. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230590" number="19688" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Personnel services.</CHARFORMAT> The term “personnel services” means services related to personnel management, such as communication and guidance regarding agency policies; benefits information; and agency resources that are provided to employees. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230589" number="19689" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Communications relating to benefits.</CHARFORMAT> On the date on which an employee commences employment at an agency, such agency shall provide the following information to such employee in clear and plain language: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230588" number="19690" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Information regarding the availability of city-administered benefits; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230587" number="19691" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any required actions such employee must take to enroll in such city-administered benefits, including any relevant deadlines; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230586" number="19692" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any required actions such employee must take to maintain such city-administered benefits, to the extent such employee transfers employment from one agency to a different agency, without any interruption in service, including any relevant deadlines; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230585" number="19693" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The names and contact information of persons at the agency where such employee commences employment who provide guidance to employees regarding accessing city-administered benefits; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230584" number="19694" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>5.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The names and contact information of persons at the agency where such employee commences employment who provide personnel services, including the type of guidance such persons are designated to provide; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230583" number="19695" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.<TAB tab-count="1"/>To the extent such agency provides any information to such employee regarding available employee benefits that are not city-administered benefits, contact information for persons who can provide guidance to such employees regarding such benefits, to the extent such contact information is available. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230582" number="19696" version="2148">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Language accessibility</CHARFORMAT>. Upon request by an employee for translation of the information required pursuant to subdivision b into one of the 10 designated city languages, as defined by <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="T23C011" destination-id="0-0-0-9295">chapter 11 of title 23</LINK>, an agency shall provide such translation to such employee. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-230580" number="19697" version="2148">
												<PARA>(L.L. 2025/003, 1/13/2025, eff. 3/14/2025) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16244" number="19698" version="2148">
											<HEADING>§ 12-127 City employees injured in course of duty. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4613" name="12-127"/>§ 12-127 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">City employees injured in course of duty. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16245" number="19699" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any member of the uniformed forces of the fire or police departments or any person employed in the department of sanitation in the sanitation service classification of the classified civil service who shall be injured while actually employed in the discharge of police orders of his or her superior officers in the police station, fire house or sanitation section station, as the case may be, or as the result of illness traceable directly to the performance of police, fire or sanitation duty, as the case may be, or any employee of the department of parks, general services, ports and terminals or environmental protection or a person employed by the police commissioner as a school crossing guard who shall be injured while actually employed in the discharge of duty, shall be received by any hospital for care and treatment when such facts are certified to by the head of the department. Unless otherwise provided in this section, such members shall be received by any hospital at the usual ward patient rates. The bill for such care and treatment at such rates, when certified by the superintendent or other person in charge of such hospital and approved by the head of the department concerned, shall be paid by the city. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16246" number="19700" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any member of the uniformed forces of the fire or police department or any person employed in the department of sanitation in the sanitation service classification of the classified civil service or a person employed by the police commissioner as a school crossing guard who, while in the actual performance of duty, and by reason of the performance of such duty and without fault or misconduct on his or her part, shall receive injuries to an extent which may endanger his or her life, shall be received by any hospital for care and treatment, and shall be afforded such medical or surgical care and hospitalization as may be ordered by the chief medical officer of the respective departments in conformity with the provisions of this section. Such medical officer shall forthwith notify the comptroller of the care and hospitalization so ordered. The rate charged for such care and hospitalization for such member or such person shall not exceed the rate charged any person in receipt of an income equal to the salary of such member or of such person for the same accommodations. The comptroller and the heads of the departments affected shall make necessary rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this section. Upon certification by the chief medical officer of the department concerned, the bill for such care and hospitalization, when certified by the superintendent or other person in charge of the hospital and approved by the head of the department concerned, shall be paid by the city. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, a provider of medical treatment or hospital care furnished pursuant to the provisions of this section shall not collect or attempt to collect reimbursement for such treatment or care from any such city employee.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114811" number="19701" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> For purposes of this subdivision, the term &quot;<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">occupational disease</CHARFORMAT>&quot; has the same meaning as such term is defined in section 2 of the workers&apos; compensation law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114833" number="19702" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each agency shall keep a record of, and shall, as soon as practicable, transmit to the law department, any workers&apos; compensation claim filed by an employee, the subject of which concerns an injury sustained in the course of duty while such employee was employed at such agency. Such record shall include, but not be limited to, the following data: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114832" number="19703" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the name of the agency where such employee worked; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114831" number="19704" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>such employee&apos;s title; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114830" number="19705" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the date such employee or the city filed such claim with the appropriate office of the state of New York, if any; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114829" number="19706" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the date the city began to make payment for such claim, or the date such claim was established by the appropriate state office and the date the city began to make payment for such claim pursuant to such establishment, if any; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114828" number="19707" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the date such injury occurred or occupational disease was contracted; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114827" number="19708" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vi)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the location at which such injury occurred or occupational disease was contracted; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114826" number="19709" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the nature of such injury or occupational disease, including, but not limited to, the circumstances, the type or diagnosis and a description of how such injury occurred or such occupational disease was contracted; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114825" number="19710" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(viii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the length of time such employee is unable to work due to such injury or occupational disease, if any; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114824" number="19711" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ix)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whether the employee was given modified assignment(s) or was transferred because of such injury or occupational disease and whether such employee suffered a loss of income or diminution of fringe benefits as a result of such transfer or modification; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114823" number="19712" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(x)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a list of any expenses paid as a result of such claim, including, but not limited to, expenses relating to wage replacement, medical costs, administrative costs and any penalties. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114822" number="19713" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each agency shall collect and report to the law department, no later than February 15 of the year following the reporting year, the following information: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114821" number="19714" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of persons employed by such agency as of December 31 of the reporting year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114820" number="19715" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of persons employed in each job title as of December 31 of the reporting year; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114819" number="19716" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the total, average and median number of days of lost time due to workers&apos; compensation injuries within each job title; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114818" number="19717" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the total amount of wages and workers&apos; compensation paid for disability to injured persons within each job title; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114817" number="19718" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the total amount of medical expenses paid for diagnosis and treatment of injuries and occupational diseases suffered by persons within each job title; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114816" number="19719" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vi)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number and nature of injuries and occupational diseases suffered by agency employees within each job title; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114815" number="19720" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the causal factor and nature of the injuries and occupational diseases suffered by agency employees as reported in subparagraph (vi) of this paragraph by category, including, but not limited to, lifting, assault, repetitive stress, infectious pathogen and chemical exposure; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114814" number="19721" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(viii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the average and median number of days between the onset of disability as measured by the first day of lost time and the first date of payment; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114813" number="19722" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ix)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the total number of workers&apos; compensation claims. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114812" number="19723" version="679">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The mayor, in coordination with the law department, shall ensure that an annual report is prepared utilizing the data received from each city agency pursuant to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subdivision. Such report shall be transmitted to the department of records and information services pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="1133" destination-id="0-0-0-0">1133</LINK> of the charter, the mayor, the comptroller, the public advocate and the speaker of the council by the first day of May, covering the previous calendar year. Such report shall include, but not be limited to: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114810" number="19724" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>an analysis, with respect to each agency included in the report, of expenses paid as a result of workers&apos; compensation claims, including, but not limited to, expenses relating to wage replacement, medical costs, administrative costs and any penalties paid by an agency; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114809" number="19725" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a list by agency of the cause, job title, number and cost of workers&apos; compensation claims; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114808" number="19726" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a list of the occurrence of specific claims for each agency and for the city as a whole; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114807" number="19727" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a list of the specific sites where injuries occurred or where occupational diseases were contracted for each agency and for the city as a whole; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114806" number="19728" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a ten-year comparison of data compiled pursuant to this paragraph; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114805" number="19729" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vi)<TAB tab-count="1"/>all data collected pursuant to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subdivision. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114804" number="19730" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The law department may take appropriate steps to ensure the collection and reporting of information required pursuant to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subdivision shall not violate any applicable federal, state or local law relating to privacy or confidentiality including, but not limited to, the confidentiality requirements of section 110-a of the workers&apos; compensation law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114803" number="19731" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each agency shall develop and implement an annual accident and illness prevention program designed to reduce injuries and illnesses identified in the report required pursuant to paragraph (4) of this subdivision. A listing and description of these programs shall be included in the annual report required by paragraph (4) of this subdivision and made available at each agency. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114802" number="19732" version="266">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than 90 days after submission of the report required pursuant to paragraph (4) of this subdivision, the mayor shall submit to the comptroller, the public advocate and the speaker a report on steps the city will take to develop programs to mitigate injury and illness based on the data collected pursuant to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subdivision. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16263" number="19733" version="705">
												<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2020/022, 1/19/2020, eff. 1/19/2020) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-045]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-114799" number="19734" version="476">
												<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-18">
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="L.L. 2020/022" destination-id="0-0-0-20331">L.L. 2020/022</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-053]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-114800" number="19735" version="468">
											<HEADING>§ 12-128 Claims of officers and employees of city for injuries caused by persons deeming themselves aggrieved. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4615" name="12-128"/>§ 12-128 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Claims of officers and employees of city for injuries caused by persons deeming themselves aggrieved. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16264" number="19736" version="3">
												<PARA>The comptroller with the approval of the mayor is authorized to audit, allow and certify for payment, as charges against the city, the reasonable expenses for medical and surgical treatment and maintenance incurred by the mayor or any other officer or employee of the city, by reason of gunshot wounds or other personal injuries received or sustained by the mayor or other officer or employee of the city at the hands of any person deeming himself or herself aggrieved by and seeking revenge for any alleged official act or omission on the part of said mayor or other officer or employee of the city.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16265" number="19737" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-129 Hours of service during July and August. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4617" name="12-129"/>§ 12-129 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hours of service during July and August. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16266" number="19738" version="3">
												<PARA>Four hours on any Saturday during the months of July and August, shall constitute a full day&apos;s work for all employees of any city agency. The head of any agency shall have power to employ his or her subordinates on any legal holiday, or may employ them on any such Saturday in excess of the legal day&apos;s work above prescribed, paying them compensation therefor at the rate of their usual wages or salaries. The provisions of this section shall apply to and include per diem employees, but shall not apply to the uniformed forces of the police and fire departments. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16267" number="19739" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-130 Office hours. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4619" name="12-130"/>§ 12-130 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Office hours. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16268" number="19740" version="3">
												<PARA>Except as otherwise provided by law, the office hours in all public offices of the city, and of all county offices within the city, shall be from nine o&apos;clock antemeridian to five o&apos;clock postmeridian. The head of a city office or department, or a county officer who comes within the foregoing provisions of this section, may adopt a rule that such office shall be closed to the public at four o&apos;clock postmeridian, when in the judgement of such officer, the period between the hours of four o&apos;clock postmeridian and five o&apos;clock postmeridian is required for the performance of the work in such office. During the months of July and August the office hours of such offices shall be from nine o&apos;clock antemeridian to four o&apos;clock postmeridian if the head of the office or department so orders. The office hours of any such office, however, shall be from nine o&apos;clock antemeridian to twelve o&apos;clock noon on Saturday, provided that the commissioner of the department of finance may, in his or her discretion, adopt a rule that such office or department shall be closed to the public on Saturdays.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16269" number="19741" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-131 Reproduction of records on film. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4621" name="12-131"/>§ 12-131 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Reproduction of records on film. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16270" number="19742" version="1772">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The head of each agency may cause any or all records kept in such agency to be reproduced on photographic film. Such photographic film shall be of durable material and the device used to reproduce such records on such film shall be one which accurately reproduces the original record in all details. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16271" number="19743" version="3">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such photographic film shall be deemed to be an original record for all purposes, including introduction in evidence in all courts or administrative agencies. A transcript, exemplification or certified copy thereof shall, for all purposes recited herein, be deemed to be a transcript, exemplification, or certified copy of the original. </PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16272" number="19744" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-132 Records to be kept and abstracts published. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4623" name="12-132"/>§ 12-132 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Records to be kept and abstracts published. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16273" number="19745" version="3">
												<PARA>Every agency shall keep a record of all its transactions, which shall be accessible to the public. A brief abstract, omitting formal language, shall be made, once a week of all transactions and of all contracts awarded and entered into for work and material of every description. Such abstract shall contain the name or names and residences by street and number, of the party or parties to the contract and of their sureties, if any. A copy of such abstract shall be promptly transmitted for publication in the City Record to the director thereof.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16274" number="19746" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-133 Order to use patented articles prohibited. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4625" name="12-133"/>§ 12-133 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Order to use patented articles prohibited. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16275" number="19747" version="3">
												<PARA>It shall be unlawful for any officer of the city to order any owner or occupant to use any patented article on any building or in any public street or place, except under such circumstances that there can be a fair and reasonable opportunity for competition, the conditions to secure which shall be prescribed by the board of estimate.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16276" number="19748" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-134 Powers and duties of the District Attorney&apos;s investigators. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4627" name="12-134"/>§ 12-134 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Powers and duties of the District Attorney&apos;s investigators. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16277" number="19749" version="3">
												<PARA>In the performance of their duties, all detective investigators, senior detective investigators, racket investigators, senior racket investigators and supervising racket investigators employed by the district attorney of each county contained within the city of New York, shall have all the powers and perform all the duties of police officers in the state.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16278" number="19750" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-138 Applicability of age qualifications to veterans of armed forces. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4629" name="12-138"/>§ 12-138 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Applicability of age qualifications to veterans of armed forces. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16279" number="19751" version="3">
												<PARA>When the qualifications for any examination or test for, or appointment or election to any office, position or employment in the city, includes a maximum age limit, any person who heretofore and subsequent to July first, nineteen hundred forty, entered or hereafter, in time of war, shall enter the active military or naval service of the United States, or the active service of the women&apos;s army corps, the women&apos;s reserve of the naval reserve or any similar organization authorized by the United States to serve with the army or navy, shall be deemed to meet such maximum age requirement if his or her actual age, less the period of such service, would meet such maximum age requirement.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16280" number="19752" version="3">
											<HEADING>§ 12-139 Election of qualified transportation benefits in lieu of taxable dollar compensation. </HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4631" name="12-139"/>§ 12-139 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Election of qualified transportation benefits in lieu of taxable dollar compensation. </CHARFORMAT>
											</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-16281" number="19753" version="3">
												<PARA>Employees of the city of New York shall be permitted to use pre-tax earnings to purchase qualified transportation benefits, other than qualified parking, in accordance with federal law and shall thereupon be entitled to such personal income tax benefits as may be authorized by such law.</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-113225" number="19754" version="182">
											<HEADING>§ 12-140 Line of duty sick leave for World Trade Center rescue, recovery or cleanup operations.</HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-19305" name="12-140"/>§ 12-140 Line of duty sick leave for World Trade Center rescue, recovery or cleanup operations.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-113230" number="19755" version="310">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding any other law, rule or regulation to the contrary, officers and employees of a city with a population of one million or more who (i) do not receive benefits similar to those provided by this section pursuant to a collectively bargained agreement, section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="14-122.1" destination-id="0-0-0-5803">14-122.1</LINK> of this code, section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Jump" destination-name="15-108.1" destination-id="0-0-0-5955">15-108.1</LINK> of this code, or other statutory provision and (ii) filed and received approval for such filed notice of participation in World Trade Center rescue, recovery or cleanup operations or was a participant in World Trade Center rescue, recovery, or cleanup operations as such term is defined in section one hundred sixty-one of the workers&apos; compensation law, who does not have such filed and approved notice of participation and has filed a notice of participation under section one hundred sixty-two of the workers&apos; compensation law and is now employed by a city with a population of one million or more, and subsequently developed a qualifying World Trade Center condition, as defined in section two of the retirement and social security law, shall, after receipt of a written request for line of duty sick leave, be granted line of duty sick leave commencing on the date that such employee was diagnosed with a qualifying World Trade Center condition regardless of whether such officer or employee was employed by his or her current employer at the time that such officer or employee participated in World Trade Center rescue, recovery or cleanup operations. The officer or employee shall be compensated at his or her regular rate of pay for those regular work hours during which the officer or employee is absent from work. Such leave shall be provided without loss of an officer or employee&apos;s accrued sick leave. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-048]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-113229" number="19756" version="182">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A public employer shall not take any adverse personnel action against a public employee regarding the employee&apos;s employment because either (i) the employee utilizes, or requests to utilize, sick leave or any other available leave due to a qualifying World Trade Center condition, as such term is defined in section two of the retirement and social security law, or (ii) the employee utilizes or requests to utilize line of duty sick leave provided by this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-041]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-113228" number="19757" version="310">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of this section, an &quot;adverse personnel action&quot; means any discipline, including issuing a notice of discipline, discharge, suspension, demotion, penalization, or discrimination against an employee utilizing line of duty sick leave pursuant to subdivision (a) of this section. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to diminish or impair the rights of a public employee or employer under any law, rule, regulation or collectively negotiated agreement or to prohibit any personnel action which otherwise would have been taken regardless of any request to use, or utilization of, any sick leave or other available leave due to a qualifying World Trade Center condition or request to use, or utilization of, any line of duty sick leave provided by this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-048]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-113227" number="19758" version="606">
												<PARA>(2019 N.Y. Laws Ch. 251, 9/11/2019, eff. 9/11/2019; Am. 2020 N.Y. Laws Ch. 60, 4/17/2020, retro. eff. 9/11/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-048]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-16282" number="19759" version="1996">
											<HEADING>§ 12-141 Mental health coordinator.</HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-27674" name="12-141"/>§ 12-141 Mental health coordinator.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226934" number="19760" version="1996">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The head of each agency shall designate an employee as such agency’s mental health coordinator. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226937" number="19761" version="1996">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such mental health coordinator shall assist their respective agency in coordinating such agency’s efforts to comply with the Americans with disabilities act of 1990, as amended, and other federal, state, and local laws and regulations concerning accessibility and support for city employees with mental health needs. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226936" number="19762" version="1996">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such mental health coordinator shall conduct outreach to employees of their respective agency about mental health services and support services available to such employees, including but not limited to the employee assistance program and, as appropriate, referral to the agency’s equal employment opportunity officer for assessment for a reasonable accommodation. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-226933" number="19763" version="1996">
												<PARA>(L.L. 2024/028, 1/20/2024, eff. 5/19/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-093]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
									<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-703" level-depth="9" toc-section="true">
										<RECORD id="0-0-0-226932" number="19764" version="2066">
											<HEADING>§ 12-142 Career counseling.</HEADING>
											<PARA>
												<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-27758" name="12-142"/>§ 12-142 Career counseling.</PARA>
										</RECORD>
										<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228074" number="19765" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in this section, the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228073" number="19766" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Agency.</CHARFORMAT> The term “agency” means any agency, the head of which holds office upon appointment of the mayor and those units within the executive office of the mayor designated by the mayor to be covered by the provisions of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="Chapter 16" destination-id="0-0-0-0">chapter 16</LINK> of the charter. Such term does not include agencies headed by boards, commissions, or other multi-member bodies, whether appointed by the mayor or otherwise, nor elected officials, nor other agencies the heads of which are appointed by officials other than the mayor or by multi-member bodies. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228072" number="19767" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Career counseling.</CHARFORMAT> The term “career counseling” means remote or in-person consultation with, and provision of information to, an individual regarding opportunities for promotion, training, and education. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228071" number="19768" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department.</CHARFORMAT> The term “department” means the department of citywide administrative services. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228070" number="19769" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eligible employee.</CHARFORMAT> The term “eligible employee” means a current employee of an agency who has been employed by such agency for at least 12 months after appointment. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228069" number="19770" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each agency shall appoint 1 or more career counselors to offer career counseling to eligible employees. Information included in such career counseling may include, but need not be limited to, opportunities to apply for managerial or supervisory positions or positions with higher salaries or opportunities through the promotional exam process, including where such opportunities may be available in other agencies, and the availability of department- or agency-provided trainings. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228068" number="19771" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each agency shall conduct outreach to eligible employees at least once annually regarding the availability of career counseling services, including how eligible employees may access such services, and inform such employees that their request for career counseling will remain confidential. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228067" number="19772" version="2067">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Eligible employees may request career counseling from their agency through either a remote or in-person format. Such agency shall conduct a career counseling session with the requesting eligible employee within 60 days of such eligible employee’s request. Such agency shall conduct at least 1 follow-up call to each eligible employee who participates in a career counseling session within 30 days of such session. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228066" number="19773" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each agency shall report to the department on or before January 15 of each calendar year the name and contact information of each career counselor appointed to such agency. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228065" number="19774" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall provide training to agency career counselors. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228064" number="19775" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>At least twice each calendar year, the department shall convene a meeting with agency career counselors to disseminate relevant information about the promotional examination process and opportunities through such process for employees to apply for managerial or supervisory positions or positions with higher salaries. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228063" number="19776" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall, in consultation with relevant agencies, create written materials concerning the promotional examination application process, the process for enrolling in department- or agency-provided trainings, and any other relevant information as determined by the department, to be distributed at career counseling sessions or upon request by an eligible employee. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228062" number="19777" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall provide information about the promotional process and opportunities for higher salaries to employees who have sought and received career counseling offered by their agencies. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228061" number="19778" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>j.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than September 1, 2025, and September 1 of each odd-numbered year thereafter, the head of each agency shall submit to the department a report containing the following information for the preceding 2-year period, if applicable: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228060" number="19779" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of eligible employees who sought career counseling, disaggregated by race and gender; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228059" number="19780" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of eligible employees who, subsequent to their career counseling session: (i) applied to take a promotional examination; (ii) enrolled in an agency-provided training; (iii) enrolled in a department-provided training; (iv) transferred into a title offering higher pay; (v) transferred to a different agency; or (vi) were promoted; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228058" number="19781" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of career counseling sessions conducted, disaggregated by in-person or remote format. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228057" number="19782" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>k.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No later than December 31, 2025, and December 31 of each odd-numbered year thereafter, the commissioner shall submit to the mayor and the speaker of the council a report containing the following information for the preceding 2-year period, if applicable: <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228056" number="19783" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of eligible employees who sought career counseling from their agencies, disaggregated by agency, race, and gender; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228055" number="19784" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of eligible employees who, subsequent to their career counseling session: (i) applied to take a promotional examination; (ii) enrolled in an agency-provided training; (iii) enrolled in a department-provided training; (iv) transferred into a title offering higher pay; (v) transferred to a different agency; or (vi) were promoted; <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228054" number="19785" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of career counseling sessions conducted, disaggregated by in-person or remote format; and <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228053" number="19786" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of employees who sought and received information about the promotional process and opportunities for higher salaries to employees from the department after having received career counseling offered by their agencies. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228052" number="19787" version="2066">
												<PARA>
													<TAB tab-count="1"/>l.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department shall create electronic surveys for agencies to distribute to employees upon completion of a career counseling session, to be completed on a voluntary basis. Survey questions shall include, but need not be limited to, questions designed to obtain the information required to be reported by subdivision f of this section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
											<RECORD id="0-0-0-228050" number="19788" version="2066">
												<PARA>(L.L. 2024/075, 7/6/2024, eff. 9/4/2024) <HIGHLIGHTER style="ALP" style-name-escaped="ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-25">[ALP S-099]</HIGHLIGHTER>
												</PARA>
											</RECORD>
										</LEVEL>
									</LEVEL>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>