<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-135534" number="88606" version="2332">
			<HEADING>Chapter 4: Gunsmiths and Dealers in Firearms</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10089" name="T38C004"/>Chapter 4: Gunsmiths and Dealers in Firearms</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-77171" number="88607" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-01 Introduction.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10091" name="T38C004_4-01"/>§ 4-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Introduction.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77172" number="88608" version="3">
									<PARA>The following rules are hereby promulgated for the licensing and regulation of gunsmiths, manufacturers, dealers in firearms and dealers in air pistols, air rifles or similar instruments. Licensees are held responsible for the strict enforcement of and adherence to these rules. Any violation thereof is cause for suspension and/or revocation of the subject license.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-77173" number="88609" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-02 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10093" name="T38C004_4-02"/>§ 4-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77174" number="88610" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Air pistols, air rifles, or similar instruments.</CHARFORMAT> The terms &quot;air pistols,&quot; &quot;air rifles,&quot; or &quot;similar instruments&quot; shall mean any instrument designed or redesigned, made or remade to use the energy of a spring or air to fire a projectile.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77175" number="88611" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Ammunition.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;ammunition&quot; shall mean any explosives suitable to be fired from a firearm, machine-gun, rifle, shotgun or other dangerous weapon.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77176" number="88612" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Applicant, licensee or license. </CHARFORMAT>The terms &quot;applicant,&quot; &quot;licensee&quot; or &quot;license&quot; shall mean and refer to gunsmiths, manufacturers, dealers in firearms and dealers in air pistols, air rifles, or similar instruments unless expressly restricted.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77177" number="88613" version="1875">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Assault weapon.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;assault weapon&quot; shall mean an &quot;assault weapon&quot; as defined in § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="10-301" destination-id="0-0-0-0">10-301</LINK>(16) of the New York City Administrative Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77178" number="88614" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Assembler. </CHARFORMAT>The term &quot;assembler&quot; shall include any person, firm, partnership, corporation or company who engages in the business of joining or fitting together any firearm or parts thereof.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77179" number="88615" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commissioner.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;Commissioner&quot; shall mean the Police Commissioner of the City of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77180" number="88616" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dealer in air pistols, air rifles or similar instruments.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;Dealer in air pistols, air rifles or similar instruments&quot; shall mean any person, firm, partnership, corporation or company who engages in the business of purchasing, selling, keeping for sale, loaning, leasing, or in any manner disposing of, any air pistol, air rifle or similar instrument. Dealer in air pistols, air rifles or similar instruments shall not include a wholesale dealer.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77181" number="88617" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dealer in firearms.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;dealer in firearms&quot; shall mean any person, firm, partnership, corporation or company who engages in the business of purchasing, selling, keeping for sale, loaning, leasing, or in any manner disposing of, any pistol or revolver. Dealer in firearms shall not include a wholesale dealer.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77182" number="88618" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Employee.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;employee&quot; shall mean any person who is employed by a licensed gunsmith, manufacturer or dealer in firearms and who has access in any manner to firearms, rifles, shotguns, machine-guns, or assault weapons.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77183" number="88619" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Firearm.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;firearm&quot; shall mean a &quot;firearm&quot; as defined in § 265.00 of the New York State Penal Law and shall include a pistol, a revolver, and any firearm which may be concealed upon the person.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77184" number="88620" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Gunsmith.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;gunsmith&quot; shall mean any person, firm, partnership, corporation or company who engages in the business of repairing, altering, assembling, manufacturing, cleaning, polishing, engraving or trueing, or who performs any mechanical operation on any rifle, shotgun, firearm, machine-gun, or assault weapon.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77185" number="88621" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Machine-gun.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;machine-gun&quot; shall mean a weapon of any description, irrespective of size, by whatever name known, loaded or unloaded, from which a number of shots or bullets may be rapidly or automatically discharged from a magazine with one continuous pull of the trigger and includes a submachine gun.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77186" number="88622" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Manufacturer.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;manufacturer&quot; shall include any person, firm, partnership, corporation or company who engages in the business of machining, producing, constructing, or making any firearm, rifle, shotgun, machine-gun, assault weapon, firearm frames or receivers. The term &quot;manufacturer&quot; shall include &quot;assembler&quot;.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77187" number="88623" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rifle.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;rifle&quot; shall mean a &quot;rifle&quot; as defined in § 265.00 of the New York State Penal Law, except that for purposes of this chapter a rifle shall have a barrel length of no less than sixteen inches and an overall length of no less than twenty-six inches.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77188" number="88624" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Shotgun.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;shotgun&quot; shall mean a &quot;shotgun&quot; as defined in § 265.00 of the New York State Penal Law, except that for purposes of this chapter a shotgun shall have a barrel length of no less than eighteen inches and an overall length of no less than twenty-six inches.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-77189" number="88625" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-03 Requirements of Applicants.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10095" name="T38C004_4-03"/>§ 4-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Requirements of Applicants.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77190" number="88626" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications for dealer in firearms, gunsmith, manufacturer and dealer in air pistols and air rifles shall be filed in the precinct in which the business premises is located.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77191" number="88627" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An applicant shall be over 21 years of age and maintain a place of business in the city, and if the applicant is a partnership, each member shall be over 21 years of age; if the applicant is a corporation each officer shall be over 21 years of age.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77192" number="88628" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each applicant shall be a citizen of the United States.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77193" number="88629" version="2332">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each applicant shall be of good moral character, which means having the essential character, temperament and judgment necessary to be entrusted with a weapon and to use it only in a manner that does not endanger oneself or others. For the purposes of the preceding sentence, the use of force that is reasonably necessary to protect oneself or others shall not be construed as endangering oneself or others. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-080]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77194" number="88630" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each applicant shall never have been convicted anywhere of a felony or any other &quot;serious offense&quot; as defined in § 265.00(17) of the New York State Penal Law, or of a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence, as defined in § 921(a) of title 18 of the United States Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77195" number="88631" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No license shall be issued or renewed to any applicant who has not disclosed whether s/he is or has been the subject or recipient of an order of protection or a temporary order of protection, or the subject of a suspension or ineligibility order issued pursuant to § 530.14 of the New York State Criminal Procedure Law or § 842-a of the New York State Family Court Act.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77196" number="88632" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No license shall be issued or renewed to any applicant unless s/he has stated whether s/he has ever suffered any mental illness or been confined to any hospital or institution, public or private, for mental illness.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77197" number="88633" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each applicant shall be free from any disability or condition that may affect the ability to safely possess or use a rifle, shotgun, firearm, machine-gun, assault weapon, air pistol or air rifle.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77198" number="88634" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No license shall be transferable to any other person or premises. The license shall mention and describe the premises for which it is issued and shall be valid only for such premises.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77199" number="88635" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A license issued pursuant to this section shall be prominently displayed on the licensed premises. Failure of any licensee to so exhibit or display her/his license shall be presumptive evidence that s/he is not duly licensed.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77200" number="88636" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If applicant has any branch units in the City of New York where any firearms, rifles, shotguns, machine-guns, assault weapons, air pistols, or air rifles are stored or any activities requiring a license are conducted, a separate application shall be filed with the precinct where each branch is located and a separate license secured for each premises.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77201" number="88637" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(l)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each applicant shall be fingerprinted pursuant to the provisions of New York State Penal Law § 400.00.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77202" number="88638" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(m)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A corporation shall file a certified copy of its articles of incorporation with application.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77203" number="88639" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(n)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If names of current officers do not appear in articles, a certified copy of the minutes of the directors&apos; meeting at which current officers were elected shall be submitted with application.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77204" number="88640" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(o)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If there is a change of officers in a corporation, the corporation shall send to the License Division, One Police Plaza, Room 110A, New York, New York 10038, a certified copy of the minutes showing names of new officers.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77205" number="88641" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(p)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If applicant represents a partnership or uses a trade name, a certificate from the county clerk of the county in which the certificate is recorded shall be filed with application.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77206" number="88642" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(q)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Change of residence address for any individual licensee, partner, officer, stockholder, or director of a corporation, except those stockholders or directors whose fingerprints are waived, shall be filed with the Commanding Officer of the precinct wherein the premises is located, within 48 hours after change becomes effective.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77207" number="88643" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(r)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications shall be submitted together with the application fee on forms supplied by the Commissioner and shall be subscribed and sworn to by all individual applicants, partners, stockholders or officers of the corporation as the case may be. The annual fee, to be submitted with the application, by certified check or money order payable to the N.Y.C. Police Department, shall be twenty-five ($25) dollars for a gunsmith or manufacturer, fifty ($50) dollars for a dealer in firearms and ten ($10) dollars for a dealer in air pistols and air rifles.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77208" number="88644" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(s)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A false statement on the application shall be grounds for disapproval.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77209" number="88645" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(t)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Plans and Permits.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77210" number="88646" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applicant shall submit architectural plans of the premises proposed to be licensed and such plans shall be prepared by a registered architect.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77211" number="88647" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applicant shall submit a current class (1) Federal Firearms License.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77212" number="88648" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applicant shall submit a Certificate of Occupancy (C of O) zoned for gun dealers business. The C of O will state if premises is approved for more or less than 200 rounds of ammunition. If approved for more than 200 rounds a Fire Department permit is required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77213" number="88649" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applicant shall submit a current lease or deed for license location.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77214" number="88650" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Commanding Officer or designee (crime prevention officer or community policing supervisor) of the local precinct shall inspect premises to ensure that security measures are adequate. A central station alarm shall be in place and operable.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77215" number="88651" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applicant shall submit any and all licenses issued to her/him by the License Division, including a New York City Rifle/Shotgun Dealer&apos;s License, handgun license, or rifle/shotgun permit.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77216" number="88652" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applicant shall submit a Second-Hand Dealer&apos;s License issued by the Department of Consumer Affairs, if applicable.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77217" number="88653" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(u)<TAB tab-count="1"/>During the pendency of the application, the applicant shall notify the License Division of any necessary correction to or modification of the information provided in the original application, or any change in her/his status or circumstances, which may be relevant to the application.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77218" number="88654" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If her/his license application is disapproved the applicant shall receive a written &quot;Notice of Application Disapproval&quot; from the License Division indicating the reason(s) for the disapproval. If the applicant wishes to appeal the decision s/he shall submit a sworn written statement, which shall be known as an &quot;Appeal of Application Disapproval,&quot; to the Division Head, License Division, within thirty (30) calendar days of the date on the &quot;Notice of Application Disapproval&quot; requesting an appeal of the denial, and setting forth the reasons supporting the appeal. The Appeal of Application Disapproval shall become part of the application. It shall state the grounds for the appeal and shall contain the following statement to be signed by the applicant and notarized: &quot;Under penalty of perjury, deponent being duly sworn, says that s/he is familiar with all of the statements contained herein and that each of these statements is true, and no pertinent facts have been omitted.&quot; Appeals that are unsworn by the applicant or submitted by individuals or business entities other than the applicant or her/his New York State licensed attorney shall not be accepted. All timely appeals shall receive a complete review of the applicant&apos;s entire file by the Division Head, License Division, who shall notify the applicant of her/his determination. The Division Head, License Division shall not consider any documentation that was not submitted during the initial background investigation. There shall be no personal interviews to discuss appeals. If the appeal of her/his disapproval is denied, the applicant shall receive a &quot;Notice of Disapproval After Appeal&quot; letter from the Division Head, License Division. This notice concludes the Police Department&apos;s administrative review procedure.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77219" number="88655" version="2332">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 12/16/2022, eff. 12/16/2022) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-080]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-135542" number="88656" version="2332">
								<HEADING>§ 4-04 Licensee Requirements.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10097" name="T38C004_4-04"/>§ 4-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Licensee Requirements.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77220" number="88657" version="1404">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of this section, all employees, as defined in 38 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T38C004_4-02" destination-id="0-0-0-10093">4-02</LINK>, of a licensed gunsmith or dealer in firearms, shall personally be in possession of the required, valid license(s) or permit(s) issued by the License Division to possess handguns, rifles and/or shotguns. No person shall be employed who has been convicted anywhere of a felony, misdemeanor, serious offense as defined in § 265.00(17) of the New York State Penal Law, or a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence, as defined in § 921(a) of title 18 of the United States Code. No person shall be employed who is the subject of a suspension or ineligibility order issued pursuant to § 530.14 of the New York State Criminal Procedure Law or § 842-a of the New York State Family Court Act. The fitness of any employee for continued employment is subject to review by the Commissioner. The licensee may be directed to terminate such employment if such employment involves access in any manner to firearms, rifles, shotguns, machine-guns, or assault weapons, based upon an arrest for any offense, or upon previous connection with a premises wherein the license was revoked or denied, or on said employee&apos;s character or reputation, or upon the employee&apos;s being or becoming the recipient or subject of an order of protection or a temporary order of protection. Licensees shall submit a roster of employees in triplicate on a form prescribed by the Commissioner, together with original application and with each renewal application. A report of any change of personnel, or change of residence address of an employee shall be filed in writing with the Commanding Officer of the precinct wherein the premises is located, within 48 hours after such change becomes effective.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77221" number="88658" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No firearms shall be sold, or given away, or otherwise disposed of, except to a person expressly authorized under the provisions of Articles 265 and 400 of the New York State Penal Law and §§ 1.20 and 2.10 of the New York State Criminal Procedure Law to possess and have such firearm. Any police officer or peace officer as defined in the Criminal Procedure Law shall produce her/his shield and proper identification card before purchasing a pistol or revolver. A peace officer whose status does not confer authorization to possess firearms pursuant to § 2.10 of the New York State Criminal Procedure Law shall possess a handgun license or rifle/shotgun permit in order to be a lawful transferee. Therefore, before delivering a firearm, rifle, shotgun, machine-gun or assault weapon to a peace officer, the licensee shall verify that person&apos;s status as a peace officer with the License Division Incident Section at (212) 374-5538 or 5539.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77222" number="88659" version="1875">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pursuant to New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="10-311" destination-id="0-0-0-0">10-311</LINK>(a), it shall be unlawful for any person or business enterprise to dispose of any firearm which does not contain a safety locking device, defined as a design adaptation or attachable accessory that will prevent the use of the weapon by an unauthorized user. The following types of safety locking devices will be deemed to comply with this provision:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77223" number="88660" version="888">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a trigger lock, which prevents the pulling of the trigger without the use of a key; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77224" number="88661" version="888">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a combination handle, which prevents the use of the weapon without the alignment of the combination tumblers; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77225" number="88662" version="888">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a detachable or non-detachable locking device, composed primarily of steel or other metal of significant gauge to inhibit breaking, utilizing a metallic key or combination lock, rendering the weapon inoperable until the locking device is removed by an authorized person.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77226" number="88663" version="2819">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pursuant to New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="10-311" destination-id="0-0-0-0">10-311</LINK>(b), it shall be unlawful for any licensed manufacturer, licensed importer, or licensed dealer to dispose of any firearm in New York City unless it is accompanied by the following warning, which shall appear in conspicuous and legible type in capital letters, and which shall be printed on a label affixed to the firearm and on a separate sheet of paper included within the packaging enclosing the firearm: &quot;THE USE OF A LOCKING DEVICE OR SAFETY LOCK IS ONLY ONE ASPECT OF RESPONSIBLE WEAPON STORAGE. ALL WEAPONS SHOULD BE STORED UNLOADED AND LOCKED IN A LOCATION THAT IS BOTH SEPARATE FROM THEIR AMMUNITION AND INACCESSIBLE TO CHILDREN AND ANY OTHER UNAUTHORIZED PERSONS. NEW YORK CITY LAW PROHIBITS, WITH CERTAIN EXCEPTIONS, ANY PERSON FROM ACQUIRING MORE THAN ONE FIREARM, OR MORE THAN ONE RIFLE OR SHOTGUN, WITHIN A 90-DAY PERIOD.&quot; <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77227" number="88664" version="1875">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pursuant to New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="10-311" destination-id="0-0-0-0">10-311</LINK>(c), any person who applies for and obtains authorization to purchase, or otherwise lawfully obtains, a firearm shall be required to purchase or obtain a safety locking device at the time s/he purchases or obtains the firearm.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77228" number="88665" version="1875">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pursuant to New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="10-311" destination-id="0-0-0-0">10-311</LINK>(d), the City of New York and its agencies, officers or employees shall not be liable to any party by reason of any incident involving, or the use or misuse of a safety locking device that may have been purchased in compliance with these rules.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77229" number="88666" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the event that any individual lacking authority to possess a firearm, rifle, shotgun, machine-gun or assault weapon attempts to leave such weapon with a licensee for cleaning, repairing or other processing, the licensee may accept the firearm, rifle, shotgun, machine-gun or assault weapon and obtain the name, address, telephone number, etc. of the person leaving the weapon. The licensee shall immediately report the incident to the precinct wherein the premises is located. If the licensee does not accept the firearm, rifle, shotgun, machine-gun or assault weapon for cleaning, repairing, or other processing, s/he shall report the incident to the precinct wherein the premises is located as soon as the individual possessing the weapon leaves the premises. In the event that any individual lacking authority to possess a firearm, rifle, shotgun, machine-gun or assault weapon offers to sell or otherwise dispose of such weapon to a licensee, the licensee shall attempt to obtain the name, address, and telephone number of said individual and shall notify the precinct wherein the premises is located as soon as said individual leaves the premises.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77230" number="88667" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The licensee and all stockholders, officers, directors, applicants, agents and employees shall at all times comply with all laws, rules, regulations and requirements of all federal, state and local jurisdictions and agencies having authority with respect to the premises and conduct and operation of the licensed business, now in effect or hereafter adopted.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77231" number="88668" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The licensee shall immediately make a telephone notification to the Division Head, License Division and the Commanding Officer of the precinct wherein the premises is located, followed by written notice to both within ten (10) calendar days, of any incident or violations of law or rules of federal, state or local jurisdictions regarding her/himself, partners, officers, directors, stockholders, agents or employees of the licensed corporation affecting the premises or business operations. For purposes of this subdivision, an incident includes:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77232" number="88669" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>arrest, indictment or conviction in any jurisdiction;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77233" number="88670" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>summons (except traffic infraction);</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77234" number="88671" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>suspension or ineligibility order issued pursuant to § 530.14 of the New York State Criminal Procedure Law or § 842-a of the New York State Family Court Act;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77235" number="88672" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the fact that the individual is or becomes the subject or recipient of an order of protection or a temporary order of protection;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77236" number="88673" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>admission to any psychiatric institution, sanitarium and/or the receipt of psychiatric treatment;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77237" number="88674" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>receipt of treatment for alcoholism or drug abuse;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77238" number="88675" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the presence or occurrence of a disability or condition that may affect the handling of a firearm, rifle, shotgun, machine-gun or assault weapon including but not limited to epilepsy, diabetes, fainting spells, blackouts, temporary loss of memory, or nervous disorder;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77239" number="88676" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>lost, stolen, altered or mutilated license; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77240" number="88677" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9)<TAB tab-count="1"/>unauthorized discharge of a firearm, rifle, shotgun, machine-gun or assault weapon on the licensee&apos;s premises.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77241" number="88678" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The conviction of a licensee anywhere of a felony or any other &quot;Serious Offense&quot; as defined in § 265.00(17) of the New York State Penal Law, or of a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence, as defined in § 921(a) of Title 18 of the United States Code, shall operate as a revocation of the license. A license may also be revoked or suspended by a court pursuant to § 530.14 of the New York State Criminal Procedure Law or § 842-a of the New York State Family Court Act.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77242" number="88679" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If her/his license is suspended or revoked, the licensee shall be required to deposit any firearms, rifles, shotguns, machine-guns and assault weapons as well as any handgun license or rifle/shotgun permit in her/his possession with her/his local police precinct and forward a copy of the voucher together with her/his license to the License Division. Her/his failure to comply within ten (10) calendar days from the date of suspension or revocation may result in the arrest of the licensee.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77243" number="88680" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(l)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A license may be suspended and/or revoked by the License Division for good cause by the issuance of a Notice of Determination Letter to the licensee, which shall state in brief the grounds for the suspension or revocation and notify the licensee of the opportunity for a hearing. Upon issuance of a written Notice of Determination Letter notifying the licensee of suspension or revocation of the license, a suspended/former licensee shall have thirty (30) calendar days from the date of the notice of determination to submit a written request for a hearing to the Commanding Officer, License Division, One Police Plaza, Room 110A, New York, New York 10038. A licensee whose arrest or summons resulted in suspension or revocation of her/his license may only submit a written request for a hearing within thirty (30) calendar days after the termination of the criminal action, as defined in New York State Criminal Procedure Law § 1.20(16)(c). If the suspension or revocation resulted from the licensee becoming the subject of an order of protection or a temporary order of protection, the licensee may only submit a written request for a hearing within thirty (30) calendar days after the expiration or voiding of the order of protection or temporary order of protection. If the suspension or revocation was related to both a criminal action and an order of protection or temporary order of protection, then the later of the two waiting periods shall apply.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77244" number="88681" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(m)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A license issued shall be valid only for the premises mentioned and described in the license and shall be prominently displayed on such premises.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77245" number="88682" version="1875">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(n)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pursuant to New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="10-312" destination-id="0-0-0-0">10-312</LINK>, it shall be a criminal violation for any person who is the lawful owner or lawful custodian of a firearm to store or otherwise place or leave such weapon in such a manner or under circumstances that it is out of her/his immediate possession or control, without having rendered such weapon inoperable by employing a safety locking device as defined in subdivision (c) of this section. Such offense shall constitute a misdemeanor if the offender has previously been found guilty of such violation or if the violation is committed under circumstances which create a substantial risk of physical injury to another person. Firearms may be displayed so long as the firearms are enclosed in a glass case within the premises and are removed and adequately safeguarded during the hours the business is closed. Firearms dealers may not display firearms or ammunition in the store windows or doors. Licensees are responsible for the safeguarding of their firearm inventory and the loss of firearm(s) may result in the revocation of the firearms dealer&apos;s license. All firearms shall be locked in an enclosed security room or safe, when not properly displayed.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77246" number="88683" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(o)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each licensee shall cause a physical inventory to be taken prior to making application for renewal of her/his license, which shall include a listing of each firearm by make, calibre and serial number and shall be prepared in triplicate. The original copy of the inventory shall be maintained on the premises, the duplicate forwarded to the License Division and the triplicate filed in the precinct. In addition to the annual inventory, the licensee shall maintain a perpetual inventory and establish an internal security system acceptable to the Commissioner.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77247" number="88684" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(p)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Ammunition shall not be displayed in any area. Any ammunition required in the selling area shall be kept in a locked container not visible to the public. All other ammunition shall be stored in an area of the premises that can be secured and is not in view of the public. Only the licensee and authorized employees shall have access to this area.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77248" number="88685" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(q)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A record of all ammunition received and dispensed shall be maintained in a bound book with pages consecutively numbered. It shall be the responsibility of the licensee or a designated employee to make entries in this record. This book together with all invoices received shall be kept in the ammunition storage area.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77249" number="88686" version="341">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(r)<TAB tab-count="1"/>This record shall be arranged in columnar form as outlined below. The first page of this book shall have an inscription bearing the name and address of the premises, license number, name of the owner of the premises, name of employee designated to make entries, and the date of the book being opened. Beginning on page 2, each even numbered page shall contain a record of ammunition received and starting with page 3, each odd numbered page shall contain a record of ammunition dispersed. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-100241" number="88687" version="1404">
									<PARA>AMMUNITION RECEIVED <LINEBRK/>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-100247" number="88688" version="2332">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="9">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Date </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Time </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Transporter / Manufacturer </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Invoice </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Gauge / Calibre </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Type </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Quantity </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Signature </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Comments </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-100248" number="88689" version="1404">
									<PARA>AMMUNITION SOLD <LINEBRK/>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-100249" number="88690" version="2332">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="9">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="108" percentage="no"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Date </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Time </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Manufacturer </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Gauge / Calibre </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Quantity </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Name </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Address </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Date of Birth </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">Identification<LINEBRK/>(how determined) </CELLFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>– </PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77250" number="88691" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(s)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Permission to deviate from the above indicated procedure shall be requested from the Division Head, License Division, through the Commanding Officer of the precinct in which the licensed premises is located.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77251" number="88692" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(t)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Licensees shall cooperate with all reasonable requests by the Police Department for information and assistance in matters relating to the license.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77252" number="88693" version="2819">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 12/6/2024, eff. 1/5/2025) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-148689" number="88694" version="2819">
								<HEADING>§ 4-05 Rules Affecting Gunsmiths Only.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10099" name="T38C004_4-05"/>§ 4-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rules Affecting Gunsmiths Only.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77253" number="88695" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every gunsmith shall keep a bound record book with pages numbered consecutively, in which the following information shall be entered:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77254" number="88696" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name, address, age and occupation of every person for whom any work is performed on a rifle, shotgun, firearm, machine-gun, or assault weapon.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77255" number="88697" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Make, model, calibre, serial number of the rifle, shotgun, firearm, machine-gun, or assault weapon, and time, date and nature of the work performed.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77256" number="88698" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The authority to carry or possess such rifle, shotgun, firearm, machine-gun, or assault weapon; enter date and number of license or permit, if any. If the owner is a police officer or a peace officer as defined in the New York State Criminal Procedure Law, enter rank, shield number, agency, unit assigned, identification number, and license/permit number or License Division notification reference in addition to other captioned information as required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77257" number="88699" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such records shall be maintained at the premises stated in the license and permanently preserved thereat. Such records, as well as the premises and all rifles, shotguns, firearms, machine-guns, and assault weapons thereat, shall be subject to inspection at all times by members of the New York City Police Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77258" number="88700" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the event of cancellation, suspension or revocation of the license or discontinuance of the business by a licensee, such records shall be delivered to the precinct through which the license was issued and the license forwarded to the License Division.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77259" number="88701" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A gunsmith shall not engage in the licensed activities of a dealer in firearms, unless s/he has first obtained a license as a dealer in firearms.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-77260" number="88702" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-06 Rules Affecting Dealers in Firearms Only.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10101" name="T38C004_4-06"/>§ 4-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rules Affecting Dealers in Firearms Only.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77261" number="88703" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every dealer in firearms shall keep a bound record book with pages numbered consecutively, in which the following information shall be entered:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77262" number="88704" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The date, time, name, address, age, occupation, and authority to possess, of every person or firm from whom a firearm is received, together with the make, calibre and serial number of each such firearm and the name of the employee of the dealer making the purchase. If the owner is a police officer or a peace officer as defined in the New York State Criminal Procedure Law, enter rank, shield number, agency, unit assigned, identification number, and license/permit number or License Division notification reference, in addition to other captioned information as required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77263" number="88705" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When a firearm is sold, exchanged, or in any manner disposed of by the dealer, the name, age, occupation and address of the person accepting same, her/his authority to purchase, carry or possess, enter date, name of issuing officer and number of license, if any, the make, model, calibre and serial number, time and name of the dealer or person in her/his employ effecting the transaction. If the purchaser is a police officer or a peace officer, as defined in the New York State Criminal Procedure Law, rank, shield number, agency, unit assigned, identification number and license/permit number or License Division notification reference, shall be entered in addition to other required information.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77264" number="88706" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such records shall be maintained on the premises stated in the license and permanently preserved thereat. Such records, as well as the premises and firearms, shall be subject to inspection at all times by members of the Police Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77265" number="88707" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the event of cancellation, suspension or revocation of the license, or discontinuance of business by a licensee, such records as well as the permanent inventory records, shall be delivered to the precinct through which license was issued and the license shall be forwarded to the Division Head, License Division.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77266" number="88708" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every licensed dealer who sells, gives or otherwise provides any authorized person with a firearm shall prepare and forward to Stolen Property Inquiry Section, Pistol Index, One Police Plaza, New York, New York 10038 within 72 hours, Form P.D. 524-101 (Pistol Index Card).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77267" number="88709" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every acquisition of a second-hand firearm by a licensed dealer, by trade-in or otherwise, shall be reported and forwarded to Stolen Property Inquiry Section, Pistol Index, One Police Plaza, New York, New York 10038, within 72 hours on Form P.D. 524-151, Dealer&apos;s Report on Second-Hand Guns. Each report shall give the date, hour, name and address of each person from whom a firearm is received, the authority to possess and dispose of same, and the make, model, calibre and serial number of each such firearm. No second-hand firearm shall be sold or disposed of until the expiration of fifteen (15) days after its acquisition. The date and hour of transmission of each report required hereunder shall be entered in the permanent record book which each licensed dealer is required to maintain under these Rules.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-77268" number="88710" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-07 Rules Affecting Air Pistol and Air Rifle Dealers Only.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10103" name="T38C004_4-07"/>§ 4-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rules Affecting Air Pistol and Air Rifle Dealers Only.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77269" number="88711" version="3">
									<PARA>Every dealer shall keep a record of the name and address of each person purchasing air pistols, air rifles, or similar instruments, together with place of delivery and said record shall be open to inspection during regular business hours by a member of the New York City Police Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-77270" number="88712" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-08 Validity of Licenses.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10105" name="T38C004_4-08"/>§ 4-08 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Validity of Licenses.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77271" number="88713" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A license issued to a dealer in firearms, gunsmith or manufacturer shall be valid until the 1st day of the second January after date of issuance, and may be renewed annually thereafter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77272" number="88714" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A license for dealers in air pistols/air rifles is an annual license which may be renewed thereafter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-77273" number="88715" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-09 Familiarity with Rules and Law.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10107" name="T38C004_4-09"/>§ 4-09 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Familiarity with Rules and Law.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77274" number="88716" version="1875">
									<PARA>All licensees shall be required to sign an acknowledgment that they shall be responsible for compliance with all laws, rules, regulations, standards, and procedures promulgated by federal, state, or local jurisdictions, and by federal, state, or local law enforcement agencies, that are applicable to each type of license or permit issued to them. Licensees are specifically reminded of the prohibitions against possession of assault weapons in New York City pursuant to New York City Administrative Code, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T10C003" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Title 10, Chapter 3</LINK>. The License Division shall provide the licensee with the acknowledgment statement to be executed. This acknowledgment statement shall be notarized. Failure to execute the acknowledgment statement and to have it notarized shall result in the license application being denied.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>