<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-36389" number="43340" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 8: Court and Trust Funds</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4949" name="T19C008"/>Chapter 8: Court and Trust Funds</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-36390" number="43341" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 8-01 Deposit with Commissioner of Finance of Funds or Securities.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4951" name="T19C008_8-01"/>§ 8-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Deposit with Commissioner of Finance of Funds or Securities.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36391" number="43342" version="3">
									<PARA>Each deposit of money or securities with the Commissioner of Finance must be accompanied by either:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36392" number="43343" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a certified copy of the judgment, order or decree directing the deposit or payment into court, or an excerpt thereof that includes such direction, under the seal of the court, or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36393" number="43344" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a certificate, under the seal of the court, made by the clerk of the court whose duty it is first to receive the deposit in cases in which moneys or securities may be deposited or paid into court pursuant to statute. For example, a tender into court, a deposit to discharge a judgment or a mechanic&apos;s lien, security for costs in certain cases; deposits of civil bail; a surplus arising upon the sale of property by a sheriff under an execution or by a referee in mortgage foreclosure proceedings by advertising. This certificate must contain the following information:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36394" number="43345" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>name of court, or source of receipt if deposited without court order;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36395" number="43346" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>title of the action or proceeding;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36396" number="43347" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>by whom, for whom, and for what purpose the deposit is made;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36397" number="43348" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>date of original receipt by official making deposit; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36398" number="43349" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>if the deposit consists of cash, the amount thereof, or if it be securities, the nature and description of the same.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-36399" number="43350" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 8-02 Necessity of Certified Court Order for Payment.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4953" name="T19C008_8-02"/>§ 8-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Necessity of Certified Court Order for Payment.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36400" number="43351" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No payment, investment, surrender or delivery of court funds, property or security may be made by the Commissioner of Finance or any depositary, without a certified copy of an order or decree of the court having jurisdiction of such funds, property and securities, directing each such payment, investment, surrender or delivery. Payments may not be made on affidavits and proof of age alone. Moneys deposited for or on behalf of an infant payable when the infant attains his majority are not to be paid under the order directing the deposit unless that order also expressly directs the payment of such money on or after the day, month and year therein specified when the infant becomes of legal age.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36401" number="43352" version="1558">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Court orders must be certified by the clerk of the court (CPLR § 2607).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36402" number="43353" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the whole or remaining balance of payments of money into court in an action, or of a distributive share thereof, or any security or other property, is directed to be paid out of court, the order must direct the payment of all accrued income belonging to the party to whom such money or distributive share or remaining balance thereof, or security or other property is paid.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36403" number="43354" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If it is desired that the check for payment be mailed to the attorney for the claimant, a direction to that effect must be incorporated in the order of payment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-36404" number="43355" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 8-03 Certificate of Deposit by Commissioner of Finance.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4955" name="T19C008_8-03"/>§ 8-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Certificate of Deposit by Commissioner of Finance.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36405" number="43356" version="3">
									<PARA>A certificate of deposit or other document showing the amount of money held by the Commissioner of Finance for the benefit of any person will be issued by the Court and Trust Fund Division of the Department of Finance upon fulfillment of the following prerequisites:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36406" number="43357" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An application on forms furnished by the Department of Finance must be completed and filed by the person claiming the right to possession of the funds, or by an attorney acting on his behalf.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36407" number="43358" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Commissioner of Finance or his designee may require the claimant to appear at the Commissioner&apos;s office and to produce satisfactory evidence of the fact that the claimant is the person lawfully entitled to possession of the funds, and to complete and file additional written statements to satisfactorily establish the claimant&apos;s right to the funds. If the claimant is absent from the City or is unable to appear in person at the Commissioner of Finance&apos;s office by reason of physical or other disability, or by reason of military service, satisfactory proof of such fact may be required, and an attorney or other person acting on behalf of the claimant may be required to produce proof of his or her authority to act. At any time after the issuance of a certificate of deposit, and up to the actual payment of the funds on deposit to the claimant or to such other person as may be entitled thereto, the Commissioner of Finance or the Commissioner&apos;s designee may require proof similar to that described in this section, as well as copies of the petition, affidavits and exhibits upon which the order was granted.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-36408" number="43359" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 8-04 Vouchers.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4957" name="T19C008_8-04"/>§ 8-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Vouchers.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36409" number="43360" version="3">
									<PARA>Any of the following will be considered a proper voucher for payments of money out of court, by the Department of Finance.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36410" number="43361" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A check properly endorsed and bearing proper evidence of payment by the bank on which it was drawn to the person or persons to whom payment was directed to be made.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36411" number="43362" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A proper receipt or voucher signed by the person or persons to whom payment is directed to be made or to whom securities or other property are directed to be assigned or delivered. Such receipt must be filed at the time of any payment, assignment or delivery directed by the order of the court.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-36412" number="43363" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 8-05 Transfer of Funds.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4959" name="T19C008_8-05"/>§ 8-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Transfer of Funds.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36413" number="43364" version="3">
									<PARA>Funds may not be transferred from one depositary to another except pursuant to the direction of a court order, or of the State Comptroller.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-36414" number="43365" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 8-06 Fees.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4961" name="T19C008_8-06"/>§ 8-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Fees.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36415" number="43366" version="769">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Commissioner of Finance is entitled, for services, to the following fees: <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-022]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-104727" number="43367" version="769">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each certificate of deposit - $1 <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-022]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-104728" number="43368" version="769">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon moneys paid out of court - 2% except as set forth in subdivision (c) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-022]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-104729" number="43369" version="769">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon moneys invested - 1/2 of 1% <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-022]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-104730" number="43370" version="769">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon securities deposited in court and received by the Commissioner - 2 percent of the par value of the securities <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-022]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-104731" number="43371" version="769">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon investments transferred or assigned out of court by the Commissioner, when the investments have been made by the Commissioner - 2 percent of the par value of the investments. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-022]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36416" number="43372" version="769">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Unless the court otherwise specially directs, all fees for payment of money out of court will be deducted from the amount paid and not from the balance remaining to the credit of the action or proceeding. However, if a judgment or other evidence of debt is a lien upon the funds or portion thereof, or the expenses of litigation (such as referee&apos;s fees, county clerk&apos;s fees or subpoena fees, etc.) are directed to be paid therefrom, the fees of the Department of Finance are to be deducted from the sum or sums remaining of the share or shares which bear such expenses, if sufficient; if insufficient, the amount to be applied to such expenses is the amount remaining of such sum or sums after deducting the fees of the Department of Finance.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-104732" number="43373" version="769">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Department waives the fees to which the Commissioner is entitled pursuant to subdivisions 1, 3 and 4 of Section 99-m of the general municipal law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-022]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-104725" number="43374" version="769">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 1/18/2018, eff. 2/17/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-022]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-36417" number="43375" version="769">
								<HEADING>§ 8-07 Depositaries.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4963" name="T19C008_8-07"/>§ 8-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Depositaries.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36418" number="43376" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Books of account. </CHARFORMAT>Each duly designated depositary is required to keep a separate account for each action or proceeding, in connection with which funds or moneys are deposited therein, showing the name of the court, the title of the action or proceeding, the amount deposited, the date of receipt, from whom received and a record of each additional receipt or credit of interest to and each withdrawal of moneys therefrom. Also an account of each change of investment if any.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36419" number="43377" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Payment of interest.</CHARFORMAT> Depositaries are required to pay interest on deposits of money paid into courts of record at a rate satisfactory to the State, Comptroller and in no event less than the highest rate being paid by the depositary on other accounts having similar maturities. Such interest must be computed from the date of deposit to the date of withdrawal, except that no interest shall be payable on moneys withdrawn within 30 days from the date of deposit. Interest is to be credited not less often than January 1 and July 1 of each year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36420" number="43378" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Certificate of balances.</CHARFORMAT> Each depositary shall furnish annually to the Commissioner of Finance from whom deposits of money paid into court have been received, a certificate of the proper officer of such depositary stating the exact mount on deposit to the credit of each action and proceeding separately on December 31, including interest credits as of January 1 following. Such certificate shall be furnished within 10 days after December 31 in each year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36421" number="43379" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Undertakings and collateral.</CHARFORMAT> Depositaries, other than savings banks, are required to execute and deliver undertakings and to pledge collateral to secure deposits of court and trust funds, as may be required by the State Comptroller.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>