<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-109866" number="52098" version="1960">
			<HEADING>Chapter 16: Criteria for Issuing Special Vehicle Identification Permits to Disabled Persons</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6035" name="T24C016"/>Chapter 16: Criteria for Issuing Special Vehicle Identification Permits to Disabled Persons</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-43262" number="52099" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 16-01 Introduction.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6037" name="T24C016_16-01"/>§ 16-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Introduction.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43263" number="52100" version="1743">
									<PARA>This rule establishes criteria for the issuing of Special Vehicle Identification Parking Permits (SVIPP), also known as Parking Permits for People with Disabilities (PPPD), pursuant to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="2903" destination-id="0-0-0-0">2903</LINK>(a)(15)(a) of the Charter, to or on behalf of disabled persons who have a permanent disability seriously impairing mobility and authorizes the use of physicians designated by the Department, including New York City Health &amp; Hospitals Corporation employed physicians so designated pursuant to a contract entered into by the Department with the Health &amp; Hospitals Corporation and the Department of Transportation, to make the decisions as to the eligibility of such persons for these special permits.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-43264" number="52101" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 16-02 Permanent Disabilities Seriously Impairing Mobility.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6039" name="T24C016_16-02"/>§ 16-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Permanent Disabilities Seriously Impairing Mobility.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43265" number="52102" version="1743">
									<PARA>For the purposes of Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="2903" destination-id="0-0-0-0">2903</LINK>(a)(15)(a) of the Charter the following conditions constitute permanent disabilities that seriously impair mobility:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43266" number="52103" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Complete monoplegia or paraplegia of lower extremities.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43267" number="52104" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Above ankle amputation of lower extremities, at the discretion of the examining physician. Well-fitted below the knee prosthesis with normal ambulatory gait should not routinely be regarded as mobility impaired.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43268" number="52105" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Arthritis of two major weight bearing joints of the lower extremities with clearly substantial X-rays changes and/or MRI changes, such as loss of joint space, severe degenerative changes plus one or more of the following:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43269" number="52106" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Objective finding of sizable effusion of joint(s) detected by clinical examination</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43270" number="52107" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Gross instability or valgus/varus deformities of joint(s) detected by clinical examination</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43271" number="52108" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Ankylosis or contracture of major joint(s) to such a degree as to preclude stair climbing. Joint replacement does not qualify by itself unless accompanied by one or more of the above criteria.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43272" number="52109" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Severe atrophy of one or both lower extremities (or discrepancy in leg lengths greater than three inches) which clearly and seriously impairs mobility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43273" number="52110" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Spinal column abnormalities of severe degree with unequivocal motor involvement not amenable to bracing or surgery which would seriously and permanently impair mobility. X-ray evidence of arthritis of the spine with or without pain is insufficient reason for approval. CT Scan, MRI and/or EMG results must be available for review prior to a decision.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43274" number="52111" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Neurological conditions, such as multiple sclerosis, myasthenia gravis, myopathies, Parkinsonism and Alzheimer&apos;s Disease, affecting both lower extremities that would seriously impair mobility. Objective documentation (i.e., MRI, EMG, nerve conduction studies, et al.) must be submitted, where appropriate, by the applicant.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43275" number="52112" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Cardiovascular and peripheral vascular disease of severe degree resulting in mobility impairment. Cardiovascular disease must meet ADA Class III or IV criteria; stress test, echocardiogram, Doppler or other diagnostic studies must support evidence of significant pathology and/or disability.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43276" number="52113" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pulmonary disease with documented evidence of severe obstructive or restrictive disease on pulmonary function testing. Evidence of use of supplemental oxygen for more than twelve hours per day may also be acceptable evidence of impairment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43277" number="52114" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Renal insufficiency requiring frequent renal dialysis with significant objective finding of neural or hemic abnormalities.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43278" number="52115" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Malignancies of any category that require chemotherapy and/or radiation therapy or other medical interventions which continuously and seriously impair mobility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43279" number="52116" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Post-Polio syndrome that on examination clearly and seriously impairs mobility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43280" number="52117" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(l)<TAB tab-count="1"/>AIDS related conditions, including peripheral neuropathy, wasting syndrome, dementia, which clearly seriously impair mobility on physical examination.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43281" number="52118" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(m)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Mental conditions resulting in mental retardation of a severe nature documented by appropriate psychological evaluation, which permanently and seriously impair mobility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43282" number="52119" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(n)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Congenital diseases of any type that clearly result in permanent serious mobility impairment, including cerebral palsy, spina bifida and Down syndrome.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43283" number="52120" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(o)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any other permanent disability that in the specific circumstances, would seriously impair the mobility of the applicant.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-43284" number="52121" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 16-03 Physicians Employed by Health &amp; Hospitals Corporation Designated to Perform Special Vehicle Identification Parking Permit Certifications.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6041" name="T24C016_16-03"/>§ 16-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Physicians Employed by Health &amp; Hospitals Corporation Designated to Perform Special Vehicle Identification Parking Permit Certifications.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43285" number="52122" version="1743">
									<PARA>The Department may use physicians, made available for this purpose by the Health &amp; Hospitals Corporation pursuant to a contract entered into by the Department with the Health &amp; Hospitals Corporation and the Department of Transportation, to perform medical certifications of Special Vehicle Identification Parking Permit applications submitted to the Department of Transportation. Such physicians, employed by the Health &amp; Hospitals Corporation, shall be qualified to certify persons for a Special Vehicle Identification Parking Permit as possessing a &quot;permanent disability seriously impairing mobility&quot; in accordance with Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="2903" destination-id="0-0-0-0">2903</LINK>(15)(a) of the Charter and the criteria specified in 24 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T24C016_16-02" destination-id="0-0-0-6039">16-02</LINK> above. A practitioner in an appropriate field of specialization may be used to perform a medical certification when deemed necessary by the non-specialist/physician assessing the person&apos;s medical eligibility for a SVIPP.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-43286" number="52123" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 16-04 Certification.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6043" name="T24C016_16-04"/>§ 16-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Certification.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43287" number="52124" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Certification Form.</CHARFORMAT> The Physician Certification Form shall state that, after a review of the SVIPP application and any accompanying documentation furnished by the applicant&apos;s personal physician, it has been determined that the applicant does or does not have a &quot;permanent disability seriously impairing mobility&quot;. Where certification has been denied, the Form shall indicate whether that determination was based upon the fact that the medical documentation presented does not support a finding of a &quot;permanent disability seriously impairing mobility&quot; or because the clinical findings are inconsistent with the applicant&apos;s medical history or otherwise does not support the finding of a &quot;permanent disability seriously impairing mobility&quot;. Except as otherwise provided in 24 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T24C016_16-05" destination-id="0-0-0-6045">16-05</LINK>, such determination shall be final when it is adopted by the Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43288" number="52125" version="1141">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Post-Certification Reevaluation.</CHARFORMAT> In certain cases where certification has been granted, an applicant may be required to submit, at some future time designated by the physician/provider at the time of certification, to a reevaluation/reassessment of his (her) medical condition in order to determine whether the applicant continues to have a &quot;permanent disability seriously impairing mobility&quot;. The decision to require a reevaluation of the applicant shall not be subject to appeal pursuant to 24 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T24C016_16-05" destination-id="0-0-0-6045">16-05</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-43289" number="52126" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 16-05 Appeals.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-6045" name="T24C016_16-05"/>§ 16-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Appeals.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-43290" number="52127" version="3">
									<PARA>Where certification has been denied, an applicant for a Special Vehicle Identification Parking Permit may appeal such determination. Such request for appeal must be made within thirty business days of service of the decision denying the certification upon the applicant on a form received with the decision. Where the denial of certification was based upon a determination/finding that the medical history of the person does not support a finding of a &quot;permanent disability seriously impairing mobility&quot;, the Department shall provide for a review of the file by a physician other than the physician who denied such certification. Where such denial was based upon clinical findings, or where the clinical findings were inconsistent with the medical history of the person, the Department shall provide a second assessment, which may include a physical examination by a physician selected by the Department other than the physician who denied certification. The applicant/appellant shall not be precluded from engaging an outside medical expert or specialist for purposes of his or her appeal. The results of any examination performed by such specialist and his or her conclusions shall be made part of the appeal record. The Department, or provider designated by the Department, may also provide a second assessment by a specialist when deemed necessary by the physician/provider. The results of the examination by this specialist shall also be made part of the appeal record. The determination of such appeal shall be final when it is adopted by the Department. A final determination denying certification shall preclude the filing of a Special Vehicle Identification Parking Permit application for the same condition by or on behalf of such person unless such person demonstrates that the condition has significantly worsened.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>