<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-78143" number="89587" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 15: Adjudications</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10321" name="T38C015"/>Chapter 15: Adjudications</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-78144" number="89588" version="3">
				<HEADING>Subchapter A: Disciplinary Proceedings Against Civilian and Uniform Members Before the Deputy Commissioner of Trials</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter A: Disciplinary Proceedings Against Civilian and Uniform Members Before the Deputy Commissioner of Trials</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78145" number="89589" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-01 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10323" name="T38C015_15-01"/>§ 15-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78146" number="89590" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Advocate.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Advocate&quot; means the Department Advocate or Assistant Advocates of the New York City Police Department and also means an attorney designated by the Commissioner to prosecute a disciplinary proceeding before the Deputy Commissioner of Trials, including an attorney conducting such prosecution on behalf of the Civilian Complaint Review Board in accordance with a Memorandum of Understanding executed on April 2, 2012 by the CCRB and the Department during the period that such MOU is applicable.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78147" number="89591" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Charges and Specifications.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Charges and Specifications&quot; means a written accusation or accusations of misconduct against a civilian or uniform member of the Department, specifying the activity or conduct at issue, along with the date, time and place of occurrence.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78148" number="89592" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Civilian Complaint Review Board.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Civilian Complaint Review Board&quot; or &quot;CCRB&quot; means the New York City Civilian Complaint Review Board.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78149" number="89593" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Department&quot; means the New York City Police Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78150" number="89594" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Deputy Commissioner of Trials.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Deputy Commissioner of Trials&quot; means the Deputy Commissioner or Assistant Deputy Commissioners in charge of New York City Police Department disciplinary hearings.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78151" number="89595" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Respondent.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Respondent&quot; means a uniform or civilian member of the Department against whom Charges and Specifications have been preferred.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78152" number="89596" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-02 Jurisdiction.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10325" name="T38C015_15-02"/>§ 15-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Jurisdiction.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78153" number="89597" version="3">
									<PARA>The Deputy Commissioner of Trials shall have jurisdiction over disciplinary matters adjudicated by the Department. This jurisdiction shall include the authority to render any ruling or order necessary and appropriate for the efficient adjudication of disciplinary proceedings instituted against civilian and uniform members of the Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78154" number="89598" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Applicability.</CHARFORMAT> These Rules shall apply to the conduct of all proceedings heard before the Deputy Commissioner of Trials including pre-hearing, hearing and post-hearing proceedings.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78155" number="89599" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction, Modification and Waiver.</CHARFORMAT> These Rules shall be liberally construed in order to promote just and efficient adjudication of disciplinary proceedings. Upon notice to all parties, the Deputy Commissioner of Trials shall have the authority to modify or waive these Rules where no undue hardship or prejudice to any party shall result from such modification.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78156" number="89600" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-03 Pre-Hearing Proceeding.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10327" name="T38C015_15-03"/>§ 15-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Pre-Hearing Proceeding.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78157" number="89601" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Charges and Specifications. </CHARFORMAT>Charges and specifications shall be served upon the respondent and shall include a brief statement of the disciplinary matters to be adjudicated, including the activity, behavior or incident which is the subject of the disciplinary action and, where appropriate, the date, time and place of occurrence. Additionally, the Charges and Specifications shall identify the contract provision, law, policy, regulation or rule that was allegedly violated. Charges and Specifications may be amended upon notice to all parties.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78158" number="89602" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Service of Charges and Specifications. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78159" number="89603" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Department shall be responsible for serving the respondent with Charges and Specifications. The Charges and Specifications shall be accompanied by notice of the respondent&apos;s right to reply and the time limits within which to do so pursuant to subdivision (c) of this section, and the requirement that the individual representing the respondent shall file a Notice of Appearance with the Deputy Commissioner of Trials, prior to engaging in any act of representation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78160" number="89604" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Service of the Charges and Specifications shall be made pursuant to statute, rule, contract, or other provision of law applicable to the proceeding being initiated. Absent any such applicable law, service of the Charges and Specifications shall be made in a manner reasonably calculated to achieve actual notice to the respondent. Service by certified mail, return receipt requested, contemporaneously with service by regular first-class mail, to the respondent&apos;s last address known to the Department, shall be presumed to be reasonably calculated to achieve actual notice. Appropriate proof of service shall be required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78161" number="89605" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Response to Charges and Specifications. </CHARFORMAT>If Charges and Specifications are served personally, the respondent shall have the opportunity to reply to them within eight days of service. If Charges and Specifications are served by mail, the respondent shall have the opportunity to reply to them within thirteen days of their mailing date. Upon good cause shown, the Deputy Commissioner of Trials may fix different time periods within which to reply.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78162" number="89606" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Notice of Scheduling Conference or Hearing. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78163" number="89607" version="1243">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Department shall serve the respondent with notice of the date, time and place of the Scheduling Conference or Hearing. The Scheduling Conference shall be conducted for purposes of setting a timetable within which to proceed with the Hearing. A Hearing shall be afforded to the respondent within a reasonable time. A Notice of Hearing shall contain a statement of the authority and jurisdiction under which the Hearing is being conducted, notice of the respondent&apos;s right to be represented by an attorney or other representative, the requirement that the respondent&apos;s representative file a Notice of Appearance with the Deputy Commissioner of Trials prior to engaging in any act of representation and notice that failure of the respondent or the respondent&apos;s representative to appear may result in an adverse decision and waiver of the right to a Hearing or other disposition as against the respondent.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78164" number="89608" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Notice of Hearing or Scheduling Conference shall be served personally or by mail. Appropriate proof of service shall be required. If the respondent is served personally, there shall be at least eight days notice provided. If respondent is served by mail at least thirteen days notice shall be provided, from the time of mailing. The Deputy Commissioner of Trials may modify these time periods.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78165" number="89609" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Adjournments.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78166" number="89610" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Hearing dates are firm commitments and will not be adjourned absent extraordinary circumstances. Scheduling Conferences and Hearings will begin promptly at 10 a.m. and continue until 5 p.m., if necessary. All Hearings shall be continued on consecutive days until concluded absent special circumstances. Where appropriate, Hearings may be conducted on weekends and holidays.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78167" number="89611" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications for adjournments shall be made to the Deputy Commissioner of Trials upon sufficient notice to other parties. Adjournments will be granted or denied by the Deputy Commissioner of Trials upon good cause shown. The Deputy Commissioner of Trials shall have authority to set an adjourned date. If an adjournment is granted, and it is not noted on the record, the requesting party shall confirm the adjournment, in writing, with other interested parties.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78168" number="89612" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A party requesting an adjournment because of a conflicting engagement shall file an Affirmation of Actual Engagement with the Deputy Commissioner of Trials, prior to a ruling sought on that basis. A copy of such Affirmation shall be served on the adverse party. The Affirmation shall state the name and nature of the conflicting matter, the court or tribunal hearing the matter, the judge before whom it is scheduled, the date when the conflicting engagement became known to counsel, and the date, time, place and approximate duration of the other engagement.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78169" number="89613" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Deputy Commissioner of Trials may determine that a case will proceed on an expedited basis and direct shortened pre-trial and post-trial proceedings including expedited notice periods and calendaring.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78170" number="89614" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Discovery. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78171" number="89615" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Informal discovery and the exchange of information is encouraged. Department disciplinary proceedings are not bound by formal discovery techniques or rules of civil procedure. Requests for production of relevant documents, identification of trial witnesses and inspection of real evidence to be introduced at the Hearing may be directed between the parties without leave of the Deputy Commissioner of Trials. Privileged and confidential matters shall not be subject to disclosure.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78172" number="89616" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any discovery dispute shall be presented to the Deputy Commissioner of Trials sufficiently in advance of the Hearing to allow for a timely determination. Discovery motions are subject to the discretion of the Deputy Commissioner of Trials. The timeliness of discovery requests and responses, and of discovery related motions, the complexity of the case, the need for the requested discovery, and the relative resources of the parties will be among the factors within the Deputy Commissioner of Trial&apos;s exercise of discretion.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78173" number="89617" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Pre-Hearing motions. </CHARFORMAT>Pre-Hearing motions and other preliminary matters shall be consolidated and addressed to the Deputy Commissioner of Trials as promptly as possible and sufficiently in advance of the Hearing to permit the rendering of a timely decision.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78174" number="89618" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-04 Hearings.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10329" name="T38C015_15-04"/>§ 15-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hearings.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78175" number="89619" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Consolidation and severance of Hearings.</CHARFORMAT> In the furtherance of justice, efficiency or convenience, all or portions of separate cases may be consolidated for Hearing. Additionally, portions of a single case may be severed for separate Hearing. Cases may be consolidated or severed at the discretion of the Deputy Commissioner of Trials.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78176" number="89620" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Witnesses and documents. </CHARFORMAT>Attorneys for parties to the proceedings shall have the right to subpoena witnesses. Pro Se parties shall have the right to request that the Deputy Commissioner of Trials issue a subpoena on their behalf. The parties are responsible for having their witnesses available on the Hearing date. Parties intending to introduce documents into evidence shall provide sufficient copies to the Deputy Commissioner of Trials and other parties.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78177" number="89621" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Interpreters. </CHARFORMAT>A party in need of an interpreter at a Scheduling Conference or Hearing shall advise the Deputy Commissioner of Trials of such need as soon as possible. The Deputy Commissioner of Trials may, within discretion, accept as an interpreter any person who can provide a fair and accurate translation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78178" number="89622" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Failure to appear.</CHARFORMAT> If the respondent fails to appear at the Hearing personally or by authorized representative, without good cause, the Deputy Commissioner of Trials may conduct a Hearing in the respondent&apos;s absence. If the respondent does not appear, the Deputy Commissioner of Trials shall determine whether to hold an Inquest Hearing or proceed upon written submissions of the parties. Additionally, the Deputy Commissioner of Trials may determine that no further proceedings shall be necessary.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78179" number="89623" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hearing evidence. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78180" number="89624" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Compliance with the technical rules of evidence shall not be required. Hearsay shall be admissible and may form the sole basis for making findings of fact, when consistent with existing law. Additionally, principles of civil practice and the rules of evidence may be applied, where necessary, to insure an orderly proceeding, an accurate record and to aid in the formulation of Findings of Fact. Hearing sequence may be altered by the Deputy Commissioner of Trials for the convenience of the attorneys, parties, witnesses and Deputy Commissioner of Trials. Substantial prejudice shall not result to any party as a result of change in Hearing sequence. Findings of Fact shall be made exclusively on the record as a whole.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78181" number="89625" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Deputy Commissioner of Trials may limit examination, the presentation of testimonial, documentary or other evidence, and submission of rebuttal evidence. Objections to evidence offered or to other matters will be noted in the transcript. Exceptions need not be taken to rulings made over objections. The Deputy Commissioner of Trials may call or question witnesses directly.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78182" number="89626" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Parties shall be entitled to make opening statements. Closing statements may be made orally or in writing at the discretion of the Deputy Commissioner of Trials. On motion of the Deputy Commissioner or the parties, the Deputy Commissioner of Trials may permit written post-hearing submissions including legal briefs, proposed findings of fact, conclusions of law or any other relevant documents.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78183" number="89627" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except for ministerial matters, and except on consent, or in an emergency, communications with the Deputy Commissioner of Trials concerning a case shall only occur with all parties present. If the Deputy Commissioner of Trials receives an &quot;ex parte&quot; communication concerning the merits of a case to which he or she is assigned, then he or she shall promptly disclose the communication by placing it on the record, in detail, including all written and oral communications and identifying all individuals with whom he or she has communicated. A party desiring to rebut the &quot;ex parte&quot; communication shall be allowed to do so upon request.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78184" number="89628" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Official notice. </CHARFORMAT>The Deputy Commissioner of Trials may take official notice of any fact which may be judicially noticed by the courts of New York State. Notice may be taken before or after submission of a case for decision on request of a party or &quot;sua sponte&quot;.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78185" number="89629" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Public access to hearings. </CHARFORMAT>Hearings shall be open to the public unless the Deputy Commissioner of Trials finds a legally recognizable ground for closure of all or a portion of the Hearing. The Deputy Commissioner of Trials may also exclude witnesses from the Hearing room during proceedings other than their own testimony.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78186" number="89630" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Disposition by settlement. </CHARFORMAT>Unless precluded by law, informal disposition may be made of any matter which is the subject of an adjudication by methods of alternative dispute resolution, stipulation, agreed settlement, or consent order.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78187" number="89631" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Transcripts. </CHARFORMAT>Hearings shall be stenographically recorded. A copy of the transcript or record, or any part thereof, shall be made available to any party to the Hearing for a reasonable cost upon request.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78188" number="89632" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-05 Rules of Conduct.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10331" name="T38C015_15-05"/>§ 15-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rules of Conduct.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78189" number="89633" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Conduct. </CHARFORMAT>Individuals appearing before the Deputy Commissioner of Trials shall conduct themselves in a dignified and orderly manner at all times. Disruptive conduct, including failure to comply with the orders and directives of the Deputy Commissioner of Trials, will not be tolerated. The Deputy Commissioner of Trials may bar a disruptive individual from the proceedings.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78190" number="89634" version="351">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Withdrawal and substitution of representatives. </CHARFORMAT>A representative who has filed a Notice of Appearance, in accordance with paragraph (1) of subdivision (d) of 38 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T38C015_15-03" destination-id="0-0-0-10327">15-03</LINK>, may not withdraw from representation of a party without the permission of the Deputy Commissioner of Trials. Withdrawal shall be granted upon sufficient showing of good cause and, where an attorney is the respondent&apos;s representative, consistent with the Code of Professional Responsibility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78191" number="89635" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hearing Officers. </CHARFORMAT>The Deputy Commissioner of Trials and Assistant Deputy Commissioners shall be assigned solely to adjudicative and related duties.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78192" number="89636" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-06 Report to Police Commissioner.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10333" name="T38C015_15-06"/>§ 15-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Report to Police Commissioner.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78193" number="89637" version="352">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>After the Hearing is concluded the Deputy Commissioner of Trials will review the testimony and evidence adduced and prepare a Draft Report and Recommendation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78194" number="89638" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Draft Report and Recommendation shall consist of a summary and analysis of the testimony, recommended findings of fact and conclusions of law, and recommendations for the disposition of the Charges and Specifications.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78195" number="89639" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All parties, and their counsel or other representative shall be sent a copy of the Draft Report and Recommendation in order to afford them an opportunity to comment thereon. It is the party&apos;s or the party&apos;s representative&apos;s responsibility to submit written comments timely or a final determination may be made without such comments having been considered.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78196" number="89640" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The parties will be allowed a specified period of time from the receipt of the Draft Report and Recommendation to submit comments. Such comments must be in writing and confined to the evidence in the record. The parties shall provide copies of such comments to the Deputy Commissioner of Trials who will, upon receipt of all such comments, forward them to the adverse parties. Upon receipt of such comments, the Deputy Commissioner of Trials will finalize the Report and Recommendation. The Report and Recommendation will then be forwarded to the Police Commissioner along with the transcript of the proceeding, unless waived, all exhibits received in evidence, and any comments submitted by the parties pursuant to this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78197" number="89641" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the Deputy Commissioner of Trials finds the respondent guilty of any charges, the respondent&apos;s employment record will be reviewed prior to determining a recommended penalty. The respondent may review his or her employment record prior to its submission to the Deputy Commissioner of Trials.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78198" number="89642" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-07 Penalties.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10335" name="T38C015_15-07"/>§ 15-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Penalties.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78199" number="89643" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The penalty imposed upon a respondent should take into account the respondent&apos;s employment history as well as the nature of the proven misconduct.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78200" number="89644" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Penalties shall be imposed upon a respondent consistent with applicable provisions of the Civil Service Law and Administrative Code of the City of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78201" number="89645" version="352">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An alternative penalty may be agreed upon by the parties, pursuant to subdivision (h) of 38 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T38C015_15-04" destination-id="0-0-0-10329">15-04</LINK>, outside the scope of applicable statutes.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78202" number="89646" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-08 Final Review.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10337" name="T38C015_15-08"/>§ 15-08 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Final Review.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78203" number="89647" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>After reviewing the record of the proceeding and the Report and Recommendation of the Trial Commissioner, the Police Commissioner will make a final determination. The Police Commissioner may approve the recommendation or modify the findings or the penalty consistent with the record.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78204" number="89648" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the event a respondent enters a plea of guilty in return for a specific recommended sanction by the Trial Commissioner, and the Commissioner upon review imposes a greater sanction, the respondent will be allowed to accept the Commissioner&apos;s penalty or withdraw his or her guilty plea and proceed to a Hearing.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78205" number="89649" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The written final determination shall be served on the respondent, his or her attorney or representative if one appeared at the Hearing, and the Advocate.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-78206" number="89650" version="3">
				<HEADING>Subchapter B: Substantiated Civilian Complaints Against Uniform Members</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter B: Substantiated Civilian Complaints Against Uniform Members</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78207" number="89651" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-11 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10339" name="T38C015_15-11"/>§ 15-11 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78208" number="89652" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Chair.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Chair&quot; means the Chair of the New York City Civilian Complaint Review Board.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78209" number="89653" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Charges and Specifications.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Charges and Specifications&quot; means a written accusation or accusations of misconduct against a uniform member of the Department, specifying the activity or conduct at issue, along with the date, time and place of occurrence.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78210" number="89654" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Civilian Complaint Review Board.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Civilian Complaint Review Board&quot; or &quot;CCRB&quot; means the New York City Civilian Complaint Review Board.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78211" number="89655" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Department&quot; means the New York City Police Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78212" number="89656" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department Advocate.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Department Advocate&quot; or &quot;DAO&quot; means the Department Advocate or Assistant Advocates of the New York City Police Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78213" number="89657" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Deputy Commissioner of Trials.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Deputy Commissioner of Trials&quot; means the Deputy Commissioner or Assistant Deputy Commissioners in charge of New York City Police Department disciplinary hearings.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78214" number="89658" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Executive Director.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Executive Director&quot; means the Executive Director of the New York City Civilian Complaint Review Board.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78215" number="89659" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">FADO.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;FADO&quot; means allegations of excessive force, abuse of authority, discourtesy or offensive language contained in civilian complaints falling within the jurisdiction of the Civilian Complaint Review Board.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78216" number="89660" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Police Commissioner.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Police Commissioner&quot; or &quot;Commissioner&quot; means the Police Commissioner of the City of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78217" number="89661" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-12 Prosecution of Charges and Specifications.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10341" name="T38C015_15-12"/>§ 15-12 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Prosecution of Charges and Specifications.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78218" number="89662" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon substantiation by the Civilian Complaint Review Board (CCRB) of one or more FADO allegations contained in a civilian complaint against a uniformed member of the NYPD, CCRB shall notify the Police Commissioner of the substantiation and CCRB&apos;s disciplinary recommendation. Subject to the provisions of subdivision (b) of this section, civilian complaints found to be substantiated by the CCRB in which CCRB has recommended that Charges and Specifications be preferred shall be prosecuted by the CCRB pursuant to a Memorandum of Understanding (MOU) executed on April 2, 2012 by the CCRB and the Department during the period that such MOU is applicable.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78219" number="89663" version="1036">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In those limited circumstances where the Commissioner determines that CCRB&apos;s prosecution of Charges and Specifications in a substantiated case would be detrimental to the Department&apos;s disciplinary process, the Commissioner shall notify CCRB of this determination. These instances shall be limited to cases in which 1) there are parallel or related criminal investigations, or 2) when, in the case of an officer with no disciplinary history or prior substantiated CCRB complaints, and based on such officer&apos;s record and disciplinary history, the interests of justice would not be served.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109203" number="89664" version="1036">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any request by the Commissioner for the CCRB to refrain from prosecution of Charges and Specifications in accordance with this section shall be made in writing to the CCRB, include a detailed explanation for such request and a statement detailing what discipline if any the Police Commissioner would pursue on such uniformed officer.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109204" number="89665" version="1036">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>The CCRB may reject such request to refrain from prosecution within five business days of receipt of such request. Such rejection shall be made in writing and include a statement rebutting the Commissioner&apos;s explanation for his or her request.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109205" number="89666" version="1036">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Commissioner may deny such rejection within five business days of receipt of such rejection. Such denial shall be made in writing to CCRB and include a detailed response to CCRB&apos;s rebuttal. Upon receipt of such denial the CCRB shall refrain from further prosecution of the case.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78220" number="89667" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-13 Expedited Cases.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10343" name="T38C015_15-13"/>§ 15-13 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Expedited Cases.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78221" number="89668" version="3">
									<PARA>Upon receipt of notification that a complaint has been found to be substantiated by the CCRB accompanied by a recommendation that Charges and Specifications be preferred, the DAO shall inquire as to whether the nature of the substantiated allegation and the status of the subject officer requires expedited prosecution of the substantiated case. In such cases, or in similar cases where the need for such expedited prosecution arises while the prosecution is pending, the DAO shall advise CCRB&apos;s Chair and Executive Director of the need for expedited prosecution. CCRB shall make every reasonable effort to conclude the prosecution within the required time frame. If CCRB determines that it will not be able to conclude the prosecution within the required time frame, CCRB will decline to prosecute the case and request that the DAO undertake the prosecution of such case.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78222" number="89669" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-14 Other Misconduct.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10345" name="T38C015_15-14"/>§ 15-14 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Other Misconduct.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78223" number="89670" version="3">
									<PARA>If during the course of its prosecution of a substantiated civilian complaint, CCRB becomes aware of possible misconduct falling outside its FADO jurisdiction (such as the making of a false statement), which is alleged to have been committed by the subject officer, CCRB shall immediately refer the allegation of such other misconduct to NYPD for investigation. CCRB shall not itself undertake the prosecution of such other misconduct. CCRB shall provide assistance to NYPD as requested for purposes of investigation or prosecution of the alleged misconduct. If necessary, CCRB and the Department Advocate shall coordinate their prosecutions of such related cases.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78224" number="89671" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-15 Assistance by Department and Application of Department Procedures and Disciplinary Policies.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10347" name="T38C015_15-15"/>§ 15-15 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Assistance by Department and Application of Department Procedures and Disciplinary Policies.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78225" number="89672" version="3">
									<PARA>CCRB personnel conducting administrative prosecutions pursuant to the MOU executed on April 2, 2012 shall familiarize themselves with and apply Department disciplinary policies and standards to the extent practicable and relevant. Attorneys and support staff shall be trained in all aspects of Department procedures and policies as they affect such administrative prosecution, including the provisions of Subchapter A of this Chapter. The Department shall provide all reasonable assistance requested by CCRB in the creation of a unit of attorneys and support staff responsible for conducting administrative prosecutions, including training and guidance in both legal and administrative matters. During the course of its administrative prosecution, CCRB&apos;s prosecutorial staff may contact the DAO to request the assistance of Department personnel as needed to effectively evaluate, prepare, and prosecute the case. The DAO shall arrange for Department personnel to provide reasonable assistance to CCRB.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78226" number="89673" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-16 Conclusion of Administrative Prosecution.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10349" name="T38C015_15-16"/>§ 15-16 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Conclusion of Administrative Prosecution.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78227" number="89674" version="352">
									<PARA>At the conclusion of the administrative prosecution, in all instances other than cases culminating in a report and recommendation by the Deputy Commissioner of Trials, the CCRB shall forward to the Commissioner a final recommendation reflecting the results of its prosecution of the case. The CCRB shall include all relevant forms, memoranda and background information to assist the Commissioner in making a final disciplinary determination. If the case culminated in a hearing before the Deputy Commissioner of Trials, the provisions of Subchapter A of this Chapter shall apply, subject to the provisions of 38 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T38C015_15-19" destination-id="0-0-0-10355">15-19</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78228" number="89675" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-17 Police Commissioner&apos;s Determination.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10351" name="T38C015_15-17"/>§ 15-17 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Police Commissioner&apos;s Determination.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78229" number="89676" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In all instances other than cases culminating in a report and recommendation by the Deputy Commissioner of Trials, upon receiving the final recommendation of CCRB with accompanying documents, the Commissioner may accept, reject, or modify the recommendation presented, or may ask CCRB for additional investigative or background information in its possession. He or she may also request further investigation or development of the record in the case to enable him or her to make a final determination in the case. If CCRB&apos;s recommendation is rejected or modified, CCRB will then be responsible for taking any appropriate follow-up action, such as proceeding with prosecution of the subject officer, engaging in additional investigation, or further developing the record in the case.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78230" number="89677" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Department shall notify CCRB of the final disciplinary result and specific penalty in each case within thirty calendar days of the Commissioner&apos;s final determination.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78231" number="89678" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-18 Correspondence Following Final Determination of Substantiated Civilian Complaints.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10353" name="T38C015_15-18"/>§ 15-18 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Correspondence Following Final Determination of Substantiated Civilian Complaints.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78232" number="89679" version="3">
									<PARA>In any case substantiated by the CCRB in which the Police Commissioner intends to impose discipline that is of a lower level than that recommended by CCRB or by the Deputy Commissioner of Trials, the Commissioner shall notify the CCRB, with notice to the subject officer, at least ten business days prior to the imposition of such discipline. Such notification shall be in writing and include a detailed explanation of the reasons for deviating from CCRB&apos;s recommendation including but not limited to each factor the Commissioner considered in making his or her decision. The CCRB and the subject officer may respond to such a notification within five business days of its receipt, after which the Commissioner shall make a final determination.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78233" number="89680" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-19 Confidentiality.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10355" name="T38C015_15-19"/>§ 15-19 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Confidentiality.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78234" number="89681" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Documents or verbal information provided to CCRB by the Department or created by CCRB pursuant to the MOU executed on April 2, 2012 shall be considered confidential to the extent provided by New York State Civil Rights Law § 50-a or any other applicable law. CCRB shall not disclose any such document or verbal information to any person, organization or agency without first notifying the Department&apos;s Deputy Commissioner, Legal Matters and providing the Deputy Commissioner, Legal Matters a reasonable opportunity to review the proposed disclosure. This restriction on disclosure shall not apply to disclosures to the Deputy Commissioner of Trials, DAO, or the Department&apos;s Internal Affairs Bureau.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78235" number="89682" version="352">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision (a) of this section, the CCRB and Department may also exchange information pursuant to subdivision (b) of 38 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T38C015_15-12" destination-id="0-0-0-10341">15-12</LINK> and 38 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T38C015_15-18" destination-id="0-0-0-10353">15-18</LINK> to the extent that the disclosure of such information does not tend to reveal the identity of a party or witness involved in the investigation or prosecution of the substantiated civilian complaint which is the subject matter of the correspondence.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-78236" number="89683" version="1961">
				<HEADING>Subchapter C: Hearing Rules Governing Suspension and Revocation of Handgun Licenses, Rifle/Shotgun Permits, Dealer&apos;s, Gunsmith&apos;s and Manufacturer&apos;s Licenses, Organization Registration Certificates and Special Patrolman Designations</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter C: Hearing Rules Governing Suspension and Revocation of Handgun Licenses, Rifle/Shotgun Permits, Dealer&apos;s, Gunsmith&apos;s and Manufacturer&apos;s Licenses, Organization Registration Certificates and Special Patrolman Designations</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78237" number="89684" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-21 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10357" name="T38C015_15-21"/>§ 15-21 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78238" number="89685" version="1243">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department. </CHARFORMAT>The term &quot;Department&quot; shall mean the New York City Police Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78239" number="89686" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Handgun.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;handgun&quot; shall mean a pistol or revolver.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78240" number="89687" version="1789">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hearing Officer. </CHARFORMAT>The term &quot;Hearing Officer&quot; shall mean an individual designated by the Police Commissioner to preside over hearings pertaining to suspension and revocation of handgun licenses, rifle/shotgun permits, dealer&apos;s, gunsmith&apos;s and manufacturer&apos;s licenses, organization registration certificates and special patrolman designations.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78241" number="89688" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">License. </CHARFORMAT>The term &quot;License&quot; shall mean a license or permit to possess handguns or rifles/shotguns, or to conduct business as a dealer, gunsmith or manufacturer, or the registration certificate allowing organizations to possess rifles or shotguns, or the granting of special patrolman designation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78242" number="89689" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">License Division. </CHARFORMAT>The term &quot;License Division&quot; shall mean the New York City Police Department License Division.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78243" number="89690" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Licensee. </CHARFORMAT>The term &quot;Licensee&quot; shall mean any person, business, organization or governmental agency which is requesting a hearing to contest a decision made by the Department regarding an individual license, permit or certificate.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78244" number="89691" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Party.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;Party&quot; shall mean the Department or any licensee involved in a hearing.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78245" number="89692" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Revocation.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;Revocation&quot; shall mean removal of a license and privilege to possess a handgun or rifle/shotgun and/or be designated a special patrolman, or to conduct business as a dealer, gunsmith, or manufacturer, or to possess rifles or shotguns as an organization.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78246" number="89693" version="1876">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Special Patrolman.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;Special Patrolman&quot; shall mean an individual who has been granted a designation as Special Patrolman by the Police Commissioner pursuant to New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="14-106" destination-id="0-0-0-0">14-106</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78247" number="89694" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Suspension.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;Suspension&quot; shall mean temporary removal of a license and privilege to possess a handgun or rifle/shotgun and/or be designated a Special Patrolman, or to conduct business as a dealer, gunsmith, or manufacturer, or to possess rifles or shotguns as an organization.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78248" number="89695" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-22 Commencement of Proceedings.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10359" name="T38C015_15-22"/>§ 15-22 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commencement of Proceedings.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78249" number="89696" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Entitlement to a Hearing. </CHARFORMAT>A licensee shall be entitled to submit a written request for a hearing following issuance of a Notice of Determination Letter notifying the licensee of suspension or revocation of a license and the opportunity for a hearing.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78250" number="89697" version="2819">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Scheduling of Hearings. </CHARFORMAT>A licensee who wishes to request a hearing relating to a suspension or revocation shall submit a written request to the Commanding Officer, License Division, following the issuance of a Notice of Determination Letter, within ninety (90) calendar days of the date on the Notice of Determination Letter. A licensee whose arrest or summons resulted in suspension or revocation of her/his license may only submit a written request for a hearing within ninety (90) calendar days after the termination of the criminal action, as defined in New York State Criminal Procedure Law § 1.20(16)(c). If the suspension or revocation resulted from the licensee becoming the subject of an order of protection or a temporary order of protection, the licensee may only submit a written request for a hearing within ninety (90) calendar days after the expiration or voiding of the order of protection or temporary order of protection. If the suspension or revocation was related to both a criminal action and an order of protection or temporary order of protection, then the later of the two waiting periods shall apply. The License Division shall schedule a hearing within a reasonable time of receipt of the request. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78251" number="89698" version="2819">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Notice of Hearing. </CHARFORMAT>A licensee shall receive notification of the date, time and place of the hearing by regular and/or electronic mail addressed to the licensee&apos;s last known address. Additionally, a licensee&apos;s New York State licensed attorney shall receive notification, if the attorney has filed an appearance with the Department. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-148765" number="89699" version="2819">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 12/6/2024, eff. 1/5/2025) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78252" number="89700" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-23 Proceedings upon Default.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10361" name="T38C015_15-23"/>§ 15-23 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Proceedings upon Default.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78253" number="89701" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Failure to Appear. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78254" number="89702" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon a licensee&apos;s failure to appear at a license suspension or revocation hearing, or any adjournment thereof, without good cause, it shall be deemed that the licensee does not contest the issues underlying the suspension or revocation of the license. The Hearing Officer may recommend the suspension or revocation of the license and/or may proceed to take testimony with regard to the merits of the case.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78255" number="89703" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Notice of Default.</CHARFORMAT> The parties shall be notified of the Hearing Officer&apos;s declaration of default.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78256" number="89704" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application to Vacate Default. </CHARFORMAT>An application for a rehearing and stay of default may be made within 20 calendar days of the date of the notification of default/hearing results. Such application shall be made to the Hearing Officer and may be granted upon a showing of good cause.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78257" number="89705" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-24 Adjournments.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10363" name="T38C015_15-24"/>§ 15-24 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Adjournments.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78258" number="89706" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A request for an adjournment shall be made at least 72 hours prior to the date of the hearing. An adjournment shall not be granted except for good cause shown.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78259" number="89707" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1) If an adjournment is granted, the adjourned hearing date may be marked final against the licensee requesting the adjournment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78260" number="89708" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Attorneys requesting an adjournment because of a conflicting engagement shall submit an Affirmation of Actual Engagement, setting forth the name of the court, case, and date and time of the proceedings.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78261" number="89709" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-25 Evidence.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10365" name="T38C015_15-25"/>§ 15-25 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Evidence.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78262" number="89710" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Evidence. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78263" number="89711" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Parties shall have the right to call witnesses, conduct examinations and cross-examinations, to present evidence, and make objections, motions and arguments.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78264" number="89712" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The rules of evidence governing proceedings in the courts of this State shall not be strictly enforced at hearings. Objections shall be timely and the basis for the objection shall be clearly stated.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78265" number="89713" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The introduction of cumulative or irrelevant evidence shall be avoided. The Hearing Officer may curtail the testimony of any witness which is deemed to be cumulative or irrelevant.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78266" number="89714" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Parties may stipulate to facts involved in the proceedings. Stipulations shall be noted on the record and shall be approved by the Hearing Officer.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78267" number="89715" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Requests for Records.</CHARFORMAT> Licensees or their New York State licensed attorneys may request copies of records at least three weeks in advance of the date of the hearing. Documents shall not be provided in response to such request where: (1) the documents are privileged or confidential pursuant to law or rule, or (2) where disclosure of the documents would reveal investigative techniques, would impair active investigations or judicial proceedings, would constitute an unwarranted invasion of privacy, or would endanger the life or safety of any person.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78268" number="89716" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Oral Argument. </CHARFORMAT>Oral argument may be curtailed or limited, in the Hearing Officer&apos;s discretion, and shall be included in the record.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78269" number="89717" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-26 Hearing Officers and Representation of Parties.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10367" name="T38C015_15-26"/>§ 15-26 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hearing Officers and Representation of Parties.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78270" number="89718" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hearing Officer. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78271" number="89719" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Hearing Officer shall serve both as impartial examiner and impartial judge and shall have the duty to conduct fair and impartial hearings, to take all necessary action to avoid delay in the disposition of the proceedings, and to maintain order. It shall be the duty of a Hearing Officer to inquire fully into all matters at issue and to obtain a full and complete record. The Hearing Officer shall write a Hearing Report which includes a recommended disposition. A Hearing Officer&apos;s duties shall be restricted to adjudication and related matters.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78272" number="89720" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Hearing Officer shall have all powers necessary to conduct a hearing, including the power to administer oaths and affirmations, rule upon offers of proof, receive evidence, regulate the course of hearings and the conduct of the parties and their counsel and to hold conferences, both on and off the record, for settlements, simplification of issues, or any other proper purposes.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78273" number="89721" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Prosecuting Attorney. </CHARFORMAT>An attorney designated by the Department&apos;s Legal Bureau may act as prosecutor to present the Department&apos;s case.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78274" number="89722" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Representation of Licensees. </CHARFORMAT>Licensees may be represented by an attorney who is a member in good standing of the Bar of the State of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78275" number="89723" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-27 Conduct of Hearings.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10369" name="T38C015_15-27"/>§ 15-27 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Conduct of Hearings.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78276" number="89724" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Public Access to Hearings. </CHARFORMAT>Hearings are generally open to the public. If good cause is shown by either party, the Hearing Officer may exclude the public from a particular hearing or portion of a hearing. Additionally, the public may be excluded at the Hearing Officer&apos;s discretion.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78277" number="89725" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">General Provisions. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78278" number="89726" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Hearing Officer shall rule upon matters of procedure and introduction of evidence and shall conduct the hearing in such manner as will best serve the attainment of justice.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78279" number="89727" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Licensees shall appear and testify at the hearing. They may submit evidence relevant to the matter under consideration. If a licensee fails to testify an adverse inference may be drawn against him or her by the Hearing Officer.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78280" number="89728" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any licensee desiring to subpoena a witness, document or other evidence may do so in the manner provided for in the New York Civil Practice Law and Rules. The Hearing Officer shall issue administrative subpoenas to necessary individuals and may issue administrative subpoenas upon request by a party.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78281" number="89729" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No ex parte communications relating to other than ministerial matters regarding a proceeding shall be received by a Hearing Officer, including internal agency directives not published as rules.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78282" number="89730" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Disposition by Settlement. </CHARFORMAT>Informal disposition may be made of any matter which is the subject of an adjudication by means of stipulation, agreed settlement or consent order.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78283" number="89731" version="2819">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Transcripts.</CHARFORMAT> Audio of all hearings shall be recorded. A transcript of the hearing may be ordered by any party to the hearing. The transcript shall be provided upon payment of reasonable transcription costs. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78284" number="89732" version="2819">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 12/6/2024, eff. 1/5/2025) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-148766" number="89733" version="2819">
								<HEADING>§ 15-28 Hearing Officer&apos;s Report and Recommendation.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10371" name="T38C015_15-28"/>§ 15-28 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hearing Officer&apos;s Report and Recommendation.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78286" number="89734" version="2819">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>After the conclusion of the hearing, the Hearing Officer shall prepare a written hearing report and recommended disposition. The report shall include a statement of the issues, findings of fact, and conclusions of law, as well as the reasons and basis therefor. Findings of fact shall be based exclusively upon all the material issues of fact and law presented in the record. The Director, License Division shall review the report and recommendation and make a final determination. S/he may approve the recommendation or modify the findings or the penalty consistent with the record. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-148768" number="89735" version="2819">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Licensees shall receive a copy of the Hearing Officer&apos;s report and the Director&apos;s final determination, by regular and/or electronic mail, within a reasonable time after the conclusion of the hearing. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78287" number="89736" version="2819">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 12/6/2024, eff. 1/5/2025) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-148767" number="89737" version="2819">
								<HEADING>§ 15-29 Penalties.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10373" name="T38C015_15-29"/>§ 15-29 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Penalties.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78288" number="89738" version="3">
									<PARA>Appropriate penalties may be imposed upon a licensee including suspension or revocation of the license.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78289" number="89739" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 15-30 Appeals. [Repealed]</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10375" name="T38C015_15-30"/>§ 15-30 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Appeals. [Repealed]</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>