<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-125279" number="106960" version="1958">
			<HEADING>Appendix A to Title 62: Criteria for the Location of City Facilities*</HEADING>
			<PARA>Appendix A to Title 62: Criteria for the Location of City Facilities*</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-105919" number="106961" version="1433">
				<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-20">* Adopted by the City Planning Commission on December 3, 1990 is the Criteria for the location of City Facilities. Set forth herein for the sake of convenient public access to such materials and in order to increase public familiarity and awareness of such rules, adoption of the rules is not governed by the City Administrative Procedure Act.</PARA>
			</RECORD>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-105939" number="106962" version="1433">
								<HEADING>Preface </HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
										<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15884" name="T62AppA_Preface"/>Preface</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105954" number="106963" version="1753">
									<PARA>These criteria are intended to guide the siting of city facilities, as provided by Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="203" destination-id="0-0-0-0">203</LINK> of the Charter. The fair distribution of city facilities will depend on balancing a number of factors, such as community needs for services, efficient and cost effective delivery of those services, effects on community stability and revitalization, and broad geographic distribution of facilities. Furthermore, these factors can be weighed more effectively, and siting decisions can be accepted more readily, when communities have been meaningfully informed and consulted early in the siting process. The intent of these guidelines is to improve, not to obstruct, the process of siting facilities.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105955" number="106964" version="1753">
									<PARA>Under the provisions of Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="204" destination-id="0-0-0-0">204</LINK> of the Charter, the Mayor will prepare an annual Statement of Needs in accordance with these criteria. The Statement of Needs will provide early notice of facility proposals to Borough Presidents, Community Boards, and the public at large. It will be accompanied by a map and text indicating the location and current use of all city properties and of state and federal facilities, as designated by the Charter. This will allow the public and city agencies to assess the existing distribution of facilities and analyze factors of compatibility and concentration. Section 204 also provides procedures for public review and comment on the Statement of Needs, permits Borough Presidents to propose locations for city facilities, and requires city agencies to consider the statements that ensue from that review. Those provisions, together with these criteria, should provide a more open and systematic process for the consideration of facility sites.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105956" number="106965" version="1753">
									<PARA>The criteria will have several applications in the Section 204 proceedings. The Mayor and city agencies will use them in formulating plans for facilities. Community Boards will refer to them in commenting on the Statement of Needs, and Borough Presidents will employ them in recommending specific sites for facilities. The City Planning Commission will consider them in acting on site selection and acquisition proposals subject to the Uniform Land Use Review Procedure (ULURP) and in the review of city office sites pursuant to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="195" destination-id="0-0-0-0">195</LINK> of the Charter. Sponsoring agencies will also observe them in actions that do not proceed through ULURP such as city contracts, facility reductions, and closings. Although recognizing that non-city agencies are not subject to these criteria, the Commission encourages all such agencies to consider the factors identified in these criteria when they are siting facilities in this city.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105957" number="106966" version="830">
									<PARA>Since the principles and procedures contained in these guidelines are new and untested, it is important to monitor and evaluate their effects. The Department of City Planning will undertake this evaluation and report its findings to the Commission and the Mayor within twenty-four months of adoption and periodically thereafter. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-105958" number="106967" version="1958">
								<HEADING>Article 1. Authority.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15886" name="T62AppA-Art1"/>Article 1. Authority.</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105959" number="106968" version="1753">
									<PARA>Pursuant to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="203" destination-id="0-0-0-0">203</LINK> of the Charter, the City Planning Commission is authorized to establish criteria for the location of new city facilities, the significant expansion of existing facilities, and the closing or significant reduction in size or service capacity of existing facilities.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-105961" number="106969" version="1958">
								<HEADING>Article 2. Purpose and Goals.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15888" name="T62AppA-Art2"/>Article 2. Purpose and Goals.</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105960" number="106970" version="830">
									<PARA>The purpose of these criteria is to foster neighborhood stability and revitalization by furthering the fair distribution among communities of city facilities. Toward this end, the city shall seek to:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105962" number="106971" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Site facilities equitably by balancing the considerations of community needs for services, efficient and cost-effective service delivery, and the social, economic, and environmental impacts of city facilities upon surrounding areas;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105963" number="106972" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Base its siting and service allocation proposals on the city&apos;s long-range policies and strategies, sound planning, zoning, budgetary principles, and local and citywide land use and service delivery plans;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105965" number="106973" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Expand public participation by creating an open and systematic planning process in which communities are fully informed, early in the process, of the city&apos;s specific criteria for determining the need for a given facility and its proposed location, the consequences of not taking the proposed action, and the alternatives for satisfying the identified need;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105964" number="106974" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Foster consensus building to avoid undue delay or conflict in siting facilities providing essential city services;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105966" number="106975" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Plan for the fair distribution among communities of facilities providing local or neighborhood services in accordance with relative needs among communities for those services;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105967" number="106976" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Lessen disparities among communities in the level of responsibility each bears for facilities serving citywide or regional needs;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105968" number="106977" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Preserve the social fabric of the city&apos;s diverse neighborhoods by avoiding undue concentrations of institutional uses in residential areas; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105969" number="106978" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Promote government accountability by fully considering all potential negative effects, mitigating them as much as possible, and monitoring neighborhood impacts of facilities once they are built.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-105970" number="106979" version="1958">
								<HEADING>Article 3. Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15890" name="T62AppA-Art3"/>Article 3. Definitions.</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105971" number="106980" version="830">
									<PARA>For purposes of these rules, the following definitions apply.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105972" number="106981" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>City facility: A facility providing city services whose location, expansion, closing or reduction in size is subject to control and supervision by a city agency, and which is:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105973" number="106982" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>operated by the city on property owned or leased by the city which is greater than 750 square feet in total floor area; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105921" number="106983" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>used primarily for a program or programs operated pursuant to a written agreement on behalf of the city which derives at least 50 percent and at least $50,000 of its annual funding from the city.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105974" number="106984" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>New facility: A city facility newly established as a result of an acquisition, lease, construction, or contractual action or the substantial change in use of an existing facility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105975" number="106985" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Residential facility: A city facility with sleeping accommodations which provides temporary or transitional housing, provides for pre-trial detention or custody of sentenced inmates, or provides a significant amount of on-site support services for residents with special needs for supervision, care, or treatment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105976" number="106986" version="1753">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Local or neighborhood facility: A city facility serving an area no larger than a community district or local service delivery district (pursuant to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="2704" destination-id="0-0-0-0">2704</LINK> of the Charter), in which the majority of persons served by the facility live or work (see Attachment A).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105977" number="106987" version="1753">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Regional or citywide facility: A facility which serves two or more community districts or local service delivery districts, an entire borough, or the city as a whole and which may be located in any of several different areas consistent with the specific criteria for that facility as described in the Citywide Statement of Needs pursuant to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="204" destination-id="0-0-0-0">204</LINK> of the Charter (see Attachment B).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105978" number="106988" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Significant expansion: An addition of real property by purchase, lease or interagency transfer, or construction of an enlargement, which would expand the lot area, floor area or capacity of a city facility by 25 percent or more and by at least 500 square feet. An expansion of less that 25 percent shall be deemed significant if it, together with expansions made in the prior three-year period, would expand the facility by 25 percent or more and by at least 500 square feet.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105979" number="106989" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Significant reduction: A surrender or discontinuance of the use of real property that would reduce the size or capacity to deliver service of a city facility by 25 percent or more. A reduction of less than 25 percent shall be deemed significant if it, together with reductions made in the prior three-year period, would reduce the facility by 25 percent or more.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-105980" number="106990" version="1958">
								<HEADING>Article 4. Criteria for Siting or Expanding Facilities.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15892" name="T62AppA-Art4"/>Article 4. Criteria for Siting or Expanding Facilities.</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105981" number="106991" version="830">
									<PARA>The following criteria and procedures apply to the siting of all new facilities other than administrative offices and data processing facilities ar.d the significant expansion of such facilities.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105922" number="106992" version="1753">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">4.1 </CHARFORMAT>The sponsoring agency and, for actions subject to the Uniform Land Use Review Procedure (ULURP) or review pursuant to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="195" destination-id="0-0-0-0">195</LINK> of the Charter, the City Planning Commission, shall consider the following criteria:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105982" number="106993" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Compatibility of the facility with existing facilities and programs, both city and non-city, in the immediate vicinity of the site.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105983" number="106994" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Extent to which neighborhood character would be adversely affected by a concentration of city and/or non-city facilities.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105984" number="106995" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Suitability of the site to provide cost-effective delivery of the intended services. Consideration of sites shall include properties not under city ownership, unless the agency provides a written explanation of why it is not reasonable to do so in this instance.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105985" number="106996" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Consistency with the locational and other specific criteria for the facility identified in the Statement of Needs or, if the facility is not listed in the Statement, in a subsequent submission to a Borough President.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105986" number="106997" version="1753">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Consistency with any plan adopted pursuant to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="197-a" destination-id="0-0-0-0">197-a</LINK> of the Charter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105989" number="106998" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">4.2</CHARFORMAT>&#160;<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Procedures for Consultation.</CHARFORMAT> In formulating its facility proposals, the sponsoring agency shall:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105990" number="106999" version="2184">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Consider the Mayor&apos;s and Borough President&apos;s strategic policy statements, the Community Board&apos;s Statement of District Needs and Budget Priorities, and any published Department of City Planning land use plan for the area.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105991" number="107000" version="2184">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Consider any comments received from the Community Boards or Borough Presidents and any alternative sites proposed by a Borough President pursuant to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="204" destination-id="0-0-0-0">204</LINK>(f) of the Charter, as well as any comments or recommendations received in any meetings, consultations or communications with the Community Boards or Borough Presidents. If the Statement of Needs has identified the community district where a proposed facility would be sited, then, upon the written request of the affected Community Board, the sponsoring agency should attend the Board&apos;s hearing on the Statement. If the community district is later identified, then the sponsoring agency shall at that point notify the Community Board and offer to meet with the board or its designee to discuss the proposed program.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-105987" number="107001" version="1958">
								<HEADING>Article 5. Criteria for Siting or Expanding Local/Neighborhood Facilities.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15894" name="T62AppA-Art5"/>Article 5. Criteria for Siting or Expanding Local/Neighborhood Facilities.</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105988" number="107002" version="830">
									<PARA>In addition to the criteria and procedures stated in Article 4, the following criteria and procedures apply to the siting of new local or neighborhood facilities other than administrative offices and data processing facilities, and the significant expansion of such facilities (see Attachment A).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105923" number="107003" version="1753">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">5.1 </CHARFORMAT>The sponsoring agency and, for actions subject to ULURP or review pursuant to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="195" destination-id="0-0-0-0">195</LINK> of the Charter, the City Planning Commission, shall consider the following criteria:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105992" number="107004" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Need for the facility or expansion in the community or local service delivery district. The sponsoring agency should prepare an analysis which identifies the conditions or characteristics that indicate need within a local area (e.g., infant mortality rates, facility utilization rates, emergency response time, parkland/population ratios) and which assesses relative needs among communities for the service provided by the facility. New or expanded facilities should, wherever possible, be located in areas with low ratios of service supply to service demand.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105993" number="107005" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Accessibility of the site to those it is intended to serve.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105924" number="107006" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">5.2 </CHARFORMAT>A Community Board may choose to designate or establish a committee to monitor selected local facilities after siting approval pursuant to these criteria. Following site selection and approval for such a facility, the sponsoring agency and Community Board shall jointly establish a mutually acceptable procedure by which the agency periodically reports to the committee regarding the plans and procedures that may affect the compatibility of the facility with the surrounding community and responds to community concerns.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-105994" number="107007" version="2497">
								<HEADING>Article 6. Criteria for Siting or Expanding Regional/Citywide Facilities.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15896" name="T62AppA-Art6"/>Article 6. Criteria for Siting or Expanding Regional/Citywide Facilities.</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105995" number="107008" version="830">
									<PARA>In addition to the criteria and procedures stated in Article 4, the following criteria and procedures apply to the siting of new regional and citywide facilities other than administrative offices and data processing facilities, and the significant expansion of such facilities (see Attachment B).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105925" number="107009" version="1753">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">6.1 </CHARFORMAT>The sponsoring agency and, for actions subject to ULURP or review pursuant to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="195" destination-id="0-0-0-0">195</LINK> of the Charter, the City Planning Commission, shall consider the following criteria:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105996" number="107010" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Need for the facility or expansion. Need shall be established in a citywide or borough-wide service plan or, as applicable, by inclusion in the city&apos;s ten-year capital strategy, four-year capital program, or other analyses of service needs.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105997" number="107011" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Distribution of similar facilities throughout the city. To promote the fair geographic distribution of facilities, the sponsoring agency should examine the distribution among the boroughs of existing and proposed facilities, both city and non-city, that provide similar services, in addition to the availability of appropriately zoned sites.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105998" number="107012" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Size of the facility. To lessen local impacts and increase broad distribution of facilities, the new facility or expansion should not exceed the minimum size necessary to achieve efficient and cost-effective delivery of services to meet existing and projected needs.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105999" number="107013" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Adequacy of the streets and transit to handle the volume and frequency of traffic generated by the facility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105926" number="107014" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">6.2 </CHARFORMAT>Where practicable, the Mayor may initiate and sponsor a consensus building process to determine the location of a proposed regional facility. A Borough President may submit a written request for such a process if the request is made within 90 days of publication of the Statement of Needs or, if the facility is not listed in the Statement, within 30 days of a subsequent submission to the Borough President.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106000" number="107015" version="830">
									<PARA>In the consensus building process, representatives of affected interests will convene to assess potential sites in accordance with these criteria and the specific criteria set forth in the Statement of Needs. The participants may include but need not be limited to representatives of the Mayor, the sponsoring agency, the Borough President(s), and the affected Community Board(s). The participants may review any issue relevant to site selection under these criteria. The process shall be completed within a reasonable time period to be determined by the Mayor. If location of the facility is subject to ULURP, the process shall be completed prior to submission of a ULURP application. If the participants (including the sponsoring agency) reach consensus, the agency will submit whatever agreements were reached regarding the facility and site to the City Planning Commission as part of its ULURP application for the site. If no such consensus is reached, the sponsoring agency may initiate ULURP, if applicable, for its proposed site.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105927" number="107016" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">6.3 </CHARFORMAT>Upon the request of the Borough President and/or Community Board, a sponsoring agency and Community Board shall establish a facility monitoring committee, or designate an existing Community Board committee, to monitor a facility following selection and approval of its site. The agency shall inform the committee of plans and procedures that may affect the compatibility of the facility with the surrounding community. Once the facility is constructed, the sponsoring agency shall meet with the committee according to a schedule established by the committee and agency to report on the status of those plans and procedures and to respond to community concerns. The committee may also submit reports to the agency head addressing outstanding issues. The agency head shall respond to the committee&apos;s report within 45 days and shall identify the actions, if any, that the agency plans in response to such concerns.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105928" number="107017" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">6.4 </CHARFORMAT>Transportation and Waste Management Facilities. Transportation and waste management facilities (see Attachment B) are subject to the following criteria in addition to those stated in Article 4 and Sections 6.1, 6.2, and 6.3.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105929" number="107018" version="1753">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.41 </CHARFORMAT>The proposed site should be optimally located to promote effective service delivery in that any alternative site actively considered by the sponsoring agency or identified pursuant to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="204" destination-id="0-0-0-0">204</LINK>(f) of the Charter would add significantly to the cost of constructing or operating the facility or would significantly impair effective service delivery.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105930" number="107019" version="1433">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.42 </CHARFORMAT>In order to avoid aggregate noise, odor, or air quality impacts on adjacent residential areas, the sponsoring agency and the City Planning Commission, in its review of the proposal, shall take into consideration the number and proximity of existing city and non-city facilities, situated within approximately a one-half mile radius of the proposed site, which have similar environmental impacts.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105931" number="107020" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">6.5 </CHARFORMAT>Residential Facilities. Regional or citywide residential facilities (see Attachment B) are subject to the following criteria in addition to those stated in Article 4 and Sections 6.1, 6.2, and 6.3.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105932" number="107021" version="1433">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.51 </CHARFORMAT>Undue concentration or clustering of city and non-city facilities providing similar services or serving a similar population should be avoided in residential areas.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105933" number="107022" version="1433">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.52 </CHARFORMAT>Necessary support services for the facility and its residents should be available or provided.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105934" number="107023" version="2494">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>6.53 </CHARFORMAT>In community districts with a high ratio of residential facility beds to population, the proposed siting shall be subject to the following additional considerations:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106001" number="107024" version="1433">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whether the facility, in combination with other similar city and non-city facilities within a defined area surrounding the site (approximately a half-mile radius, adjusted for significant physical boundaries), would have a significant cumulative negative impact on neighborhood character.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106002" number="107025" version="1433">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whether the site is well located for efficient service delivery.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106003" number="107026" version="1753">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whether any alternative sites actively considered by the sponsoring agency or identified pursuant to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="204" destination-id="0-0-0-0">204</LINK>(f) of the Charter which are in community districts with lower ratios of residential facility beds to population than the citywide average would add significantly to the cost of constructing or operating the facility or would impair service delivery.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106004" number="107027" version="830">
									<PARA>To facilitate this evaluation, the Department of City Planning will publish annually an index of the number of beds per thousand population, by type of residential facility (as set forth in Appendix C) and overall, in each community district. The index will be based upon the number of beds in all city, state, federal, and private facilities in operation or approved for operation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-106005" number="107028" version="1958">
								<HEADING>Article 7. Criteria for Siting or Expanding Administrative Offices and Data Processing Facilities.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15898" name="T62AppA-Art7"/>Article 7. Criteria for Siting or Expanding Administrative Offices and Data Processing Facilities.</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106006" number="107029" version="1753">
									<PARA>The following criteria apply to the siting of new city administrative offices and data processing facilities and the significant expansion of such facilities, pursuant to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="195" destination-id="0-0-0-0">195</LINK> of the City Charter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105935" number="107030" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">7.1 </CHARFORMAT>The sponsoring agency and the City Planning Commission shall consider the following criteria:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106007" number="107031" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Suitability of the site to provide cost-effective operations.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106008" number="107032" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Suitability of the site for operational efficiency, taking into consideration its accessibility to staff, the public and/or other sectors of city government.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106009" number="107033" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Consistency with the locational and other specific criteria for the facility stated in the Statement of Needs.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106010" number="107034" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whether the facility can be located so as to support development and revitalization of the city&apos;s regional business districts without constraining operational efficiency.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-106011" number="107035" version="1958">
								<HEADING>Article 8. Criteria for Closing or Reducing Facilities.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15900" name="T62AppA-Art8"/>Article 8. Criteria for Closing or Reducing Facilities.</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106012" number="107036" version="830">
									<PARA>The following criteria and procedures apply to the closing of existing facilities and the significant reduction in size or capacity to deliver service of existing facilities.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105936" number="107037" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">8.1 </CHARFORMAT>The sponsoring agency shall consider the following criteria:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106013" number="107038" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The extent to which the closing or reduction would create or significantly increase any existing imbalance among communities of service levels relative to need. Wherever possible, such actions should be proposed for areas with high ratios of service supply to service demand.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106014" number="107039" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Consistency with the specific criteria for selecting the facility for closure or reduction as identified in the Statement of Needs.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-105938" number="107040" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">8.2 </CHARFORMAT>In proposing facility closings or reductions, the sponsoring agency shall consult with the affected Community Board(s) and Borough President about the alternatives within the district or borough, if any, for achieving the planned reduction and the measures to be taken to ensure adequate levels of service.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-106015" number="107041" version="2298">
								<HEADING>Article 9. Actions not Subject to the Uniform Land Use Review Procedure or Section 195.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15902" name="T62AppA-Art9"/>Article 9. Actions not Subject to the Uniform Land Use Review Procedure or Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="195" destination-id="0-0-0-0">195</LINK>.</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106016" number="107042" version="1753">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">9.1 </CHARFORMAT>Whenever an agency takes an action with respect to a city facility that is subject to these criteria but is not subject to ULURP or to Charter Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="195" destination-id="0-0-0-0">195</LINK> review, the agency shall submit a statement to the Mayor, with copies to the affected Community Board(s), Borough President, and Department of City Planning, which describes the agency&apos;s consideration and application of the relevant sections of these criteria, and states the reasons for any inconsistencies.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-106018" number="107043" version="1433">
								<HEADING>Attachment A</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15904" name="T62AppA-AttA"/>Attachment A</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-114334" number="107044" version="1433">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Local / Neighborhood Facilities*</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106025" number="107045" version="830">
									<PARA>Branch libraries</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106019" number="107046" version="830">
									<PARA>Community cultural programs</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106020" number="107047" version="830">
									<PARA>Community health/mental health services</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106021" number="107048" version="830">
									<PARA>Community-based social programs</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106022" number="107049" version="830">
									<PARA>Day care centers</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106023" number="107050" version="830">
									<PARA>Drop-off recycling centers</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106024" number="107051" version="830">
									<PARA>Employment centers</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106026" number="107052" version="830">
									<PARA>Fire stations</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106027" number="107053" version="830">
									<PARA>Local, non-residential drug prevention and/or treatment centers</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106028" number="107054" version="830">
									<PARA>Local parks</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106029" number="107055" version="830">
									<PARA>Parking lots/garages</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106030" number="107056" version="830">
									<PARA>Police precincts</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106031" number="107057" version="830">
									<PARA>Sanitation garages</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106032" number="107058" version="830">
									<PARA>Senior centers </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106033" number="107059" version="830">
									<PARA>* List is illustrative and should not be considered to include all such facilities.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-106035" number="107060" version="1958">
								<HEADING>Attachment B</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15906" name="T62AppA-AttB"/>Attachment B</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-114335" number="107061" version="1433">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Regional / Citywide Facilities:*</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106036" number="107062" version="830">
									<PARA>Administrative offices</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106037" number="107063" version="830">
									<PARA>Courts</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106038" number="107064" version="830">
									<PARA>Data processing facilities</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106039" number="107065" version="830">
									<PARA>Department of Health centers</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106040" number="107066" version="830">
									<PARA>Income maintenance centers</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106041" number="107067" version="830">
									<PARA>Maintenance/storage facilities</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106042" number="107068" version="830">
									<PARA>Museums, zoos, performance centers, galleries and gardens</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106043" number="107069" version="830">
									<PARA>Regional, non-residential drug prevention and/or treatment centers</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106044" number="107070" version="830">
									<PARA>Regional parks</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106045" number="107071" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Transportation and Waste Management Facilities:</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106046" number="107072" version="830">
									<PARA>Airports, heliports</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106047" number="107073" version="830">
									<PARA>Ferry terminals</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106048" number="107074" version="830">
									<PARA>Sewage treatment plants</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106049" number="107075" version="830">
									<PARA>Sludge management and transfer facilities</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106050" number="107076" version="830">
									<PARA>Solid waste transfer and recycling facilities</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106051" number="107077" version="830">
									<PARA>Solid waste landfills</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106052" number="107078" version="830">
									<PARA>Solid waste incinerators, resource recovery plants</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106053" number="107079" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Residential Facilities:</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106054" number="107080" version="830">
									<PARA>Group homes/halfway houses</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106055" number="107081" version="830">
									<PARA>Hospices</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106056" number="107082" version="830">
									<PARA>Nursing homes/health-related facilities</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106057" number="107083" version="830">
									<PARA>Prisons, jails, detention, remand facilities</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106058" number="107084" version="830">
									<PARA>Residential facilities for children</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106059" number="107085" version="830">
									<PARA>Residential substance abuse facilities</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106060" number="107086" version="830">
									<PARA>Secure and non-secure detention facilities for children</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106061" number="107087" version="830">
									<PARA>Supported housing for people with mental health or physical problems</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106062" number="107088" version="830">
									<PARA>Temporary housing</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106063" number="107089" version="830">
									<PARA>Transitional housing</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106064" number="107090" version="830">
									<PARA>* List is illustrative and should not be considered to include all such facilities.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-106065" number="107091" version="1433">
								<HEADING>Attachment C</HEADING>
								<PARA>Attachment C</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106066" number="107092" version="1433">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Types of Residential Facilities (as referenced in Section 6.53)</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">*</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106067" number="107093" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Correctional facilities, including prisons, jails, detention and remand facilities, and secure detention for children</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106068" number="107094" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nursing homes and health-related facilities, including hospices</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106069" number="107095" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Small residential care facilities and temporary housing facilities, serving no more than 25 people, including group homes, halfway houses, residential facilities for children, residential substance abuse and mental health/retardation facilities, supported housing, shelters, temporary and transitional housing, non-secure detention for children</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106070" number="107096" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Large temporary and transitional housing facilities, providing shelter or transitional housing for more than 25 people</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106071" number="107097" version="830">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Large residential care facilities, serving more than 25 people, including halfway houses, residential facilities for children, homes for adults, residential substance abuse and mental health/retardation facilities, supported housing, psychiatric centers</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-106072" number="107098" version="830">
									<PARA>* Lists by type are illustrative and should not be considered to include all such facilities.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>