<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-40702" number="48127" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 38: Conciliation Bureau</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5553" name="T19C038"/>Chapter 38: Conciliation Bureau</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40703" number="48128" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 38-01 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5555" name="T19C038_38-01"/>§ 38-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40704" number="48129" version="748">
									<PARA>Unless the context of these rules requires otherwise, the definitions contained in this section apply. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40705" number="48130" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Code. </CHARFORMAT>The term &quot;code&quot; means the Administrative Code of the City of New York. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40706" number="48131" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Commissioner.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;commissioner&quot; means the New York City Commissioner of Finance. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40707" number="48132" version="2472">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Conciliation bureau.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;conciliation bureau&quot; means that the Bureau within the department that is responsible for providing conciliation conferences and issuing conciliation decisions. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40708" number="48133" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Conciliation decision.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;conciliation decision&quot; means the final order issued by the director of the conciliation bureau discontinuing conciliation with regard to one or more issues. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40709" number="48134" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Conciliation proceeding.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;conciliation proceeding&quot; means the proceeding conducted by the conciliation bureau, which shall commence with the filing of a timely request for conciliation and conclude with an executed consent and waiver or the issuance of a conciliation decision. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40710" number="48135" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Conciliator. </CHARFORMAT>The term &quot;conciliator&quot; means any person duly designated and authorized by the commissioner to conduct conciliation conferences. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40711" number="48136" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Department.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;department&quot; means the New York City Department of Finance. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40712" number="48137" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Domestic partner.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;domestic partner&quot; means a person who has registered a domestic partnership in accordance with applicable law with the City Clerk, or has registered such partnership with the former City Department of Personnel pursuant to Executive Order 123 (dated August 7, 1989) during the period August 7, 1989 through January 7, 1993. (The records of domestic partnerships registered at the former City Department of Personnel have been transferred to the City Clerk.) </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40713" number="48138" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Operating division. </CHARFORMAT>The term &quot;operating division&quot; means that division or bureau within the department responsible for the particular action or actions being protested. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40714" number="48139" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Party.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;party&quot; means either the person on whose behalf the request for conciliation is filed, an authorized representative of such person,or the operating division. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40715" number="48140" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Person.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;person&quot; includes, but is not limited to, an individual, partnership, society, association, joint stock company, corporation, estate, receiver, trustee, assignee, referee, any other individual or entity acting in a fiduciary or representative capacity and any combination of the foregoing, other than the conciliation bureau or the department. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40716" number="48141" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Petition</CHARFORMAT>. The term &quot;petition&quot; includes an &quot;application for hearing,&quot; &quot;petition for hearing,&quot; &quot;demand for hearing&quot; or any variation of such terms as used in the applicable sections of the Code for a form requesting a formal hearing before the tribunal. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40717" number="48142" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Request for conciliation.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;request for conciliation&quot; means the written application or request for a conciliation proceeding. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40718" number="48143" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Requestor. </CHARFORMAT>The term &quot;requestor&quot; means the person on whose behalf conciliation is requested and, except for purposes of 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C038_38-03" destination-id="0-0-0-5559">38-03</LINK>, any person authorized to represent such person at conciliation. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40719" number="48144" version="1845">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Statutory notice.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;statutory notice&quot; means any written notice of the commissioner that gives a person the right to a hearing in the tribunal, including but not limited to a notice of determination of tax due, of a tax deficiency, of a denial of a refund or a credit application or of the refusal to grant, the suspension of, or the revocation of, a license. For the purposes of this definition, if the commissioner fails to act with respect to a refund application before the expiration of the time period after which the taxpayer may file a petition for refund with the tribunal pursuant to § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-529" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-529</LINK>(c) or § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-680" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-680</LINK>(3) of the Code, such failure shall be deemed to be a notice of denial of a refund. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40720" number="48145" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Tribunal.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;tribunal&quot; means the New York City Tax Appeals Tribunal.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40721" number="48146" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 38-02 Establishment of Conciliation Bureau and Delegation of Authority.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5557" name="T19C038_38-02"/>§ 38-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Establishment of Conciliation Bureau and Delegation of Authority.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40722" number="48147" version="3">
									<PARA>There shall be within the department a conciliation bureau which shall be headed by a director. This bureau shall function independently from other operating divisions in order to resolve controversies with the department and shall report directly to the commissioner. The director shall exercise all powers and perform all functions of the conciliation bureau under the Code and these rules. The director of the conciliation bureau may designate other persons to act on his or her behalf.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40723" number="48148" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 38-03 Representation of Requestor.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5559" name="T19C038_38-03"/>§ 38-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Representation of Requestor.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40724" number="48149" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Personal appearance.</CHARFORMAT> An individual on whose behalf a conciliation conference is requested may appear and represent himself or herself or may be represented by his or her spouse, domestic partner, parent or child. A partnership may act through one of its general partners without filing a power of attorney, provided written evidence of such designation is presented. When a corporation requests a conciliation conference, it may act through one of its duly authorized officers or employees. When the corporation acts through an employee who is not a duly authorized officer, a power of attorney executed by a duly authorized officer of the corporation must be filed.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40725" number="48150" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Representation by others.</CHARFORMAT> Any of the following may act as the representative of a requestor, if authorized by a proper power of attorney signed by the requestor and filed with the conciliation bureau before or concurrently with such representation:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40726" number="48151" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>an attorney-at-law admitted to practice in any jurisdiction of the United States;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40727" number="48152" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a certified public accountant duly qualified to practice in any jurisdiction of the United States;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40728" number="48153" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a public accountant duly qualified in any jurisdiction of the United States; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40729" number="48154" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>an agent enrolled to practice before the Internal Revenue Service.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40730" number="48155" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Minors and individuals under disability. If the requestor is under 18 years of age, the adult spouse, parent or guardian of the requestor, or the person who prepared the requestor&apos;s return, may request a conciliation proceeding and appear on the requestor&apos;s behalf without filing a power of attorney. If the requestor is mentally or physically incapable of requesting a conciliation proceeding or appearing on his or her own behalf, a court-appointed representative may request a conciliation proceeding, or appear on behalf of said individual without filing a power of attorney. An emancipated minor may request a conciliation proceeding and appear on his or her own behalf. Anyone who may represent a requestor pursuant to this subdivision may also authorize representation by by a person who meets the requirements of subdivision (b) or (d) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40731" number="48156" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Representation by permission of director.</CHARFORMAT> Any other individual may appear and represent a requestor for a particular matter by special permission of the director of the conciliation bureau or the director&apos;s designee. A request for such permission shall be made in writing to the conciliation bureau.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40732" number="48157" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Other representation forbidden.</CHARFORMAT> No person other than one authorized in the foregoing subdivisions of this section may represent a requestor in any conciliation proceeding.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40733" number="48158" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 38-04 Request for Conciliation Proceeding.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5561" name="T19C038_38-04"/>§ 38-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Request for Conciliation Proceeding.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40734" number="48159" version="2472">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Filing of conciliation request.</CHARFORMAT> Any person who has the right to file a petition for a hearing from a statutory notice may request conciliation. A request for conciliation may be made by filing a written request and one copy thereof, with the conciliation bureau. The request should be typewritten,if possible, and should include the information set forth in paragraph (1) of subdivision (b) of this section. The request may be made on a Request for Conciliation form.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40735" number="48160" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Form of conciliation request.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40736" number="48161" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The request should contain:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40737" number="48162" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the name, address, and taxpayer identification number (employer identification number or social security number) of the person on whose behalf the request is made;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40738" number="48163" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the name, address and taxpayer identification number of such person&apos;s representative, if applicable;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40739" number="48164" version="2472">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the taxable years or periods involved and the amount and type of the tax in question;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40740" number="48165" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the action or actions of the operating division being protested;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40741" number="48166" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the facts, law or reasons that the requestor asserts are relevant to the controversy;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40742" number="48167" version="1846">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vi)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a signed acknowledgement by the requestor that the request is made with knowledge that a willfully false representation is a misdemeanor punishable under § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-4004" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-4004</LINK> of the Code;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40743" number="48168" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a legible copy of the statutory notice being protested; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40744" number="48169" version="1119">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(viii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>if required pursuant to 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C038_38-03" destination-id="0-0-0-5559">38-03</LINK>, an original power of attorney or a legible copy of a power of attorney previously submitted to the department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40745" number="48170" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>At any time during the conciliation proceeding, the conciliator may ask the requestor to supply additional information in order to properly process the request and resolve the issues raised in the request.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40746" number="48171" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Time limitations.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40747" number="48172" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A request for conciliation must be filed within the statutory period for filing a petition.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40748" number="48173" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The filing of a timely request for conciliation will suspend the running of the period for filing a petition. The filing of a request for conciliation does not suspend the accrual of any amount that may be due as an additional to tax, interest or penalty on any amount of tax finally determined to be due.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40749" number="48174" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Referral from tribunal. </CHARFORMAT>Where a petition has been timely filed, and where a conciliation conference has not been conducted prior to the filing of such petition, the tribunal may, at the request of the petitioner and with the consent of the commissioner, suspend action on the petition and refer the matter to the conciliation bureau. In the case of a referral by the tribunal, all of these rules shall apply except that the effect of any conciliation decision discontinuing conciliation shall be to reinstate the petition with regard to any issues not resolved at conciliation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40750" number="48175" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 38-05 Conciliation Conference and Review of Request.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5563" name="T19C038_38-05"/>§ 38-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Conciliation Conference and Review of Request.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40751" number="48176" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Acknowledgement of receipt of request and review of documents.</CHARFORMAT> The conciliation bureau shall acknowledge the receipt of a request and seek any additional information necessary to process the request. The request and other documents concerning the controversy shall then be reviewed to ascertain that the request is timely filed and is complete. Where the review indicates that the request is not timely filed, the director of the conciliation bureau shall dismiss the request. Such dismissal shall not constitute a conciliation decision giving the requestor 90 days to file a petition.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40752" number="48177" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Notice of conciliation conference; location; attendance requirements.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40753" number="48178" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A conciliation conference will be scheduled at the office of the conciliation bureau. Written notice of the time and place of the opening of the first conciliation conference shall be mailed to all parties at least 30 days prior to the date of such conference. Written notice of the time and place of any adjourned or continued conciliation shall be mailed at least ten days prior to the date of such adjourned or continued conference unless all parties agree to reconvene within a shorter period of time.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40754" number="48179" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The conciliator may grant an adjournment where good cause is shown upon receipt of a written request for adjournment at least five days in advance of the scheduled conciliation conference date. In the event of an emergency, an adjournment may be granted on less notice.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40755" number="48180" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where a requestor fails to appear and where an adjournment has not been granted, the director of the conciliation bureau may issue a conciliation decision discontinuing conciliation. If within 30 calendar days after service on the requestor of a conciliation decision discontinuing conciliation for failure to appear, the requestor files a written application with the conciliation bureau showing a reasonable excuse for the failure to appear and requesting that the conciliation conference be reopened, then such decision may be withdrawn and a conciliation conference rescheduled at the discretion of the conciliator. Unless such decision is withdrawn, the 90 day period to file a petition commences from the service of the conciliation decision and is not extended by the request to reopen.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40756" number="48181" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Conciliation scope and procedure.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40757" number="48182" version="2472">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Conciliation is intended to provide the parties with an opportunity to resolve disagreements. With the cooperation of the parties, the conciliator will endeavor to develop those facts and issues on which there is no disagreement and those facts and issues that are in dispute. The goal of conciliation is, in whole or in part, to resolve the controversy between the parties within the framework of the Code, thereby narrowing the scope of, or eliminating the need for, a hearing at the tribunal. The conciliator shall conduct the conciliation conference in an informal manner and shall hear or receive statements and documentation deemed necessary or desirable for a just and equitable result. To accomplish the expeditious resolution of controversies, the conciliator may waive or modify penalties and additions to tax in accordance with the commissioner&apos;s authority to waive or modify penalties and additions to tax under the Code. At the request of the conciliator or the operating division, a representative of the operating division may appear and participate in the conciliation proceeding.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40758" number="48183" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>After reviewing the statements, documentation and comments, the conciliator will serve on the requestor a proposed resolution, incorporating a consent and waiver. In developing the proposed resolution, the conciliator may contact any party to clarify any issues or facts in dispute. Notice of any such contact, including the nature of any matter discussed and an opportunity to comment, shall be provided to all parties. The proposed resolution may provide for the full or partial resolution of the case including, but not limited to, revising the amounts of deficiencies or refunds specified in the statutory notice, or withdrawing or adhering to the statutory notice.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40759" number="48184" version="2472">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The requestor shall have 15 days following service of the proposed resolution to execute and return the consent and waiver agreeing in all respects to the terms of the proposed resolution and waiving the right to a hearing on any issue resolved by the proposed resolution. Such consent and waiver executed by a requestor shall be a determination of the commissioner as to those issues resolved by a proposed resolution fixing the amount of tax due or the amount of any refund owed. In the absence of a showing of fraud, malfeasance or misrepresentation of a material fact, the executed consent and waiver shall be binding on all parties with regard to all issues that it resolves. Upon receipt of an executed consent and waiver that is a partial resolution of a case at conciliation, the director of the conciliation bureau shall issue a conciliation decision discontinuing conciliation for those issues not resolved.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40760" number="48185" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where the requestor fails to execute and return the consent and waiver as in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph within 15 days, the proposed resolution may be deemed withdrawn and the director of the conciliation bureau will issue a conciliation decision discontinuing conciliation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40761" number="48186" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Conciliation decisions and proposed resolutions shall not be published. Such decisions and resolutions shall not be considered precedent, nor shall they be given any force or effect in any subsequent proceeding with respect to the requestor or any other person.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40762" number="48187" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the executed consent and waiver provides for a refund, the case will be forwarded to the Miscellaneous Refunds Unit to process and issue the refund.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40763" number="48188" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 38-06 Request for Discontinuance.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5565" name="T19C038_38-06"/>§ 38-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Request for Discontinuance.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40764" number="48189" version="3">
									<PARA>At any time before the conclusion of conciliation, the requestor may serve on the conciliation bureau a written request for discontinuance. Once a request for discontinuance has been served, the director of the conciliation bureau shall issue and serve a conciliation decision confirming discontinuance of conciliation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40765" number="48190" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 38-07 Effect of Conciliation Decision.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5567" name="T19C038_38-07"/>§ 38-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Effect of Conciliation Decision.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40766" number="48191" version="1119">
									<PARA>The service of a conciliation decision discontinuing conciliation shall start the running of the 90 day period for filing a petition, or shall reinstate any previously filed petition as provided in 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C038_38-04" destination-id="0-0-0-5561">38-04</LINK>(d), with regard to all issues not resolved at conciliation. A conciliation decision shall be served on the requestor and a copy thereof shall be mailed to the tribunal.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40767" number="48192" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 38-08 Miscellaneous Provisions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5569" name="T19C038_38-08"/>§ 38-08 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Miscellaneous Provisions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40768" number="48193" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Service.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40769" number="48194" version="2472">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Service of all requests and filing of other papers with the conciliation bureau shall be made either by delivery to its office during office hours, or by mail properly addressed to such office. Where service or filing is made by mail, the date of service or filing is the date specified in 19 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C017" destination-id="0-0-0-5229">Chapter 17</LINK>. Where service or filing is made by courier, delivery, messenger or similar services, the date of service or filing is the date of receipt.Subject to paragraph (2) of this subdivision, service on parties can be made in the same manner and the same rules regarding date of service or filing shall apply.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40770" number="48195" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Service of conciliation decisions shall be made by hand delivery or by registered or certified mail.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40771" number="48196" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the last day prescribed by any section of these rules for service of a request or filing of other papers with the conciliation bureau or performing any other act falls on a Saturday, Sunday or legal holiday in the State of New York, such service, filing or act shall be considered timely if it is performed on the next succeeding day that is not a Saturday, Sunday or legal holiday.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40772" number="48197" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Extension of time.</CHARFORMAT> The conciliation bureau may for good cause, on its own or at the request of any party, grant a continuance, adjournment, or extension of time, other than the extension of time for filing the request for conciliation, provided no statutory prohibition exists. Notice of any such action shall be given to all parties.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>