<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-80918" number="93375" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 3: Fees</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10777" name="T42C003"/>Chapter 3: Fees</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-80919" number="93376" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 3-01 Probation Administrative Fee.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10779" name="T42C003_3-01"/>§ 3-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Probation Administrative Fee.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80920" number="93377" version="1878">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">General.</CHARFORMAT> Pursuant to § 257-c of the Executive Law and § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="9-201" destination-id="0-0-0-0">9-201</LINK> of the Administrative Code of the City of New York, any individual currently serving or who shall be sentenced to a period of probation in New York City upon conviction of any crime under article thirty-one of the Vehicle and Traffic Law shall pay an administrative fee of thirty dollars per month to the New York City Department of Probation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80921" number="93378" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Collection of the Probation Administrative Fee.</CHARFORMAT> The probation administrative fee shall be paid on the first of every month, commencing on November 1, 2010. The fee shall be payable by money order, certified check or cashier&apos;s check made out to the New York City Department of Probation or any electronic, credit card or debit card payment method that the New York City Department of Probation develops the capacity to accept. The probationer shall include his or her case name and case number on the money order or check. The fee shall be sent to:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80922" number="93379" version="3">
									<PARA>New York City Department of Probation <LINEBRK/>33 Beaver Street, 21st Floor <LINEBRK/>New York, New York 10004 <LINEBRK/>Attn: Financial Operations </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80923" number="93380" version="2513">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Enforcement.</CHARFORMAT> Failure to pay the probation administrative fee in full, unless the fee has been waived pursuant to subdivision d of this section, shall subject the probationer to collection pursuant to all applicable laws.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80924" number="93381" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Waiver.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80925" number="93382" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in this subdivision, the following terms shall have the following meanings:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80926" number="93383" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Department.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Department&quot; means the Department of Probation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80927" number="93384" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Dependent.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Dependent&quot; means a person who resides in the probationer&apos;s household and has any of the following relationships with the probationer:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80928" number="93385" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Husband, wife, or registered domestic partner;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80929" number="93386" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Minor child of the probationer or sibling of the minor child who is also a minor child (including half and step-siblings); or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80930" number="93387" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Non-minor child of the probationer or a descendant of such a child, brother or sister of the probationer or his or her descendant, or parent or grandparent of the probationer:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80931" number="93388" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>whose income is less than $3650 and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80932" number="93389" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>with respect to whom the probationer provides over one half of the individual&apos;s support for the calendar year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80933" number="93390" version="848">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Federal Poverty Guidelines.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Federal Poverty Guidelines&quot; are the annual guidelines prepared by the United States Department of Health and Human Services and published in the Federal Register. The Federal Poverty Guidelines are available at<LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url=" http://aspe.hhs.gov/poverty/"> http://aspe.hhs.gov/poverty/</LINK>. These guidelines are based on household income and number of dependents.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80934" number="93391" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Income.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Income&quot; means all income before taxes and other deductions. Income shall include but not be limited to wages, salary, tips from work, self-employment income (after business expenses), unemployment compensation, workers&apos; compensation, Social Security, Supplemental Security Income, public assistance, veterans&apos; payments, survivor benefits, pension or retirement income, interest, dividends, rents, royalties, income from estates or trusts, alimony, child support, and assistance from outside the household.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80935" number="93392" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Minor child.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Minor child&quot; is a child who is under eighteen years of age or is under nineteen years of age and attending a secondary school (high school) or an equivalent level of vocational or technical training.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80936" number="93393" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eligibility.</CHARFORMAT> The Department shall grant a temporary waiver of all of the probation administrative fee when a probationer has provided proof that (i) his or her combined household income is less than 200% of the Federal Poverty Guidelines or (ii) there exist additional financial circumstances that would render the probationer indigent, such that the payment of the administrative fee would work an unreasonable hardship on the probationer, his or her immediate family, or any other person who is dependent on such person for financial support.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80937" number="93394" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80938" number="93395" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A probationer applying for a waiver or the renewal of a waiver shall mail a signed and dated &quot;Request for Temporary Waiver&quot; form, including an explanation of any additional financial circumstances that would render the probationer indigent, to the address below: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80939" number="93396" version="3">
									<PARA>New York City Department of Probation <LINEBRK/>33 Beaver Street, 23rd Floor <LINEBRK/>New York, New York 10004. <LINEBRK/>Attn: &quot;DWI Fee Review Officer&quot;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80940" number="93397" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The probationer shall attach proof of income and proof of dependants with the &quot;Request for Temporary Waiver&quot; form.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80941" number="93398" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Proof of income shall include but not be limited to all of the following documentation that are applicable: income tax returns, paystubs, pay checks, public assistance, Supplementary Security Income, Social Security Disability, unemployment benefits, workers&apos; compensation, veteran payments, and pension or retirement income.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80942" number="93399" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Proof of dependents shall include but not be limited to any of the following documentation: birth certificate, letters or certificates of guardianship, marriage certificate, and domestic partner registration certificate.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80943" number="93400" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department determinations. </CHARFORMAT>The Department shall review the application and determine whether to issue a waiver or to return the application with a request for further documentation. If the Department denies the application for a waiver, written notice shall be mailed or sent electronically to the probationer at the address in the Department&apos;s records informing the probationer of the reasons for denial and of the probationer&apos;s right to appeal the determination in writing within fifteen calendar days of the date of the notice. The commissioner or his or her designee shall review the probationer&apos;s written appeal and shall issue a determination, which shall be final.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80944" number="93401" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Duration of waiver.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80945" number="93402" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A waiver shall remain in effect for one year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80946" number="93403" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A probationer who has been granted a waiver shall inform the Department of Probation immediately upon a change of his or her circumstances affecting the probationer&apos;s eligibility for the waiver.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80947" number="93404" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Department may terminate the waiver upon a determination that the probationer is no longer eligible for the waiver. Written notice of the proposed termination shall be mailed or sent electronically to the probationer at the address in the Department&apos;s records and shall inform the probationer of the reasons for the proposed termination and that the probationer has the right to appeal the determination in writing with fifteen calendar days of the date of notice. The commissioner or his or her designee shall review the probationer&apos;s written appeal and shall issue a determination, which shall be final.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80948" number="93405" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A probationer may apply to renew a waiver by submitting an application as provided in paragraph 3 of this subdivision.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>