<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-41337" number="48950" version="1960">
			<HEADING>Chapter 48: Rules Relating to the Biotechnology Credit Against Unincorporated Business Tax and General Corporation Tax</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5679" name="T19C048"/>Chapter 48: Rules Relating to the Biotechnology Credit Against Unincorporated Business Tax and General Corporation Tax</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-41338" number="48951" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 48-01 Purpose and Scope of Rules.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5681" name="T19C048_48-01"/>§ 48-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Purpose and Scope of Rules.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41339" number="48952" version="3">
									<PARA>The purpose of these rules is to set forth the application and credit allocation process for the New York City biotechnology credit to be applied against New York City unincorporated business tax and general corporation tax. The Tax Law authorizes the New York City Department of Finance to promulgate rules to establish procedures for the allocation of such credits including, but not limited to, the application process, due dates for applications, the standards to be used for evaluating applications, documentation that will be provided to taxpayers to substantiate the amount of tax credits allocated to such taxpayers and any other provisions deemed necessary and appropriate. Although much of the law that established the New York City biotechnology credit is substantially identical to the law that established the New York State Qualified Emerging Technologies Facilities, Operations and Training Credit, these rules only apply to determination and implementation of the New York City credit. For purposes of this chapter, &quot;credit&quot; shall mean the New York City biotechnology credit.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-41340" number="48953" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 48-02 Application Procedure.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5683" name="T19C048_48-02"/>§ 48-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application Procedure.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41341" number="48954" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An applicant for the credit must submit an application on a form or in a format established by the Commissioner of Finance (&quot;Commissioner&quot;) to the Department of Finance (&quot;Department&quot;) no later than January 15 in the calendar year that immediately follows the calendar year for which the credit is sought.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41342" number="48955" version="1119">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Department shall make a determination on the application based upon the applicable provisions of State and local law and the criteria set forth in 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C048_48-03" destination-id="0-0-0-5685">48-03</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41343" number="48956" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Department may request additional documentation to support representations made in any credit application, including, but not limited to, copies of tax returns and financial statements.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41344" number="48957" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any application is approved, the Department shall issue a certificate of eligibility for benefits to the applicant. If the application is denied, the Department shall provide the applicant with a notice of denial which shall state the reasons therefor. An applicant shall not receive a biotechnology credit against tax until the Department has issued the applicant a certificate of eligibility for benefits.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-41345" number="48958" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 48-03 Allocation of Credit.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5685" name="T19C048_48-03"/>§ 48-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Allocation of Credit.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41346" number="48959" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Maximum aggregate amount of credits. The aggregate amount of biotechnology credits allowed for all applicants in any calendar year shall not exceed $3 million.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41347" number="48960" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Allocated credit. In the event that for any calendar year, the Department approves credit applications which in the aggregate total more than $3 million in credits, the Department shall allocate the amount of the credits for such calendar year among eligible applicants on a pro rata basis. The allocated credit to each applicant shall be determined by multiplying the amount of the original credit that was approved by the Department for such applicant by a fraction, the numerator of which is $3 million, and the denominator of which is the aggregate amount of the credits approved by the Department for all applicants for the calendar year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41348" number="48961" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notice of allocated credit. The Department shall mail a notice substantiating the amount of the allocated credit to all applicants who qualified to receive an allocated credit.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41349" number="48962" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The amount of the credit determined in the manner described in subdivision (b) of this section shall be the final amount of the credit for such calendar year. An applicant may not carry over to a subsequent tax year the difference between the allocated credit and the original amount of approved credit.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-41350" number="48963" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 48-04 Criteria for Evaluation of Applications.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5687" name="T19C048_48-04"/>§ 48-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Criteria for Evaluation of Applications.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41351" number="48964" version="3">
									<PARA>Any of the following shall be grounds for the Department to deny an application:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41352" number="48965" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>an application is not substantially complete;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41353" number="48966" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>an application is not filed on a form or in a format established by the Commissioner of Finance;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41354" number="48967" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>an application is submitted later than January 15 in the calendar year that immediately follows the calendar year for which the credit is sought;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41355" number="48968" version="1119">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>an applicant has not submitted any additional documentation requested by the Department as authorized by 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C048_48-02" destination-id="0-0-0-5683">48-02</LINK>(c); or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41356" number="48969" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the Department determines that an applicant knowingly submitted false or misleading information.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-41357" number="48970" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 48-05 Examination of Credit Application and Tax Return; Retention of Records.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5689" name="T19C048_48-05"/>§ 48-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Examination of Credit Application and Tax Return; Retention of Records.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-41358" number="48971" version="3">
									<PARA>The Commissioner of Finance, for the purpose of ascertaining the correctness of any application for credit or tax return on which a credit was claimed, shall have the power to examine or to cause to have examined, by any agent or representative designated by the commissioner for that purpose, any books, papers, records or memoranda bearing upon the matters required to be included in an application for a credit or a return on which a credit is claimed.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>