<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-40112" number="47111" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 30: Relocation and Employment Assistance Program</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5461" name="T19C030"/>Chapter 30: Relocation and Employment Assistance Program</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40113" number="47112" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 30-01 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5463" name="T19C030_30-01"/>§ 30-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40114" number="47113" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Aggregate employment shares.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;aggregate employment shares&quot; means the sum of all employment shares maintained by an eligible business in a taxable year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40115" number="47114" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Determination of number of eligible aggregate employment shares.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40116" number="47115" version="1841">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of the credit allowed by subdivision (i) of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-503" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-503</LINK>, subdivision 17 of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-604" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-604</LINK> or § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-643.7" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-643.7</LINK> of the Administrative Code of the City of New York and the reduction in base rent allowed by subdivision f of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-704" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-704</LINK> of such Code, the number of eligible aggregate employment shares of an eligible business is the amount, if any, by which the number of aggregate employment shares maintained by it in the eligible area in the taxable year in which it claims such credit or reduction exceeds the number of aggregate employment shares maintained by it in the eligible area in the taxable year immediately preceding the taxable year during which it first relocates. (Note: when used in these rules the term &quot;relocate&quot; has the meaning set forth in this definition section. Note also, the taxable year preceding the taxable year of an eligible business&apos; first relocation shall hereafter be referred to as the &quot;base year&quot;.)</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40117" number="47116" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The amount determined under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall not exceed whichever of the following is the least:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40118" number="47117" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the amount, if any, by which the number of aggregate employment shares maintained by the eligible business in particular to which it has relocated premises in the taxable year in which the credit or reduction is claimed exceeds the number of aggregate employment shares maintained in such premises in the taxable year immediately preceding the taxable year during which the eligible business relocates to such premises. (This amount shall hereafter be referred to as &quot;Limitation 1&quot;.);</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40119" number="47118" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>for any taxable year following the third taxable year immediately succeeding the taxable year of relocation to particular eligible premises, the amount, if any, by which the highest number of aggregate employment shares maintained by the eligible business in the premises in the taxable year during which it relocates to such premises or in any of the three immediately succeeding taxable years exceeds the number of aggregate employment shares maintained in such premises in the taxable year immediately preceding the taxable year of the relocation. (This amount shall hereafter be referred to as &quot;Limitation 2&quot;.);</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40120" number="47119" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>an amount equal to twice the number of aggregate employment shares maintained by the eligible business outside the eligible area in the base year. (This amount shall hereafter be referred to as &quot;Limitation 3&quot;).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40121" number="47120" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If an eligible business relocates to more than one particular premises, Limitations 1 and 2 must be calculated separately for each particular premises. In such case, the amount determined under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall not exceed the lesser of</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40122" number="47121" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the sum of the lesser of Limitations 1 and 2 for each particular premises or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40123" number="47122" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Limitation 3.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40124" number="47123" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Calculation of shares.</CHARFORMAT> The calculation of eligible aggregate employment shares may be illustrated by the following examples (Assume that a year has exactly 52 weeks): </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40125" number="47124" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 1:</CHARFORMAT> During 1987 a calendar year taxpayer has 200 full time employees, 100 of whom work in Manhattan south of 96th Street and 100 of whom work in New Jersey. On January 1, 1988, taxpayer relocates all 200 employees to eligible premises in Brooklyn, and hires an additional 50 employees to work at the new location. All 250 employees work full time during the taxable year. Taxpayer has 250 eligible aggregate employment shares in 1988. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40126" number="47125" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 2:</CHARFORMAT> Same facts as in example 1. For the commercial rent tax year ending May 31, 1988, the number of eligible aggregate employment shares is calculated by multiplying 250 workers by the number of weeks they worked ending within the period January 1, 1988 to May 31, 1988, then dividing by the number of weeks ending within the period of June 1, 1987 to May 31, 1988. From this amount, the number of aggregate employment shares in the base year would be subtracted (except that here the number is zero). The base year for the commercial rent tax is January 1, 1987 to December 31, 1987, the same as the base year for the general corporation tax, unincorporated business tax, or banking corporation tax, whichever is applicable. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40127" number="47126" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 3:</CHARFORMAT> Same facts as in example 1, except that the relocation and hiring take place on the first day of the 27th week of 1988. Taxpayer has 125 eligible aggregate employment shares in 1988 (250 workers times 26 work weeks per worker divided by 52 weeks in the taxable year). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40128" number="47127" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 4:</CHARFORMAT> Same facts as in example 1, except that, instead of having 100 employees in Manhattan, these employees were in non-eligible premises in Queens prior to relocation to Brooklyn. Taxpayer has 150 eligible aggregate employment shares in 1988 (250 shares in eligible area in 1988 less 100 shares in eligible area in 1987). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40129" number="47128" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 5:</CHARFORMAT> Same facts as in example 1, except that, instead of hiring 50 new employees at the eligible premises, taxpayer hires 300 new employees for a total of 500 employees at the eligible premises. Taxpayer has 400 eligible aggregate employment shares in 1988 (Limitation 3 applies). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40130" number="47129" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 6:</CHARFORMAT> Same facts as in example 1, except that 100 of the employees were moved to non-eligible premises in Queens so that only 150 employees were working at the eligible premises in Brooklyn. Taxpayer has 150 eligible aggregate employment shares in 1988 (Limitation 1 applies). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40131" number="47130" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 7:</CHARFORMAT> Same facts as in example 1, with the following additional facts: The taxable year in question is 1991, the third taxable year after the year of relocation. On January 1, 1991, taxpayer hires 50 more employees for a total of 300 full-time employees working the entire year. Taxpayer has 300 eligible aggregate employment shares in 1991. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40132" number="47131" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 8:</CHARFORMAT> Same facts as in example 7, except that the taxable year in question is 1992, the fourth taxable year after the year of the relocation. On January 1, 1992, taxpayer hires an additional 100 employees to work at the eligible premises, for a total of 400 full-time employees working the entire year. Taxpayer has 300 eligible aggregate employment shares in 1992 (Limitation 2 applies). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40133" number="47132" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 9:</CHARFORMAT> Same facts as in example 1, with the following additional facts: On January 1, 1992, taxpayer hires 100 additional employees, 50 of whom work at the eligible premises in Brooklyn (P1) for a total of 300, and 50 of whom work at new eligible premises in the Bronx (P2). Taxpayer has 300 eligible aggregate employment shares in 1992. (Pursuant to Reg. § 13(c), the lesser of Limitations 1 and 2 for P1 is Limitation 2, or 250. This is added to 50 for P2 pursuant to limitation 1, resulting in a sum of 300.) </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40134" number="47133" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 10.</CHARFORMAT> Same facts as in example 1, except that on June 1, 1988, taxpayer hires an additional 50 workers who work full-time through May 31, 1989. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40135" number="47134" version="3">
									<PARA>For the commercial rent tax year June 1, 1988 through May 31, 1989, taxpayer has 300 eligible aggregate employment shares. (Taxpayer has 300 aggregate employment shares in the year June 1, 1988 through May 31, 1989. Since there were no aggregate employment shares in the base year, which is calendar year 1987, no shares are subtracted.)</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40136" number="47135" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Base year. </CHARFORMAT>&quot;Base year&quot; shall mean the taxable year preceding the taxable year during which an eligible business first relocates. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40137" number="47136" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commencement date of improvements.</CHARFORMAT> For buildings receiving tax abatement benefits under the Industrial and Commercial Incentive Program, or from the Industrial and Commercial Incentive Board, commencement date shall mean the date a &quot;Certificate of Eligibility&quot; issued relating to such benefits is effective. For buildings owned by not-for-profit corporations, the Urban Development Corporation, or the City of New York, or for buildings financed with Industrial Development Agency bonds, commencement date shall mean the date of issuance of the first building permit which authorizes commencement of the work which involves the expenditures for improvements to real property which would qualify the premises for this program. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40138" number="47137" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eligible area.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Eligible area&quot; means the area of the city excluding that area in the borough of Manhattan lying south of the center line of 96th Street. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40139" number="47138" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eligible business.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Eligible business&quot; shall mean:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40140" number="47139" version="2307">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person subject to the unincorporated business tax imposed under <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C005" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 5</LINK>, the general corporation tax imposed under Subchapter 2 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C006" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 6</LINK>, or the banking corporation tax imposed under Subchapter 3 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C006" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 6 of Title 11</LINK> of the Administrative Code, or for purposes of the reduction in base rent allowed by the subdivision f of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-704" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-704</LINK> of the Code, any person subject to one of such taxes or any insurance corporation as defined in § 1500 of the New York State Tax Law, which:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40141" number="47140" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>has been conducting substantial business operations at one or more business locations outside the eligible area for at least 24 consecutive months immediately preceding the taxable year during which such eligible business relocates; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40142" number="47141" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>on or after May 27, 1987 relocates all or part of such business operations; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40143" number="47142" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>either:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40144" number="47143" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>on or after May 27, 1987 first enters into a contract to purchase or lease the premises to which it relocates, or a parcel on which will be constructed such eligible premises, or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40145" number="47144" version="1841">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>as of May 27, 1987 owns such parcel or premises and has not prior to such date made application for benefits under the Industrial and Commercial Incentive Program pursuant to Part 4 of Subchapter 2 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C002" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 2 of Title 11</LINK> of the Administrative Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40146" number="47145" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A business shall not be rendered ineligible solely because it has entered into a contract prior to May 27, 1987 to purchase or lease other premises in the same building as those premises to which it relocates provided that:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40147" number="47146" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the premises to which it relocates are physically separate and distinct from the other premises;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40148" number="47147" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>no contract to purchase or lease the premises to which it relocates was entered into prior to May 27, 1987; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40149" number="47148" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>if the premises to which it relocates are rented, the rent for such premises is separately stated in the lease for such premises. For purposes of these rules, an option to purchase or lease premises or a parcel of land will be considered a contract to purchase or lease such premises or parcel. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40150" number="47149" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eligible premises.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Eligible premises&quot; shall mean:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40151" number="47150" version="2472">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Non-residential premises which are wholly contained in real property which is certified as eligible to receive benefits pursuant to Part 3 or Part 4 of Subchapter 2 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C002" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 2 of Title 11</LINK> of the Administrative Code, provided, that such premises have been improved by construction or renovation, that expenditures have been made for improvements to such real property in excess of 50% of the value at which such real property was assessed for tax purposes for the tax year in which such improvements commenced and such expenditures have been made within 36 months or, in the case of expenditures for such improvements to such real property in excess of fifty million dollars, within 72 months from such commencement, that such real property is located in the eligible area, and provided further that no contract to purchase or lease such premises has been entered into prior to May 27 1987;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40152" number="47151" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Non-residential premises which are:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40153" number="47152" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>wholly contained in or situated on real property which has been leased from the New York City Industrial Development Agency established pursuant to Article 18-A of the General Municipal Law, provided that such premises were constructed or renovated subsequent to the approval of such construction or renovation by such Agency; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40154" number="47153" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>wholly contained or situated on real property owned by the city in accordance with the applicable provisions of the New York City Charter, a lease for which was approved, provided that such premises were constructed or renovated subsequent to such approval, or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40155" number="47154" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>wholly contained in or situated on real property which has been leased from the port authority of the State of New York and New Jersey or the New York State Urban Development Corporation, or a subsidiary thereof, provided that such premises were constructed or renovated subsequent to the execution of such lease, or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40156" number="47155" version="1841">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>wholly contained in real property which would be eligible to receive benefits pursuant to Part 4 of Subchapter 2 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C002" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 2 of Title 11</LINK> of the Administrative Code except that such property is exempt from real property taxation; provided that expenditures have been made for improvements to such real property in excess of 50 percent of the value at which such real property was assessed for tax purposes for the tax year in which such improvements commenced and such expenditures have been made within 36 months or, in the case of expenditures for such improvements to such real property in excess of fifty million dollars, within 72 months from the date of such commencement, that such real property is located in the eligible area, and provided further that no contract to purchase or lease such premises has been entered into prior to May 27, 1987.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40157" number="47156" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The determination of whether premises meet the requirements for eligibility set forth in this definition shall be made as of the effective date of the initial certification of eligibility issued pursuant to 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-02" destination-id="0-0-0-5465">30-02</LINK>(b). Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraphs (1) and (2) of this definition, if, subsequent to such date, the property in which such premises are contained ceases to meet the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of this definition, such premises shall nonetheless remain eligible premises, provided that the eligible business continues to occupy such premises; provided however, that if after such property ceases to meet the requirements of paragraph (1) and (2), an eligible business first leases or purchases additional premises contained in such property, such additional premises shall not be considered eligible premises. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40158" number="47157" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Employment share. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40159" number="47158" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;employment share&quot; means, with respect to each employee, partner or sole proprietor of an eligible business, the sum of</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40160" number="47159" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of full-time work weeks worked by such employee, partner or sole proprietor during the eligible business&apos; taxable year, divided by the number of weeks in the taxable year, and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40161" number="47160" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of part-time work weeks worked by such employee, partner or sole proprietor during the eligible business&apos; taxable year divided by an amount equal to twice the number of weeks in the taxable year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40162" number="47161" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An individual will be considered an employee for purposes of these rules if the relationship existing between the eligible business and the individual is that of employer and employee. Generally, the relationship of employer and employee exists when the eligible business has the right to control and direct the individual not only as to the result to be accomplished by him or her but also as to the means by which such result is to be accomplished. If the relationship of employer and employee exists, the designation or description of the relationship is immaterial. The directors of a corporation in their capacity as directors are not employees of an eligible business. Directors of a corporation may be considered employees if, in addition to serving in the capacity of directors, they serve in the capacity of employees.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40163" number="47162" version="2472">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>As used in this definition, the term &quot;work week&quot; means a period of seven or fewer successive days, beginning with a specified day, which an eligible business has adopted and regularly utilizes as its work week. A full-time work week is a work week during which an employee, partner or sole proprietor has performed at least 35 hours of labor for compensation. A full time work week is attributable to the eligible area if at least 35 hours of labor for compensation are either performed in the eligible area or are attributable to particular premises in the eligible area. A part-time work week is a work week during which an employee, partner or sole proprietor has performed at least 15 but fewer than 35 hours of labor for compensation. A part time work week is attributable to the eligible area if at least 15 but fewer than 35 hours of labor for compensation are either performed in the eligible area or are attributable to particular premises in the eligible area. Hours in excess of 35 worked by an employee, partner or sole proprietor during a work week cannot be carried over and counted during any other work week provided, however, if an employee, partner or sole proprietor works on a regular compressed time schedule that requires an average of 35 or more hours of labor per week, hours from a week when such schedule provides for more than 35 hours of labor may be carried over and counted during an immediately preceding or succeeding week when such schedule provides for fewer than 35 hours of work.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40164" number="47163" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of an employee, partner or sole proprietor who works part of the week within and part of the week without a particular premises, hours are attributable to such particular premises as follows:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40165" number="47164" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If an employee, partner or sole proprietor spends substantially all of his or her time at a particular premises, all hours are attributable to such premises.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40166" number="47165" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If an employee, partner or sole proprietor does not spend substantially all of his or her time at a particular premises, all hours are nonetheless attributable to such premises if the employee, partner or sole proprietor is present at such premises at the beginning or end of each work day and all of the employee&apos;s, partner&apos;s or sole proprietor&apos;s time spent outside of such premises relates primarily to business operations carried on at such premises, provided that hours worked at a particular premises cannot be attributed by reason of this subparagraph to another particular premises maintained by the same eligible business. If an eligible business has both eligible and non-eligible premises in the same building, hours worked at the non-eligible premises cannot be attributed by reason of this subparagraph (ii)(B) to the eligible premises.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40167" number="47166" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If neither subparagraph (ii)(A) or (ii)(B) of this paragraph (3) applies, only hours worked at a particular premises are attributable to such premises.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40168" number="47167" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Time not actually worked by an employee, partner or sole proprietor due to vacation, sick leave or other leave may nevertheless be counted as time worked by that employee, partner or sole proprietor provided</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40169" number="47168" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>such vacation, sick leave or other leave time is granted pursuant to an established policy of the eligible business which is applied uniformly to all employees, partners or sole proprietors of the business or to all employees, partners or sole proprietors within a specific class, and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40170" number="47169" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the employee, partner or sole proprietor continues to receive his or her regular rate of pay during such vacation, sick leave or other leave. Such time shall be attributed to the eligible area and the eligible premises in the same proportion as the number of work weeks actually worked by an employee, partner or sole proprietor attributable to the eligible area and eligible premises bears to the total number of work weeks actually worked by the employee, partner or sole proprietor in the taxable year in question. Terminal leave preceding the termination of an employee&apos;s, partner&apos;s or sole proprietor&apos;s employment may not be counted as time worked by the employee, partner or sole proprietor. A work week which begins in one taxable year and ends in the following taxable year shall be treated as a work week in the taxable year in which it ends.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40171" number="47170" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The operation of this paragraph (3) is illustrated by the following examples: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40172" number="47171" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 1:</CHARFORMAT> X, an employee of ABC Corporation, an eligible business having one eligible premises, works 40 hours a week driving a truck and making deliveries. X loads his truck every morning at ABC Corp.&apos;s eligible premises and spends the rest of his time making deliveries outside the eligible area. Since X starts each day at the eligible premises and spends the rest of his time on deliveries from the eligible premises, all of his time will be attributable to the eligible premises. Thus, ABC Corp. may count a full time work week in the eligible area and at the eligible premises with respect to each week worked by X. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40173" number="47172" version="2472">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 2:</CHARFORMAT> Y, who also drives a truck and works 40 hours a week for ABC Corp., spends 10 hours each week loading at the eligible premises, 10 hours loading at premises maintained by the business outside of the eligible area, and 20 hours making deliveries outside of the eligible area. The 10 hours spent at the eligible premises are counted toward a work week at the eligible premises. The 10 hours spent at the non-eligible premises are counted toward the non-eligible premises and do not qualify. The 20 hours spent making deliveries cannot be counted toward either premises. Thus, Y does not have a full or part time work week in the eligible area or at the eligible premises. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40174" number="47173" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 3:</CHARFORMAT> Z, a salesman, spends substantially all of his time in Alaska selling products manufactured at ABC Corp.&apos;s eligible premises. Since Z does not start or end each day at the eligible premises, none of Z&apos;s time is attributable to the eligible premises. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40175" number="47174" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 4:</CHARFORMAT> E, an executive of ABC Corp., spends 16 hours a week at ABC Corp.&apos;s eligible premises and 25 hours at the premises outside the eligible area. Only 16 hours (i.e., a part-time work week) are attributable to the eligible premises. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40176" number="47175" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be within the discretion of the Commissioner to determine whether hours worked by an employee, partner or sole proprietor outside of eligible premises maintained by the eligible business have been fairly apportioned within and without the eligible area, and within and without the eligible premises.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40177" number="47176" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of an employee, partner or sole proprietor with work weeks both within and without the eligible area in a given taxable year, the employment shares maintained by the eligible business within the eligible area with respect to the employee shall be the sum of</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40178" number="47177" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of full-time work weeks worked by the employee, partner or sole proprietor during the eligible business&apos; taxable year attributable to the eligible area divided by the number of weeks in the taxable year, and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40179" number="47178" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of part-time work weeks worked by such employee, partner or sole proprietor during the eligible business&apos; taxable year attributable to the eligible area divided by an amount equal to twice the number of weeks in the taxable year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40180" number="47179" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of an employee, partner or sole proprietor with work weeks both within and without the eligible premises in a given taxable year, the employment shares maintained by the eligible business within the eligible premises with respect to the employee, partner or sole proprietor shall be the sum of</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40181" number="47180" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of full-time work weeks worked by the employee, partner or sole proprietor during the eligible business&apos; taxable year attributable to the eligible premises divided by the number of weeks in the taxable year and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40182" number="47181" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of part-time work weeks worked by such employee, partner or sole proprietor during the eligible business&apos; taxable year attributable to the eligible premises divided by an amount equal to twice the number of weeks in the taxable year. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40183" number="47182" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Expenditure.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Expenditure&quot; shall mean an amount actually paid, incurred, or provided in kind to improve the real property which in part improves the premises. Expenditures may include those made for: construction contracts, materials, labor, rental equipment, insurance, permit fees and other direct expenses of construction; installation of partitions and other tenant work by or for the first tenant or occupant of new or substantially renovated space; architectural, engineering, construction management, legal, accounting and other services rendered in connection with the construction work; marketing, brokerage, legal and other services rendered in connection with the initial leasing or sale of eligible property created or substantially renovated by eligible construction work; interest on construction loans, insurance and other fixed costs arising during the course of construction; and fees for connection to existing sewer, water or utility lines. Expenditures shall not include the costs of acquiring the site. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40184" number="47183" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hotel services.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Hotel services&quot; shall mean:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40185" number="47184" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any services which consist predominantly of the lodging of guests at a building or a portion thereof which is regularly used and kept open for such services. The term &quot;hotel services&quot; shall include the lodging of guests at an apartment hotel, a hotel, boarding house or club, whether or not meals are served.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40186" number="47185" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Services at any particular eligible premises shall be deemed to consist predominantly of hotel services if either 50 percent or more of total floor space at such premises is devoted to the lodging of guests as described in paragraph (1) of this definition, or if 50 percent or more of the work hours of employees of the eligible business at such premises are devoted to such lodging of guests. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40187" number="47186" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Particular premises. </CHARFORMAT>&quot;Particular premises&quot; shall mean all premises occupied by an eligible business within a single building except that if there are eligible and non-eligible premises in the same building, such eligible and non-eligible premises constitute separate particular premises. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40188" number="47187" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Person.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Person&quot; shall mean any individual, partnership, association, joint-stock company, corporation, estate or trust, and any combination of the foregoing. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40189" number="47188" version="2472">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Relocate.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Relocate&quot; shall mean to transfer pre-existing business operations which are not retail activities or hotel services to premises that are or will become eligible premises, or the establishment of new business operations which are not retail activities or hotel services at such premises, provided that a relocation will not be deemed to have taken place unless at least one employee, partner or sole proprietor of the eligible business is transferred to such premises from pre-existing business operations outside the eligible area. The date of relocation to any particular premises shall be any date elected by the eligible business is transferred to the particular premises from a pre-existing business location outside the eligible area and begins to work at such premises, provided that such date is subsequent to the date of the commencement of improvements to real property in which such premises are located, which improvements will meet the requirements in the definition of &quot;eligible premises&quot; of these rules relating to expenditures for improvements, and provided further that such date is prior to the date of issuance of an initial certification of eligibility pursuant to 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-02" destination-id="0-0-0-5465">30-02</LINK>. No claim for credit or refund of an overpayment of tax shall be allowed under this definition which is otherwise barred by any statute of limitations. The election provided for in this section shall be irrevocable. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40190" number="47189" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Retail activity.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Retail activity&quot; shall mean:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40191" number="47190" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any activity which consists predominantly of the sale, other than through the mail, of tangible personal property to any person, for any purpose unrelated to the trade or business of such person, or which consists predominantly of the selling of services to individuals which generally involve the physical care of the personal property of any person unrelated to the trade or business of such person, or which consists predominantly of the provision of retail banking services.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40192" number="47191" version="1114">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Activity at any particular premises shall be deemed to be predominantly retail activity if either 50 percent or more of total floor space at such premises is utilized for such sales or services described in paragraph (1) of this definition, or if 50 percent or more of total employee work hours at such premises are devoted to such sales or services. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40193" number="47192" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Taxable Year. </CHARFORMAT>&quot;Taxable year&quot; shall mean:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40194" number="47193" version="2300">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of the reduction in base rent allowed by subdivision (i) of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-503" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-503</LINK>, subdivision 17 of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-604" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-604</LINK> of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-643.7" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-643.7</LINK> of the Administrative Code, the term &quot;taxable year&quot; means the taxable year on the basis of which the taxpayer reports for purposes of banking corporation tax imposed by <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C005" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 5</LINK> and Subchapters 2 and 3 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C006" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 6 of Title 11</LINK> of the Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40195" number="47194" version="2472">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of reduction in base rent allowed by subdivision f of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-704" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-704</LINK> of the Code, the term &quot;taxable year&quot; means the annual reporting period for commercial tax rent purposes, which is the period beginning on June 1 of a calendar year and ending on May 31, of the following calendar year; however, for taxpayers that are subject to the unincorporated business tax, the general corporation tax or the banking corporation tax, when the taxable year referred to is the base year, it shall mean the taxable year on the bases of which the taxpayer reports for purposes of the unincorporated business tax, the general corporation tax or the banking corporation tax. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40196" number="47195" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 30-02 Authorization to Provide Relocation and Employment Assistance Credits and Base Rent Reductions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5465" name="T19C030_30-02"/>§ 30-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Authorization to Provide Relocation and Employment Assistance Credits and Base Rent Reductions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40197" number="47196" version="1841">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An eligible business which relocates shall be allowed a credit against the unincorporated business tax imposed by <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C005" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 5</LINK>, the general corporation tax imposed under Subchapter 2 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C006" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 6</LINK>, or the banking corporation tax imposed under Subchapter 3 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C006" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 6 of Title 11</LINK> of the Administrative Code as described in subdivision (i) of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-503" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-503</LINK>, subdivision 17 of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-604" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-604</LINK> and § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-643.7" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-643.7</LINK> of the Administrative Code. Any such eligible business which is subject to the commercial rent tax shall also receive a reduction in base rent subject to tax as described in subdivision f of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-704" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-704</LINK> of the Administrative Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40198" number="47197" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No eligible business shall be authorized to receive a credit against tax or a reduction in base rent pursuant to this section until it has received from the Department of Finance an initial certification of eligibility to receive benefits under this program and a certification of the number of aggregate employment shares maintained by such eligible business within the eligible area, outside the eligible area and at the particular premises to which it relocates in the base year. If an eligible business subsequently relocates to a separate particular premises, such eligible business must obtain an additional initial certification of eligibility for the subsequent relocation and a certification of the number of aggregate employment shares at the separate particular premises in the taxable year prior to the taxable year of relocation to such separate particular premises.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40199" number="47198" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Before receiving a credit against the general corporation tax, unincorporated business tax or the banking corporation tax in any taxable year, an eligible business must obtain an annual certification from the Department of Finance of the number of eligible aggregate employment shares maintained by such eligible business in the eligible area and in each particular premises to which it has relocated for the eligible business&apos; taxable year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40200" number="47199" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Before a reduction in base rent may be authorized in any tax year, the taxpayer must obtain an annual certification of the number of eligible aggregate employment shares maintained by such eligible business in the eligible area and in each particular premises to which it has relocated for the eligible business&apos; commercial rent tax year. The taxpayer may claim an estimated reduction on its quarterly commercial rent tax returns pursuant to 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-08" destination-id="0-0-0-5477">30-08</LINK> prior to receiving such annual certification.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40201" number="47200" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With regard to the initial certifications specified in subdivision (b) of this section, an eligible business may contest a denial of eligibility or contest the number of aggregate employment shares certified by the Department of Finance by appealing in writing to the Commissioner of Finance within 90 days of such denial of eligibility or certification of shares.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40202" number="47201" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No initial certification with regard to particular premises shall be issued until such premises meet the requirements for qualification as eligible premises contained in the definition of eligible premises in 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-01" destination-id="0-0-0-5463">30-01</LINK>. After such certification has been issued, a credit or base rent reduction may be taken retroactively to the year of relocation for any taxable year which has not been closed by a statute of limitations. No initial certification of eligibility shall be issued to an eligible business on or after July 1, 1999 unless such business meets the requirements of either paragraph one or two below:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40203" number="47202" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Prior to such date such business has purchased, leased or entered into a contract to purchase or lease particular premises or a parcel on which will be constructed such premises, or already owned such premises or parcel;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40204" number="47203" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>prior to such date improvements have been commenced on such premises or parcel which improvements will meet the requirements of the definition of eligible premises relating to expenditures for improvements;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40205" number="47204" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>prior to such date such business submits a preliminary application for a certificate of eligibility with respect to a proposed relocation to such premises; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40206" number="47205" version="2472">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>such business relocates to such premises no later than 36 months or, in a case where the expenditures made for improvements specified in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph are in excess of 50 million dollars, within 72 months from the date of submission of such preliminary application; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40207" number="47206" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>not later than June 30, 2002, such business has purchased, leased or entered into a contract to purchase or lease particular premises wholly contained in a building in which at least 40 percent or 200,000 square feet, whichever is less, of the nonresidential floor area of such building has been purchased or leased by a business or businesses that did not receive certifications of eligibility with respect to such floor area under these rules prior to July 1, 1999 but which meet or will meet the requirements of paragraph one of this subdivision with respect to such floor area and which are or will become certified to receive a credit under these rules with respect to such floor area;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40208" number="47207" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>not later than June 30, 2002, such business submits a preliminary application for a certificate of eligibility with respect to a proposed relocation to such particular premises; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40209" number="47208" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>not later than June 30, 2002 such business relocates to such particular premises.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40210" number="47209" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 30-03 Continued Eligibility Despite Sale of Business.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5467" name="T19C030_30-03"/>§ 30-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Continued Eligibility Despite Sale of Business.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40211" number="47210" version="3">
									<PARA>An eligible business receiving benefits under this program will not be rendered ineligible for the program solely by virtue of the sale of the business.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40212" number="47211" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 30-04 Unincorporated Business Tax Credit.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5469" name="T19C030_30-04"/>§ 30-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Unincorporated Business Tax Credit.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40213" number="47212" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The amount of the unincorporated business tax credit authorized by 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-02" destination-id="0-0-0-5465">30-02</LINK> is determined by multiplying $500 by the number of eligible aggregate employment shares maintained during the taxable year by the taxpayer with respect to particular premises to which the taxpayer has relocated during the taxable year, provided, however, that no credit shall be allowed for the relocation of any retail activity or hotel services.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40214" number="47213" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The credit allowed under this section with respect to eligible aggregate employment shares maintained during the taxable year with respect to particular premises to which the taxpayer has relocated shall be allowed for the first taxable year during which such eligible aggregate employment shares are maintained with respect to such premises and for any of the eleven succeeding taxable years during which the eligible aggregate employment shares are maintained with respect to such premises. If the amount of the credit allowable under this section for any taxable year exceeds the tax imposed for such year, the excess may be carried over, in order, to the five immediately succeeding taxable years and, to the extent not previously deductible, may be deducted from the taxpayer&apos;s tax for such years. For any taxable year in which there are carryover credits, the credit for the taxable year shall be taken first, followed by the carryover credits, in order starting with the earliest applicable year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40215" number="47214" version="1842">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The credit allowable under this section shall be deducted prior to the deduction of any other credit allowed by § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-503" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-503</LINK> of the Administrative Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40216" number="47215" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 30-05 General Corporation Tax Credit.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5471" name="T19C030_30-05"/>§ 30-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">General Corporation Tax Credit.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40217" number="47216" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The amount of the general corporation tax credit authorized by 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-02" destination-id="0-0-0-5465">30-02</LINK> is determined by multiplying $500 by the number of eligible aggregate employment shares maintained during the taxable year by the taxpayer with respect to particular premises during the taxable year by the taxpayer with respect to particular premises to which the tax payer has relocated, provided, however, that no credit shall be allowed for the relocation of any retail activity or hotel services.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40218" number="47217" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The credit allowed under this section with respect to eligible aggregate employment shares maintained during the taxable year with respect to particular premises to which the taxpayer has relocated shall be allowed for the first taxable year during which such eligible aggregate employment shares are maintained with respect to such premises and for any of the eleven succeeding taxable years during which the eligible aggregate employment shares are maintained with respect to such premises. If the amount of the credit allowable under this section for any taxable year exceeds the tax imposed for such year, the excess may be carried over, in order, to the five immediately succeeding taxable years and, to the extent not previously deductible, may be deducted from the taxpayer&apos;s tax for such years. For any taxable year in which there are carryover credits, the credit for the taxable year shall be taken first, followed by the carryover credits, in order starting with the earliest applicable year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40219" number="47218" version="1842">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The credit allowable under this section shall be deducted prior to the deduction of any other credit allowed by § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-604" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-604</LINK> of the Administrative Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40220" number="47219" version="1842">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The amount equal to 25% of the preceding year&apos;s tax, to be paid pursuant to subdivision 1 of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-608" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-608</LINK> of the Administrative Code, shall be computed without regard to the credit provided for in this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40221" number="47220" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 30-06 Banking Corporation Tax Credit.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5473" name="T19C030_30-06"/>§ 30-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Banking Corporation Tax Credit.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40222" number="47221" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The amount of the banking corporation tax credit authorized by 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-02" destination-id="0-0-0-5465">30-02</LINK> is determined by multiplying $500 by the number of eligible aggregate employment shares maintained during the taxable year by the taxpayer with respect to particular premises to which the taxpayer has relocated, provided, however, that no credit shall be allowed for the relocation of any retail activity or hotel services.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40223" number="47222" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The credit allowed under this section with respect to eligible aggregate employment shares maintained with respect to particular premises to which the taxpayer has relocated shall be allowed for the first taxable year during which such eligible aggregate employment shares are maintained with respect to such premises and for any of the eleven succeeding taxable years during which the eligible aggregate employment shares are maintained with respect to such premises. If the amount of the credit allowable under this section for any taxable year exceeds the tax imposed for such year, the excess may be carried over, in order, to the five immediately succeeding taxable years and, to the extent not previously deductible, may be deducted from the taxpayer&apos;s tax for such years. For any taxable year in which there are carryover credits, the credit for the taxable year shall be taken first, followed by the carryover credits, in order starting with the earliest applicable year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40224" number="47223" version="1842">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The credit allowable under this section shall be deducted prior to the deduction of any other credit allowed by Part 4 of Subchapter 3 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C006" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 6 of Title 11 </LINK>of the Administrative Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40225" number="47224" version="1842">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The amount equal to 25% of the preceding year&apos;s tax, to be paid pursuant to subdivision (a) of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-645" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-645</LINK> of the Administrative Code, shall be computed without regard to the credit provided for in this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40226" number="47225" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 30-07 Commercial Rent Tax Base Rent Reduction.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5475" name="T19C030_30-07"/>§ 30-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commercial Rent Tax Base Rent Reduction.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40227" number="47226" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each particular eligible premises occupied by a tenant which has obtained the certification required by 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-02" destination-id="0-0-0-5465">30-02</LINK>, base rent shall be reduced by an amount determined by multiplying such base rent by a fraction, the numerator of which is the number of eligible aggregate employment shares maintained by such tenant at such eligible premises in the tax year for which the reduction is claimed and the denominator of which is a number equal to the number of aggregate employment shares maintained by such tenant in such eligible premises in such tax year, provided that the denominator shall not exceed the highest number of aggregate employment shares maintained by such eligible tenant in such eligible premises in the tax year during which such tenant relocates to such eligible premises and in each of the three immediately succeeding tax years.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40228" number="47227" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of calculating eligible aggregate employment shares as specified in 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-01" destination-id="0-0-0-5463">30-01</LINK> &quot;Aggregate employment shares&quot; (1), aggregate employment shares in the eligible area and eligible premises for the tax year for which reduction is claimed shall be determined on the basis of the commercial rent tax annual reporting period; however, the aggregate employment shares within the eligible area, within the eligible premises and outside the eligible area for the year prior to relocation shall be calculated on the basis of the taxpayer&apos;s taxable year for the general corporation tax, unincorporated business tax or banking corporation tax (whichever is applicable) immediately preceding the taxable year of the relocation to the eligible area or the eligible premises in question.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40229" number="47228" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Base rent may be reduced as provided in this section for the tax year during which the tenant relocates to eligible premises and for any of the eleven immediately succeeding tax years during which the tenant maintains eligible aggregate employment shares with respect to such eligible premises, provided, however, that there shall be no reduction with respect to base rent for any part of the tax year preceding the date of relocation to such eligible premises. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40230" number="47229" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 1:</CHARFORMAT> X, a calendar year taxpayer, relocated to eligible premises on June 1, 1989 and received the certifications required by 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-02" destination-id="0-0-0-5465">30-02</LINK>. X&apos;s annual rent for the eligible premises is $100,000. During 1988, X had 100 employees at the eligible premises and another 100 employees at another premises in Manhattan south of 96th Street. On June 1, 1989 (the date of the relocation), X moved all 100 employees from Manhattan to the eligible premises.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40231" number="47230" version="3">
									<PARA>The fraction by which base rent is reduced in the tax year June 1, 1989 to May 31, 1990, is computed as follows: (Assume that the tax year has exactly 52 weeks, that each quarter has exactly 13 weeks, and that all employees work full time during the entire tax year.) The numerator of the fraction is the number of eligible aggregate employment shares in the eligible premises. The number of eligible aggregate employment shares is the number of aggregate employment shares in the area in the tax year in question less the number of aggregate employment shares in the eligible area in the taxable year preceding the taxable year of relocation (subject to limitations). During the commercial rent tax year June 1, 1989 to May 31, 1990, X maintained 200 employees at the eligible premises, each of whom worked 52 weeks. The number of aggregate employment shares for the tax year is 200 (200 employees times 52 weeks worked by each employee, divided by 52 weeks). During calendar year 1988 (the taxable year preceding the taxable year of relocation), X maintained 100 employees at the eligible premises, each of whom worked 52 weeks. The number of aggregate employment shares for 1988 is 100 (100 employees × 52/52). The numerator of the fraction (the number of aggregate employment shares) is 100 (200 shares in the current year, less 100 shares in 1988). The denominator (the number of aggregate employment shares in the eligible premises in the tax year) is 200.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40232" number="47231" version="3">
									<PARA>The percentage reduction is 100/200 = 50%. Since base rent prior to the deduction was $100,000 the deduction is $50,000 ($100,000 times 50%). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40233" number="47232" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 2:</CHARFORMAT> Assume the same facts as in example 1, except that the relocation takes place on September 1, 1989. There are 100 employees in the eligible premises for the entire tax year and 100 additional employees in the eligible premises for 39 weeks of the tax year (September 1, 1989 through May 31, 1990). Aggregate employment shares for the tax year thus equals 175. ((100 × 52) (100 × 39))/52.) The numerator of the fraction by which base rent is reduced is 75 (175 shares in the current year, less 100 shares in 1988). The denominator is 175.The percentage reduction is 75/175 = 42.86%. Since X relocated on September 1, this percentage is applied only to the base rent attributable to the portion of the tax year following relocation, or $75,000. The reduction is equal to 42.86% of $75,000, or $32,145. Thus, taxpayer&apos;s base rent for the tax year June 1, 1989 through May 31, 1990, is $100,000 less $32,145, or $67,855. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40234" number="47233" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 30-08 Quarterly Reductions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5477" name="T19C030_30-08"/>§ 30-08 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Quarterly Reductions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40235" number="47234" version="1118">
									<PARA>A tenant who has received the initial certification required by 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-02" destination-id="0-0-0-5465">30-02</LINK> of these rules may reduce its base rent for premises to which it has relocated on an estimated basis on the returns filed for the quarterly tax periods ending on the last days of August, November and February of the tax year. Such rent reduction shall be computed in the same manner as the annual rent reduction except that, in determining the numerator and denominator of the fraction by which base rent is reduced, the number of employment shares for each employee for the quarter in question is the sum of</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40236" number="47235" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of full-time work weeks worked by such employee during the eligible business&apos; tax year until the end of such quarter divided by the number of weeks in the tax year to the end of such quarter and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40237" number="47236" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the number of part-time work weeks worked by such employee during the eligible business&apos; tax year until the end of such quarter divided by an amount equal to twice the number of weeks in the tax year to the end of such quarter. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40238" number="47237" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">To illustrate:</CHARFORMAT> Assume the same facts as in example 2 of 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-07" destination-id="0-0-0-5475">30-07</LINK>. The rent reduction for the third quarter ending February 28, 1990 is computed as follows: (Assume 13 weeks in each quarter). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40239" number="47238" version="3">
									<PARA>There are 100 employees in the eligible premises for 39 weeks (June 1, 1989 through February 28, 1990) and 100 additional employees in the eligible premises for 26 weeks (September 1, 1989 through February 29, 1990). Aggregate employment shares until the end of the third quarter equals:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40240" number="47239" version="3">
									<PARA>((100 workers × 39 weeks) (100 workers × 26 weeks))/39 weeks = 167. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40241" number="47240" version="3">
									<PARA>The numerator of the fraction by which base rent is reduced is 67 </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40242" number="47241" version="3">
									<PARA>(167 shares through February 28, 1990, less 100 shares in 1988.) </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40243" number="47242" version="3">
									<PARA>The denominator is 167. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40244" number="47243" version="3">
									<PARA>The percentage reduction is 67/167 = 40.12% </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40245" number="47244" version="3">
									<PARA>Assuming that the base rent for the quarter ending February 28 is $25,000 (i.e., 25% of $100,000), the reduction is 40.12% of $25,000 or $10,030. Thus, X&apos;s base rent for the quarter is $25,000 less $10,030, or $14,970. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-40246" number="47245" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 30-09 Apportionment of Reduction.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5479" name="T19C030_30-09"/>§ 30-09 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Apportionment of Reduction.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40247" number="47246" version="1118">
									<PARA>To determine the percentage reduction of base rent at a particular premises to which the taxpayer has relocated where the taxpayer has more than one such premises, the taxpayer must first calculate the total number of eligible aggregate employment shares pursuant to 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-01" destination-id="0-0-0-5463">30-01</LINK> &quot;Aggregate employment shares&quot; (1). The eligible aggregate employment shares must then be apportioned between the premises so that for each particular premises the apportioned eligible aggregate employment shares is in the same proportion to total eligible aggregate employment shares as the maximum number of eligible aggregate employment shares for that particular premises pursuant to the limitations delineated in 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-01" destination-id="0-0-0-5463">30-01</LINK> &quot;Aggregate employment shares&quot; (1)(ii)(A) and (1)(ii)(B) is to the sum of the maximum number of eligible aggregate employment shares for all premises to which the taxpayer has relocated pursuant to these limitations. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40248" number="47247" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example:</CHARFORMAT> Y, a company with 1,000 employees outside the eligible area in the base year, has relocated to two eligible premises denoted PI and P2. The columns below headed P1 and P2 indicate the number of aggregate employment shares in each premises in the designated year. The column headed NE shows aggregate employment shares in the eligible area which are not in eligible premises. The column headed TA shows total aggregate employment shares in the eligible area. The base year is the taxable year preceding the taxable year of the relocation. <LINEBRK/>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40249" number="47248" version="1118">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="5" left-border-space="43" left-border-width="15" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="43" right-border-width="15" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="43" top-border-width="15" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="43" bottom-border-width="15" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="43" horizontal-border-width="15" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="43" vertical-border-width="15" vertical-border-color="#000000">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="72" percentage="no"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Year </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">P1 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">P2 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">NE </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">TA </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Base Year </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">10 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">0 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">90 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">100 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">65 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">200 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">2 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">65 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">200 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">3 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">65 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">200 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">4 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">65 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">200 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">5 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">100 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">55 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">60 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">215 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40250" number="47249" version="3">
									<PARA>The following computation illustrates the percentage base rent deduction for Year 5: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40251" number="47250" version="1118">
									<PARA>Step (1) – Compute eligible aggregate employment shares for Year 5 (basic computation – see: 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-01" destination-id="0-0-0-5463">30-01</LINK> &quot;Aggregate employment shares&quot; (1)(i).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40252" number="47251" version="3">
									<PARA>Eligible aggregate employment shares (subject to limitations) equals 115 (215 aggregate employment shares in the eligible area in the tax year less 100 aggregate employment shares in the eligible area in the taxable year preceding the taxable year of relocation). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40253" number="47252" version="1118">
									<PARA>Step (2) – Premises Limitations (See: 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-01" destination-id="0-0-0-5463">30-01</LINK> &quot;Aggregate employment shares&quot; (1)(iii)) Determine the lesser of Limitations 1 and 2 specified in 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-01" destination-id="0-0-0-5463">30-01</LINK> &quot;Aggregate employment shares&quot; (1)(ii) for each premises. Eligible aggregate employment shares cannot exceed the sum of the limitations so determined for all premises (See: 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-01" destination-id="0-0-0-5463">30-01</LINK> &quot;Aggregate employment shares (1)(iii)). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40254" number="47253" version="3">
									<PARA>For P1, Limitation 2 is the lesser limitation. For P2, Limitation 1 is the lesser limitation. The computation is as follows: P1 85 aggregate employment shares (highest number in first 4 years) less 10 shares (number at premises in year prior to relocation) = 75 </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40255" number="47254" version="3">
									<PARA>P2 55 aggregate employment shares (number in year 5), less 0 shares (number at premises in year prior to relocation) = 55 </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40256" number="47255" version="3">
									<PARA>Sum of the limitations for P1 and P2 = 130 Since this sum is greater than the 115 shares determined in the basic computation (Step 1), it does not reduce the number of eligible aggregate employment shares. However, it is used for the apportionment of the eligible aggregate employment shares. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40257" number="47256" version="1337">
									<PARA>Step (3) – Limitation 3 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C030_30-01" destination-id="0-0-0-5463">30-01</LINK> &quot;Aggregate employment shares&quot; (1)(ii)(c). Limitation 3 equals 2,000 shares and is, therefore, not applicable. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40258" number="47257" version="3">
									<PARA>Step (4) – Apportionment The 115 eligible aggregate employment shares are apportioned to the two premises in the same ratio as the maximum number of eligible aggregate employment shares for each premises bears to the sum of the maximum number of such shares for all premises. Thus, the number of shares apportioned to P1 is computed as follows: 75/130 × 115 = 66.35 shares. The number of shares apportioned to P2 is computed as follows: 55/130 × 115 = 48.65 shares. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40259" number="47258" version="1379">
									<PARA>Step (5) – The percentage reductions are then computed as follows (See: § 30-04): P1 66.35 eligible aggregate employment shares in the eligible premises divided by 85 aggregate employment shares yields a percentage reduction of 78.06%. (Note – the denominator would have been 100, the number of aggregate employment shares in the premises in the tax year in question, except that it is limited here by the highest number of such shares in the year of relocation and the three succeeding tax years.) P2 48.65 eligible aggregate employment shares divided by 55 aggregate employment shares yields a percentage reduction of 88.45%. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-40260" number="47259" version="3">
									<PARA> Step (6) – Apply percentage reduction computed in step 4 to base rent for each eligible premises. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>