<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-78042" number="89486" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 13: Special Patrolmen</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10295" name="T38C013"/>Chapter 13: Special Patrolmen</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78043" number="89487" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 13-01 Appointment.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10297" name="T38C013_13-01"/>§ 13-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Appointment.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78044" number="89488" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pursuant to New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="14-106" destination-id="0-0-0-0">14-106</LINK>, the Police Commissioner may appoint Special Patrolmen upon application by individuals whose employers demonstrate need for such appointment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78045" number="89489" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications for appointment as Special Patrolman from employees, properly endorsed by the following agencies or institutions, shall be given consideration:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78046" number="89490" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>City and state governmental agencies.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78047" number="89491" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Housing complexes.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78048" number="89492" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Hospitals, cemeteries and social welfare agencies.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78049" number="89493" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Educational and cultural institutions, schools, libraries, museums, etc.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78050" number="89494" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Financial institutions and business entities.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78051" number="89495" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>As deemed appropriate by the Police Commissioner.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78052" number="89496" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Special Patrolmen are appointed in connection with special duties of employment, and such designation confers limited Peace Officer powers upon the employee pursuant to New York State Criminal Procedure Law § 2.10(27). The exercise of these powers is limited to the employee&apos;s geographical area of employment and only while such employee is actually on duty. Such duties of employment may include:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78053" number="89497" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Issuing of summonses; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78054" number="89498" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Making arrests and issuing desk appearance tickets; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78055" number="89499" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Controlling crowds and maintaining order in governmental or public buildings.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78056" number="89500" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Special Patrolman designations shall be renewed every two years upon a showing, to the satisfaction of the Police Commissioner, of continuing fitness of the employee, continuing necessity by the employer, <CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">i.e.,</CHARFORMAT> that the duties and responsibilities of the positions require the special powers conferred by the New York City Administrative Code and New York State Criminal Procedure Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78057" number="89501" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>To be eligible for appointment as a Special Patrolman, an applicant shall be of good character, as more specifically defined in these rules, cooperate in a background investigation by the License Division of the Police Department and possess the following qualifications:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78058" number="89502" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A citizen of the United States and resident of the City of New York unless exempted by law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78059" number="89503" version="351">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Presently employed or about to be employed for the purpose of performing duties as specified in 38 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T38C013_13-01" destination-id="0-0-0-10297">13-01</LINK>(b) above, within the City of New York for an employer approved by the Police Department. Appointments are made for the benefit of the employing agency, institution or business entity, at whose request the appointment is made, and the duration of the appointment shall be coterminous with such employment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78060" number="89504" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No record of convictions for any felony or serious offense as enumerated in § 265.00(17) of the New York State Penal Law. If an applicant presents a Certificate of Relief from Disabilities for a conviction as aforesaid, consideration shall be given to the circumstances of the underlying arrest, the age of the applicant when arrested, the time elapsed since the occurrence of the act which led to the arrest and conviction, and the subsequent conduct of the applicant.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78061" number="89505" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Be at least 21 years of age at the time of appointment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78062" number="89506" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If discharged from the military service, it shall not have been dishonorably.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78063" number="89507" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Not possess a condition or disability which, even with reasonable accommodations, would prevent the performance of the essential functions of Special Patrolman.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78064" number="89508" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to the above, applicants for Special Patrolman designation may be disapproved by failure to meet character requirements as disclosed by a background investigation. This determination shall be based upon a review of the circumstances of previous arrests, employment records, mental history, reports of misconduct reflecting on character as referred to above, and any other pertinent records or information.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78065" number="89509" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An applicant may be disapproved if a false statement is made on the application.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78066" number="89510" version="1965">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All applicants shall be fingerprinted upon the filing of the application on forms provided by the License Division. A processing fee, required by the New York State Division of Criminal Justice Services, shall be paid at the time the applicant is fingerprinted, by a money order payable to the N.Y.S. Division of Criminal Justice Services. An application fee shall also be paid at that time, by certified check or money order made payable to the N.Y.C. Police Department. The following items of information shall be provided by applicants: Court disposition of any arrest in which Police Department records do not indicate a final determination; two color photos 1 1/2 × 1 1/2 inches, front view, taken within the past thirty (30) days; certified copy of birth certificate; certified copy of DD214 and military discharge; proof of residence; if foreign born, naturalization certificate; handgun license or rifle/shotgun permit if applicable; driver&apos;s license or New York State Department of Motor Vehicles identification card. All application forms shall be typed and notarized, and co-signed by the employer&apos;s Chief of Security. The Special Patrolman Section shall be notified at least three (3) business days prior to any scheduled appointments if the applicant is unable to appear.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78067" number="89511" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>During the pendency of the application, the applicant shall notify the License Division of any necessary correction to or modification of the information provided in the original application, or any change in her/his status or circumstances, which may be relevant to the application.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78068" number="89512" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An employer seeking approval to employ one or more Special Patrolmen shall be evaluated utilizing the following criteria:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78069" number="89513" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Demonstrated need for Special Patrolman services.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78070" number="89514" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Financial ability to support adequate compensation, uniform, training, and supervision expenses.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78071" number="89515" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Establishment of training program and sufficient management supervision.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78072" number="89516" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Character and reputation of employer including any criminal activity associated with employer&apos;s operations.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78073" number="89517" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Prior experiences with Special Patrolmen engaged by employer.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78074" number="89518" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Compliance with the rules and requirements of this chapter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78075" number="89519" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Once an application for Special Patrolman appointment has been disapproved, or appointment once granted has been revoked, the disqualified individual shall be ineligible to file a new application for at least two (2) years, unless reinstated earlier after a suspension or revocation hearing.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78076" number="89520" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(l)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each Special Patrolman shall be required to sign an acknowledgment that s/he shall be responsible for compliance with all laws, rules, regulations, standards, and procedures promulgated by federal, state, or local jurisdictions, and by federal, state, or local law enforcement agencies, that are applicable to her/his appointment. The License Division shall provide the Special Patrolman with the acknowledgment statement. This acknowledgment statement shall be notarized. Failure to execute the acknowledgment statement and to have it notarized shall result in disapproval of the application.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78077" number="89521" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(m)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Special Patrolmen shall cooperate with all reasonable requests by the Police Department for information and assistance in matters relating to their designation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78078" number="89522" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(n)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If her/his application for special patrolman appointment is disapproved the applicant shall receive a written &quot;Notice of Application Disapproval&quot; from the License Division indicating the reason(s) for the disapproval. If the applicant wishes to appeal the decision s/he shall submit a sworn written statement, which shall be known as an &quot;Appeal of Application Disapproval,&quot; to the Division Head, License Division, within thirty (30) calendar days of the date on the &quot;Notice of Application Disapproval&quot; requesting an appeal of the denial, and setting forth the reasons supporting the appeal. The Appeal of Application Disapproval shall become part of the application. It shall state the grounds for the appeal and shall contain the following statement to be signed by the applicant and notarized: &quot;Under penalty of perjury, deponent being duly sworn, says that s/he is familiar with all of the statements contained herein and that each of these statements is true, and no pertinent facts have been omitted.&quot; Appeals that are unsworn by the applicant or submitted by individuals or business entities other than the applicant or her/his New York State licensed attorney shall not be accepted. All timely appeals shall receive a complete review of the applicant&apos;s entire file by the Division Head, License Division, who shall notify the applicant of her/his determination. The Division Head, License Division shall not consider any documentation that was not submitted during the initial background investigation. There shall be no personal interviews to discuss appeals. If the appeal of her/his disapproval is denied, the applicant shall receive a &quot;Notice of Disapproval After Appeal&quot; letter from the Division Head, License Division. This notice concludes the Police Department&apos;s administrative review procedure.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78079" number="89523" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 13-02 Cancellations, Suspensions and Revocations.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10299" name="T38C013_13-02"/>§ 13-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cancellations, Suspensions and Revocations.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78080" number="89524" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A Special Patrolman and her/his employer shall immediately notify the License Division of the Police Department, Special Patrolman Section, whenever an employee, appointed as Special Patrolman is:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78081" number="89525" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Arrested.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78082" number="89526" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Suspended from employment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78083" number="89527" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Terminated from employment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78084" number="89528" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Disabled or subject to a condition which prevents the Special Patrolman from being able to perform the duties of a Special Patrolman.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78085" number="89529" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Transferred to a position not requiring such appointment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78086" number="89530" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Involved in an incident which demonstrates conduct which is contrary to the purpose of appointment as a Special Patrolman, <CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">i.e.,</CHARFORMAT> the protection of property, or the safety of specific individuals or the public at large, and to her/his continued designation as a Special Patrolman.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78087" number="89531" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon receipt of this notice from the Special Patrolman, her/his employer, or otherwise, the License Division shall immediately notify the Special Patrolman and the employer that the appointment is cancelled, suspended or revoked.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78088" number="89532" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A Special Patrolman and her/his employer shall immediately notify the License Division of the Police Department, Special Patrolman Section, whenever said employee changes her/his address. The failure of a Special Patrolman and/or her/his employer to report a Special Patrolman&apos;s change of address to the Special Patrolman Section may result in the immediate revocation of the appointment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78089" number="89533" version="351">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The appointment of a Special Patrolman may also be cancelled, suspended or revoked by the Police Commissioner on her/his own initiative for any of the reasons enumerated in 38 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T38C013_13-02" destination-id="0-0-0-10299">13-02</LINK>(a) above, or upon a finding that a condition exists, which would be cause for a disapproval of an application, or revocation, as aforesaid. In appropriate circumstances, the approval for an employer to participate in the Special Patrolman program may be revoked.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78090" number="89534" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When a cancellation, suspension or revocation is initiated by the Police Department, written notice shall be given to the employer and the employee whose designation has been cancelled, suspended or revoked, advising them of the reasons for the action taken.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78091" number="89535" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 13-03 Appeal from Written Notice of Determination of Suspension or Revocation.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10301" name="T38C013_13-03"/>§ 13-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Appeal from Written Notice of Determination of Suspension or Revocation.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78092" number="89536" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An employer or suspended/former Special Patrolman may within thirty (30) calendar days from the date of the Notice of Determination Letter notifying the employer or Special Patrolman of suspension or revocation make a written request for a hearing to the Commanding Officer, License Division, One Police Plaza, Room 110A, New York, New York 10038.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78093" number="89537" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A Special Patrolman whose arrest or summons resulted in suspension or revocation of her/his appointment may only submit a written request for a hearing within thirty (30) calendar days after the termination of the criminal action, as defined in New York State Criminal Procedure Law § 1.20(16)(c). If the suspension or revocation resulted from the Special Patrolman becoming the subject of an order of protection or a temporary order of protection, the Special Patrolman may only submit a written request for a hearing within thirty (30) calendar days after the expiration or voiding of the order of protection or temporary order of protection. If the suspension or revocation was related to both a criminal action and an order of protection or temporary order of protection, then the later of the two waiting periods shall apply.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78094" number="89538" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 13-04 Uniform and Equipment.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10303" name="T38C013_13-04"/>§ 13-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Uniform and Equipment.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78095" number="89539" version="1876">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The shield of a Special Patrolman shall be of a design and color approved by the Police Commissioner. The Special Patrolman&apos;s uniform shall be prescribed by the employer, shall not resemble in any way the uniform of a New York City Police Officer, and shall be worn at all times while the Special Patrolman is on duty unless the Special Patrolman&apos;s identification card authorizes the wearing of civilian clothes or s/he is otherwise excused by the Police Commissioner. A Special Patrolman shall not wear her/his uniform while off-duty. (New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="14-107" destination-id="0-0-0-0">14-107</LINK>.)</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78096" number="89540" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When appointed, a Special Patrolman shall be provided with a shield and identification card. To insure the return of the shield, a $25 deposit shall be required for each shield issued. The deposit shall be refunded upon the return of the shield. The theft or loss of a shield or identification card shall be reported without delay to the precinct of occurrence and in writing to the License Division.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78097" number="89541" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification cards bearing the raised seal of the License Division, including an expiration date, shall be issued to Special Patrolmen who are in compliance with all applicable standards.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78098" number="89542" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon the death, resignation, termination of employment, cancellation, suspension or revocation of the appointment of a Special Patrolman, the employer shall cause the Special Patrolman&apos;s shield, identification card and pistol or revolver, if any, to be delivered to Police Department custody immediately, if this has not already been done.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78099" number="89543" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If handguns are required, applications for a handgun license authorizing the possession of a handgun in connection with Special Patrolman duties should be made to the License Division&apos;s Handgun License Application Section. A determination shall be made as to whether sufficient need exists for approval. It is a crime for a Special Patrolman to possess a handgun without having a valid handgun license therefor, and grounds for revocation of the Special Patrolman designation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78100" number="89544" version="1876">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If handcuffs are required, Special Patrolmen are restricted to possession while on duty or while traveling to and from their assigned place of duty. Unlawful possession of handcuffs is a criminal violation (New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="10-147" destination-id="0-0-0-0">10-147</LINK>(b)).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78101" number="89545" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 13-05 Conduct.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10305" name="T38C013_13-05"/>§ 13-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Conduct.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78102" number="89546" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>It is a crime for a Special Patrolman to represent her/himself as a Police Officer (§ 190.25 of the New York State Penal Law).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78103" number="89547" version="1876">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Unlawful use and possession of a police uniform, shields or emblems, as prescribed by § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="14-107" destination-id="0-0-0-0">14-107</LINK> of the New York City Administrative Code, shall be cause for revocation of a Special Patrolman designation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78104" number="89548" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A Special Patrolman shall be subject to the orders and regulations of the Police Commissioner, and shall cooperate in the performance of duty with members of the Police Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78105" number="89549" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon making an arrest, a Special Patrolman shall, without delay, bring the prisoner before the Desk Officer at the precinct in which the arrest is made, or directly to the Central Booking facility as appropriate.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78106" number="89550" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A Special Patrolman employed by a city or state governmental agency other than the New York City Police Department, which has a formalized procedure for the issuing, recording, and forwarding of summonses for personnel of the agency concerned, shall comply with the regulations of that agency. Any other Special Patrolman who serves a summons shall deliver the necessary papers to the Desk Officer of the precinct in which it was served, without delay.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78107" number="89551" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A Special Patrolman shall promptly notify the Special Patrolman Section of a change in residence, telephone number or employment status.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78108" number="89552" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If a Special Patrolman is arrested, s/he shall immediately notify her/his employer and the Special Patrolman Section of that occurrence.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78109" number="89553" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Non-compliance with any provision of these rules by a Special Patrolman may result in suspension or revocation of her/his designation. Non-compliance with any of these rules by an employer may result in revocation of its approval to participate in the Special Patrolman program.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78110" number="89554" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 13-06 Training.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10307" name="T38C013_13-06"/>§ 13-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Training.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78111" number="89555" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Persons appointed as Special Patrolmen by the Police Commissioner are mandated to have received training pursuant to New York State Criminal Procedure Law § 2.30(1), within 12 months of their designation. Employers are solely responsible for providing such training.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78112" number="89556" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Employers of Special Patrolmen shall be responsible for certifying to the Division Head, License Division that their designated personnel have completed the required training and shall submit copies of completion certificates to the License Division within 30 days of such training.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78113" number="89557" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Non-compliance with these mandated training provisions by employers or their designated Special Patrolmen shall be cause for revocation of their designations and revocation of approval for the employer to participate in the Special Patrolman program.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-78114" number="89558" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 13-07 Required Reports.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10309" name="T38C013_13-07"/>§ 13-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Required Reports.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78115" number="89559" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Agencies, institutions, et al., employing persons appointed as Special Patrolmen are solely responsible for compliance with mandatory reporting requirements as established by the New York State Division of Criminal Justice Services. Tel: (518) 457-6101.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-78116" number="89560" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Failure to comply with New York State Division of Criminal Justice Services mandated reporting requirements may be grounds for removal from the Special Patrolman program.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>