<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-25466" number="29397" version="2455">
			<HEADING>Chapter 14: Rules Concerning the Use of Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel and Emissions Control Technology in Nonroad Vehicles Used in City Construction</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3481" name="T15C014"/>Chapter 14: Rules Concerning the Use of Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel and Emissions Control Technology in Nonroad Vehicles Used in City Construction</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-25467" number="29398" version="3">
				<HEADING>Subchapter A: General Provisions</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter A: General Provisions</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25468" number="29399" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 14-01 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3483" name="T15C014_14-01"/>§ 14-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25469" number="29400" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Code.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Code&quot; shall mean the Administrative Code of the City of New York. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25470" number="29401" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commissioner.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Commissioner&quot; shall mean the commissioner of the New York City Department of Environmental Protection or his or her designee. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25471" number="29402" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Nonroad engine.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Nonroad engine&quot; shall mean an internal combustion engine (including the fuel system) that is not used in a motor vehicle or a vehicle used solely for competition, or that is not subject to standards promulgated under § 7411 or § 7521 of Title 42 of the United States code, except that this term shall apply to internal combustion engines used to power generators, compressors or similar equipment used in any construction program or project. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25472" number="29403" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Nonroad vehicle.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Nonroad vehicle&quot; shall mean a vehicle powered by a nonroad engine, fifty horsepower and greater, and that is not a motor vehicle or a vehicle used solely for competition, which shall include, but not be limited to, excavators, backhoes, cranes, compressors, generators, bulldozers, and similar equipment, except that this term shall not apply to horticultural maintenance vehicles used for landscaping purposes that are powered by a nonroad engine of sixty-five horsepower or less and that are not used in any construction program or project. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25473" number="29404" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Ultra low sulfur diesel fuel.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Ultra low sulfur diesel fuel&quot; shall mean diesel fuel that has a sulfur content of no more than fifteen parts per million.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-25474" number="29405" version="3">
				<HEADING>Subchapter B: Use of Best Available Technology and Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter B: Use of Best Available Technology and Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25475" number="29406" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 14-02 Best Available Technology Determination.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3485" name="T15C014_14-02"/>§ 14-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Best Available Technology Determination.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25476" number="29407" version="2503">
									<PARA>An engine that has been certified to meet the United States Environmental Protection Agency&apos;s (&quot;EPA&quot;) Tier IV Exhaust Emission Standards is deemed to be using the Best Available Technology (&quot;BAT&quot;), and does not require additional retrofit technologies. EPA&apos;s Tier IV Exhaust Emission Standards are described in Table 1 of the EPA&apos;s Clean Air Nonroad Diesel Rule Fact Sheet, EPA420-F-04-032, May 2004, available at <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="http://www.epa.gov/nonroaddiesel/2004fr/420f04032.htm">http://www.epa.gov/nonroaddiesel/2004fr/420f04032.htm</LINK>. If an engine has not been certified to meet the Tier IV Exhaust Emission Standards, pursuant to § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-163.3" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-163.3</LINK> of the Administrative Code, the BAT that must be utilized is one of the following, provided, that this technology shall achieve the greatest reduction in emissions of particulate matter and shall in no event result in an increase in the emissions of either particulate matter or nitrogen oxides: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25477" number="29408" version="748">
									<PARA>&#160;<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Category I (a)</CHARFORMAT> Any properly installed and functioning system utilizing a Diesel Particulate Filter (&quot;DPF&quot;) that primarily reduces emissions of particulate matter (&quot;PM&quot;), demonstrating an 85% or greater reduction in PM, and secondarily nitrogen oxide (&quot;NOx&quot;) that appears on either the United States Environmental Protection Agency (&quot;EPA&quot;) or the California Air Resources Board (&quot;CARB&quot;) verified lists at <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="http://www.epa.gov/otaq/retrofit/verif-list.htm">http://www.epa.gov/otaq/retrofit/verif-list.htm</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="http://www.arb.ca.gov/diesel/verdev/background.htm">http://www.arb.ca.gov/diesel/verdev/background.htm</LINK> for onroad or nonroad engines. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25478" number="29409" version="748">
									<PARA>&#160;<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Category I (b)</CHARFORMAT> Any properly installed DPF from either the EPA or CARB verified lists. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25479" number="29410" version="748">
									<PARA>&#160;<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Category I(c)</CHARFORMAT> A filter that has undergone the Verminderung der Emissionen Realer Dieselmotoren im Tunnelbau (&quot;VERT&quot;) test procedure and appears as approved for continuous use on the VERT list maintained by <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="http://akpf.org/pub/vert__filterliste.pdf">http://akpf.org/pub/vert__filterliste.pdf</LINK> or similar test procedures to those conducted by EPA/CARB and has demonstrated an 85% or greater reduction in emissions of PM. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25480" number="29411" version="748">
									<PARA>&#160;<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Category II</CHARFORMAT> Any properly installed and functioning system utilizing a Flow through Filer (&quot;FTF&quot;) that primarily reduces emissions of particulate matter (&quot;PM&quot;) and secondarily nitrogen oxide (&quot;NOx&quot;) that appears on either the verified lists for onroad or nonroad engines or any properly installed FTF on the verified list and that produces the greater PM reduction but not less than a 50% reduction in PM. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25481" number="29412" version="748">
									<PARA>&#160;<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Category III</CHARFORMAT> Any properly installed and functioning system utilizing a Diesel Oxidation Catalyst (&quot;DOC&quot;) or any emulsified diesel fuel that appears on either the EPA or CARB verified lists for onroad or nonroad engines that produces not less than a 25% reduction in FM. Fuel technologies must be compatible with the use of ultra low sulfur diesel fuel.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25482" number="29413" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 14-03 Method of Best Available Technology Selection.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3487" name="T15C014_14-03"/>§ 14-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Method of Best Available Technology Selection.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25483" number="29414" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any contractor or agency operating a type of nonroad vehicle must select the appropriate BAT for use with such type of nonroad vehicle. For each type of nonroad vehicle subject to the BAT requirement, the contractor or agency operating such type of vehicle must identify, in list form, all types of pollution control technology devices that qualify as BAT in Category I for such nonroad vehicle.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25484" number="29415" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All types of pollution control technology devices identified by the contractor or agency as Category I (a) BAT that are not technologically feasible for use with the subject type of nonroad vehicle are to be eliminated from the list of Category I (a) BAT. To eliminate a specific type of pollution control technology or individual device, the contractor or agency must demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Commissioner and document that operational constraints or physical, chemical or engineering principles preclude the successful and effective use of the nonroad vehicle when used with the specific pollution control technologies of that type. The contractor or agency shall then consider DPFs that satisfy the requirements set forth in Category I(b). If use of a Category I(b) DPF is technologically feasible, the contractor or agency must notify the Commissioner of the selection and the installation schedule. If none are technologically feasible, the contractor or agency shall select the technology devices set forth in Category I(c).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25485" number="29416" version="2455">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If, after the elimination process, no technologies remain in Category I (a), (b), or (c) from which the contractor or agency can select a BAT, the contractor or agency shall apply for Approval of a Written Finding of Unavailability. Upon approval by the DEP, the same identification and elimination process shall be done for Category II. If, after the elimination process, no technologies remain in Category II from which the contractor or agency can select a BAT, the same identification and elimination process shall be done for Category III. If, after the elimination process, no technologies remain in Category III from which the contractor or agency can select a BAT, the contractor or agency operating the subject nonroad vehicle shall apply for an Approval of a Written Finding of Unavailability or a Safety Waiver.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25486" number="29417" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Once a category is selected as provided for in (c) above, an economic impact analysis is to be performed on the remaining technologies if the technology reduces both PM and NOx. If the cost of the technology that provides NOx control is equal to or greater than thirty percent more than that of the technology without NOx control, then the technology without NOx control shall be selected. For the purpose of this paragraph, the criteria that shall be considered is the cost of the strategies, themselves and the cost of installation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25487" number="29418" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For newly purchased vehicles, BAT may be Original Equipment Manufacturer (&quot;OEM&quot;) installed control technology, provided that the technology is selected in a manner such that it provides the greatest reduction in particulate matter above the PM standard that the EPA has certified without increasing NOx and that reduction is verified by the manufacturer. The BAT need not be on EPA or CARB verified retrofit lists.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25488" number="29419" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The contractor or agency must use the pollution control technology identified as BAT by the process set forth in this subchapter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25489" number="29420" version="1813">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Prior to the installation of the selected technology, the contractor or agency shall notify the DEP of the BAT selection and contact the DEP when the DPF or other BAT is installed pursuant to this chapter and § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-163.3" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-163.3</LINK> of the Administrative Code. The contractor or agency shall make arrangements to have the unit inspected and registered and the DEP shall label the vehicle as compliant. The contractor shall retain all documentation generated in the BAT selection process for as long as the selected BAT is in use. A contractor&apos;s failure to fully document the selection process or to provide such documentation shall be considered a violation of subdivision e of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-163.3" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-163.3</LINK> and is subject to applicable penalties.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25490" number="29421" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 14-04 Best Available Technology Selection Applicability.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3489" name="T15C014_14-04"/>§ 14-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Best Available Technology Selection Applicability.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25491" number="29422" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The BAT listed in this subchapter may be amended, superseded, or repealed at any time. However, no contractor or agency will be required to replace a selected BAT within three years of first using such BAT on any nonroad vehicle.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25492" number="29423" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A contractor or agency who is using a DPF that does not appear on the EPA or CARB verified lists may use such DPF for three years from the date it was first installed. After such three-year period, if such DPF does not appear on either the EPA or CARB verified lists, such DPF may not be used in nonroad vehicles used in City projects.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25493" number="29424" version="2455">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A contractor or agency who is using Category I(c) technology may use such technology for three years from the date it was first installed. After such three-year period, if such technology does not appear on either the EPA or CARB verified lists, such technology may not be used in nonroad vehicles used in City projects.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25494" number="29425" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A contractor or agency that has installed technology that appears on either the EPA and/or CARB verified lists at the time of installation, but which has been removed from the EPA and/or CARB verified lists during the thirty months following installation, may not use such technology in nonroad vehicles used in City projects at the conclusion of the three-year period following installation. A contractor or agency that has installed technology that appears on the EPA and/or CARB verified lists at the time of installation, but which has been removed from the EPA and/or CARB verified lists during the six months preceding the conclusion of the three-year period following installation, or at any time after the conclusion of such three-year period, may use such technology in nonroad vehicles for an additional six months following the date it was removed from the EPA and/or CARB verified lists.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25495" number="29426" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 14-05 Use of Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3491" name="T15C014_14-05"/>§ 14-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Use of Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25496" number="29427" version="3">
									<PARA>All nonroad vehicles subject to this rule must be powered by ultra low sulfur diesel fuel, regardless of which BAT is selected, unless the Commissioner has issued a written determination pursuant to subdivision i of § 24-163.3 permitting the use of diesel fuel that has a sulfur content of no more than thirty parts per million.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25497" number="29428" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 14-06 Public Works Contracts.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3493" name="T15C014_14-06"/>§ 14-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Public Works Contracts.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25498" number="29429" version="2309">
									<PARA>Any contractor acting pursuant to a public works contract that is subject to the provisions of paragraph four of subdivision f of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-163.3" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-163.3</LINK>, but not paragraph one or three of such subdivision, shall comply with this subchapter and Subchapters A and C of this chapter as of June 19, 2005.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-25499" number="29430" version="3">
				<HEADING>Subchapter C: Waiver Procedures</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter C: Waiver Procedures</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25500" number="29431" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 14-07 Application for Approval of a Written Finding of Unavailability.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3495" name="T15C014_14-07"/>§ 14-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application for Approval of a Written Finding of Unavailability.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25501" number="29432" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the BAT required for any nonroad vehicle is unavailable, an agency may submit a Written Finding of Unavailability for the Commissioner&apos;s approval. Any application for approval of a Written Finding of Unavailability for the applicable BAT must contain the following information:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25502" number="29433" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name of the agency applying for approval of the Written Finding of Unavailability;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25503" number="29434" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name and identification number of the subject contract, if applicable;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25504" number="29435" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification of the specific nonroad vehicle that is the subject of the Written Finding of Unavailability;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25505" number="29436" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification of the required BAT;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25506" number="29437" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An explanation as to why the applicable BAT is unavailable. Such explanation must include all documentation generated in the BAT selection process described in this chapter;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25507" number="29438" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification of a technology for reducing the emission of pollutants, if any, that is available and appropriate for such vehicle, which may include a technology that does not appear on the EPA or CARB verified lists, and that, if available and appropriate, will be used instead of the BAT.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25508" number="29439" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name and contact number of the applicant.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25509" number="29440" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications should be sent to: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25510" number="29441" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Director of the Division of Air and Noise Programs, Enforcement and Policy <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Bureau of Environmental Compliance <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>New York City Department of Environmental Protection <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>59-17 Junction Blvd. <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Flushing, NY 11373 </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25511" number="29442" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Department will make a determination whether to approve the Written Finding of Unavailability no later than thirty days after receipt of the Written Finding.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25512" number="29443" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Approvals shall expire 180 days after issuance, unless the agency renews the Written Finding and the Commissioner approves such Finding, in accordance with the procedures set forth in subdivisions (a), (b) and (c) of this section. Any such application for renewal shall be submitted no later than thirty days prior to the expiration date of the approval.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25513" number="29444" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 14-08 Application for a Safety Waiver.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3497" name="T15C014_14-08"/>§ 14-08 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application for a Safety Waiver.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25514" number="29445" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any application for a waiver from the applicable BAT must contain the following information:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25515" number="29446" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If a contractor applies, the name of the contractor applying for the waiver and the agency to which the contractor is under contract;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25516" number="29447" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If an agency applies, the name of the agency applying for the waiver;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25517" number="29448" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name and identification number of the subject contract, if applicable;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25518" number="29449" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification of the specific nonroad vehicle that is the subject of the waiver request;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25519" number="29450" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification of the required BAT;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25520" number="29451" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A technical explanation as to why use of such Best Available Technology may endanger the operator of the vehicle or those working near the vehicle, due to engine malfunction;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25521" number="29452" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification of a technology for reducing the emission of pollutants, if any, that is available and appropriate for such vehicle, which may include a technology that does not appear on EPA or CARB verified lists, and that, if available and appropriate, will be used instead of the BAT;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25522" number="29453" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name and contact number of the applicant.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25523" number="29454" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Waiver applications should be sent to: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25524" number="29455" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Director of the Division of Air and Noise Programs, Enforcement and Policy <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Bureau of Environmental Compliance <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>New York City Department of Environmental Protection <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>59-17 Junction Blvd. <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Flushing, NY 11373 </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25525" number="29456" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Department will make a determination whether to issue a waiver no later than thirty days after receipt of the waiver request.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25526" number="29457" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Waivers shall expire 180 days after issuance, unless the Commissioner renews the waiver in accordance with the procedures set forth in subdivisions (a), (b) and (c) of this section. Any such application for renewal shall be submitted no later than thirty days prior to the expiration date of the waiver.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>