<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-96475" number="64776" version="29">
			<HEADING>Chapter 20: Rules Concerning Article 7-a of the Real Property Actions and Proceedings Law</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7717" name="T28C020"/>Chapter 20: Rules Concerning Article 7-a of the Real Property Actions and Proceedings Law</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-56745" number="64777" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 20-01 Criteria for Appointment.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7719" name="T28C020_20-01"/>§ 20-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Criteria for Appointment.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-56746" number="64778" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person proposed for appointment as an administrator pursuant to Article 7-A of the Real Property Actions and Proceedings Law shall, prior to appointment:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-56747" number="64779" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>be a graduate of the 7-A Training Program administered by the Department of Housing Preservation and Development and submit to a review by the Inspector General of the Department in relation to matters which are within the jurisdiction of such Inspector General, or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-56748" number="64780" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>if such person is not a graduate of such Program, possess experience which, in the discretion of the Department, warrants appointment as an administrator and such person submits to a review by the Inspector General of the Department in relation to matters which are within the jurisdiction of such Inspector General, or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-56749" number="64781" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>if such person is not a graduate of such Program and if such person does not possess experience which warrants appointment as an administrator, consents in good faith as a condition for such appointment to enroll in and graduate from such Program and such person submits to a review by the Inspector General of the Department in relation to matters which are within the jurisdiction of such Inspector General.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-56750" number="64782" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the purposes of subdivision (a) of this section, the evaluation of the &quot;experience&quot; of such person may include, but is not limited to, consideration of the ownership or management history of residential property by such person, whether such person served previously as a 7-A administrator or as a manager of City-owned property and, if such person was previously a 7-A administrator, the date or dates of prior appointments, compliance with prior Court orders of appointment, compliance with reporting requirements of the Department&apos;s 7-A Counseling and Assistant Unit, and such other indicators of experience which may be contained in the records of the Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-56751" number="64783" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 20-02 Applicability.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7721" name="T28C020_20-02"/>§ 20-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Applicability.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-56752" number="64784" version="3">
									<PARA>These rules apply to any building for which (i) an administrator is appointed pursuant to Article 7-A of the Real Property Actions and Proceedings Law (&quot;RPAPL&quot;) on or after August 19, 2003, or (ii) an administrator was appointed pursuant to Article 7-A of the RPAPL prior to August 19, 2003 and has not been discharged as of August 19, 2003.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-56753" number="64785" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 20-03 Regulatory Agreement.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7723" name="T28C020_20-03"/>§ 20-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Regulatory Agreement.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-56754" number="64786" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When a building covered by these rules is transferred to a new owner at any time following appointment of such administrator, § 778(10) of the RPAPL authorizes the Department of Housing Preservation and Development (&quot;Department&quot;) to enter into a regulatory agreement (&quot;Regulatory Agreement&quot;) with the new owner.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-56755" number="64787" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A Regulatory Agreement shall require the new owner to provide adequate, safe and sanitary housing accommodations for persons of low income, as such term is defined in Subdivision 19 of § 2 of the Private Housing Finance Law, for a period of not less than thirty years and may require such additional provisions as the Department deems appropriate, including, but not limited to, income and occupancy restrictions and a plan for the continuing repair and maintenance of the property.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-56756" number="64788" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A Regulatory Agreement shall include a certification by the new owner of the real property containing such building that (i) the prior owner has no direct or indirect interest in such real property, and (ii) the prior owner has no direct or indirect interest in such new owner.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-56757" number="64789" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A Regulatory Agreement may provide that, upon transfer of such building to the new owner, any outstanding liens filed with and recorded by the City pursuant to § 778(1) of the RPAPL and § 309 of the Multiple Dwelling Law shall immediately be reduced to zero upon execution of such Regulatory Agreement.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-56758" number="64790" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 20-04 Miscellaneous Provisions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-7725" name="T28C020_20-04"/>§ 20-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Miscellaneous Provisions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-56759" number="64791" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All determinations to be made by the Department in accordance with these rules shall be in the sole discretion of the Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-56760" number="64792" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing in these rules shall be deemed to limit the Department&apos;s authority pursuant to any applicable law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-56761" number="64793" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Provided that there has been a good faith effort to comply with these rules, technical violations of these rules shall not invalidate any action taken pursuant to these rules, nor shall such technical violations give rise to any rights, claims or causes of action. The Commissioner, upon good cause shown, may alter the timing or sequence of the actions described in these rules, provided all affected parties are given reasonable notice.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>