<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-38651" number="45636" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 24: Refunds of Real Property Taxes</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5341" name="T19C024"/>Chapter 24: Refunds of Real Property Taxes</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38652" number="45637" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 24-01 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5343" name="T19C024_24-01"/>§ 24-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38653" number="45638" version="748">
									<PARA>Unless the context requires otherwise, as used in these rules: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38654" number="45639" version="1108">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Assessment.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Assessment&quot; means charges other than real property taxes, water charges and sewer rents, that are imposed on real property in the City of New York and which remain a lien on such real property until paid. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38655" number="45640" version="1108">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Beneficial owner.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Beneficial owner&quot; means an individual or entity that has an ownership interest in excess of fifty percent of either (i) the real property or (ii) the entity that is the record owner of the property. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38656" number="45641" version="1108">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Department.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Department&quot; means the New York City Department of Finance. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38657" number="45642" version="1108">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Ordinary overpayment.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Ordinary overpayment&quot; means an overpayment, as defined herein, that resulted from means other than real property assessment review proceedings. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38658" number="45643" version="1108">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Overpayment.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Overpayment&quot; means a payment that exceeds the amount of the real property taxes, water and sewer charges or assessments for which the payment was intended. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38659" number="45644" version="1108">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Record owner.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Record owner&quot; means the owner of a property as it appears on the records of the New York City Department of Finance. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38660" number="45645" version="1108">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Taxpayer.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Taxpayer&quot; means the payor of a tax, water and sewer charge or assessment, whether or not such party is the owner of the property to which the payment was applied. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38661" number="45646" version="1108">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Tax year.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Tax year&quot; means the fiscal year of the City of New York, which commences July 1 and ends June 30. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38662" number="45647" version="1108">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Transfer of overpayment.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Transfer of overpayment&quot; means the application of a credit to an unpaid tax, charge or assessment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38663" number="45648" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 24-02 Ordinary Overpayments and Double Payments.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5345" name="T19C024_24-02"/>§ 24-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Ordinary Overpayments and Double Payments.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38664" number="45649" version="3">
									<PARA>Any application required by the Commissioner of Finance for refunds (or transfers) of over and double payments of real property taxes, assessments, water charges and sewers rents may be made by filing an application on a form or in a format established by the Commissioner of Finance, plus any documentation requested by the Department in order to evidence that the applicant is entitled to the refund or transfer of the overpayment, within six years after the date of the over or double payment. Any such documentation required may include, but is not limited to, copies of both sides of cancelled checks, receipted bills, a printout of the confirmation of payment of taxes by electronic means, statements or other documentation from the taxpayer&apos;s bank or an affidavit setting forth facts alleged by the applicant.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38665" number="45650" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 24-03 Real Property Assessment Review Proceedings.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5347" name="T19C024_24-03"/>§ 24-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Real Property Assessment Review Proceedings.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38666" number="45651" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application for refund.</CHARFORMAT> Refunds (or transfers) of overpayments of real property taxes resulting from a Tax Commission remission order or a Supreme Court order or judgment entered after trial or pursuant to settlement in a real property assessment review proceeding may be obtained in accordance with § 726 of the Real Property Tax Law only by filing an application on a form or in a format established by the Commissioner of Finance, plus any other documentation requested by the Department in order to evidence that the applicant is entitled to the refund or transfer of the overpayment, within three (3) years of the entry of the Supreme Court order or judgment, or within six (6) years of the date of the Tax Commission order, as the case may be. Other documentation required may include, but is not limited to, a copy of the Supreme Court order or judgment, if any, copies of both sides of cancelled checks, a printout of the confirmation of payment of taxes by electronic means, statements or other documentation from the taxpayer&apos;s bank or an affidavit setting forth facts alleged by the applicant.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38667" number="45652" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Interest on refunds.</CHARFORMAT> Interest shall be paid on the amount of any refund made pursuant to this section that resulted from a Supreme Court order or judgment, to be computed from the date of payment of the tax or portion thereof to be refunded until the date of such order or judgment. Interest shall also be paid on the amount of such refund for the period after the entry of a final order or judgment but shall accrue only from the date on which an application for Audit and Payment of such refund was duly made to the Department of Finance in accordance with the requirements of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38668" number="45653" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 24-04 Department of Finance Application of Overpayments to Arrears in Real Property Taxes and Property-Related Charges.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5349" name="T19C024_24-04"/>§ 24-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department of Finance Application of Overpayments to Arrears in Real Property Taxes and Property-Related Charges.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38669" number="45654" version="3">
									<PARA>With respect to an overpayment of real property taxes or property-related charges on a property for which there are unpaid taxes or charges, the Department of Finance may apply the overpayment to satisfy such unpaid taxes and charges and refund only the balance of the overpayment, if any, that remains after the Department has so applied the overpayment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38670" number="45655" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 24-05 Transfer of Overpayment.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5351" name="T19C024_24-05"/>§ 24-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Transfer of Overpayment.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38671" number="45656" version="3">
									<PARA>A taxpayer may transfer an overpayment from one property to another under the following conditions:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38672" number="45657" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An overpayment may be transferred only between properties owned by the same beneficial owner.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38673" number="45658" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A transfer of an overpayment from one property to another shall have no effect on the accrual of interest as required by law on arrears on the property to which the overpayment is transferred. Nothing in this provision, however, shall prevent the taxpayer from requesting that an overpayment, or a portion thereof, be applied to interest on the property to which the overpayment is transferred.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38674" number="45659" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the event that an application for a transfer of an overpayment concerns properties that are not owned by the same record owner, the applicant must furnish proof required to establish that the properties are owned by the same beneficial owner. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38675" number="45660" version="1108">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 1:</CHARFORMAT> In January, 2007, X made an overpayment of real property taxes on property A in the amount of $1,000. Property B has an outstanding balance of real estate taxes and interest from July, 2008, in the amount of $1,000. There are no other outstanding charges on either of the two properties. X is the record owner of both property A and property B and desires to transfer the overpayment from property A to property B. X must submit to the Department a request for transfer of the overpayment pursuant to 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C024_24-02" destination-id="0-0-0-5345">24-02</LINK>. The $1,000 overpayment will be transferred from property A to property B to be applied to the outstanding balance on property B.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109596" number="45661" version="1108">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 2:</CHARFORMAT> The facts are the same as in Example 1 except that Y made the overpayment on property A. If X wishes to transfer the overpayment from property A to property B, X must submit to the Department an application pursuant to 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C024_24-02" destination-id="0-0-0-5345">24-02</LINK> certifying that X is entitled to the refund.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109595" number="45662" version="1108">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 3:</CHARFORMAT> In January, 2007, X made an overpayment of real property taxes on property A in the amount of $1,000. Property B has an outstanding balance of real estate taxes and interest in the amount of $2,000 from July, 2008. There are no other outstanding charges on either of the two properties. X owns 75% of the stock of X Corp. which is the record owner of property A. X also owns 75% of Y Corp. which is the record owner of property B. X desires to transfer the overpayment from property A to property B. X must submit to the Department an application pursuant to 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C024_24-02" destination-id="0-0-0-5345">24-02</LINK> together with any documentation requested by the Department to establish that X is the beneficial owner of both property A and property B. The $1,000 overpayment will be transferred from property A to property B to reduce the outstanding balance on property B by $1,000.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109594" number="45663" version="1108">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example 4:</CHARFORMAT> The facts are the same as in Example 3 except that X Corp. made the overpayment on property A. If X wishes to transfer the overpayment from property A to property B, X must submit to the Department an application pursuant to 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C024_24-02" destination-id="0-0-0-5345">24-02</LINK> certifying that X is entitled to the refund and any documentation requested by the Department to establish that X is the beneficial owner of both property A and property B. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>