<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-28952" number="33343" version="1940">
			<HEADING>Chapter 27: Rules Concerning the Use of Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel and Emissions Control Technology On Solid Waste Vehicles</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3855" name="T15C027"/>Chapter 27: Rules Concerning the Use of Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel and Emissions Control Technology On Solid Waste Vehicles</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-28953" number="33344" version="3">
				<HEADING>Subchapter A: General Provisions</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter A: General Provisions</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28954" number="33345" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 27-01 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3857" name="T15C027_27-01"/>§ 27-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28955" number="33346" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Best available retrofit technology.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Best available retrofit technology&quot; means a technology, verified by the United States environmental protection agency or the California air resources board, for reducing the emission of pollutants that achieves reductions in particulate matter emissions at the highest classification level for diesel emission control strategies, as set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C027_27-04" destination-id="0-0-0-3863">27-04</LINK>, that is applicable to the particular engine and application. Such technology shall also, at a reasonable cost, achieve the greatest reduction in emissions of nitrogen oxides at such particulate matter reduction level and shall in no event result in a net increase in the emissions of either particulate matter or nitrogen oxides. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28956" number="33347" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">City agency.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;City agency&quot; means a city, county, borough, administration, department, division, bureau, board or commission, or a corporation, institution or agency of government, the expenses of which are paid in whole or in part from the city treasury. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28957" number="33348" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commissioner.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Commissioner&quot; means the Commissioner of the New York City Department of Environmental Protection or her designee. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28958" number="33349" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Contractor.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Contractor&quot; means any person or entity that enters into a solid waste contract or recyclable materials contract with a city agency, or any person or entity that enters into an agreement with such person or entity, to perform work or provide labor or services related to such solid waste contract or recyclable materials contract. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28959" number="33350" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Motor vehicle.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Motor vehicle&quot; means a vehicle operated or driven upon a public highway which is propelled by any power other than muscular power, except electrically-driven mobility assistance devices operated or driven by a person with a disability. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28960" number="33351" version="2297">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Nonroad engine.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Nonroad engine&quot; means an internal combustion engine (including the fuel system) that is not used in a motor vehicle or a vehicle used solely for competition, or that is not subject to standards promulgated under section 7411 or section 7521 of title 42 of the United States Code, except that this term shall apply to internal combustion engines used to power generators, compressors or similar equipment used in the fulfillment of any solid waste contract or recyclable materials contract. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28961" number="33352" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Nonroad vehicle.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Nonroad vehicle&quot; means a vehicle that is powered by a nonroad engine, fifty horsepower and greater, and that is not a motor vehicle or a vehicle used solely for competition, which shall include, but not be limited to, front loaders, excavators, backhoes, cranes, compressors, generators, bulldozers and similar equipment. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28962" number="33353" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Operate primarily within the city of New York.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Operate primarily within the city of New York&quot; means that greater than fifty percent of the time spent or miles traveled by a motor vehicle or nonroad vehicle during the performance of a solid waste contract or recyclable materials contract occurs within the city of New York. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28963" number="33354" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Person.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Person&quot; means any natural person, co-partnership, firm, company, association, joint stock association, corporation or other like organization. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28964" number="33355" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Reasonable cost.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Reasonable cost&quot; shall mean that such technology does not cost greater than thirty percent more than other technology applicable to the particular engine and application that falls within the same classification level for diesel emission control strategies, as set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C027_27-04" destination-id="0-0-0-3863">27-04</LINK>, when considering the cost of the strategies, themselves, and the cost of installation. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28965" number="33356" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Recyclable materials.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Recyclable materials&quot; means solid waste that may be separated, collected, processed, marketed and returned to the economy in the form of raw materials or products, including but not limited to types of metal, glass, paper, plastic, food waste, tires and yard waste. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28966" number="33357" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Recyclable materials contract.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Recyclable materials contract&quot; means a contract with a city agency, the primary purpose of which is to provide for the handling, transport or disposal of recyclable materials. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28967" number="33358" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Solid waste.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Solid waste&quot; means all materials or substances discarded or rejected as being spent, useless, or worthless, including but not limited to garbage, refuse, industrial and commercial waste, sludges from air or water pollution control facilities or water supply treatment facilities, rubbish, ashes, contained gaseous material, incinerator residue, demolition and construction debris and offal, but not including sewage and other highly diluted water-carried materials or substances and those in gaseous forms. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28968" number="33359" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Solid waste contract.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Solid waste contract&quot; means a contract with a city agency, the primary purpose of which is to provide for the handling, transport or disposal of solid waste. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28969" number="33360" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Ultra low sulfur diesel fuel.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Ultra low sulfur diesel fuel&quot; shall mean diesel fuel that has a sulfur content of no more than fifteen parts per million.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-28970" number="33361" version="3">
				<HEADING>Subchapter B: Use of Best Available Retrofit Technology and Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter B: Use of Best Available Retrofit Technology and Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28971" number="33362" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 27-02 Best Available Retrofit Technology Requirement.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3859" name="T15C027_27-02"/>§ 27-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Best Available Retrofit Technology Requirement.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28972" number="33363" version="1813">
									<PARA>Pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-163.5" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-163.5</LINK> of the Code, any solid waste contract or recyclable materials contract shall specify that all diesel fuel-powered motor vehicles and diesel fuel-powered nonroad vehicles used in the performance of such contract that operate primarily within the City of New York shall use the Best Available Retrofit Technology (&quot;BART&quot;). All contractors in the performance of such contract shall utilize the &quot;BART&quot;, as defined in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C027_27-01" destination-id="0-0-0-3857">27-01</LINK>. In making their selections, contractors are directed to consult the EPA and CARB verified lists at <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="http://www.epa.gov/otaq/retrofit/retroverifiedlist.htm">http://www.epa.gov/otaq/retrofit/retroverifiedlist.htm</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="http://www.arb.ca.gov/diesel/verdev/background.htm">http://www.arb.ca.gov/diesel/verdev/background.htm</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28973" number="33364" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 27-03 Motor Vehicles and Nonroad Vehicles That Are Not Subject to BART.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3861" name="T15C027_27-03"/>§ 27-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Motor Vehicles and Nonroad Vehicles That Are Not Subject to BART.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28974" number="33365" version="2297">
									<PARA>Any diesel fuel-powered motor vehicle that is equipped with an engine certified to the applicable 2007 United States Environmental Protection Agency standard for particulate matter as set forth in section 86.007-11 of title 40 of the Code of Federal Regulations or to any subsequent United States environmental protection agency standard for such pollutant that is at least as stringent, shall not be required to utilize the BART as defined in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C027_27-01" destination-id="0-0-0-3857">27-01</LINK>. Any diesel fuel-powered nonroad vehicle that is equipped with an engine certified to the applicable United States environmental protection agency standard for particulate matter for such vehicle as set forth in the Control of Emissions of Air Pollution from Nonroad Diesel Engines and Fuel; Final Rule as set forth in the federal register at 69 Fed. Reg. 38,958 et seq., or to any subsequent United States environmental protection agency standard for such pollutant that is at least as stringent shall not be subject to the BART as defined in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C027_27-01" destination-id="0-0-0-3857">27-01</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28975" number="33366" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 27-04 Classification Levels.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3863" name="T15C027_27-04"/>§ 27-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Classification Levels.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28976" number="33367" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Level 4</CHARFORMAT> A Closed Crankcase Filtration System in combination with any Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF) or other technology verified for a specific application from either the CARB or EPA verified lists that reduces particulate matter emissions by 85 percent or greater, or reduces engine emissions to less than or equal to 0.01 grams diesel particulate matter per brake horsepower-hour. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28977" number="33368" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Level 3</CHARFORMAT> A Closed Crankcase Filtration System in combination with any DPF or Flow Through Filter or combination of technologies verified for a specific application from either the CARB or EPA verified lists that reduces diesel particulate matter emissions by between 50 and 84 percent. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28978" number="33369" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Level 2</CHARFORMAT> A Closed Crankcase Filtration System in combination with any DOC or Flow Through Filter or other technology verified for a specific application from either the CARB or EPA verified lists that reduces diesel particulate matter emissions by between 25 and 49 percent. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28979" number="33370" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Level 1</CHARFORMAT> A Closed Crankcase Filtration System in combination with any DOC or emulsified diesel fuel or Flow Through Filter or other technology verified for a specific application from either the CARB or EPA verified lists that reduces diesel particulate matter emissions by between 20 and 24 percent.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28980" number="33371" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 27-05 Selection Process.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3865" name="T15C027_27-05"/>§ 27-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Selection Process.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28981" number="33372" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each solid waste or recyclable materials contract that specifies that all diesel fuel-powered motor vehicles and diesel fuel-powered nonroad vehicles used in the performance of such contract that operate primarily within the city of New York shall utilize BART, the contractor operating such vehicle must identify, in list form, all types of pollution control technology devices verified for such vehicle at classification Level 4.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28982" number="33373" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All types of pollution control technology devices identified by the contractor as classification Level 4 devices that are not technologically feasible for use with respect to the particular vehicle, engine or application are to be eliminated from such list. To eliminate all types of pollution control technology devices identified by the contractor at classification Level 4, or a specific type of pollution control technology, or a particular pollution control technology device, the contractor must demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Commissioner that operational constraints or physical, chemical or engineering principles preclude the successful and effective use of the vehicle when used with such types of technology devices, or type of technology, or particular pollution control technology device.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28983" number="33374" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If, after the elimination process, no pollution control technology devices remain in classification Level 4 from which the contractor can select a BART, the same identification and elimination process must be done for classification Level 3. If, after the elimination process, no pollution control technology devices remain in classification Level 3 from which the contractor can select a BART, the same identification and elimination process must be done for classification Level 2. If, after the elimination process, no pollution control technology devices remain in classification Level 2 from which the contractor can select a BART, the same identification and elimination process must be done for classification Level 1.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28984" number="33375" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Once a level is selected as provided for in subdivisions (a), (b), and (c) of this section, an economic impact analysis is to be performed on the remaining technologies where the technology reduces both PM and nitrogen oxide (NOx). The contractor shall select the technology achieving, at a reasonable cost, the greatest reduction in NOx emissions. If the NOx emission does not meet the reasonable cost test, the technology that achieves the greatest PM reduction from the other remaining technologies must be selected.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28985" number="33376" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 27-06 Best Available Retrofit Technology Selection Applicability.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3867" name="T15C027_27-06"/>§ 27-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Best Available Retrofit Technology Selection Applicability.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28986" number="33377" version="3">
									<PARA>No contractor shall be required to replace a selected BART within three years of having first utilized such technology. Furthermore, no contractor shall be required to replace Level 4 technology until it has reached the end of its useful life.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28987" number="33378" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 27-07 Use of Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3869" name="T15C027_27-07"/>§ 27-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Use of Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28988" number="33379" version="3">
									<PARA>All solid waste or recyclable materials contracts shall specify that diesel fuel-powered motor vehicles and diesel fuel-powered nonroad vehicles used in the performance of such contracts that operate primarily in the City of New York shall be powered by ultra low sulfur diesel fuel (&quot;ULSDF&quot;).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-28989" number="33380" version="3">
				<HEADING>Subchapter C: Waiver Procedures</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter C: Waiver Procedures</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28990" number="33381" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 27-08 Application for Approval of a Written Finding of Unavailability for ULSDF.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3871" name="T15C027_27-08"/>§ 27-08 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application for Approval of a Written Finding of Unavailability for ULSDF.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28991" number="33382" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Once the solid waste contract or recyclable materials contract has been entered into, the Commissioner may issue a waiver for the use of ULSDF where the city agency that has entered into the contract makes a written finding that a sufficient quantity of ULSDF is unavailable. Any application for approval of a Written Finding of Unavailability for the ULSDF must contain the following information:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28992" number="33383" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name of the contractor applying for approval of the Written Finding of Unavailability;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28993" number="33384" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name and identification number of the subject contract;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28994" number="33385" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification of the specific diesel-fuel powered vehicle or diesel fuel-powered nonroad vehicle that is the subject of the Written Finding of Unavailability;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28995" number="33386" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An explanation as to why the ULSDF is unavailable.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28996" number="33387" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications should be sent to: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28997" number="33388" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Director of the Division of Air and Noise Programs, Enforcement and Policy <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Bureau of Environmental Compliance <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>New York City Department of Environmental Protection <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>59-17 Junction Blvd. <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Flushing, NY 11373 </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28998" number="33389" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Department will make a determination whether to approve the Written Finding of Unavailability no later than thirty days after receipt of the Written Finding.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28999" number="33390" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Waivers shall expire two months after issuance, unless the agency renews the Written Finding and the Commissioner approves such Finding, in accordance with the procedures set forth in subdivisions (a), (b) and (c) of this section. Any such application for renewal shall be submitted no later than thirty days prior to the expiration date of the approval.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-29000" number="33391" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 27-09 Application for Approval of a Written Finding of Unavailability for BART.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3873" name="T15C027_27-09"/>§ 27-09 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application for Approval of a Written Finding of Unavailability for BART.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29001" number="33392" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the BART required for a diesel fuel-powered motor vehicle or diesel fuel-powered nonroad vehicle that is subject to a solid waste contract or recyclable materials contract with a city agency is unavailable, and the city agency that has entered into the applicable contract has made a written finding that such technology is unavailable, the city agency may submit a Written Finding of Unavailability for the Commissioner&apos;s approval. Any application for approval of a Written Finding of Unavailability for the BART must contain the following information:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29002" number="33393" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name of the contractor applying for approval of the Written Finding of Unavailability;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29003" number="33394" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name and identification number of the subject contract;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29004" number="33395" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification of the specific diesel-fuel powered vehicle or diesel fuel-powered nonroad vehicle that is the subject of the Written Finding of Unavailability;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29005" number="33396" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification of the required BART;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29006" number="33397" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An explanation as to why the BART is unavailable. Such explanation must include all documentation generated in the BART selection process described in this chapter;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29007" number="33398" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification of a technology for reducing the emission of pollutants, if any, that is available and appropriate for such vehicle, which may include a technology that does not appear on the EPA or CARB verified lists, and that, if available and appropriate, will be used instead of the BART.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29008" number="33399" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name and contact number of the applicant.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29009" number="33400" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications should be sent to:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29010" number="33401" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Director of the Division of Air and Noise Programs, Enforcement and Policy <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Bureau of Environmental Compliance <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>New York City Department of Environmental Protection <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>59-17 Junction Blvd. <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Flushing, NY 11373 <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>or by email to bartwaivers@dep.nyc.gov <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-012]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29011" number="33402" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Department will make a determination whether to approve the Written Finding of Unavailability no later than thirty days after receipt of the Written Finding.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29012" number="33403" version="33">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Waivers shall expire three years after issuance, unless the agency renews the Written Finding and the Commissioner approves such Finding, in accordance with the procedures set forth in subdivisions (a), (b) and (c) of this section. Any such application for renewal shall be submitted no later than thirty days prior to the expiration date of the approval.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-96906" number="33404" version="33">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 3/15/2017, eff. 4/14/2017) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-012]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>