<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-29013" number="33405" version="33">
			<HEADING>Chapter 28: Citywide Construction Noise Mitigation</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3875" name="T15C028"/>Chapter 28: Citywide Construction Noise Mitigation</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-29014" number="33406" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 28-100 General Construction Noise Mitigation Plan.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3877" name="T15C028_28-100"/>§ 28-100 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">General Construction Noise Mitigation Plan.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29016" number="33407" version="1814">
									<PARA>In accordance with § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-219" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-219</LINK> and § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-220" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-220</LINK> of the New York City Noise Control Code, every construction site where construction activities take place shall have, conspicuously posted and filed with the Department of Environmental Protection (DEP), a complete and accurate Construction Noise Mitigation Plan, except such sites that will have emergency work completed within three days or less, shall not be required to file the plan. An after hours variance, pursuant to § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-223" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-223</LINK> of the Noise Control Code may be applied for if work is not possible during otherwise allowable hours. Such plan must be readily available for inspection at the construction site. The Construction Noise Mitigation Plan Form is available at: <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="http://www.nyc.gov/html/dep/html/noise/construction-noise.shtml">http://www.nyc.gov/html/dep/html/noise/construction-noise.shtml</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109920" number="33408" version="1185">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 9/18/2018, eff. 10/18/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-29017" number="33409" version="1185">
								<HEADING>§ 28-101 Required Noise Mitigation Measures for General Construction.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3879" name="T15C028_28-101"/>§ 28-101 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Required Noise Mitigation Measures for General Construction.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29018" number="33410" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party shall self-certify in its Construction Noise Mitigation Plan that all construction tools and equipment have been maintained so that they operate at normal manufacturer&apos;s operating specifications, including at peak loading. Such self-certification shall be indicated on the Construction Noise Mitigation Plan form required by 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-100" destination-id="0-0-0-3877">28-100</LINK>. Upon a DEP inspection of the work site, DEP shall use the noise level guidelines in the Federal Highway Administration Roadway Construction Noise Model User&apos;s Guide, Jan. 2006, page 3, located in the Appendix to this chapter, as a means of identifying equipment that may be the cause of a noise complaint. If an individual piece of equipment is identified by DEP as exceeding the level specified in such Guide located in the Appendix to this chapter, upon notification by DEP, the responsible party shall have the option of: (i) performing maintenance to demonstrate a good faith effort, notwithstanding the model year of the equipment, to mitigate the noise by a measurable level acceptable to the Department, (ii) replacing the equipment with equipment that complies with said level, or (iii) filing an Alternative Noise Mitigation Plan pursuant to 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-104" destination-id="0-0-0-3885">28-104</LINK>, within five business days of said inspection. If the responsible party elects to perform maintenance pursuant to option (i), but cannot demonstrate within five business days a reduction in noise by a measurable level acceptable to the Department, such party shall pursue one of the other two options to the satisfaction of the Department. The failure to exercise and complete one of such three options within five business days of said inspection shall be a violation of this rule. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29019" number="33411" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All construction equipment being operated on site must be equipped with the appropriate manufacturer&apos;s noise reduction device(s), including, but not limited to, a manufacturer&apos;s muffler (or equivalently rated material) that is free of rust, holes and exhaust leaks. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29020" number="33412" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party shall mitigate noise from construction devices with internal combustion engines by ensuring that the engine&apos;s housing doors are kept closed, and by using noise-insulating material mounted on the engine housing that does not interfere with the manufacturer&apos;s guidelines for engine operation or exhaust. The responsible party shall further reduce noise by operating the device at lower engine speeds during the work to the maximum extent possible. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29021" number="33413" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Portable compressors, generators, pumps and other such devices shall be covered with noise-insulating fabric to the maximum extent possible that does not interfere with the manufacturer&apos;s guidelines for engine operation or exhaust, and shall further reduce noise by operating the device at lower engine speeds during the work to the maximum extent possible. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29022" number="33414" version="1814">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vehicle engine idling on site shall be prevented in accordance with New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-163" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-163</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29023" number="33415" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Quieter back-up alarms shall be used in pre-2008 model year vehicles when practicable for the job site. 2008 model year or newer vehicles shall be equipped with a quieter back-up warning device in accordance with OSHA standards, as set forth in paragraph 4 of subdivision d of 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-102" destination-id="0-0-0-3881">28-102</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29024" number="33416" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When DOB regulations require a perimeter barrier, or &quot;construction fence,&quot; and the site is within 200 feet of a receptor or a receiving property as defined in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="" destination-id="0-0-0-3895">28-109</LINK>, perimeter noise barriers shall be fabricated in accordance with the standards set forth in subdivision e of 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-107" destination-id="0-0-0-3891">28-107</LINK> and lined with material set forth in subdivisions c and e of 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-107" destination-id="0-0-0-3891">28-107</LINK>. Further, the responsible party shall fill in any gaps and holes in adjacent panels of noise barriers with noise attenuation material, so as to maximize the effectiveness of such barriers. Such noise attenuation material shall include noise curtain material, additional plywood, or similar material. When viewing ports are required in the curtain material, they shall be filled in with clear plastic attached to the curtain. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29025" number="33417" version="1953">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The contractor shall create and utilize a noise mitigation training program, which shall be implemented for all field-worker supervisory personnel including subcontractor supervisors. Supervisory personnel shall field-train all field workers to minimize construction noise. Such training program shall be developed in consultation with DEP. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29026" number="33418" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When work is planned near sensitive receptors, including but not limited to facilities such as schools, hospitals, places of worship, and homes for the aging, the responsible party shall cooperate with the facility owner or operator to coordinate the work schedule so as to minimize the noise impact on the facility. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29027" number="33419" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>j.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A DEP inspector may visit a construction site to examine the Noise Mitigation Plan upon receiving a complaint, or as a matter of routine inspection, to ensure that the responsible party is complying with such Plan. A responsible party found not to be complying with such Plan shall be provided a cure period of three business days to correct the condition or to file an Alternative Noise Mitigation Plan under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-104" destination-id="0-0-0-3885">28-104</LINK>. If the condition is not corrected nor an Alternative Noise Mitigation Plan filed with DEP within three business days, then a Notice of Violation shall be issued against the responsible party. Said violations may be issued on-site or by mail. Notwithstanding the preceding sentences in this subdivision, there shall be no cure period afforded with respect to compliance with 15 RCNY §§ <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-100" destination-id="0-0-0-3877">28-100</LINK>; <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(a), (b), (e), (f), (h); <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-104" destination-id="0-0-0-3885">28-104</LINK>; <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-105" destination-id="0-0-0-3887">28-105</LINK>; and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-106" destination-id="0-0-0-3889">28-106</LINK>(a), (b), (d) (g) &amp; (i). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29028" number="33420" version="2461">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>k.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Construction activities may take place during the hours of 7:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m. on weekdays. At all other times, the permittee shall obtain after-hours authorization, pursuant to 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-103" destination-id="0-0-0-3883">28-103</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29029" number="33421" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>l.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where construction projects are of shorter duration of less than 15 days and within the property line and do not require Department of Buildings (DOB) perimeter barriers (&quot;construction fences&quot;), and where the work site is within 75 feet of a residential receptor, a temporary or portable (i.e. unanchored) noise barrier shall be fabricated in accordance with the specifications in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-108" destination-id="0-0-0-3893">28-108</LINK>. For long-term street work, defined as 15 days or longer, that is outside the property line and within 75 feet of a residential receptor and where there is a dedicated lane available, a temporary barrier in accordance with the specifications in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-108" destination-id="0-0-0-3893">28-108</LINK> shall be required. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29030" number="33422" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>m.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever a responsible party is engaged in sandblasting operations that require a perimeter or other barrier during sandblasting, said barrier shall be lined with noise barrier material as set forth in subdivision e of 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-107" destination-id="0-0-0-3891">28-107</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29031" number="33423" version="1186">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>n.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Responsible parties conducting construction and roadway work that will commence and be completed within a continuous period of no longer than 24 hours or for emergency work that will last no longer than three consecutive days, need not file with DEP a Construction Noise Mitigation Plan. However, the responsible party for such construction work shall not create unreasonable noise. In addition, if the work occurs near or adjacent to a sensitive receptor as defined in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(i), then the responsible party shall make modifications including scheduling changes or employing additional noise mitigation methods listed in 15 RCNY §§ <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-102" destination-id="0-0-0-3881">28-102</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-107" destination-id="0-0-0-3891">28-107</LINK>, and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-108" destination-id="0-0-0-3893">28-108</LINK>. This subdivision shall not apply to construction work that occurs after hours. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29032" number="33424" version="204">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>o.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Technical terms in these rules are defined in the Noise Code or in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="" destination-id="0-0-0-3895">28-109</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109922" number="33425" version="1186">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 9/18/2018, eff. 10/18/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-29033" number="33426" version="1186">
								<HEADING>§ 28-102 Construction Devices and Activities.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3881" name="T15C028_28-102"/>§ 28-102 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction Devices and Activities.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29034" number="33427" version="748">
									<PARA>The devices listed in this section require additional noise mitigation. A responsible party using any of these devices shall mitigate the noise by following the rules set forth in this section for the specific device. There are five categories of devices: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29039" number="33428" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Impact Equipment: Pile Drivers, Jackhammers, Hoe Rams, Blasting.<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Earth Moving Devices: Vacuum Excavators.<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Construction Trucks: Dump Trucks.<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Stationary Devices: Cranes, Auger Drills, Street Plates, Backup Alarms.<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Manual Devices: Concrete Saws. If the responsible party cannot in good faith comply with the noise mitigation rules for each device, the responsible party shall file with DEP an Alternative Noise Mitigation Plan in accordance with 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-104" destination-id="0-0-0-3885">28-104</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29040" number="33429" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Impact Equipment.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29041" number="33430" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Pile Drivers.</CHARFORMAT> This rule provides noise mitigation strategies that responsible parties shall utilize in order to reduce the noise emissions from pile driving and related equipment. Pile drivers for sheet piles and/or column piles are a common necessity on a construction project. Piles can be used to stabilize trench walls during excavation, create coffer dams to hold back water, or to provide an anchored platform upon which structures can be built. There are two basic types of pile drivers – impact hammers and vibratory drivers. Noise emission levels from pile drivers can vary widely based on the type of driver, the type of pile (steel, concrete, wood), and the underlying ground conditions. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29042" number="33431" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>A.<TAB tab-count="1"/>GENERAL RULES OF OPERATION </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29043" number="33432" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The hours of operation shall be in accordance with 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-103" destination-id="0-0-0-3883">28-103</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29044" number="33433" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>B.<TAB tab-count="1"/>SOURCE CONTROLS: QUIETER MODELS &amp; MUFFLERS </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29045" number="33434" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The quietest pile driving method shall be selected that allows the work to be performed based on structural, geotechnical, and pile friction requirements and ground conditions. The following list or their equivalent are acceptable pile-driving methods to the Department: a hydraulic pile pushing system, a vibratory pile driver; a hydraulic impact pile driver; a drop hammer, a diesel impact pile driver. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29046" number="33435" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Hydraulic pushing method pile drivers, including the Ken-Jet Still Worker, the Giken Silent Piler, or the SERF Pilemaster, or equivalent, shall be utilized rather than louder impact or vibratory pile drivers when ground conditions permit such use. Further, such quieter pile drivers shall be utilized whenever a responsible party is working within 100 feet of a receptor. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29047" number="33436" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In accordance with the noise mitigation criteria outlined in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(b), an impact pile driver shall be equipped with a well maintained exhaust muffler in order to mitigate the amount of noise escaping out with the diesel exhaust. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29048" number="33437" version="1378">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party shall select the type of pile being driven based on structural and/or geotechnical performance requirements. In order of loudness, wooden piles shall be preferred first, followed by concrete piles, and then steel piles. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29049" number="33438" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>v.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party shall pre-auger or pre-trench the pile holes to soften the underlying ground, reduce ground resistance, and thus reduce pile driving noise based upon geotechnical conditions at the location. Auger drill rigs may be mounted to the same crane as the pile driver or alternatively, an excavator with a long bucket arm may pre-trench as deep as 25 feet below grade. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29050" number="33439" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>vi.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A properly secured impact cushion shall be installed on top of piles that are being driven by an impact hammer. Commercially available pile cushions or those fabricated on the job site, out of scrap wood, leather or rubber, may be utilized. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29051" number="33440" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>vii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Quieter alternative methods to pile driving, including the use of drilled caissons filled with concrete, or slurry walls dug out initially with a milling machine, shall be used whenever possible, depending on structural and geotechnical performance requirements. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29052" number="33441" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>viii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Noise bellows systems such as the IHC Hydrohammer, or an equivalent bellows device, may be used to provide further noise attenuation. Bellows enclosures accompany the pile down to the ground and collapse accordion style as the pile reaches the ground. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29053" number="33442" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ix.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the responsible party uses a vibratory pile driver or a hydraulic impact pile driver as set forth in clause (ii) of this subparagraph and/or noise bellows as set forth in clause (viii) of this subparagraph, between the hours of 7:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m. on weekdays, the responsible party need not utilize additional pathway controls listed in subparagraph C of this paragraph, unless the responsible party is performing work within 35 feet of an indoor receptor and with the exception of any required perimeter barriers as specified in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(g). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29054" number="33443" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>x.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No violation shall be issued to the responsible party if the bellows in clause (viii) of this subparagraph B or the barriers listed in subparagraph C of this paragraph are adjusted such that the operator can view the end of the hammer for safety purposes. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29055" number="33444" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>C.<TAB tab-count="1"/>NOISE PATHWAY CONTROLS: NOISE BARRIERS &amp; ENCLOSURES. The responsible party shall utilize one of the following pathway controls. However, if the Department receives noise complaints concerning the site, the responsible party shall utilize additional pathway controls listed in this subparagraph as required by DEP. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29056" number="33445" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party shall construct a portable noise barrier that shall be free from gaps and holes and constructed of a sufficiently massive material to achieve a Sound Transmission Class rating of STC 30 or greater. It shall be positioned as close as possible to the pile driver. A portable (i.e. unanchored) noise barrier can be made, for example, of concrete jersey bases with 3/4-inch plywood panels attached to fence posts extending upwards to an overall height of 15 feet. This shall be the maximum height for a free-standing barrier in order to avoid it tipping over from wind load. Multiple jersey bases and plywood panels shall be positioned adjacent to one another to form a barrier of any desired length. The gaps between adjacent panels shall be filled-in with noise curtain material, additional plywood, or similar material when practicable. A properly balanced canted panel, not susceptible to windy conditions, may be placed on top of the barrier in order to provide better shielding for multi-story receptors. However, said barrier&apos;s height shall not exceed 15 feet including the balanced canted portion. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29057" number="33446" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The noise barrier shall be long and tall enough to completely block the line of sight between the pile driver and any indoor receptor within 200 feet and that is a maximum of 20 feet above grade level, when work occurs. The barrier should be placed as close to the actual pile driving work as feasible. Greater noise attenuation occurs when barriers are placed as close as possible to the noise source. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29058" number="33447" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where applicable, portable noise shields made of steel frames wrapped with noise curtain material, such as SoundSeal model BBC-13-2, or equivalently rated material, shall be hoisted up into position on the crane&apos;s second cable to form a noise barrier in the direction of sensitive receptors. The shield shall be large enough to completely block the line of sight between the receptors and the pile driver, and shall be lowered to the ground as the pile is being driven in order to maintain the shielding effect. Such portable noise shield shall be utilized when the pile driver is higher than any barrier at the site required under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(g). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29059" number="33448" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Alternative barriers may be utilized in accordance with site-specific conditions. For example, shipping container (Conex) boxes or truck trailers may be positioned along the edge of the work site to form an effective semi-permanent noise barrier. Sufficient space at the site is necessary, as these containers are generally 8 feet wide by 8 feet tall and can be double-stacked to form a noise barrier 16 feet in height. The gaps between and/or under container boxes shall be filled-in with heavy vinyl noise curtains or similar materials. It should be noted that gaps and spaces are one of the primary contributors to degrading a noise barrier&apos;s performance. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29060" number="33449" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Jackhammers/Pavement Breakers.</CHARFORMAT> This rule shall provide noise mitigation strategies that the responsible party shall utilize in order to reduce the noise emissions from jackhammers and pavement breakers. These devices are defined as manually-operated, powered (pneumatic or other) devices, consisting of chisel-hammers or bits used to cut or break through pavement, concrete, or street surfaces. Jackhammers can be very loud as the steel chisel or bit hits the target object. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29061" number="33450" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>A.<TAB tab-count="1"/>GENERAL RULES OF OPERATION </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29062" number="33451" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The hours of operation shall be in accordance with the rules as set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-103" destination-id="0-0-0-3883">28-103</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29063" number="33452" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>B.<TAB tab-count="1"/>SOURCE CONTROLS: QUIETER MODELS &amp; MUFFLERS </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29064" number="33453" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Quieter makes and models of jackhammers such as the Copco model TEX P90S or equivalent model with an elongated effective muffler casing or bellows measuring a total of greater than 15 inches in length, shall be used whenever practicable. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29065" number="33454" version="1814">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The quietest jackhammer suitable to perform the given work shall be selected for use. The quieter jackhammers, including the jackhammer specified in clause (i) of this subparagraph or the Chicago Pneumatic CP1240, with a model F-814004 muffler, or equivalent, shall be used when suitable and whenever a responsible party is working in close proximity to receptors, whenever a responsible party is using multiple jackhammers, and whenever jackhammer operations are occurring during after hours as set forth in § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-223" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-223</LINK> of the Administrative Code. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29066" number="33455" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>In all cases, jackhammers shall be equipped with an effective muffler, provided either from the manufacturer or from an aftermarket vendor, which effectively reduces noise from the exhaust air by about 4 dBA or more. In accordance with 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(b), an effective muffler shall be properly fitted to the jackhammer to insure against air or noise leakage. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29067" number="33456" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>If appropriate to the size of the job, smaller jackhammers shall be used, as they tend to be quieter. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29068" number="33457" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>v.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the responsible party uses a device described in clause (i) of this subparagraph between the hours of 7:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m. on weekdays, the responsible party need not utilize additional pathway controls listed in subparagraph C of this paragraph, unless the responsible party is performing work within 35 feet of an indoor receptor and with the exception of any required perimeter barriers as specified in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(g). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29069" number="33458" version="1186">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>C.<TAB tab-count="1"/>NOISE PATHWAY CONTROLS: NOISE BARRIERS &amp; ENCLOSURES. The responsible party shall utilize one of the following pathway controls for jackhammers or pavement breaker operations within a property line or for long-term work when outside of the property line as specified in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(l). However, if the Department receives noise complaints concerning the site, the responsible party shall utilize additional pathway controls listed in this subparagraph as required by DEP. The pathway controls are set forth as follows: jersey barriers, tents, or other portable noise barriers. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29070" number="33459" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party shall construct a portable noise barrier that shall be free from gaps and holes and constructed of a sufficiently massive material to achieve a Sound Transmission Class rating of STC 30 or greater and that shall be positioned as close as possible to the jack hammer. The noise barrier shall be long and tall enough to completely block the line of sight between the jackhammer and any indoor receptor within 200 feet and that is a maximum of 20 feet above grade level, when work occurs. The barrier shall be placed as close to the actual jackhammering work as feasible. Greater noise attenuation occurs when barriers are placed as close as possible to the noise source. A balanced canted panel, not susceptible to high winds shall be placed, when feasible, on top of the barrier in order to provide better shielding for multi-story receptors. However, said barrier&apos;s height shall not exceed 15 feet including the balanced canted portion. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29071" number="33460" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Jersey barriers. A portable (i.e. unanchored) noise barrier can be made, for example, of concrete jersey bases with 3/4-inch plywood panels attached to fence posts extending upwards to an overall height of 15 feet. This shall be the maximum height for a free-standing barrier in order to avoid it tipping over from wind load. Multiple jersey bases and plywood panels can be positioned adjacent to one another to form a barrier of any desired length. The gaps between adjacent panels should be filled-in with noise curtain material, additional plywood, or similar material. All jersey barriers shall comply with the requirements in clause (i) of this subparagraph, including a Sound Transmission Class rating of STC 30 or greater. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29072" number="33461" version="204">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Portable noise enclosures.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29073" number="33462" version="204">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Portable noise enclosures (so-called &quot;noise tents&quot;) made of steel frames wrapped with noise curtain material, such as SoundSeal model BBC-13-2, or equivalently rated material, may be built to surround the jackhammer (on the top and 3 sides) and the operator. A properly constructed enclosure, using curtain material with a Sound Transmission Class rating of STC 30 or greater, generally provides a 5 dBA insertion loss. Such barrier shall meet OSHA standards for worker exposure to particulate matter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29074" number="33463" version="204">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party shall utilize multiple tents for multiple jackhammers. For example, when two jackhammers are being utilized and they cannot fit under the same noise tent, the responsible party shall provide an additional noise tent.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29075" number="33464" version="204">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The noise tent shall be moved as the jackhammer work progresses in order to maintain the tent&apos;s ability to block the line of sight between the jackhammer and the receptors.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29076" number="33465" version="1814">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In accordance with § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-223" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-223</LINK> of the Administrative Code, when emergency jackhammering occurs after normal working hours within 500 feet of any residential receptor, the responsible party shall use noise tents with double thick noise curtain material or a noise tent augmented with a portable noise barrier to form a double layer of mitigation. See 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-108" destination-id="0-0-0-3893">28-108</LINK>. Quieter jackhammers and compressor vehicles shall also be utilized during after hours work whenever feasible.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29077" number="33466" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where there are receptors surrounding the jackhammer work site on all sides, two tents shall be used on either side of the jackhammer to form a complete enclosure as close to the jackhammer as practicable. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29078" number="33467" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hoe Rams.</CHARFORMAT> This rule shall provide noise mitigation strategies that the responsible party shall utilize in order to reduce the noise emissions from hoe rams. Hoe rams, and hoe ram-like devices, are used to cut through roadway pavement or concrete walls and for demolition of large concrete or steel structures. They are typically large hydraulic chisel-hammers attached on the end of a backhoe or excavator arm that can be very loud as the steel chisel hits the target object. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29079" number="33468" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>A.<TAB tab-count="1"/>GENERAL RULES OF OPERATION </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29080" number="33469" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The hours of operation shall be in accordance with the rules as set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-103" destination-id="0-0-0-3883">28-103</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29081" number="33470" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>B.<TAB tab-count="1"/>SOURCE CONTROLS: QUIETER MODELS &amp; MUFFLERS </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29082" number="33471" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Quieter makes and models of hoe rams, such as the Bosma Hammer-Head or equivalent quieter devices, shall be used whenever feasible, especially near receptors. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29083" number="33472" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The smallest hoe ram necessary shall be selected to perform the task, as smaller devices tend to produce less noise. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29084" number="33473" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A noise shroud enclosure shall be wrapped around the head (i.e. chisel) of the hoe ram whenever working within 200 feet of a receptor. Shrouds may be selected from various manufacturers such as Krupp Industries, Allied Hi-Ram, Montabert, or Rammer Inc. with steel shrouds to attach to the hoe ram head. Alternatively, a shroud may be fabricated on-site by wrapping the chisel head with a heavy vinyl noise curtain material, such as SoundSeal BBC-13-2, or equivalently rated material, and securing it with tie wire. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29085" number="33474" version="1953">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A skilled hoe ram operator can significantly affect the amount of noise produced during the work. In accordance with 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(h), responsible party and subcontractor personnel shall be trained on the proper angle or position when the hoe ram chisel is placed against the work. The operator shall position and operate the device in such a manner as to minimize its noise output. A violation shall only be issued for failure to train the operator as set forth in subdivision (h) of 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29086" number="33475" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>v.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Alternative methods to hoe ramming concrete, including hydraulic jacks or chemical splitting (use of expansive demolition agents), shall be utilized whenever feasible. For steel demolition, alternative quieter methods may include the use of hydraulic shears and grapples, or the use of torches to cut the steel into more manageable pieces, which can then be trucked off-site for further demolition. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29087" number="33476" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>vi.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the responsible party uses specific makes and models as set forth in clause (i) of this subparagraph or a noise shroud as set forth in clause (iii) of this subparagraph, between the hours of 7:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m. on weekdays, then the responsible party need not utilize additional pathway controls listed in subparagraph C of this paragraph, unless the responsible party is performing work within 35 feet of an indoor receptor and with the exception of any required perimeter barriers as specified in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(g). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29088" number="33477" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>vii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>No violation shall be issued to the responsible party if any of the shrouds in clause (iii) of this subparagraph are adjusted such that the operator can view the end of the bit for safety purposes. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29089" number="33478" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>C.<TAB tab-count="1"/>NOISE PATHWAY CONTROLS: NOISE BARRIERS &amp; ENCLOSURES. The responsible party shall utilize one of the following pathway controls below. However, if the Department receives noise complaints concerning the site, the responsible party shall utilize additional pathway controls listed in this subparagraph as required by DEP. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29090" number="33479" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party shall construct a portable noise barrier that shall be free from gaps and holes and constructed of sufficiently massive material to achieve a Sound Transmission Class rating of STC 30 or greater and shall be positioned as close as possible to the hoe ram. A portable (i.e. unanchored) noise barrier can be made, for example, of concrete jersey bases with 3/4-inch plywood panels attached to fence posts extending upwards to a overall height of 15 feet. This shall be the maximum height for a free-standing barrier in order to avoid it tipping over from wind load. Multiple jersey bases and plywood panels can be positioned adjacent to one another to form a barrier of any desired length. The gaps between adjacent panels should be filled-in with noise curtain material, additional plywood, or similar material. A balanced canted panel, not susceptible to high winds shall be placed, when feasible, on top of the barrier in order to provide better shielding for multi-story receptors. However, said barrier&apos;s height shall not exceed 15 feet including the balanced canted portion. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29091" number="33480" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The noise barrier shall be long and tall enough to completely block the line of sight between the hoe ram and any indoor receptor within 200 feet and that is a maximum of 20 feet above grade level, when work occurs. The barrier should be placed as close to the actual hoe ram work as feasible. Greater noise attenuation occurs when barriers are placed as close as possible to the noise source. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29092" number="33481" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Alternative barriers may be utilized in accordance with site-specific conditions. For example, shipping container (Conex) boxes or truck trailers may be positioned along the edge of the work site to form a semi-permanent noise barrier. Sufficient space must be available since containers are generally 8 feet wide by 8 feet tall and can be double-stacked to form a noise barrier 16 feet in height. The gaps between and/or under container boxes should be filled-in with heavy vinyl noise curtains or similar material. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29093" number="33482" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where there are receptors surrounding the hoe ram work site on all sides, several noise barriers shall be used to form a complete enclosure around the hoe ram. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29094" number="33483" version="1814">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Blasting.</CHARFORMAT> This rule shall provide noise mitigation strategies that the responsible party shall utilize in order to reduce the noise emissions from blasting. The controlled use of explosives is occasionally necessary on a construction site, primarily to loosen hard rock ledges or to demolish large concrete structures. This rule does not apply to tunneling activities subject to the regulations set forth in § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-246" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-246</LINK> of the Administrative Code. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29095" number="33484" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>A.<TAB tab-count="1"/>GENERAL RULES OF OPERATION </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29096" number="33485" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The hours of operation shall be in accordance with the rules as set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-103" destination-id="0-0-0-3883">28-103</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29097" number="33486" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The necessary and FDNY-regulated use of blasting shall be done in close coordination with the affected public in order to minimize potential disturbance. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29098" number="33487" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>B.<TAB tab-count="1"/>SOURCE CONTROLS: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29099" number="33488" version="204">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The smallest appropriate blasting charge possible shall be used in order to minimize blasting noise at its source. The quietest explosive material possible shall also be selected. Relatively slow-burning explosives produce quieter noise emissions as compared to faster-burning explosives. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29100" number="33489" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>C.<TAB tab-count="1"/>NOISE PATHWAY CONTROLS: BLAST MATS AND BARRIERS </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29101" number="33490" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Blast mats made of heavy rubber shall be laid over the blast site. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29102" number="33491" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When blasting occurs close to receptors, the responsible party shall construct a portable noise barrier that shall be free from gaps and holes, constructed of a sufficiently massive material to achieve a Sound Transmission Class rating of STC 30 or greater, and positioned as close as possible to the blast site. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29103" number="33492" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The noise barrier shall be long and tall enough to completely block the line of sight between the blasting and any indoor receptor within 200 feet and that is a maximum of 20 feet above grade level, when work occurs. A portable (i.e. unanchored) noise barrier can be made, for example, of concrete jersey bases with 3/4-inch plywood panels attached to fence posts extending upwards to a maximum height of 15 feet. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29104" number="33493" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Earth Moving Equipment.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29105" number="33494" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Vacuum Excavators.</CHARFORMAT> This rule shall provide noise mitigation strategies the responsible party shall utilize when working with a vacuum excavator, or vac-truck. A vac-truck is a vehicle equipped with a low pressure suction hose leading to an on-board storage tank. Vac-trucks are generally used when removing dirt to avoid disrupting underground utility services such as telecommunications cables, water and sewer pipes, gas lines, or electrical cables. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29106" number="33495" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>A.<TAB tab-count="1"/>GENERAL RULES OF OPERATION </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29107" number="33496" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The hours of operation shall be in accordance with the rules as set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-103" destination-id="0-0-0-3883">28-103</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29108" number="33497" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>B.<TAB tab-count="1"/>SOURCE CONTROLS: QUIETER MODELS &amp; SILENCERS </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29109" number="33498" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Smaller capacity (lower suction) vac-trucks tend to be quieter and shall be used whenever practicable. Listed from the quietest to the loudest order, examples include GapVac, BSI Dewitz, BoVac and Guzzler. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29110" number="33499" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vac-trucks shall be run in their lower power setting whenever practicable. While suction capacity is reduced with lower engine speeds, there remains adequate suction to perform almost any job. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29111" number="33500" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Several manufacturers do provide silencers on the air intake and exhaust sides of the blower. Heavier duty silencers including Universal, Industrial Acoustics, McGill and Burgess-Manning, or equivalent, shall be used whenever practicable. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29112" number="33501" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The vac-truck&apos;s suction creating component (i.e. blower) shall be covered with a noise-reducing housing or enclosure. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29113" number="33502" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>v.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the responsible party uses a specific vac-truck as set forth in clause (i) of this subparagraph and/or silencers specifically set forth in clause (iii) of this subparagraph between the hours of 7:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m. on weekdays, then the responsible party need not utilize additional pathway controls listed in subparagraph C of this paragraph, unless the responsible party is performing work within 35 feet of an indoor receptor and with the exception of any required perimeter barriers as specified in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(g). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29114" number="33503" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>C.<TAB tab-count="1"/>NOISE PATHWAY CONTROLS: NOISE BARRIERS &amp; CURTAINS. The responsible party shall utilize one of the following pathway controls below. However, if the Department receives noise complaints concerning the site, the responsible party shall utilize additional pathway controls listed in this subparagraph as required by DEP. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29115" number="33504" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party shall construct a portable noise barrier that shall be free of gaps and holes and constructed of a sufficiently massive material to achieve a Sound Transmission Class rating of STC 30, or greater, and shall be positioned as close as possible to the vac-truck. A portable (i.e. unanchored) noise barrier can be made, for example, of concrete jersey bases with 3/4-inch plywood panels attached to fence posts extending upwards to an overall height of 15 feet. This shall be the maximum height for a free-standing barrier in order to avoid it tipping over from wind load. Multiple jersey bases and plywood panels shall be positioned adjacent to one another to form a barrier of any desired length. The gaps between adjacent panels should be filled-in with noise curtain material, additional plywood, or similar material. A properly balanced canted panel, not susceptible to windy conditions, may be placed on top of the barrier in order to provide better shielding for multi-story receptors. However, such barrier&apos;s height shall not exceed 15 feet including the balanced canted portion. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29116" number="33505" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The noise barrier shall be long and tall enough to completely block the line of sight between the vac-truck and any indoor receptor within 200 feet and that is a maximum of 20 feet above grade level, when work occurs. The barrier should be placed as close to the actual vac-truck work as feasible. Greater noise attenuation occurs when barriers are placed as close as possible to the noise source. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29117" number="33506" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Portable noise shields made of steel frames wrapped with noise curtain material, such as SoundSeal model BBC-13-2, or equivalently rated material, shall be used to form a noise barrier in the direction of sensitive receptors and completely block the line of sight between the receptors and vac-truck. Noise curtains are typically made out of a 1/4-inch thick heavy vinyl material, often with a noise absorptive quilt attached to one side. These noise curtains generally weigh 1.5 lbs/sq. ft., have an STC rating of about 32, and come in 4-foot wide sheets complete with grommets and Velcro edges to aid in hanging the curtains and sealing the sheets side-by-side. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29118" number="33507" version="204">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Alternative barriers may be utilized in accordance with site-specific conditions. For example, shipping container (Conex) boxes or truck trailers can be positioned along the edge of the work site to form a semi-permanent noise barrier. Sufficient space at the site is necessary as these containers are typically 8 feet wide by 8 feet tall and can be double-stacked to form a noise barrier 16 feet in height. The gaps between and/or under container boxes should be filled-in with heavy vinyl noise curtains or similar materials.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29119" number="33508" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>v.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever possible, vac-truck exhaust shall be positioned and directed away from receptors. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29120" number="33509" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction Trucks and Vehicles.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29121" number="33510" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dump Trucks.</CHARFORMAT> This paragraph shall provide noise mitigation strategies that the responsible party shall utilize in order to reduce the noise emissions from dump trucks. Dump trucks are commonly used on construction sites in order to deliver construction materials, remove and excavate debris, or transfer materials around the job site. However they can produce loud noises when their tailgates are slammed when dumping a load, when their engines are revved with inadequate exhaust mufflers, when the first shovel-full is dropped into the bed, or due to use of their backup alarms. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29122" number="33511" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>A.<TAB tab-count="1"/>GENERAL RULES OF OPERATION </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29123" number="33512" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The hours of operation shall be in accordance with the rules as set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-103" destination-id="0-0-0-3883">28-103</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29124" number="33513" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>B.<TAB tab-count="1"/>SOURCE CONTROLS </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29125" number="33514" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The smallest sized and quietest dump truck that is adequate for a particular job shall be selected. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29126" number="33515" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A bed liner made of thick rubber, spray-on liner, plywood, sand or gravel shall be installed to mitigate the noise of the first load being dropped into the dump truck. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29127" number="33516" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Though not required for use in the United States (U.S.), most U.S. dump truck manufacturers produce quieter models for use in Europe. European Environmental Label (i.e. Blue Angel) low noise emission construction equipment, which is required for import and use in European Union (EU) nations in accordance with Quality Assurance Publication RAL UZ 53 and the Treaty on European Union 992-02-07 Journal C224, shall be used whenever feasible if it meets the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency&apos;s emission requirements and/or regulations. These models are generally 10 dBA quieter than similar equipment used in the U.S. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29128" number="33517" version="204">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The positioning of the dump truck shall be carefully selected in order to minimize operation near receptors. Responsible parties shall attempt to reduce the necessity of backing-up by selecting a straight drive-through truck route. If a backup alarm is used, a quieter warning device shall be installed in accordance with 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(f). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29129" number="33518" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>v.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The truck shall be equipped with an effective muffler in accordance with 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(b), which shall be well-maintained to ensure maximum noise reduction. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29130" number="33519" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>vi.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Slamming a tail gate shall be avoided to the extent possible to prevent unreasonable noise. Alternately, a pad made of heavy rubber, leather or wood, when practicable, shall be used under the tail gate to prevent metal contact. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29131" number="33520" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>vii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The engine housing doors shall be kept closed while the engine is in operation. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29132" number="33521" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>viii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the responsible party uses quieter dump truck models as set forth in clause (iii) of this subparagraph, between the hours of 7:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m. on weekdays, the responsible party need not utilize additional pathway controls listed in subparagraph C of this paragraph, unless the responsible party is performing work within 35 feet of an indoor receptor and with the exception of any required perimeter barriers as specified in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(g). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29133" number="33522" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>C.<TAB tab-count="1"/>NOISE PATHWAY CONTROLS: NOISE BARRIERS &amp; CURTAINS The responsible party shall utilize one of the following pathway controls. However, if the Department receives noise complaints concerning the site, the responsible party shall utilize additional pathway controls listed in this subparagraph as required by DEP. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29134" number="33523" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party shall construct a portable noise barrier that shall be free from gaps and holes and constructed of a sufficiently massive material to achieve a Sound Transmission Class rating of STC 30, and shall be positioned as close as possible to the vehicle, in order to provide the greatest insertion loss. A portable (i.e. unanchored) noise barrier can be made, for example, of concrete jersey bases with 3/4-inch plywood panels attached to fence posts extending upwards to an overall height of 15 feet. This shall be the maximum height for a free-standing barrier in order to avoid it tipping over from wind load. Multiple jersey bases and plywood panels may be positioned adjacent to one another to form a barrier of any desired length. The gaps between adjacent panels shall be filled-in with noise curtain material, additional plywood, or similar material. A canted panel may be placed on top of the barrier in order to provide better shielding for multi-story receptors; however care must be taken to avoid having the barrier tip over from unbalanced loading. Further, said barrier&apos;s height shall not exceed 15 feet including the balanced canted portion. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29135" number="33524" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The noise barrier shall be long and tall enough to completely block the line of sight between the dump truck and any indoor receptor within 200 feet and that is a maximum of 20 feet above grade level, when work occurs. The barrier shall be placed as close to the actual dump truck work as feasible. Greater noise attenuation occurs when barriers are placed as close as possible to the noise source. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29136" number="33525" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Noise curtain material, such as SoundSeal model BBC-13-2, or equivalently rated material, shall be used to form a noise barrier in the direction of sensitive receptors and completely block the line of sight between the receptors and dump truck. It shall also be draped over the dump truck to augment the engine housing and exhaust stack. Noise curtains are typically made out of a 1/4-inch thick heavy vinyl material, often with a noise absorptive quilt attached to one side. These noise curtains generally weigh 1.5 lbs/sq. ft., have an STC rating of about 32, and come in 4-foot wide sheets complete with grommets and Velcro edges to aid in hanging the curtains and sealing the sheets side-by-side. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29137" number="33526" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Conveyor belts shall be used whenever practicable, as they may allow the dump trucks to operate much farther away from receptors. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29138" number="33527" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>v.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Alternative barriers may be utilized in accordance with site-specific conditions. For example, shipping container (Conex) boxes or truck trailers may be positioned along the edge of the work site to form a semi-permanent noise barrier. Sufficient space at the site is necessary as these containers are generally 8 feet wide by 8 feet tall and can be double-stacked to form a noise barrier 16 feet in height. The gaps between and/or under container boxes shall be filled-in with heavy vinyl noise curtains or similar material. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29139" number="33528" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Stationary Equipment.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29140" number="33529" version="1953">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cranes.</CHARFORMAT> This rule shall provide noise mitigation strategies that the responsible party shall utilize in order to reduce the noise emissions from cranes. Cranes are an essential piece of equipment on most large construction sites in order to load and unload delivery trucks, lift building materials to required heights, lift excavated materials out of tunnels and for other subsurface excavations, and move other equipment and personnel around the job site. Cranes come in many varieties and sizes, including tracked or wheeled mobile cranes, fixed or floating derricks, and tower cranes. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29141" number="33530" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>A.<TAB tab-count="1"/>GENERAL RULES OF OPERATION </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29142" number="33531" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The hours of operation shall be in accordance with the rules set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-103" destination-id="0-0-0-3883">28-103</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29143" number="33532" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>B.<TAB tab-count="1"/>SOURCE CONTROLS: QUIETER MODELS </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29144" number="33533" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>There are various makes and models that are inherently quieter than others. Smaller, quieter cranes, including rubber-tired mobile cranes, shall be used whenever possible based on load lifting requirements. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29145" number="33534" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>New modern hydraulic cranes shall be used whenever possible to avoid the squeal produced by cable drum brakes on mechanical cranes. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29146" number="33535" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Though not required for use in the United States, most U.S. crane manufacturers produce quieter models for use in Europe. European Environmental Label (i.e. Blue Angel) low noise emission construction equipment, which is required for import and use in European Union (EU) nations in accordance with Quality Assurance Publication RAL UZ 53 and the Treaty on European Union 992-02-07 Journal C224, shall be used whenever feasible and if it meets the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency&apos;s emission requirements and/or regulations. These cranes are about 10 dBA quieter than similar models sold in the U.S. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29147" number="33536" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The positioning of the crane shall be carefully selected in order to minimize the need to relocate it around the job site. Whenever possible, tower cranes shall be used, as they essentially produce no noise at ground level. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29148" number="33537" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>v.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The crane shall be equipped with an effective muffler in accordance with 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(b), which shall be well maintained to ensure maximum noise reduction. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29149" number="33538" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>vi.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the responsible party uses new modern hydraulic cranes as set forth in clause (ii) of this subparagraph and/or additional source controls set forth in clause (iii) of this subparagraph, between the hours of 7:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m. on weekdays, the responsible party need not utilize additional pathway controls listed in subparagraph C of this paragraph, unless the responsible party is performing work within 35 feet of an indoor receptor and with the exception of any required perimeter barriers as specified in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(g). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29150" number="33539" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>C.<TAB tab-count="1"/>NOISE PATHWAY CONTROLS: NOISE BARRIERS &amp; CURTAINS The responsible party shall utilize one of the following pathway controls. However, if the Department receives noise complaints concerning the site, the responsible party shall utilize additional pathway controls listed in this subparagraph as required by DEP. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29151" number="33540" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party shall construct a portable noise barrier that shall be free from gaps and holes constructed of a sufficiently massive material to achieve a Sound Transmission Class rating of STC 30 or greater, and shall be positioned as close as possible to the crane. A portable (i.e. unanchored) noise barrier can be made, for example, of concrete jersey bases with 3/4-inch plywood panels attached to fence posts extending upwards to an overall height of 15 feet. This shall be the maximum height for a free-standing barrier in order to avoid it tipping over from wind load. Multiple jersey bases and plywood panels shall be positioned adjacent to one another to form a barrier of any desired length. The gaps between adjacent panels shall be filled-in with noise curtain material, additional plywood, or similar material. A properly balanced canted panel, not susceptible to windy conditions, may be placed on top of the barrier in order to provide better shielding for multi-story receptors. However, said barrier&apos;s height shall not exceed 15 feet including the balanced canted portion. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29152" number="33541" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The noise barrier shall be long and tall enough to completely block the line of sight between the crane and any indoor receptor within 200 feet and that is a maximum of 20 feet above grade level, when work occurs. The barrier shall be placed as close to the actual crane work as feasible. Greater noise attenuation occurs when barriers are placed as close as possible to the noise source. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29153" number="33542" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Portable noise shields made of steel frames wrapped with noise curtain material, such as SoundSeal model BBC-13-2, or equivalently rated material, shall be used to form a noise barrier in the direction of sensitive receptors and completely block the line of sight between the receptors and crane. Noise curtains are typically made out of a 1/4-inch thick heavy vinyl material, often with a noise absorptive quilt attached to one side. These noise curtains generally weigh 1.5 lbs/sq. ft., have an STC rating of about 32, and come in 4-foot wide sheets complete with grommets and Velcro edges to aid in hanging the curtains and sealing the sheets side-by-side. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29154" number="33543" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Alternative barriers may be utilized in accordance with site-specific conditions. For example, shipping container (Conex) boxes or truck trailers may be positioned along the edge of the work site to form a semi-permanent noise barrier. Sufficient space at the site is necessary as these containers are generally 8 feet wide by 8 feet tall and can be double-stacked to form a noise barrier 16 feet in height. The gaps between and/or under container boxes shall be filled-in with heavy vinyl noise curtains or similar material. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29155" number="33544" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Auger Drill Rigs.</CHARFORMAT> This rule shall provide mitigation strategies the responsible party shall utilize when using auger drill rigs. Auger drill rigs are typically mounted to cranes or they can be built as dedicated machines as well. Auger drill rigs are used to drill shafts into the ground, which are then filled with cement form concrete piles, to loosen underlying soil and allow solid piles to be driven more easily, or used in multiple configuration to &quot;mix&quot; grout into the soil and change the soil&apos;s properties (i.e. strengthen it and reduce its water content). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29156" number="33545" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>A.<TAB tab-count="1"/>GENERAL RULES OF OPERATION </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29157" number="33546" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The hours of operation shall be in accordance with the rules set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-103" destination-id="0-0-0-3883">28-103</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29158" number="33547" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>B.<TAB tab-count="1"/>SOURCE CONTROLS: QUIETER MODELS &amp; SILENCERS </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29159" number="33548" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The auger drill rig or crane shall be equipped with an effective muffler in accordance with 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(b), which shall be well- maintained to ensure maximum noise reduction. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29160" number="33549" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All moving parts shall be well lubricated for proper drilling performance and to avoid unnecessary noise from squeaking parts. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29161" number="33550" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Debris on the drill bit shall be removed without quick twisting, jerking or hammering the bit, unless geotechnical conditions at the location so require. Alternative quieter methods include use of a high pressure water hose where debris is not contaminated or a laborer using a hand shovel. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29162" number="33551" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>C.<TAB tab-count="1"/>PATHWAY CONTROLS: NOISE BARRIERS &amp; CURTAINS The responsible party shall utilize one of the following pathway controls. However, if the Department receives noise complaints concerning the site, the responsible party shall utilize additional pathway controls listed in this subparagraph as required by DEP. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29163" number="33552" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party shall construct a portable noise barrier that shall be free from gaps and holes and constructed of a sufficiently massive material to achieve a Sound Transmission Class rating of STC 30, or greater, and shall be positioned as close as possible to the auger drill rig. A portable (i.e. unanchored) noise barrier may be made, for example, of concrete jersey bases with 3/4-inch plywood panels attached to fence posts extending upwards to an overall height of 15 feet. This shall be the maximum height for a free-standing barrier in order to avoid it tipping over from wind load. Multiple jersey bases and plywood panels shall be positioned adjacent to one another to form a barrier of any desired length. The gaps between adjacent panels shall be filled-in with noise curtain material, additional plywood, or similar material. A properly balanced canted panel, not susceptible to windy conditions, may be placed on top of the barrier in order to provide better shielding for multi-story receptors. However, said barrier&apos;s height shall not exceed 15 feet including the balanced canted portion. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29164" number="33553" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The noise barrier shall be long and tall enough to completely block the line of sight between the auger drill rig and any indoor receptor within 200 feet and that is a maximum of 20 feet above grade level, when work occurs. The barrier should be placed as close to the actual auger drill rig work as feasible. Greater noise attenuation occurs when barriers are placed as close as possible to the noise source. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29165" number="33554" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Noise curtain material, such as SoundSeal model BBC-13-2, or equivalently rated material, shall be used to form a noise barrier in the direction of sensitive receptors and completely block the line of sight between the receptors and auger drill rig. Noise curtains are typically made out of a 1/4-inch thick heavy vinyl material, often with a noise absorptive quilt attached to one side. These noise curtains generally weigh 1.5 lbs/sq. ft., have an STC rating of about 32, and come in 4-foot wide sheets complete with grommets and Velcro edges to aid in hanging the curtains and sealing the sheets side-by-side. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29166" number="33555" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Alternative barriers may be utilized in accordance with site-specific conditions. For example, shipping container (Conex) boxes or truck trailers may be positioned along the edge of the work site to form a semi-permanent noise barrier. Sufficient space at the site is necessary as these containers are generally 8 feet wide by 8 feet tall and can be double-stacked to form a noise barrier 16 feet in height. The gaps between and/or under container boxes shall be filled-in with heavy vinyl noise curtains or similar material. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29167" number="33556" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Street Plates.</CHARFORMAT> In addition to the Department of Transportation rules set forth in 34 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T34C002_2-11" destination-id="0-0-0-8359">2-11</LINK>(10), the responsible party shall follow one or more of the following methods to reduce noise emissions from loose or rattling street plates. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29168" number="33557" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>A.<TAB tab-count="1"/>SOURCE CONTROLS: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29169" number="33558" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The street plates shall be installed in the street surface in accordance with 34 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T34C002_2-11" destination-id="0-0-0-8359">2-11</LINK>(10) in order to have a level and smooth transition from pavement to plate surface and to keep the plates firmly in place. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29170" number="33559" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Asphalt cold-patch shall be applied when feasible around the edges of the street plate to minimize vehicular tire impact on the plate and to help keep the plate in place. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29171" number="33560" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>B.<TAB tab-count="1"/>NOISE PATHWAY CONTROLS: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29172" number="33561" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever feasible, traffic shall be routed around the street plates by placing traffic cones, barrels, and/or warning tape around the plated area. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29173" number="33562" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Backup Alarms.</CHARFORMAT> In accordance with 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(f), all existing vehicles that enter a work site shall be equipped with OSHA-approved, and OEM manufacturer-approved (if necessary), quieter backup alarms by January 1, 2008. All new vehicles that enter the work site shall be equipped with OSHA-approved quieter backup alarms by January 1, 2008. All on-road vehicles that do not enter the work site, but are in operation after hours pursuant to 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-103" destination-id="0-0-0-3883">28-103</LINK>, shall also be equipped with OSHA-approved, and OEM manufacturer-approved (if necessary), quieter backup alarms by January 1, 2008. The work site referenced in this paragraph shall mean construction sites within the property line. Subparagraph A of this paragraph contains a list of quieter OSHA-approved backup alarms pursuant to OSHA Regulations, 29 C.F.R. Part 1926, Subpart &quot;O&quot;, 1926.601.b.4 and 1926.602.a.9. If the responsible party cannot reasonably comply with the requirements of this paragraph, such person shall file an Alternative Noise Mitigation Plan in accordance with 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-104" destination-id="0-0-0-3885">28-104</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29174" number="33563" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>A.<TAB tab-count="1"/>SOURCE CONTROLS: QUIETER MAKES &amp; MODELS </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29175" number="33564" version="204">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Quieter alarms or similar backup devices that meet OSHA requirements may be selected from the list below or from equivalent quieter alarms.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29176" number="33565" version="204">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Examples of manually-adjustable backup alarms include:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29177" number="33566" version="2461">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>•<TAB tab-count="1"/>Preco Model 45AA</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29178" number="33567" version="2461">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>•<TAB tab-count="1"/>Ecco Model 820</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29179" number="33568" version="204">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Examples of automatically-adjustable backup alarms include:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29180" number="33569" version="2461">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>•<TAB tab-count="1"/>Preco Model 1048</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29181" number="33570" version="2461">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>•<TAB tab-count="1"/>Ecco Model SA907</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29182" number="33571" version="2461">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>•<TAB tab-count="1"/>Grote Model 73100</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29183" number="33572" version="204">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Examples of community sensitive backup alarms include:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29184" number="33573" version="2461">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>•<TAB tab-count="1"/>BBS-TEK Brigade Model BBS-92 </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29185" number="33574" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the responsible party uses quieter backup alarms as described in clause (i) of this subparagraph, the responsible party need not utilize additional pathway controls listed in subparagraph B of this paragraph, unless the responsible party is performing work within 35 feet of an indoor receptor and with the exception of any required perimeter barriers as specified in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(g). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29186" number="33575" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>B.<TAB tab-count="1"/>NOISE PATHWAY CONTROLS. If it is not feasible to select one of the OSHA-approved alarms in subparagraph A of this paragraph, responsible parties shall utilize one of the following pathway controls. However, if the Department receives noise complaints concerning the site, the responsible party shall utilize additional pathway controls listed in this subparagraph as required by DEP. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29187" number="33576" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Responsible parties shall attempt to reduce the necessity of backing-up by selecting a straight drive-through truck route. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29188" number="33577" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party shall construct a portable noise barrier that shall be free from gaps and holes and constructed of a sufficiently massive material to achieve a Sound Transmission Class rating of STC 30 or greater. It shall be positioned as close as possible to the vehicle, in order to provide the greatest insertion loss. A portable (i.e. unanchored) noise barrier may be made, for example, of concrete jersey bases with 3/4-inch plywood panels attached to fence posts extending upwards to an overall height of 15 feet. This shall be the maximum height for a free-standing barrier in order to avoid it tipping over from wind load. Multiple jersey bases and plywood panels may be positioned adjacent to one another to form a barrier of any desired length. The gaps between adjacent panels shall be filled-in with noise curtain material, additional plywood, or similar material. A canted panel may also be built on top of the barrier in order to provide better shielding for multi-story receptors; however care must be taken to avoid having the barrier tip over from unbalanced loading. Further, said barrier&apos;s height shall not exceed 15 feet including the balanced canted portion. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29189" number="33578" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The noise barrier shall be long and tall enough to completely block the line of sight between the backup alarm and any indoor receptor within 200 feet and that is a maximum of 20 feet above grade level, when work occurs. The barrier should be placed as close to the actual backup alarm as feasible. Greater noise attenuation occurs when barriers are placed as close as possible to the noise source. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29190" number="33579" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Alternative barriers may be utilized in accordance with site specification. Conex containers are likely already available to the responsible party. For example, where sufficient work site space exists, container (Conex) boxes or truck trailers may be positioned along the edge of the work site to form a semi-permanent noise barrier. These containers are typically 8 feet wide by 8 feet tall and can be double-stacked to form a noise barrier 16 feet in height. The gaps between and/or under container boxes shall be filled-in with heavy vinyl noise curtains or similar material. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29191" number="33580" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Manually Operated Equipment.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29192" number="33581" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Concrete Saws.</CHARFORMAT> This rule shall provide noise mitigation strategies that the responsible party shall utilize in order to reduce the noise emissions from concrete saws. Concrete saws are used on construction projects primarily for demolition purposes, but can also be used for opening access holes, cutting stress relief channels, and finishing off new construction. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29193" number="33582" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>A.<TAB tab-count="1"/>GENERAL RULES OF OPERATION </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29194" number="33583" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The hours of operation shall be in accordance with the rules as set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-103" destination-id="0-0-0-3883">28-103</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29195" number="33584" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>B.<TAB tab-count="1"/>SOURCE CONTROLS: QUIETER MODELS </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29196" number="33585" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Smaller saws shall be used, based on the power and cutting depth necessary to perform the job, as they tend to be quieter. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29197" number="33586" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A quieter-type saw blade, including a grinding saw blade or one made of ceramic or special-tipped cutting teeth, shall be chosen whenever practicable. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29198" number="33587" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>C.<TAB tab-count="1"/>NOISE PATHWAY CONTROLS: NOISE BARRIERS &amp; ENCLOSURES. The responsible party shall utilize one of the following pathway controls. However, if the Department receives noise complaints concerning the site, the responsible party shall utilize additional pathway controls listed in this subparagraph as required by DEP. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29199" number="33588" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party shall construct a portable noise barrier that shall be free from gaps and holes and constructed of a sufficiently massive material to achieve a Sound Transmission Class rating of STC 30 or greater, and is positioned as close as possible to the saw. A portable (i.e. unanchored) noise barrier may be made, for example, of concrete jersey bases with 3/4-inch plywood panels attached to fence posts extending upwards to an overall height of 15 feet. This shall be the maximum height for a free-standing barrier in order to avoid it tipping over from wind load. Multiple jersey bases and plywood panels shall be positioned adjacent to one another to form a barrier of any desired length. The gaps between adjacent panels shall be filled-in with noise curtain material, additional plywood, or similar material. A properly balanced canted panel, not susceptible to windy conditions, may be placed on top of the barrier in order to provide better shielding for multi-story receptors. However, said barrier&apos;s height shall not exceed 15 feet including the balanced canted portion. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29200" number="33589" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The noise barrier shall be long and tall enough to completely block the line of sight between the saw and any indoor receptor within 200 feet and that is a maximum of 20 feet above grade level, when work occurs. The barrier shall be placed as close to the actual saw work as feasible. Greater noise attenuation occurs when barriers are placed as close as possible to the noise source. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29201" number="33590" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Portable noise enclosures made of steel frames wrapped with noise curtain material, such as SoundSeal model BBC-13-2, or equivalently rated material, shall be built to surround (top and 3 sides) the concrete saw and the operator. A well made enclosure, using curtain material with a Sound Transmission Class rating of STC 30 or greater, can generally provide a 5 dBA insertion loss providing there are no gaps in the enclosure. Noise tents may be reused at other sites with proper care and maintenance. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29202" number="33591" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iv.<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be multiple tents for multiple concrete saws. For example, when two saws are being utilized and they cannot fit under the same noise tent, the responsible party shall provide an additional noise tent. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29203" number="33592" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>v.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The noise tent shall be moved as the concrete saw work progresses in order to maintain the tent&apos;s ability to block the line-of-sight between the saw and the receptors. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29204" number="33593" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>vi.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Emergency concrete sawing that occurs on any public right-of-way after normal working hours as set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-103" destination-id="0-0-0-3883">28-103</LINK>, within 500 feet of any residential receptor, shall require noise tents with double-thick noise curtain material, or a noise tent augmented with a portable noise barrier to form a double layer of mitigation. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29205" number="33594" version="204">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>vii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where there are receptors surrounding the concrete saw work site on all sides, two tents shall be used whenever practicable, on either side of the saw, to form a complete enclosure.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109924" number="33595" version="1186">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 9/18/2018, eff. 10/18/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-29206" number="33596" version="1186">
								<HEADING>§ 28-103 Authorized Work Hours.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3883" name="T15C028_28-103"/>§ 28-103 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Authorized Work Hours.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29207" number="33597" version="1814">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Equipment shall be used only during the hours of 7:00 a.m. and 6:00 p.m. on weekdays, unless the responsible party obtains an after hours work authorization, in which case the equipment shall be used in accordance with the hours specified in the permit and in the after hours work authorization, as set forth in § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-223" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-223</LINK> of the Administrative Code. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29208" number="33598" version="1814">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When work occurs after hours in accordance with § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-223" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-223</LINK> of the Administrative Code, or falls within one of the exceptions to limits on after hours and weekend construction work set forth in § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-222" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-222</LINK> of such Code, additional noise mitigation measures and/or techniques shall be implemented when required by DEP.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-29209" number="33599" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 28-104 Alternative Noise Mitigation Plan.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3885" name="T15C028_28-104"/>§ 28-104 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Alternative Noise Mitigation Plan.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29210" number="33600" version="1814">
									<PARA>When required by § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-221" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-221</LINK> of the Administrative Code or this chapter, a complete and accurate Alternative Noise Mitigation Plan shall be filed with DEP in accordance with § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-221" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-221</LINK> of such Code. If and when approved by DEP, such plan shall be conspicuously posted at the job site. When an Alternative Noise Mitigation Plan is required, no construction activities shall take place until said plan is filed with and approved by DEP. The Alternative Noise Mitigation Plan Form is available at: <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="http://www.nyc.gov/dep">http://www.nyc.gov/dep</LINK> or at DEP&apos;s Offices at: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29211" number="33601" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>New York City Department of Environmental Protection <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Bureau of Environmental Compliance, 9th Floor <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>59-17 Junction Blvd. <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Flushing, NY 11373 </PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-29212" number="33602" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 28-105 Utility Noise Mitigation Plan.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3887" name="T15C028_28-105"/>§ 28-105 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Utility Noise Mitigation Plan.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29214" number="33603" version="1814">
									<PARA>Pursuant to § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-219" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-219</LINK> and § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-220" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-220</LINK> of the Administrative Code, every authorized publicly franchised New York City utility company that provides gas, electric, steam and telecommunication services, except when emergency work will be performed in three days or less, shall have conspicuously posted, a complete and accurate Utility Noise Mitigation Plan at all sites where construction activities take place. A generic plan per borough may be used to satisfy the filing and posting requirement, provided such plan is posted and filed with the department and otherwise complies with the requirements for a Utility Noise Mitigation Plan. Although the plan need not be filed with DEP, it shall be readily available for inspection should a complaint be filed or during a routine inspection. The Utility Noise Mitigation Plan Form is available at: <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="http://www.nyc.gov/html/dep/html/noise/construction-noise.shtml">http://www.nyc.gov/html/dep/html/noise/construction-noise.shtml</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109926" number="33604" version="1186">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 9/18/2018, eff. 10/18/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-29215" number="33605" version="1186">
								<HEADING>§ 28-106 Required Noise Mitigation Measures for Utilities.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3889" name="T15C028_28-106"/>§ 28-106 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Required Noise Mitigation Measures for Utilities.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29216" number="33606" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A utility company conducting construction activity shall self-certify in its Construction Noise Mitigation Plan that all construction tools and equipment have been maintained so that they operate at normal manufacturer&apos;s operating specifications, including at peak loading. Such self-certification shall be indicated on the Construction Noise Mitigation Plan form required by 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-100" destination-id="0-0-0-3877">28-100</LINK>. Upon a DEP inspection of the work site, DEP shall use the noise level guidelines in the Federal Highway Administration Roadway Construction Noise Model User&apos;s Guide, Jan. 2006, page 3, located in the Appendix to this chapter, as a means of identifying equipment that may be the cause of a noise complaint. If an individual piece of equipment is identified by DEP as exceeding the level specified in such Guide located in the Appendix to this chapter, upon notification by DEP, the responsible party shall have the option of: (i) performing maintenance to demonstrate a good faith effort, notwithstanding the model year of the equipment, to mitigate the noise by a measurable level acceptable to the Department, (ii) replacing the equipment with equipment that complies with said level, or (iii) filing an Alternative Noise Mitigation Plan pursuant to 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-104" destination-id="0-0-0-3885">28-104</LINK>, within five business days of said inspection. If the responsible party elects to perform maintenance pursuant to option (i), but cannot demonstrate within five business days a reduction in noise by a measurable level acceptable to the Department, such party shall pursue one of the other two options to the satisfaction of the Department. The failure to exercise and complete one of such three options within five business days of said inspection shall be a violation of this rule. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29217" number="33607" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All tools and equipment being operated on site must be equipped with the appropriate manufacturer&apos;s noise reduction device. These devices, including but not limited to portable compressors and other such pneumatic tools, such as jackhammers/pavement breakers, shall be equipped with a standard muffler and jacket, free from air or exhaust leaks. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29218" number="33608" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Specialized vehicles, including but not limited to compressor trucks, vacuum excavators, pavement-coring, power-roding, flush trucks, and other vehicles with internal combustion motors, shall require additional noise mitigation measures as specified by DEP, such as the use of noise-insulating material that does not interfere with the engine operation and/or other techniques to reduce noise. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29219" number="33609" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Portable compressors, generators, pumps and other such devices shall be covered with noise-insulating fabric, which is not to interfere with engine operations, and/or shall employ other techniques to reduce noise. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29220" number="33610" version="1814">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The time of day that work is in progress shall also determine the technology that provides the appropriate noise mitigation. All work that occurs after the hours of 7:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m. on weekdays shall require an after hours work authorization in accordance with § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-223" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-223</LINK> of the Administrative Code. From the hours of 6:00 p.m. to 10:00 p.m. on weekdays, the utility shall use daytime noise mitigation controls. However, work between the hours of 10:00 p.m. and 7:00 a.m. on weekdays and between 7:00 p.m. and 7:00 a.m. on weekends may be required by DEP to employ additional techniques, including noise blankets and barriers to reduce the level of noise for receptors within 200 feet. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29221" number="33611" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Quieter jackhammers, compressors, and other such construction devices shall be used when available and/or may be required by DEP. A program shall be initiated between DEP and the utilities to perform additional noise-testing of construction devices and to make recommendations to DEP for future rules and use of devices. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29222" number="33612" version="1814">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All unnecessary vehicle engine-idling on site shall be prevented in accordance with § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-163" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-163</LINK> of the Administrative Code. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29223" number="33613" version="888">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>h.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All steel traffic plates are to be properly installed and secured to the roadway surface in compliance with 34 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T34C002_2-11" destination-id="0-0-0-8359">2-11</LINK>(10)(e). Within 24 hours after a call to the utility from DEP, plates shall be re-set and secured properly. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29224" number="33614" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notification shall be given to residents within 200 feet of the construction when work is scheduled for longer than 3 days. Such notification shall include information on construction work schedules and locations. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29225" number="33615" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>j.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The permit-holder shall respond to all noise complaints and/or official notice from DEP the same day as received or the next day if received after regular utility work hours or as may be required by DEP. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29226" number="33616" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>k.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All new vehicles will be phased in with the installation of quieter backup warning devices in accordance with paragraph 4 of subdivision d of 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-102" destination-id="0-0-0-3881">28-102</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29227" number="33617" version="1953">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>l.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A formal noise mitigation training program shall be established and implemented for all field-worker supervisory personnel including subcontractor supervisors. Supervisory personnel shall field-train all field workers in an effort to minimize construction noise. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29228" number="33618" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>m.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When work is planned near sensitive receptors, including but not limited to schools, hospitals, places of worship, homes for the aging, etc., the permit-holder shall cooperate with the facility owner/operator to coordinate the work whenever possible so as to minimize the impact on the facility and the utility shall use quieter devices and other noise mitigation methods, such as blankets and barriers. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29229" number="33619" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>n.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A DEP Inspector may visit the site to examine the Utility Noise Mitigation Plan upon receiving a complaint and may require further action to reduce the level of noise. The responsible party will be provided a 24-hour cure period to correct the condition or to file an Alternative Noise Mitigation Plan under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-104" destination-id="0-0-0-3885">28-104</LINK>. If the condition is not corrected after 24 hours or if an Alternative Noise Mitigation Plan is not filed with DEP, a Notice of Violation shall be issued. However, there shall be no 24-hour cure period with respect to compliance with 15 RCNY §§ <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-100" destination-id="0-0-0-3877">28-100</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(a), (b), (f), or (h), <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-104" destination-id="0-0-0-3885">28-104</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-105" destination-id="0-0-0-3887">28-105</LINK>, and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-106" destination-id="0-0-0-3889">28-106</LINK>(a), (b), (d), (g), or (i). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29230" number="33620" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>o.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Perimeter noise barriers shall be used as set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C028_28-101" destination-id="0-0-0-3879">28-101</LINK>(g). All gaps and spaces in the semi-permanent or temporary barriers shall be filled with noise attenuation material, and such barriers shall be placed as close as possible to the noise source to promote greater noise attenuation. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29231" number="33621" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>p.<TAB tab-count="1"/>[<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Repealed.</CHARFORMAT>] <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109928" number="33622" version="1187">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 9/18/2018, eff. 10/18/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-29232" number="33623" version="1187">
								<HEADING>§ 28-107 Perimeter Noise Barriers.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3891" name="T15C028_28-107"/>§ 28-107 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Perimeter Noise Barriers.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29233" number="33624" version="33">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Perimeter Noise Barriers - Noise barriers, positioned between construction equipment and receptors, must be used for all construction projects. Such barriers may be semi-permanent given the time and space requirements of the job site. They may be made of wood, plastic, Plexiglas, precast concrete or steel panels, or where work site space permits, natural materials, such as dirt piles or earthen berms. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-012]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29234" number="33625" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Noise barriers shall be used to reduce noise affecting pedestrians. Being relatively tall and solid, noise barriers form an excellent perimeter and/or security fence around a job site in addition to reducing noise at street level. Greater noise attenuation occurs when barriers are placed as close as possible to the noise source. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29235" number="33626" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the work site is within 200 feet of a residential receptor, the responsible party that is required to use a work site perimeter noise barrier (or &quot;construction fence&quot;) under DOB rules and regulations shall ensure that noise-resistant material fully lines the interior face (facing the work site) of the perimeter barrier, and shall ensure that: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29236" number="33627" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>the barrier breaks the line-of-sight between the noise source and indoor receptors within 200 feet and a maximum of 20 feet above grade level where practicable; however, said barrier&apos;s height shall not exceed 15 feet, including the balanced canted portion; </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29237" number="33628" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>the barrier is made of a material sufficiently resistant to noise in accordance with subdivision e of this section; and </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29238" number="33629" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>there are no leaks or gaps that will allow noise to pass through the barrier. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29239" number="33630" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Noise Barrier Design Options.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29240" number="33631" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Semi-permanent noise barriers are barriers that, due to their height, will require some form of anchoring system. Typically, semi-permanent barriers are intended for long term continuous use. Thus they are built out of materials suitable to withstand weather conditions for several years. Materials such as tongue and groove wooden timbers, vertical I-beam posts and lagging, or precast concrete panels, serve very well as semi-permanent noise barriers. Being anchored, semi-permanent barriers can easily extend to heights of 15 feet and must be in accordance with DOB and FDNY rules and regulations. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29241" number="33632" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where practicable, the responsible party shall build a pitched panel on top of the barrier in order to provide better shielding for multi-story receptor buildings, however care must be taken to avoid having the barrier tip over from unbalanced loading. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29242" number="33633" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Alternative barriers may be utilized in accordance with site-specific conditions. For example, shipping container (Conex) boxes are likely already available to the responsible party. For example, where work site space permits, these container boxes or truck trailers may be positioned along the edge of the work site to form a semi-permanent noise barrier. These containers are typically 8 feet wide by 8 feet tall and can be double-stacked to form a noise barrier 16 feet in height. The gaps between and/or under container boxes shall be filled-in to avoid having noise flank around or under the container boxes. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29243" number="33634" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>4.<TAB tab-count="1"/>There are also several product vendors that design and manufacture noise barrier materials and barrier systems. These special purpose products are available in various colors and materials including wood, plastic, Plexiglas, precast concrete or steel panels. They are available with or without anchoring systems, as needed. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29244" number="33635" version="2295">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Noise Barrier Specifications.</CHARFORMAT> Noise barriers shall be made of noise-resistant material sufficient to achieve a Sound Transmission Class (STC) rating of STC 30 or greater, based on sound transmission loss data taken according to ASTM Test Method E 90. Such a barrier can provide as much as a 10 dBA insertion loss providing it is positioned as close as possible to the noise source or to the receptors. To be at all effective, the barrier must be long and tall enough to completely block the line-of-sight between the noise source and the receptors. The gaps between adjacent panels must be filled-in to avoid having noise penetrate directly through the barrier.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-96908" number="33636" version="33">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 3/15/2017, eff. 4/14/2017) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-012]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-29245" number="33637" version="33">
								<HEADING>§ 28-108 Temporary or Portable Noise Barriers.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3893" name="T15C028_28-108"/>§ 28-108 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Temporary or Portable Noise Barriers.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29246" number="33638" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where there is a dedicated lane for such barrier, temporary or portable (i.e. unanchored) noise barriers shall be used for street work lasting longer than 15 days as set forth in this section. All such barriers shall be placed as close as possible to the noise source in order to maximize noise attenuation. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29247" number="33639" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where construction projects are of shorter duration than 15 days and within the property line and do not require perimeter barriers and are within 75 feet of a residential receptor, a temporary or portable (i.e. unanchored) noise barrier shall be made in accordance with this section. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29248" number="33640" version="2295">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction of temporary barrier.</CHARFORMAT> Noise barriers shall be made of noise-resistant material sufficient to achieve a Sound Transmission Class (STC) rating of STC 30 or greater, based on sound transmission loss data taken according to ASTM Test Method E 90. Such a barrier may provide as much as a 10 dBA insertion loss, provided it is positioned as close as possible to the noise source or to the receptors. To be at all effective, the barrier must be long and tall enough to completely block the line-of-sight between the noise source and the receptors. The gaps between adjacent panels must be filled-in to avoid having noise penetrate directly through the barrier. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29249" number="33641" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Temporary or portable noise barriers, where required, may be made, for example, of concrete jersey bases with 3/4-inch plywood panels attached to fence posts extending upwards to an overall height of 15 feet and must be in accordance with DOB and FDNY rules and regulations. This shall be the maximum height for a free-standing barrier in order to avoid it tipping over from wind load. Multiple jersey bases and plywood panels may be positioned adjacent to one another to form a barrier of any desired length. The gaps between adjacent sections shall be filled-in to form a continuous solid barrier surface. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29250" number="33642" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Wherever practicable, a pitched panel shall be built on top of the barrier in order to provide better shielding for multi-story receptor buildings; however care must be taken to avoid having the barrier tip over from unbalanced loading. Further, the barrier shall not exceed 15 feet in height including the pitched panel. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29251" number="33643" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Noise curtains.</CHARFORMAT> Noise curtain material may be mounted or hung over perimeter chain link fences, or draped over small noise sources, to form a flexible noise barrier. The chain link fences can also be attached to the top of jersey bases. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29252" number="33644" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Noise curtains shall be made of a 1/4-inch thick heavy vinyl material, with a noise absorptive quilt attached to one side (the side facing the noise source). </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29253" number="33645" version="2295">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Noise control curtains shall have a Sound Transmission Class (STC) rating of STC 30 or greater, based on sound transmission loss data according to ASTM Test Method E 90. The noise absorptive face of the curtains shall have a Noise Reduction Coefficient (NRC) rating of 0.85 or greater, based on sound absorption coefficient data taken according to ASTM Test Method C 423. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29254" number="33646" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>iii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Noise curtains of this sort, such as SoundSeal model BBC-13-2, or equivalently rated material, generally weigh about 1.5 lbs/sq. ft. They come in 4-foot wide sheets complete with grommets and Velcro edges to aid in hanging the curtains and sealing the sheets side-by-side. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29255" number="33647" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Noise Tents.</CHARFORMAT> A noise tent may be used within the property line. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29256" number="33648" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>i.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Noise curtain material may be attached to a metal frame to form a portable enclosure (known as a &quot;noise tent&quot;). The noise tent shall have noise curtain material attached on three sides and on top of the frame, with the remaining side of the frame left open for work access and ventilation. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29257" number="33649" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>ii.<TAB tab-count="1"/>A frame size of 8 feet tall by 6 feet wide by 6 feet deep shall allow the tent to be positioned over small noise sources, such as pumps, generators or compressors. The tent may also be used to cover a laborer using hand-held power tools, such as jackhammers, saws or grinders. Caster wheels may be placed under the frame for mobility, or the tent may be picked up and moved with the arm of a backhoe, for example.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-29258" number="33650" version="1187">
								<HEADING>§ 28-109 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15394" name="T15C028_28-109"/>§ 28-109 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29259" number="33651" version="33">
									<PARA>For the purpose of this chapter, the meaning of terms shall be as follows (unless the context specifically indicates otherwise):</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-96912" number="33652" version="2502">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>ASTM.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;ASTM&quot; shall mean ASTM International, the international standards organization. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-012]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29260" number="33653" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Canted Panel.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Canted Panel&quot; shall mean a tilted panel of noise mitigation material that extends a noise barrier to protect upper floor receptors from noise sources. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29261" number="33654" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Insertion Loss.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Insertion Loss&quot; shall mean the reduction in noise level at the receptor&apos;s location attributable to the introduction of a noise barrier, muffler, or other mitigation measure. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29262" number="33655" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Jersey Bases.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Jersey Bases,&quot; also known as concrete traffic dividers or jersey barriers, shall mean movable concrete bases used in construction that can accommodate fencing poles to which noise curtain material can be attached. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29263" number="33656" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Noise absorptive quilt.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Noise absorptive quilt&quot; shall mean padded light-weight porous material sewn together into a quilt-like pattern and then attached to one side of a vinyl sheet. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29264" number="33657" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Noise Barrier.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Noise Barrier&quot; shall mean a structure used for the purpose of placing near a noise source to reduce the noise level measurable at a receptor location. This can consist of noise resistant materials such as plywood, timbers, trailer containers, or noise curtains. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29265" number="33658" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Noise curtain.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Noise curtain&quot; shall mean noise control product comprised of (typically) 1/4-inch thick vinyl sheet, to act as a noise resistant material, with some noise absorptive quilt material attached on one side of the vinyl as well. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29266" number="33659" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Noise Pathway Controls.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Noise Pathway Controls&quot; shall mean noise mitigation techniques placed between the source of noise and the receptor. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29267" number="33660" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Noise-resistant material.</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0"> &quot;Noise-resistant material&quot; shall mean material that has sufficient mass and stiffness to resist noise from transmitting through the material. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29268" number="33661" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Receptor.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Receptor,&quot; also known as receiving property, shall mean real property, including but not limited to buildings, grounds, offices and dwelling units, from which sound levels from sound sources outside such property may be measured. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29269" number="33662" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Responsible party.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Responsible party&quot; shall mean, with respect to any activity regulated or covered by these rules, the owner of the premises on or where such activity occurs, and any agent of the owner engaged in such activity or any participant in such activity, including contractors and subcontractors. Any agency of the City of New York may also be a responsible party. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29270" number="33663" version="2295">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Sound Transmission Class (STC).</CHARFORMAT> The &quot;Sound Transmission Class&quot;, or &quot;STC rating&quot;, shall mean a single index number used to describe a solid panel or material&apos;s ability to prevent noise from transferring directly through it. Determination of a material&apos;s STC is done in accordance with ASTM Test Method E 90.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-96910" number="33664" version="33">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 3/15/2017, eff. 4/14/2017) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-012]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
							<LEVEL style-name="Subsection" style-name-escaped="Subsection" style-id="0-0-0-489" level-depth="8" toc-section="true">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-29271" number="33665" version="1187">
									<HEADING>§ 28-109 Appendix – Federal Highway Administration Roadway Construction Noise Model User&apos;s Guide, Jan. 2006.</HEADING>
									<PARA>
										<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
											<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3895" name=""/>§ 28-109 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Appendix – Federal Highway Administration Roadway Construction Noise Model User&apos;s Guide, Jan. 2006.</CHARFORMAT>
										</PARAFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-29272" number="33666" version="1071">
										<PARA>
											<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">CA/T Equipment 50 ft Noise Emission Reference Levels and Usage Factors – All noise levels expressed in A-weighted decibels with RMS &quot;slow&quot; time constant<LINEBRK/>&#160;</CHARFORMAT>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-29273" number="33667" version="1967">
										<PARA>
											<TABLE>
												<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="6" left-border-space="43" left-border-width="15" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="43" right-border-width="15" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="43" top-border-width="15" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="43" bottom-border-width="15" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="43" horizontal-border-width="15" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="43" vertical-border-width="15" vertical-border-color="#000000">
													<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="3" percentage="yes"/>
													<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
													<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="6" percentage="yes"/>
													<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="6" percentage="yes"/>
													<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="7" percentage="yes"/>
													<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="7" percentage="yes"/>
												</TABLEFORMAT>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
																<CELL header="true">
																	<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">
																		<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Label ID</CHARFORMAT>
																	</CELLFORMAT>
																</CELL>
															</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
																<CELL header="true">
																	<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">
																		<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Equipment Description</CHARFORMAT>
																	</CELLFORMAT>
																</CELL>
															</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
																<CELL header="true">
																	<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">
																		<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Impact Device? </CHARFORMAT>
																	</CELLFORMAT>
																</CELL>
															</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
																<CELL header="true">
																	<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">
																		<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Usage Factor (%)</CHARFORMAT>
																	</CELLFORMAT>
																</CELL>
															</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
																<CELL header="true">
																	<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">
																		<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Spec 721.560 Lmax<LINEBRK/>@ 50 ft (dBA, slow)</CHARFORMAT>
																	</CELLFORMAT>
																</CELL>
															</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center" tab-count="1">
																<TABSTOP number="0" position="0" justification="left" leader="none"/>
																<CELL header="true">
																	<CELLFORMAT alignment="bottom">
																		<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Actual Measured Lmax<LINEBRK/>@ 50 ft (dBA, slow)</CHARFORMAT>
																	</CELLFORMAT>
																</CELL>
															</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">A</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">All Other Equipment &gt; 5 HP</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">n/a </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">B</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Auger Drill Rig</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">84 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">C</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Backhoe</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">78 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">D</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Bar Bender</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">E</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Blasting</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Yes </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">N/A </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">94 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">n/a </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">F</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Boring Jack Power Unit</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">83 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">G</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Chain Saw</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">84 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">H</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Clam Shovel (dropping)</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Yes </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">93 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">87 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">I</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Compactor (ground)</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">83 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">J</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Compressor (air)</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">78 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">K</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Concrete Batch Plant</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">15 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">83 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">83 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">L</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Concrete Mixer Truck</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">79 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">M</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Concrete Pump Truck</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">82 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">81 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">N</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Concrete Saw</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">90 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">90 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">O</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Crane</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">16 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">81 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">P</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Dozer</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">82 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Q</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Drill Rig Truck</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">84 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">79 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">R</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Drum Mixer</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">S</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Dump Truck</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">84 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">76 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">T</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Excavator</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">81 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">U</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Flat Bed Truck</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">84 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">74 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">V</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Front End Loader</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">79 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">W</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Generator</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">82 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">81 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">X</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Generator (&lt;25KVA, VMS signs)</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">70 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">73 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Y</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Gradall</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">83 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Z</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Grader</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AA</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Grapple (on backhoe)</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">87 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AB</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Horizontal Boring Hydr. Jack</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">25 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">82 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AC</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Hydra Break Ram</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Yes </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">10 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">90 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">90 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AD</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Impact Pile Driver</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Yes </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">95 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">101 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AE</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Jackhammer</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Yes </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">89 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AF</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Man Lift</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">75 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AG</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Mounted Impact Hammer (hoe ram)</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Yes </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">90 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">90 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AH</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Pavement Scarafier</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">90 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AI</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Paver</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">77 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AJ</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Pickup Truck</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">55 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">75 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AK</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Pneumatic Tools</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AL</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Pumps</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">77 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">81 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AM</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Refrigerator Unit</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">100 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">82 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">73 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AN</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Rivet Buster/chipping gun</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Yes </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">79 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AO</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Rock Drill</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">81 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AP</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Roller</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AQ</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Sand Blasting</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">96 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AR</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Scraper</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">84 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AS</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Shears (on backhoe)</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">96 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AT</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Slurry Plant</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">100 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">78 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">78 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AU</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Slurry Trenching Machine</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">82 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AV</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Soil Mix Drill Rig</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AW</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Tractor</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">84 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">84 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AX</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Vacuum Excavator (Vac-truck)</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AY</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Vacuum Street Sweeper</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">10 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">82 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">AZ</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Ventilation Fan</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">100 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">79 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">BA</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Vibrating Hopper</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">50 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">87 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">BB</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Vibratory Concrete Mixer</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">80 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">BC</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Vibratory Pile Driver</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">95 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">101 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">BD</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Warning Horn</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">5 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">83 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">BE</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Water Jet deleading</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">20 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">85 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">92 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
												<ROW>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">BF</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">Welder/Torch</PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">No </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">40 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">73 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
													<COL>
														<PARA style-name="Small" style-name-escaped="Small" style-id="0-0-0-27">
															<PARAFORMAT justify="center">74 </PARAFORMAT>
														</PARA>
													</COL>
												</ROW>
											</TABLE>
										</PARA>
										<PARA>
										</PARA>
									</RECORD>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-109930" number="33668" version="1187">
								<HEADING>§ 28-110 Interior Renovation Work Noise Measures.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15396" name="T15C028_28-110"/>§ 28-110 Interior Renovation Work Noise Measures.</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109964" number="33669" version="2461">
									<PARA>Pursuant to Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-219" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-219</LINK>(a)(6), the responsible party performing interior renovation work, defined as work within an existing building, must utilize noise mitigation strategies and techniques to reduce noise from such interior renovation work. Construction activities that have a minimal noise impact as set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C030_30-102" destination-id="0-0-0-3911">30-102</LINK> shall not be required to utilize the interior renovation work noise measures set forth below provided such activities do not exceed the decibel levels set forth in § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-228" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-228</LINK> of the New York City Noise Control Code. The form for the Interior Noise Mitigation Plan is available at <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="http://www.nyc.gov/html/dep/html/noise/construction-noise.shtml">http://www.nyc.gov/html/dep/html/noise/construction-noise.shtml</LINK> and shall be filed and kept on site. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109963" number="33670" version="2313">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">General Rules of Operation.</CHARFORMAT> It shall be unlawful to engage in or to cause or permit any person to engage in interior renovation work other than on weekdays between the hours of 7:00 a.m. and 6:00 p.m. A person may however perform interior renovation work in connection with the alteration or repair of an existing one or two family owner-occupied dwelling classified in occupancy group J-3 or a convent or rectory on Saturdays and Sundays between the hours of 10:00 a.m. and 4:00 p.m. provided that such dwelling is located more than 300 feet from a house of worship. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109962" number="33671" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Source and Pathway Controls.</CHARFORMAT> Build sound barriers around noisy tool tasks as per below. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109961" number="33672" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Noise Barriers.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109960" number="33673" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>A.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Acceptable examples include but are not limited to: <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109959" number="33674" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>• Carsonite Sound Barrier <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.carsonite.com">www.carsonite.com</LINK>
										<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>• Sound Fighter LSE Sound Barrier <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.soundfighter.com">www.soundfighter.com</LINK>
										<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>• Kinetics Noise Block <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.kineticsnoise.com">www.kineticsnoise.com</LINK>
										<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>• one inch plywood rated at 30 STC</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109958" number="33675" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>B.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Place noise curtains on the walls of rooms where noisy operations are being performed. Acceptable examples include but are not limited to: <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109957" number="33676" version="1814">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>• Sound Seal BBC-13-2 <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.soundseal.com">www.soundseal.com</LINK>
										<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>• Illbruck Acoustic SONEX Curtain <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.illbruck-sonex.com">www.illbruck-sonex.com</LINK>
										<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>• McGill AirSilence Fibersorb Curtains <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.mcgillairsilence.com">www.mcgillairsilence.com</LINK>
										<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>• Acoustiblok, Acoustiblok-Wallcover <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.acoustiblok.com">www.acoustiblok.com</LINK>
										<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>• AcoustiGuard, GenieClip, Mass Loaded Vinyl, Barrer Material, Iso-sill <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.acoustiguard.com">www.acoustiguard.com</LINK>
										<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>• Kinetics Model ICC, KSCH, IsoGrid, IsoMax, PSB,Wallmat, IPRB <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.kinetcsnoie.com">www.kinetcsnoie.com</LINK>
										<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>• any equivalent curtain that meets the applicable decibel level set forth in § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-228" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-228</LINK> of the New York City Noise Control Code</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109956" number="33677" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>C.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Floor Sound Isolation.</CHARFORMAT> Acceptable examples include but are not limited to: <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109955" number="33678" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>• Acoustiblok, Acoustiwool, Acoustipad <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.acoustiblok.com">www.acoustiblok.com</LINK>
										<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>• AcoustiGuard, OT 4005&amp; 4010, Duraoustic, Barrier Material, Iso Sep 25HD <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.kineticsnoise.com">www.kineticsnoise.com</LINK>
										<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>• Kinetics, Model RIM, SR Floorboard, Soundmatt, FC Isolayment BR <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.kineticsnoise.com">www.kineticsnoise.com</LINK>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109954" number="33679" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Tools.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109953" number="33680" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>A.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Drills.</CHARFORMAT> The responsible party should select drills with the lowest loaded A-weighted sound power level (SWLA) that meet their needs. Acceptable examples include but are not limited to:<LINEBRK/>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109952" number="33681" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2" left-border-space="0" left-border-width="14" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="0" right-border-width="14" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="0" horizontal-border-width="14" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="0" vertical-border-width="14" vertical-border-color="#000000">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Manufacturer brand name</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Model number</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Milwaukee</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>0302-20</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Milwaukee</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>0299-20</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Milwaukee</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>0300-20</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Makita</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>6303H</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Hitachi</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>D10VH</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Makita</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>6408</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109951" number="33682" version="2513">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>B.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Circular Saws.</CHARFORMAT> The responsible party should select saws with the lowest loaded A-weighted sound power level (SWLA) that meet their needs. Acceptable examples include but are not limited to:<LINEBRK/>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109950" number="33683" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2" left-border-space="0" left-border-width="14" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="0" right-border-width="14" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="0" horizontal-border-width="14" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="0" vertical-border-width="14" vertical-border-color="#000000">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Manufacturer brand name</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Model number</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Porter Cable</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>345</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Milwaukee</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>6370-20</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Porter Cable</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>314</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Makita</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>5277NB</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Makita</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>5057KB</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Hitachi</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>C7SB2</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Porter Cable</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>743</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Bosch</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>CS20</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109949" number="33684" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>C.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Portable Generators.</CHARFORMAT> The responsible party should select models with the lowest levels (dBA) that meet their needs. Acceptable examples include but are not limited to:<LINEBRK/>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109948" number="33685" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2" left-border-space="0" left-border-width="14" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="0" right-border-width="14" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="0" horizontal-border-width="14" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="0" vertical-border-width="14" vertical-border-color="#000000">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Manufacturer brand name</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Model number</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Honda</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>EU3000isAN</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Honda</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>EU1000iAN</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Honda</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>EU2000 series</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Honda</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>EU6500isA</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109947" number="33686" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>D.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Orbital Sanders.</CHARFORMAT> The responsible party should select orbital sanders with the lowest loaded A-weighted sound power level (SWLA) that meet their needs. Acceptable examples include but are not limited to:<LINEBRK/>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109946" number="33687" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2" left-border-space="0" left-border-width="14" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="0" right-border-width="14" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="0" horizontal-border-width="14" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="0" vertical-border-width="14" vertical-border-color="#000000">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Manufacturer brand name</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Model number</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Black and Decker</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>MS500K</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Black and Decker</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>MS550GB</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109945" number="33688" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>E.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Power Screw Drivers.</CHARFORMAT> The responsible party should select power screw drivers with the lowest loaded A-weighted sound power level (SWLA) that meet their needs. Acceptable examples include but are not limited to:<LINEBRK/>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109944" number="33689" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2" left-border-space="0" left-border-width="14" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="0" right-border-width="14" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="0" horizontal-border-width="14" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="0" vertical-border-width="14" vertical-border-color="#000000">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Manufacturer brand name</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Model number</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Hitachi</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>W6V3</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>DeWalt</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>DW272</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109943" number="33690" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>F.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Reciprocating Saws.</CHARFORMAT> The responsible party should select reciprocating saws with the lowest loaded A-weighted sound power level (SWLA) that meet their needs. Acceptable examples include but are not limited to:<LINEBRK/>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109942" number="33691" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2" left-border-space="0" left-border-width="14" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="0" right-border-width="14" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="0" horizontal-border-width="14" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="0" vertical-border-width="14" vertical-border-color="#000000">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Manufacturer brand name</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Model number</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>DeWalt</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>DW309K</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Milwaukee</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>6519-22</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Milwaukee</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>6509-22</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Milwaukee</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>6524-21</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109941" number="33692" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>G.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Miter Saws.</CHARFORMAT> The responsible party should select miter saws with the lowest loaded A-weighted sound power level (SWLA) that meet their needs. Acceptable examples include but are not limited to:<LINEBRK/>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109940" number="33693" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2" left-border-space="0" left-border-width="14" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="0" right-border-width="14" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="0" horizontal-border-width="14" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="0" vertical-border-width="14" vertical-border-color="#000000">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Manufacturer brand name</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Model number</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Delta</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>MS250</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Hitachi</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>C10FCE</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>DeWalt</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>DW706</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109939" number="33694" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>H.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Grinders.</CHARFORMAT> The responsible party should select grinders with the lowest loaded A-weighted sound power level (SWLA) that meet their needs. Acceptable examples include but are not limited to:<LINEBRK/>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109938" number="33695" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2" left-border-space="0" left-border-width="14" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="0" right-border-width="14" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="0" horizontal-border-width="14" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="0" vertical-border-width="14" vertical-border-color="#000000">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Manufacturer brand name</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Model number</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Ryobi</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>AG401</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Ryobi</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>AG451</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Hitachi</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>G12SR2</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Ridgid</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>R1000</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Milwaukee</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>6148-6</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>DeWalt</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>DW402</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Bosch</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>1700A</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109937" number="33696" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>I.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Jig Saws.</CHARFORMAT> The responsible party should select jig saws with the lowest loaded A-weighted sound power level (SWLA) that meet their needs. Acceptable examples include but are not limited to:<LINEBRK/>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109936" number="33697" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2" left-border-space="0" left-border-width="14" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="0" right-border-width="14" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="0" horizontal-border-width="14" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="0" vertical-border-width="14" vertical-border-color="#000000">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Manufacturer brand name</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Model number</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Skil</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>4380</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Milwaukee</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>6266-22</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Black and Decker</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>JS600</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109935" number="33698" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>J.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hammer Drills.</CHARFORMAT> The responsible party should select hammer drills with the lowest loaded A-weighted sound power level (SWLA) that meet their needs. Acceptable examples include but are not limited to:<LINEBRK/>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109934" number="33699" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2" left-border-space="0" left-border-width="14" left-border-color="#000000" right-border-space="0" right-border-width="14" right-border-color="#000000" top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000" horizontal-border-space="0" horizontal-border-width="14" horizontal-border-color="#000000" vertical-border-space="0" vertical-border-width="14" vertical-border-color="#000000">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Manufacturer brand name</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Model number</CHARFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Hitachi</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>DH24PE</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>DeWalt</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>D25103</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Bosch</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>11224VSR</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>DeWalt</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>DW505</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109933" number="33700" version="1187">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>K.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The responsible party must consult the Federal CDC NIOSH power tools database to ensure that no quieter tools are available. If any of the tools set forth in subparagraphs A through J of this paragraph have been discontinued, the responsible party must contact the manufacturer to obtain the model number for any available newer model that has an equivalent or lower decibel level. If a tool is selected that is not on the DEP approved list, the tool must be rated to the same sound reduction or be certified to a lower decibel level than the tool cited in each applicable section. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109932" number="33701" version="1187">
									<PARA>(Added City Record 9/18/2018, eff. 10/18/2018) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-030]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>