<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-76997" number="88402" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 2: Organizations Possessing Rifles and Shotguns</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10041" name="T38C002"/>Chapter 2: Organizations Possessing Rifles and Shotguns</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-76998" number="88403" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 2-01 Introduction.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10043" name="T38C002_2-01"/>§ 2-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Introduction.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-76999" number="88404" version="3">
									<PARA>The following Rules have been promulgated by the Police Commissioner for the registration and regulation of organizations possessing rifles and shotguns. Such organizations are held responsible for the strict enforcement of and adherence to these Rules. Any violation thereof is cause for suspension or revocation of the privilege to possess rifles and shotguns.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-77000" number="88405" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 2-02 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10045" name="T38C002_2-02"/>§ 2-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77001" number="88406" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Ammunition. </CHARFORMAT>The term &quot;ammunition&quot; shall mean any explosives suitable to be fired from a rifle or shotgun.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77002" number="88407" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Certificate of registration.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;certificate of registration&quot; shall mean the Certificate of Registration of Rifles and Shotguns issued by the New York City Police Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77003" number="88408" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Custodian.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;custodian&quot; shall mean an individual personally possessing a rifle/shotgun permit, and designated by an organization to be held responsible for the safeguarding and supervision of any rifle or shotgun owned by the organization.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77004" number="88409" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Alternate custodian.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;alternate custodian&quot; shall mean an individual personally possessing a rifle/shotgun permit, and designated by an organization to be held responsible for the safeguarding and supervision of any rifle or shotgun owned by the organization when the custodian is unavailable to perform her/his duties.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77005" number="88410" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Fire Commissioner.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;Fire Commissioner&quot; shall mean the Fire Commissioner of the City of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77006" number="88411" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Organization. </CHARFORMAT>The term &quot;organization&quot; shall mean any firm, partnership, corporation, company or other entity, association, educational institution, cultural institution, or paramilitary organization registered by the Rifle/Shotgun Section to possess rifles and/or shotguns for the purpose of holding itself out to the general public as a business providing security or protection services for compensation; or instructing individuals in the use of rifles and/or shotguns; or organizing and supervising a competition or target practice involving the use of rifles and/or shotguns.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77007" number="88412" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Organization registration certificate.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;organization registration certificate&quot; shall mean the certificate issued by the Rifle/Shotgun Section to approved organizations registered to possess rifles and shotguns.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77008" number="88413" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rifle.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;rifle&quot; shall mean a &quot;rifle&quot; as defined in § 265.00 of the New York State Penal Law, except that for purposes of this chapter, a rifle shall have a barrel length of no less than sixteen inches, and an overall length of no less than twenty-six inches.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77009" number="88414" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rifle/Shotgun Section.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;Rifle/Shotgun Section&quot; shall mean the Rifle/Shotgun Section of the License Division of the New York City Police Department. The &quot;Rifle/Shotgun Section&quot; was at one time known as the &quot;Firearms Control Section.&quot;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77010" number="88415" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rifle/shotgun permit.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;rifle/shotgun permit&quot; shall mean the permit issued by the Rifle/Shotgun Section for the possession and purchase of rifles and shotguns.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77011" number="88416" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Shotgun.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;shotgun&quot; shall mean a &quot;shotgun&quot; as defined in § 265.00 of the New York State Penal Law, except that for purposes of this chapter, a shotgun shall have a barrel length of no less than eighteen inches and an overall length of no less than twenty-six inches.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77012" number="88417" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Storage permit.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;storage permit&quot; shall mean the permit for the storage of more than two hundred (200) rounds of ammunition issued by the Fire Commissioner.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-77013" number="88418" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 2-03 Applicability.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10047" name="T38C002_2-03"/>§ 2-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Applicability.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77014" number="88419" version="3">
									<PARA>These Rules shall apply to any person, firm, partnership, corporation, company or other entity, association, educational institution, cultural institution, or paramilitary organization possessing rifles and/or shotguns for the purpose of holding itself out to the general public as a business providing security or protection services for compensation; or instructing individuals in the use of rifles and/or shotguns; or engaging in a military drill or parade with rifles and/or shotguns; or organizing and supervising a competition or target practice involving the use of rifles and/or shotguns.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-77015" number="88420" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 2-04 Original Applications and Renewals.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10049" name="T38C002_2-04"/>§ 2-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Original Applications and Renewals.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77016" number="88421" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All applications, renewals, requests for information and inquiries by an organization pursuant to these Regulations shall be made to the Rifle/Shotgun Section, License Division, New York City Police Department, 120-55 Queens Blvd., Kew Gardens, N.Y. 11424, (718) 520-9300. The Rifle/Shotgun Section shall prescribe and enforce the manner in which an organization may be registered to possess rifles and shotguns.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77017" number="88422" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A letter prepared on the letterhead of the organization shall accompany the official application. In addition to a request to be designated an organization to possess rifles and shotguns, this letter shall set forth:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77018" number="88423" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the names of the custodian and alternate custodian;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77019" number="88424" version="1965">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the manner in which the rifles and shotguns shall be secured when not in use. The applicant shall also submit two (2) color photographs each of the designated custodian and alternate custodian, size 1 1/2 × 1 1/2 inches, taken within the past thirty (30) days, front view from the chest up, with the application.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77020" number="88425" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>During the pendency of the application, the applicant shall notify the Rifle/Shotgun Section of any necessary correction to or modification of the information provided in the original application, or any change in her/his status or circumstances, which may be relevant to the application.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77021" number="88426" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the application is disapproved the organization shall receive a written &quot;Notice of Application Disapproval&quot; from the Rifle/Shotgun Section indicating the reason(s) for the disapproval. If the organization wishes to appeal the decision it shall submit a sworn written statement, which shall be known as an &quot;Appeal of Application Disapproval,&quot; to the Division Head, License Division, One Police Plaza, Room 110A, New York, New York 10038 within thirty (30) calendar days of the date on the &quot;Notice of Application Disapproval&quot; requesting an appeal of the denial, and setting forth the reasons supporting the appeal. The Appeal of Application Disapproval shall become part of the application. It shall state the grounds for the appeal and shall contain the following statement to be signed by the applicant and notarized: &quot;Under penalty of perjury, deponent being duly sworn, says that s/he is familiar with all of the statements contained herein and that each of these statements is true, and no pertinent facts have been omitted.&quot; Appeals that are unsworn by the applicant or submitted by individuals or business entities other than the organization or its New York State licensed attorney shall not be accepted. All timely appeals shall receive a complete review of the applicant&apos;s entire file by the Division Head, License Division, who shall notify the organization of her/his determination. The Division Head, License Division shall not consider any documentation that was not submitted during the initial background investigation. There shall be no personal interviews to discuss appeals. If the appeal of the disapproval is denied, the organization shall receive a &quot;Notice of Disapproval After Appeal&quot; letter from the Division Head, License Division. This notice concludes the Police Department&apos;s administrative review procedure.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77022" number="88427" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An organization registration certificate shall expire on the last day of the third December after the date of issue and may be renewed every three (3) years thereafter. A renewal application shall be forwarded to the organization at least thirty (30) calendar days prior to the expiration date. If the renewal application is not received in a timely manner, the custodian or alternate custodian shall so notify the Rifle/Shotgun Section by telephone. Certificates may be renewed under the same conditions as original issuance. An application for issuance or renewal of a certificate may be disapproved if a false statement is made therein. All organizations shall be held responsible for renewing a certificate upon expiration. Failure to renew a registration prior to its expiration date shall result in its cancellation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77023" number="88428" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An organization registration certificate issued shall be valid only for the organization, custodian and alternate custodian mentioned and described in the certificate. A certificate shall not be transferable to another organization. The certificate and all rifles and shotguns possessed by an organization shall be available for inspection by members of the New York City Police Department. Failure by any organization to so exhibit a registration certificate shall be presumptive evidence that it is not duly registered.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77024" number="88429" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All organizations shall abide by the laws, rules, standards, and procedures promulgated by federal, state and local jurisdictions and law enforcement agencies applicable to the organization. A violation thereof is cause for suspension or revocation of a registration certificate issued by the Rifle/Shotgun Section. Upon suspension or revocation of a registration certificate, the custodian or alternate custodian shall deposit all rifles/shotguns in the organization&apos;s possession with her/his local police precinct and forward a copy of the voucher together with the registration certificate to the Rifle/Shotgun Section, 120-55 Queens Boulevard, Kew Gardens, N.Y. 11424, Room B-11. Her/his failure to comply within ten (10) calendar days from the date of suspension or revocation may result in arrest or other action by the Police Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77025" number="88430" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An organization registration certificate may be revoked or suspended by the Rifle/Shotgun Section for good cause by the issuance of a Notice of Determination Letter to the organization, which shall state in brief the grounds for the suspension or revocation and notify the organization of the opportunity for a hearing.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77026" number="88431" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon issuance of a written Notice of Determination Letter from the Rifle/Shotgun Section notifying the organization of suspension or revocation of a registration certificate by the Rifle/Shotgun Section, the organization shall have thirty (30) calendar days from the date of the notice to submit a written request for a hearing to the Commanding Officer, License Division, One Police Plaza, Room 110A, New York, New York 10038.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-77027" number="88432" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 2-05 Custodian Appointment and Duties.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10051" name="T38C002_2-05"/>§ 2-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Custodian Appointment and Duties.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77028" number="88433" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon application an organization shall appoint two (2) active members or employees of the organization to be personally responsible for all rifles and shotguns possessed by the organization, its employees or members. These individuals shall be known as the custodian and alternate custodian.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77029" number="88434" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be certified upon an application for registration that the custodian and alternate custodian are rifle/shotgun permit holders; the identification numbers thereof; that they are active members or employees of the organization; that they undertake to supervise the acts of the employees and members of the organization while they use any rifles or shotguns possessed by the organization; and that they have not been previously denied or had revoked appointment as a custodian or alternate custodian for the applicant or any other organization. If the organization does not have two active members or employees, the custodian shall be an active member or employee and the alternate custodian shall be a suitable designated individual who possesses a rifle/shotgun permit.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77030" number="88435" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Rifle/Shotgun Section reserves the right to require the custodian and alternate custodian to be fingerprinted and/or photographed in contemplation of issuing an organization registration certificate.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77031" number="88436" version="1404">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The custodian and alternate custodian shall ensure that all members or employees using rifles and shotguns registered by the organization are licensed by the Rifle/Shotgun Section to possess rifles and shotguns. The provisions of 38 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T28C002_2-05" destination-id="0-0-0-7393">2-05</LINK>(d) shall not be applicable to the following organizations:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77032" number="88437" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An organization actively engaged in the instruction of minors in the use of rifles and/or shotguns or the supervision of a competition or target practice for minors. A custodian and alternate custodian, designated by an organization of this nature, shall closely supervise all minors using rifles and/or shotguns registered by the organization, and ensure that such minors are instructed in the safe use of rifles and/or shotguns.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77033" number="88438" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A paramilitary organization actively engaged in the presentation of military drill or parade. A custodian and alternate custodian designated by an organization of this nature shall closely supervise all individuals using rifles and/or shotguns during all military drills or parades. The custodian and alternate custodian shall also ensure that such rifles and/or shotguns are not loaded during such events.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77034" number="88439" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The conviction of a custodian or alternate custodian anywhere of a felony or serious offense as defined in § 265.00(17) of the New York State Penal Law, or of a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence as defined in § 921(a) of title 18, United States Code, may require suspension or revocation of an organization&apos;s registration certificate. An organization&apos;s registration certificate may be suspended or revoked if the custodian or alternate custodian is the subject or recipient of an order of protection or a temporary order of protection, or the subject of an ineligibility order issued pursuant to § 530.14 of the New York State Criminal Procedure Law or § 842-a of the New York State Family Court Act.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77035" number="88440" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A custodian or alternate custodian shall immediately notify the Rifle/Shotgun Section by telephone, followed by written notice within ten (10) calendar days, of any incident or violation of law or rules of federal, state, or local jurisdictions regarding the custodian or alternate custodian, or affecting the premises or business operations. For purposes of this subdivision, an incident includes:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77036" number="88441" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>arrest, indictment or conviction in any jurisdiction;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77037" number="88442" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>summons (except traffic infraction);</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77038" number="88443" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>suspension or ineligibility order issued pursuant to § 530.14 of the New York State Criminal Procedure Law or § 842-a of the New York State Family Court Act;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77039" number="88444" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the fact that the custodian or alternate custodian is or becomes the subject or recipient of an order of protection or a temporary order of protection;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77040" number="88445" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>admission to any psychiatric institution, sanitarium and/or the receipt of psychiatric treatment;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77041" number="88446" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>receipt of treatment for alcoholism or drug abuse;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77042" number="88447" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the presence or occurrence of a disability or condition that may affect the handling of a rifle/shotgun, including but not limited to epilepsy, diabetes, fainting spells, blackouts, temporary loss of memory, or nervous disorder;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77043" number="88448" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>lost, stolen, altered or mutilated certificate of registration or organization registration certificate; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77044" number="88449" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9)<TAB tab-count="1"/>unlawful discharge of a rifle/shotgun.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77045" number="88450" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An organization shall inform the Rifle/Shotgun Section in writing of any proposed change of custodianship or any other amendment of its registration. An organization shall not alter a registration certificate without the permission of the Rifle/Shotgun Section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77046" number="88451" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The custodian and alternate custodian shall each be required to sign an acknowledgment that s/he shall be responsible for compliance with all laws, rules, regulations, standards, and procedures promulgated by federal, state, or local jurisdictions, and by federal, state, or local law enforcement agencies, that are applicable to each type of license or permit issued to her/him and to the organization. The Rifle/Shotgun Section shall provide the custodian and alternate custodian with the acknowledgment statement. These acknowledgment statements shall be affirmed in writing. Failure to affirm the acknowledgment statements shall result in denial of the application for the organization registration certificate. Upon appointment, each successive custodian and alternate custodian shall be required to affirm in writing an acknowledgment statement. Failure to do so shall result in the suspension or revocation of the organization&apos;s registration certificate. Custodians and alternate custodians shall be held responsible for having knowledge of all new laws and rules that may be enacted by local, state, or federal legislatures or promulgated by the New York City Police Department affecting their organization.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77047" number="88452" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The custodian and alternate custodian shall be responsible for securing all rifles and shotguns and all ammunition possessed by the organization at the close of business/activities every day. Failure to do so shall constitute good cause for suspension or revocation of the organization&apos;s registration certificate.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77048" number="88453" version="1875">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pursuant to New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="10-311" destination-id="0-0-0-0">10-311</LINK>(a), it shall be unlawful for any person or business enterprise to dispose of any rifle or shotgun which does not contain a safety locking device, defined as a design adaptation or attachable accessory that will prevent the use of the weapon by an unauthorized user. The following types of safety locking devices will be deemed to comply with this provision:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77049" number="88454" version="888">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a trigger lock, which prevents the pulling of the trigger without the use of a key; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77050" number="88455" version="888">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a combination handle, which prevents the use of the weapon without the alignment of the combination tumblers; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77051" number="88456" version="888">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a detachable or non-detachable locking device, composed primarily of steel or other metal of significant gauge to inhibit breaking, utilizing a metallic key or combination lock, rendering the weapon inoperable until the locking device is removed by an authorized person.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77052" number="88457" version="2819">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pursuant to New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="10-311" destination-id="0-0-0-0">10-311</LINK>(b), it shall be unlawful for any licensed manufacturer, licensed importer, or licensed dealer to dispose of any rifle or shotgun in New York City unless it is accompanied by the following warning, which shall appear in conspicuous and legible type in capital letters, and which shall be printed on a label affixed to the rifle or shotgun and on a separate sheet of paper included within the packaging enclosing the rifle or shotgun: &quot;THE USE OF A LOCKING DEVICE OR SAFETY LOCK IS ONLY ONE ASPECT OF RESPONSIBLE WEAPON STORAGE. ALL WEAPONS SHOULD BE STORED UNLOADED AND LOCKED IN A LOCATION THAT IS BOTH SEPARATE FROM THEIR AMMUNITION AND INACCESSIBLE TO CHILDREN AND ANY OTHER UNAUTHORIZED PERSONS. NEW YORK CITY LAW PROHIBITS, WITH CERTAIN EXCEPTIONS, ANY PERSON FROM ACQUIRING MORE THAN ONE FIREARM, OR MORE THAN ONE RIFLE OR SHOTGUN, WITHIN A 90-DAY PERIOD.&quot; <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77053" number="88458" version="1875">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(l)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pursuant to New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="10-311" destination-id="0-0-0-0">10-311</LINK>(c), any person who applies for and obtains authorization to purchase, or otherwise lawfully obtains, a rifle or shotgun shall be required to purchase or obtain a safety locking device at the time s/he purchases or obtains the rifle or shotgun.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77054" number="88459" version="1875">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(m)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pursuant to New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="10-311" destination-id="0-0-0-0">10-311</LINK>(d), the City of New York and its agencies, officers or employees shall not be liable to any party by reason of any incident involving, or the use or misuse of a safety locking device that may have been purchased in compliance with these rules.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77055" number="88460" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(n)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Organizations, custodians and alternate custodians shall cooperate with all reasonable requests by the Police Department for information and assistance in matters relating to the certificate.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77056" number="88461" version="2819">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 12/6/2024, eff. 1/5/2025) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-105]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-148661" number="88462" version="2819">
								<HEADING>§ 2-06 Storage of Rifles and Shotguns and Ammunition.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10053" name="T38C002_2-06"/>§ 2-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Storage of Rifles and Shotguns and Ammunition.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77057" number="88463" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pursuant to New York City Administrative Code § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="10-312" destination-id="0-0-0-0">10-312</LINK>, it shall be a criminal violation for any person who is the lawful owner or lawful custodian of a rifle or shotgun to store or otherwise place or leave such weapon in such a manner or under circumstances that it is out of her/his immediate possession or control, without having rendered such weapon inoperable by employing a safety locking device as defined in 38 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T38C002_2-05" destination-id="0-0-0-10051">2-05</LINK>(j). Such offense shall constitute a misdemeanor if the offender has previously been found guilty of such violation or if the violation is committed under circumstances which create a substantial risk of physical injury to another person. The Rifle/Shotgun Section recognizes that all organizations have incurred an obligation by being registered to maintain and use rifles and shotguns in a responsible fashion. In order to assist organizations, the Rifle/Shotgun Section has issued the following safety guidelines for storing rifles and shotguns on the premises:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77058" number="88464" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All rifle and shotgun cases shall be kept locked and secured at all times and shall be inaccessible to unauthorized individuals. All keys to such cases shall not leave the control of the custodian or alternate custodian.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77059" number="88465" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Rifles and shotguns shall be incapable of firing when not in use. Rifles and shotguns may be temporarily deactivated by removing magazines or bolts; by securing with bars or chains through the trigger guard; or by using individual trigger locks or other safety locking devices composed primarily of steel or other metal of significant gauge to inhibit breaking.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77060" number="88466" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A custodian and alternate custodian shall keep one updated inventory of all rifles and shotguns possessed by the organization in the event of loss or theft. Such inventory shall include a full description of each rifle and shotgun including manufacturer, model, serial number, if applicable, and calibre or gauge. The certificate of registration issued for each rifle and shotgun shall accompany these records.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77061" number="88467" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the event of loss or theft of any rifle or shotgun, certificate of registration, ammunition, or organization registration certificate, the custodian or alternate custodian is required to report the loss or theft to her/his local precinct and notify the Rifle/Shotgun Section by telephone on the next business day after discovery of the loss or theft. Follow up with a written notification to the Rifle/Shotgun Section within 10 calendar days of discovery of the loss or theft is also required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77062" number="88468" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any organization that stores in excess of two hundred (200) cartridges shall be required to obtain a storage permit from the Fire Commissioner. The storage of ammunition without a valid permit issued by the Fire Commissioner shall be deemed sufficient cause to revoke an organization&apos;s registration certificate.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77063" number="88469" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The quantities of cartridges and other ammunition stored on the premises shall not exceed the amounts fixed by the Fire Commissioner for storage of ammunition. The quantities so fixed shall be stated in the storage permit.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77064" number="88470" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All ammunition kept on the premises shall not be stored in an area where other materials of a highly flammable nature are manufactured or stored.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77065" number="88471" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Ammunition shall be stored in an area of the premises that can be reasonably secured. Only the custodian, alternate custodian, and authorized members or employees shall have access to this storage area.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77066" number="88472" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A custodian and alternate custodian shall take reasonable precautions to make the premises secure. These precautions shall include but not be limited to all applicable measures as listed below:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77067" number="88473" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Adequately protecting and securing all rear windows, doors and skylights.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77068" number="88474" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Securing windows at or near ground level with expanded metal welded to belted angle-iron frames.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77069" number="88475" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Installing alarms or other appropriate security/service systems upon the premises.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77070" number="88476" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Posting signs prominently on the premises warning of the presence of electronic or other types of security systems and containing penalties for criminal violations.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77071" number="88477" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Installing high-security cylinder locks in all doors.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77072" number="88478" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Illuminating fully the exterior and interior of the premises at night, and during the hours when business is not conducted within.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-77073" number="88479" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 2-07 Security Plan.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10055" name="T38C002_2-07"/>§ 2-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Security Plan.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77074" number="88480" version="3">
									<PARA>In order to properly protect an organization&apos;s premises and the rifles, shotguns and ammunition stored within, the Rifle/Shotgun Section requires that custodians utilize the New York City Police Department&apos;s Crime Prevention Security Survey. A member of the New York City Police Department will come to an organization&apos;s premises and inspect the building for security measures. After the inspection, the officer will recommend and suggest various methods designed to better protect the premises. These recommendations may include the choice of locks, gates, and alarm systems suitable for the premises. The inspection is free of charge. An organization shall contact its local police precinct, and request an appointment with the Crime Prevention Officer or the Community Policing Supervisor for a survey of the premises of the organization.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-77075" number="88481" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 2-08 Separability.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10057" name="T38C002_2-08"/>§ 2-08 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Separability.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-77076" number="88482" version="3">
									<PARA>If any clause, sentence, paragraph, or part of these Rules of the application to any organization, custodian, or circumstances shall be determined to be invalid, such determination shall not affect, impair or invalidate the remainder thereof.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>