<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-91100" number="108927" version="1359">
			<HEADING>Chapter 12: Historic District Master Plans</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-12773" name="T63C012"/>Chapter 12: Historic District Master Plans</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-91101" number="108928" version="2544">
								<HEADING>§ 12-01 District Master Plans.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-12775" name="T63C012_12-01"/>§ 12-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">District Master Plans.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91102" number="108929" version="2544">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Introduction.</CHARFORMAT> The Commission may develop master plans for the historic district, specific types of buildings within a historic district, distinctive areas within the historic district or for landmark sites containing multiple buildings. A district master plan may address common design issues such as storefront design, signage, sidewalk and areaway alterations as well as set forth specific alterations for individual buildings in an historic district or on a landmark site in a comprehensive manner that respects the significant architectural features and particular history of the historic district with allowances for specific building conditions. A district master plan may serve as a research tool or design guide for owners or tenants who wish to make alterations to their buildings. Upon the adoption of implementation rules as set forth in this rule, Commission staff can also issue a Certificate of No Effect (&quot;CNE&quot;) or a Permit for Minor Work (&quot;PMW&quot;) for certain types of alterations or work set forth in the district master plan. A District Master Plan does not preclude the Commission&apos;s consideration and approval of applications for proposed work that is not in compliance with the District Master Plan. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91103" number="108930" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">District Master Plans.</CHARFORMAT> Upon its own motion, the Commission may consider a master plan for alterations in a specific historic district, an individual landmark site containing multiple buildings or with respect to certain types of buildings or types of work in a specific historic district (&quot;District Master Plan&quot;). A District Master Plan may be approved by a Certificate of Appropriateness, a Certificate of No Effect on Protected Architectural Features, or a Permit for Minor Work, depending on the work covered by the plan.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91104" number="108931" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Calendaring.</CHARFORMAT> A District Master Plan will not be scheduled for the Commission&apos;s consideration unless the Commission, in its discretion and upon the adoption of a motion, votes to calendar the District Master Plan for a public hearing. A motion to calendar a proposed District Master Plan for further consideration must be approved by the majority of Commissioners present in order to be adopted. The date of the public hearing on the proposed District Master Plan may be set by the motion to calendar or may be set at some later time by the Chairman, acting at his or her discretion.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91105" number="108932" version="2545">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Public Hearing.</CHARFORMAT> If the Commission votes to calendar a District Master Plan for further consideration, a public hearing will be held in accordance with § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="25-308" destination-id="0-0-0-0">25-308</LINK> of the Administrative Code of New York City and the provisions of 63 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C001" destination-id="0-0-0-12611">Chapter 1</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91106" number="108933" version="2544">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Approval and Implementation.</CHARFORMAT> Following the public hearing, the Commission may vote to approve, approve with modifications, or disapprove the District Master Plan. If the District Master Plan is approved or approved with modifications, the District Master Plan may be implemented by the enactment of Rules in accordance with the City Administrative Procedure Act that specifically reference the District Master Plan (&quot;Implementation Rules&quot;). The Implementation Rules shall establish the scope and applicability of the District Master Plan and shall set forth the application procedures and the criteria for issuance of CNEs and PMWs pursuant to the District Master Plan. Any work permitted under the Implementation Rules pursuant to a CNE or PMW must be described with reasonable specificity as to design and materials in the District Master Plan. The public hearing for the proposed District Master Plan may be held concurrently with the public hearing for the Implementation Rules. However, the Commission must vote to approve the District Master Plan before it votes to approve the Implementation Rules and the District Master Plan shall have no force and effect until the Implementation Rules are adopted in accordance with the City Administrative Procedure Act. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91107" number="108934" version="2544">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application Procedure for Work Pursuant to Approved Master Plan.</CHARFORMAT> All applications for work pursuant to the District Master Plan must be signed by the building owner in accordance with 63 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C002_2-01" destination-id="0-0-0-12625">2-01</LINK> and must state that the application is being filed pursuant to the District Master Plan. Each application shall include drawings, specifications and other materials which describe the proposed work in detail. Commission staff will review the application to ascertain whether the proposed work is in accordance with the District Master Plan and the Implementation Rules. If Commission staff determines that the work is in compliance with the District Master Plan and the Implementation Rules, the staff will issue a CNE or PMW allowing the work to commence. The CNE or PMW must be obtained prior to the commencement of work and posted on the building while work is in progress. Each CNE or PMW shall be valid for four (4) years from the date of issuance and may be renewed upon application provided that Commission staff determines that the work authorized under the original approval remains in compliance with the District Master Plan and the Implementation Rules in effect on the date of such renewal. Issuance or renewal of a District Master Plan CNE or PMW is contingent upon the work&apos;s adherence to the District Master Plan and the materials and plans submitted and approved by Commission staff. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91108" number="108935" version="2544">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Amendment and Rescission.</CHARFORMAT> Upon its own motion, the Commission may amend or rescind a District Master Plan at any time, provided the Commission first holds a public hearing on the proposed amendment or rescission. In its discretion, the Commission shall calendar a public hearing with respect to such proposed amendment or rescission in accordance with the provisions of subdivision (b) of this section. Any Commission action to amend or rescind a District Master Plan shall be in accordance with the provisions of 63 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C001_1-04" destination-id="0-0-0-12619">1-04</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91109" number="108936" version="2544">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 7/20/2023, eff. 8/19/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-139663" number="108937" version="2544">
								<HEADING>§ 12-02 Stone Street Historic District Master Plan Implementation Rules.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-12777" name="T63C012_12-02"/>§ 12-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Stone Street Historic District Master Plan Implementation Rules.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91110" number="108938" version="2546">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Introduction.</CHARFORMAT> The Stone Street Historic District is a low-scale cluster of early nineteenth-century commercial structures, complemented by several picturesque early twentieth-century buildings designed by prominent architects. The Stone Street Historic District is a distinct enclave amidst the surrounding twentieth-century skyscrapers and is sited on narrow winding streets originally laid out by Dutch Colonists. The Stone Street Historic District Master Plan Implementation Rules (&quot;Rules&quot;) are promulgated to assist building owners who own buildings located within the Stone Street Historic District in applying to the Landmarks Preservation Commission (&quot;LPC&quot;) for approval of applications to undertake repair, rehabilitation, replacement, or alterations to storefronts (including but not limited to storefront infill, lighting, signage, security gates) and cellar entrances, and to make such buildings accessible to persons with disabilities, that are in accordance with the Stone Street Master Plan approved by the Commission. The Stone Street Master Plan is a master plan governing work to storefronts and cellar entrances, as well as alterations to make buildings within the historic district accessible to persons with disabilities. The Stone Street Master Plan will be the subject of a Certificate of Appropriateness determination at the same public hearing as these Rules. The Rules set forth herein will permit the LPC staff to issue Certificates of No Effect (&quot;CNE&quot;) or Permits for Minor Work (&quot;PMW&quot;) for work that complies with the approved Stone Street Master Plan. The goal of these Rules is to encourage appropriate repair, rehabilitation, replacement and alterations in the Stone Street Historic District by expediting the process of obtaining permits to perform such work. Work that is not in accordance with the Stone Street Master Plan will be reviewed by the Commission in accordance with its usual review procedures as set forth in the Landmarks Law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91111" number="108939" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in these Rules, the following terms shall have the following meanings:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91113" number="108940" version="2546">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Commission.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Commission&quot; shall mean the eleven Commissioners, including the Chairman, as established by Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3020" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3020</LINK> of the Charter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91114" number="108941" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>District Master Plan.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;District Master Plan&quot; shall have the meaning set forth in 63 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C012_12-01" destination-id="0-0-0-12775">12-01</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91115" number="108942" version="1891">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Landmarks Law.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Landmarks Law&quot; shall refer to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3020" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3020</LINK> of the Charter and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T25C003" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 3 of Title 25</LINK> of the Administrative Code of the City of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91116" number="108943" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>LPC.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;LPC&quot; shall mean the Landmarks Preservation Commission acting in its agency capacity to implement the Landmarks Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91117" number="108944" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Stone Street Master Plan.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Stone Street Master Plan&quot; shall mean the District Master Plan for the Stone Street Historic District and approved by the Commission as a Certificate of Appropriateness. Copies of the Stone Street Master Plan may be obtained by contacting the Commission&apos;s Public Information Specialist at (212) 487-6782 or by writing to the same at the Commission&apos;s office by appointment. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-139664" number="108945" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Terms not otherwise defined in these rules shall have the meanings given them in the Landmarks Law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91118" number="108946" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eligible buildings.</CHARFORMAT> The buildings located within the Stone Street Historic District are subject to these Rules.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91119" number="108947" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Permitted alterations pursuant to the Stone Street Master Plan.</CHARFORMAT> The LPC staff shall issue a CNE or PMW for work on eligible buildings within the Stone Street Historic District if the staff determines that: (1) the proposed work meets the criteria set forth in the Stone Street Master Plan; and (2) the staff determines that the proposed work will not adversely affect any significant exterior architectural feature of the eligible building or the Stone Street Historic District. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91120" number="108948" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application procedures.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91121" number="108949" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Submission of Application.</CHARFORMAT> See 63 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C002" destination-id="0-0-0-12623">Chapter 2</LINK>, Subchapter A (&quot;Application Procedure&quot;) and 63 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C012" destination-id="0-0-0-12773">Chapter 12</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91122" number="108950" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application Materials.</CHARFORMAT> The applicant must submit adequate materials that clearly set forth the scope and details of the proposed work. At a minimum, the applicant must submit detailed drawings that specifically show the proposed work and all other materials required by the LPC staff. Drawings must be made to scale, and include all pertinent dimensions. LPC staff may require applicants to submit other materials, including but not limited to photographs of existing conditions, construction details, material samples, specifications, or maps as necessary to clearly explain the proposed work. LPC staff may also require probes or other investigations to determine the existing conditions and critical dimensions peculiar to each eligible building.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91123" number="108951" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Review Procedure.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91124" number="108952" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The application will be deemed complete when the LPC staff determines that adequate materials have been submitted that clearly set forth the scope and details of the proposed work.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91125" number="108953" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the application is complete, LPC staff will review the application for conformity with these Rules and the criteria of the Stone Street Master Plan. Upon determination that the criteria of the Rules have been met, a CNE or PMW will be issued pursuant to subdivision (f) 63 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C012_12-01" destination-id="0-0-0-12775">12-01</LINK>. A determination that a CNE or PMW should be issued shall mean that the proposed work satisfies the criteria set forth in the Stone Street Master Plan and that the work is appropriate to or will have no effect on protected architectural features of the specific eligible building in question and is otherwise appropriate to the Stone Street Historic District. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91126" number="108954" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the criteria set forth in these rules for a CNE or PMW have not been met, the LPC staff will provide the applicant with a notice of the proposed denial of the application. The applicant may request a meeting with the Director of the Preservation Department, or, in the absence of the Director, with a Deputy Director, to discuss the interpretation of these Rules. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91127" number="108955" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications for work that do not qualify for an approval in accordance with these Rules shall be subject to the LPC&apos;s usual review procedure as set forth in the Landmarks Law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91128" number="108956" version="2544">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 7/20/2023, eff. 8/19/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-139662" number="108957" version="2544">
								<HEADING>§ 12-03 Implementation Rules for the District Master Plan for Storefronts on Madison Avenue in the Upper East Side Historic District.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-12779" name="T63C012_12-03"/>§ 12-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Implementation Rules for the District Master Plan for Storefronts on Madison Avenue in the Upper East Side Historic District.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91129" number="108958" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Introduction.</CHARFORMAT> The implementation rules (&quot;Rules&quot;) for the District Master Plan for Storefronts on Madison Avenue in the Upper East Side Historic District (&quot;District Master Plan&quot;) are promulgated to assist building owners in applying to the Landmarks Preservation Commission (&quot;LPC&quot;) for approval of applications to undertake repair, rehabilitation, replacement, or alterations to storefronts (including but not limited to storefront infill, lighting, signage, security gates, windows and doors) along Madison Avenue within the Upper East Side Historic District that are in accordance with the District Master Plan approved by the Commission. The rules set forth herein permit the LPC staff to issue Certificates of No Effect (&quot;CNE&quot;) or Permits for Minor Work (&quot;PMW&quot;) for work that complies with the approved District Master Plan. Work that is not in accordance with the requirements of the District Master Plan will be reviewed by the Commission in accordance with its usual review procedures under the Landmarks Law. The objective of the District Master Plan is to provide owners, architects and store tenants with design criteria which will allow timely review of storefront alterations while protecting the architecturally and historically significant features of the buildings. The District Master Plan will cover buildings on Madison Avenue that fall within the Upper East Side Historic District. Additionally, at corner buildings the District Master Plan will cover the building facades facing both Madison Avenue and the side streets. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91130" number="108959" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in these Rules, the following terms shall have the following meanings:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91132" number="108960" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Commission.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Commission&quot; shall mean the eleven Commissioners, including the Chairman, as established by Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3020" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3020</LINK> of the Charter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91133" number="108961" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>District Master Plan.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;District Master Plan&quot; shall mean the District Master Plan for Storefronts on Madison Avenue in the Upper East Side Historic District and approved by the Commission as a Certificate of Appropriateness. A copy of the District Master Plan may be reviewed at the offices of the Commission by appointment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91134" number="108962" version="1891">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Landmarks Law.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Landmarks Law&quot; shall refer to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3020" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3020</LINK> of the Charter and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T25C003" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 3 of Title 25</LINK> of the Administrative Code of the City of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91135" number="108963" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>LPC.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;LPC&quot; shall mean the Landmarks Preservation Commission acting in its agency capacity to implement the Landmarks Law. Terms not otherwise defined in these rules shall have the meanings given them in the Landmarks Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91136" number="108964" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eligible buildings.</CHARFORMAT> As specifically set forth and described in the District Master Plan, these Rules shall cover buildings facing Madison Avenue and located within the Upper East Side Historic District, including the commercial portions of a building facing onto both Madison Avenue and a side street.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91137" number="108965" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Permitted alterations pursuant to the District Master Plan.</CHARFORMAT> The LPC staff shall issue a CNE or PMW for work on storefronts in eligible buildings along Madison Avenue if the staff determines that: <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91138" number="108966" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The proposed work meets the design criteria for storefront alterations as set forth in the District Master Plan; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91139" number="108967" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The staff determines that the proposed work would not adversely affect any significant architectural feature of the building.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91140" number="108968" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application procedures.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91141" number="108969" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Submission of application.</CHARFORMAT> See 63 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C002" destination-id="0-0-0-12623">Chapter 2</LINK>, Subchapter A (&quot;Application Procedure&quot;) and 63 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C012" destination-id="0-0-0-12773">Chapter 12</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91142" number="108970" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application materials.</CHARFORMAT> The applicant shall submit adequate materials that clearly set forth the scope and details of the proposed work. At a minimum, the applicant shall submit detailed drawings that specifically show the proposed work and all other materials required by the LPC staff. Drawings shall be made to scale, and include all pertinent dimensions. LPC staff may require applicants to submit other materials, including but not limited to photographs of existing conditions, construction details, material samples, specifications, or maps as necessary to clearly explain the proposed work. LPC staff may also require probes or other investigations to determine the existing conditions and critical dimensions peculiar to each eligible building storefront.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91143" number="108971" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Review procedure.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91144" number="108972" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The application will be deemed complete when the LPC staff determines that adequate materials have been submitted that clearly set forth the scope and details of the proposed work.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91145" number="108973" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the application is complete, LPC staff will review the application for conformity with these Rules and the criteria of the District Master Plan. Upon determination that the criteria of the Rules have been met, a CNE or PMW will be issued pursuant to subdivision (f) of 63 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C012_12-01" destination-id="0-0-0-12775">12-01</LINK>. A determination that a CNE or PMW should be issued shall mean that the proposed work satisfies the criteria of the District Master Plan and that the work is appropriate to or will have no effect on protected architectural features of the specific eligible building in question and is otherwise appropriate to the Upper East Side Historic District. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91146" number="108974" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the LPC staff determines that the criteria set forth in these Rules have not been met, the LPC staff shall provide the applicant with a notice of the proposed denial of the application. The applicant may request a meeting with the Director of the Preservation Department, or, in the absence of the Director, with a Deputy Director, to discuss the determination.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91147" number="108975" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications for work that do not qualify for approval in accordance with these Rules shall be subject to the LPC&apos;s usual review procedure as set forth in the Landmarks Law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91148" number="108976" version="2544">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 7/20/2023, eff. 8/19/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-139661" number="108977" version="2544">
								<HEADING>§ 12-04 Implementation Rules for the District Master Plan for Storefronts on Madison Avenue in the Metropolitan Museum Historic District.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-12781" name="T63C012_12-04"/>§ 12-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Implementation Rules for the District Master Plan for Storefronts on Madison Avenue in the Metropolitan Museum Historic District.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91149" number="108978" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Introduction.</CHARFORMAT> The implementation rules (&quot;Rules&quot;) for the District Master Plan for Storefronts on Madison Avenue in the Metropolitan Museum Historic District (&quot;District Master Plan&quot;) are promulgated to assist building owners in applying to the Landmarks Preservation Commission (&quot;LPC&quot;) for approval of applications to undertake repair, rehabilitation, replacement, or alterations to storefronts (including but not limited to storefront infill, lighting, signage, security gates, windows and doors) along Madison Avenue within the Metropolitan Museum Historic District that are in accordance with the District Master Plan approved by the Commission. The rules set forth herein permit the LPC staff to issue Certificates of No Effect (&quot;CNE&quot;) of Permits for Minor Work (&quot;PMW&quot;) for work that complies with the approved District Master Plan. Work that is not in accordance with the requirements of the District Master Plan will be reviewed by the Commission in accordance with its usual review procedures under the Landmarks Law. The objective of the District Master Plan is to provide owners, architects and store tenants with design criteria which will allow timely review of storefront alterations while protecting the architecturally and historically significant features of the buildings. The District Master Plan will cover buildings on Madison Avenue that fall within the Metropolitan Museum Historic District. Additionally, at corner buildings the District Master Plan will cover the building facades facing both Madison Avenue and the side streets. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91150" number="108979" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in these Rules, the following terms shall have the following meanings:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91152" number="108980" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Commission.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Commission&quot; shall mean the eleven Commissioners, including the Chairman, as established by Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3020" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3020</LINK> of the Charter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91153" number="108981" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>District Master Plan.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;District Master Plan&quot; shall mean the District Master Plan for Storefronts on Madison Avenue in the Metropolitan Museum Historic District and approved by the Commission as a Certificate of Appropriateness. A copy of the District Master Plan may be reviewed at the offices of the Commission by appointment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91154" number="108982" version="1891">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Landmarks Law.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Landmarks Law&quot; shall refer to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3020" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3020</LINK> of the Charter and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T25C003" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 3 of Title 25</LINK> of the Administrative Code of the City of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91155" number="108983" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>LPC.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;LPC&quot; shall mean the Landmarks Preservation Commission acting in its agency capacity to implement the Landmarks Law. Terms not otherwise defined in these rules shall have the meanings given them in the Landmarks Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91156" number="108984" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eligible buildings.</CHARFORMAT> As specifically set forth and described in the District Master Plan, these Rules shall cover buildings facing Madison Avenue and located within the Metropolitan Museum Historic District, including the commercial portions of a building facing onto both Madison Avenue and a side street.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91157" number="108985" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Permitted alterations pursuant to the District Master Plan.</CHARFORMAT> The LPC staff shall issue a CNE or PMW for work on storefronts in eligible buildings along Madison Avenue if the staff determines that: <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91158" number="108986" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The proposed work meets the design criteria for storefront alterations as set forth in the District Master Plan; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91159" number="108987" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The staff determines that the proposed work would not adversely affect any significant architectural feature of the building.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91160" number="108988" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application procedures.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91161" number="108989" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Submission of application.</CHARFORMAT> See 63 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C002" destination-id="0-0-0-12623">Chapter 2</LINK>, Subchapter A (&quot;Application Procedure&quot;) and 63 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C012" destination-id="0-0-0-12773">Chapter 12</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91162" number="108990" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application materials.</CHARFORMAT> The applicant shall submit adequate materials that clearly set forth the scope and details of the proposed work. At a minimum, the applicant shall submit detailed drawings that specifically show the proposed work and all other materials required by the LPC staff. Drawings shall be made to scale, and include all pertinent dimensions. LPC staff may require applicants to submit other materials, including but not limited to photographs of existing conditions, construction details, material samples, specifications, or maps as necessary to clearly explain the proposed work. LPC staff may also require probes or other investigations to determine the existing conditions and critical dimensions peculiar to each eligible building storefront.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91163" number="108991" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Review procedure.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91164" number="108992" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The application will be deemed complete when the LPC staff determines that adequate materials have been submitted that clearly set forth the scope and details of the proposed work.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91165" number="108993" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the application is complete, LPC staff will review the application for conformity with these Rules and the criteria of the District Master Plan. Upon determination that the criteria of the Rules have been met, an ATP will be issued pursuant to subdivision (f) of 63 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C012_12-01" destination-id="0-0-0-12775">12-01</LINK>. A determination that a CNE or PMW should be issued shall mean that the proposed work satisfies the criteria of the District Master Plan and that the work is appropriate to or will have no effect on protected architectural features of the specific eligible building in question and is otherwise appropriate to the Metropolitan Museum Historic District. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91166" number="108994" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the LPC staff determines that the criteria set forth in these Rules have not been met, the LPC staff shall provide the applicant with a notice of the proposed denial of the application. The applicant may request a meeting with the Director of the Preservation Department, or, in the absence of the Director, with a Deputy Director, to discuss the determination.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91167" number="108995" version="2547">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications for work that do not qualify for approval in accordance with these Rules shall be subject to the LPC&apos;s usual review procedure as set forth in the Landmarks Law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91168" number="108996" version="2544">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 7/20/2023, eff. 8/19/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-139660" number="108997" version="2544">
								<HEADING>§ 12-05 Implementation Rules for the District Master Plan for Storefronts on Madison Avenue in the Carnegie Hill (and Extension) Historic District.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-12783" name="T63C012_12-05"/>§ 12-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Implementation Rules for the District Master Plan for Storefronts on Madison Avenue in the Carnegie Hill (and Extension) Historic District.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91169" number="108998" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Introduction.</CHARFORMAT> The implementation rules (&quot;Rules&quot;) for the District Master Plan for Storefronts on Madison Avenue in the Carnegie Hill (and Extension) Historic District (&quot;District Master Plan&quot;) are promulgated to assist building owners in applying to the Landmarks Preservation Commission (&quot;LPC&quot;) for approval of applications to undertake repair, rehabilitation, replacement, or alterations to storefronts (including but not limited to storefront infill, lighting, signage, security gates, windows and doors) along Madison Avenue within the Carnegie Hill (and Extension) Historic District that are in accordance with the District Master Plan approved by the Commission. The rules set forth herein permit the LPC staff to issue Certificates of No Effect (&quot;CNE&quot;) or Permits for Minor Work (&quot;PMW&quot;) for work that complies with the approved District Master Plan. Work that is not in accordance with the requirements of the District Master Plan will be reviewed by the Commission in accordance with its usual review procedures under the Landmarks Law. The objective of the District Master Plan is to provide owners, architects and store tenants with design criteria which will allow timely review of storefront alterations while protecting the architecturally and historically significant features of the buildings. The District Master Plan will cover buildings on Madison Avenue that fall within the Carnegie Hill (and Extension) Historic District. Additionally, at corner buildings the District Master Plan will cover the building facades facing both Madison Avenue and the side streets. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91170" number="108999" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in these Rules, the following terms shall have the following meanings:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91172" number="109000" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Commission.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Commission&quot; shall mean the eleven Commissioners, including the Chairman, as established by Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3020" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3020</LINK> of the Charter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91173" number="109001" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>District Master Plan.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;District Master Plan&quot; shall mean the District Master Plan for Storefronts on Madison Avenue in the Carnegie Hill (and Extension) Historic District and approved by the Commission as a Certificate of Appropriateness. A copy of the District Master Plan may be reviewed at the offices of the Commission by appointment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91174" number="109002" version="1891">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Landmarks Law.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Landmarks Law&quot; shall refer to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3020" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3020</LINK> of the Charter and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T25C003" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 3 of Title 25</LINK> of the Administrative Code of the City of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91175" number="109003" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>LPC.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;LPC&quot; shall mean the Landmarks Preservation Commission acting in its agency capacity to implement the Landmarks Law. Terms not otherwise defined in these rules shall have the meanings given them in the Landmarks Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91176" number="109004" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eligible buildings.</CHARFORMAT> As specifically set forth and described in the District Master Plan, these Rules shall cover buildings facing Madison Avenue and located within the Carnegie Hill (and Extension) Historic District, including the commercial portions of a building facing onto both Madison Avenue and a side street.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91177" number="109005" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Permitted alterations pursuant to the District Master Plan.</CHARFORMAT> The LPC staff shall issue a CNE or PMW for work on storefronts in eligible buildings along Madison Avenue if the staff determines that: <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91178" number="109006" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The proposed work meets the design criteria for storefront alterations as set forth in the District Master Plan; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91179" number="109007" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The staff determines that the proposed work would not adversely affect any significant architectural feature of the building.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91180" number="109008" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application procedures.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91181" number="109009" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Submission of application.</CHARFORMAT> See 63 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C002" destination-id="0-0-0-12623">Chapter 2</LINK>, Subchapter A (&quot;Application Procedure&quot;) and 63 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C012" destination-id="0-0-0-12773">Chapter 12</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91182" number="109010" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application materials.</CHARFORMAT> The applicant shall submit adequate materials that clearly set forth the scope and details of the proposed work. At a minimum, the applicant shall submit detailed drawings that specifically show the proposed work and all other materials required by the LPC staff. Drawings shall be made to scale, and include all pertinent dimensions. LPC staff may require applicants to submit other materials, including but not limited to photographs of existing conditions, construction details, material samples, specifications, or maps as necessary to clearly explain the proposed work. LPC staff may also require probes or other investigations to determine the existing conditions and critical dimensions peculiar to each eligible building storefront.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91183" number="109011" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Review procedure.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91184" number="109012" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The application will be deemed complete when the LPC staff determines that adequate materials have been submitted that clearly set forth the scope and details of the proposed work.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91185" number="109013" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the application is complete, LPC staff will review the application for conformity with these Rules and the criteria of the District Master Plan. Upon determination that the criteria of the Rules have been met, a CNE or PMW will be issued pursuant to subdivision (f) of 63 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C012_12-01" destination-id="0-0-0-12775">12-01</LINK>. A determination that a CNE or PMW should be issued shall mean that the proposed work satisfies the criteria of the District Master Plan and that the work is appropriate to or will have no effect on protected architectural features of the specific eligible building in question and is otherwise appropriate to the Carnegie Hill (and Extension) Historic District. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91186" number="109014" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the LPC staff determines that the criteria set forth in these Rules have not been met, the LPC staff shall provide the applicant with a notice of the proposed denial of the application. The applicant may request a meeting with the Director of the Preservation Department, or, in the absence of the Director, with a Deputy Director, to discuss the determination.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91187" number="109015" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications for work that do not qualify for approval in accordance with these Rules shall be subject to the LPC&apos;s usual review procedure as set forth in the Landmarks Law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91188" number="109016" version="2544">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 7/20/2023, eff. 8/19/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-139659" number="109017" version="2544">
								<HEADING>§ 12-06 Implementation Rules for the District Master Plan for the Douglaston Historic District.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-12785" name="T63C012_12-06"/>§ 12-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Implementation Rules for the District Master Plan for the Douglaston Historic District.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91189" number="109018" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Introduction.</CHARFORMAT> The implementation rules (&quot;Rules&quot;) for The District Master Plan for the Douglaston Historic District (&quot;District Master Plan&quot;) are promulgated to assist building owners in applying to the Landmarks Preservation Commission (&quot;LPC&quot;) for approval of applications to undertake various types of work on properties located within the Douglaston Historic District, including additions, outbuildings, window replacement, heating, venting and air conditioning, and work on or affecting significant landscape improvements. The rules set forth herein permit the LPC staff to issue Certificates of No Effect (&quot;CNE&quot;) or Permits for Minor Work (&quot;PMW&quot;) for work that complies with the approved District Master Plan. Work that is not in accordance with the requirements of the District Master Plan will be reviewed by the Commission in accordance with its usual review procedures under the Landmarks Law. The objective of the District Master Plan is to provide owners, architects and store tenants with design criteria which will allow timely review of proposed alterations while protecting the architecturally and historically significant features of the buildings and historic district&apos;s sense of place. The District Master Plan will cover all buildings in the Douglaston Historic District. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91190" number="109019" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in these Rules, the following terms shall have the following meanings:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91192" number="109020" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Commission.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Commission&quot; shall mean the appointed Commissioners, including the Chairman, acting as the Landmarks Preservation Commission as established by Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3020" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3020</LINK> of the Charter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91193" number="109021" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>District Master Plan.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;District Master Plan&quot; shall mean the District Master Plan for the Douglaston Historic District approved by the Commission as a Certificate of Appropriateness. A copy of the District Master Plan may be reviewed at the offices of the Commission by appointment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91194" number="109022" version="1891">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Landmarks Law.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Landmarks Law&quot; shall refer to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3020" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3020</LINK> of the Charter and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T25C003" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 3 of Title 25</LINK> of the Administrative Code of the City of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91195" number="109023" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Landscape Improvement.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Landscape Improvement&quot; shall mean a physical betterment of real property or any part thereof, consisting of natural or artificial landscape, including but not limited to grade, body of water, hedge, mature tree, walkway, road, plaza, wall, fence, step, fountain, or sculpture.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91196" number="109024" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>LPC.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;LPC&quot; shall mean the Landmarks Preservation Commission acting in its agency capacity to implement the Landmarks Law. Terms not otherwise defined in these rules shall have the meanings given them in the Landmarks Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91197" number="109025" version="2495">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eligible buildings.</CHARFORMAT> All buildings in the Douglaston Historic District are subject to the District Master Plan.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91198" number="109026" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Permitted alterations.</CHARFORMAT> The LPC staff shall issue a CNE or PMW if the staff determines that: <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91199" number="109027" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The proposed work meets the criteria set forth in the District Master Plan; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91200" number="109028" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The proposed work will not adversely affect any significant architectural feature of the building or significant Landscape Improvement, not otherwise permitted by the District Master Plan or other LPC approval.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91201" number="109029" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application procedures.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91202" number="109030" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Submission of application.</CHARFORMAT> See 63 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C002" destination-id="0-0-0-12623">Chapter 2</LINK>, Subchapter A (&quot;Application Procedure&quot;) and 63 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C012" destination-id="0-0-0-12773">Chapter 12</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91203" number="109031" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application materials.</CHARFORMAT> The applicant shall submit adequate materials that clearly set forth the scope and details of the proposed work. At a minimum, the applicant shall submit detailed drawings that specifically show the proposed work and all other materials required by the LPC staff. Drawings shall be made to scale, and include all pertinent dimensions. LPC staff may require applicants to submit other materials, including but not limited to photographs of existing conditions, construction details, material samples, specifications, or maps as necessary to clearly explain the proposed work. LPC staff may also require mockups of proposed additions or outbuildings to determine the visibility of such additions or outbuildings, and probes or other investigations to determine existing conditions.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91204" number="109032" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Review procedure.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91205" number="109033" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The application will be deemed complete when the LPC staff determines that the materials submitted adequately and clearly set forth the scope and details of the proposed work.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91206" number="109034" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the application is complete, LPC staff will review the application for conformity with these Rules and the criteria of the District Master Plan. Upon determination that the criteria of the Rules have been met, a CNE or PMW will be issued pursuant to subdivision (f) of 63 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C012_12-01" destination-id="0-0-0-12775">12-01</LINK>. A determination that a CNE or PMW should be issued shall mean that the proposed work satisfies the criteria of the District Master Plan and that the work is appropriate to or will have no effect on protected architectural features of the specific building in question and is otherwise appropriate to the Douglaston Historic District. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91207" number="109035" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the LPC staff determines that the criteria set forth in these Rules have not been met, the LPC staff shall provide the applicant with a notice of the proposed denial of the application. The applicant may request a meeting with the Director of the Preservation Department, or, in the absence of the Director, with a Deputy Director, to discuss the determination.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91208" number="109036" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications for work that do not qualify for approval in accordance with these Rules shall be subject to the LPC&apos;s usual review procedure as set forth in the Landmarks Law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91209" number="109037" version="2544">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 7/20/2023, eff. 8/19/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-139658" number="109038" version="2544">
								<HEADING>§ 12-07 Implementation Rules for the District Master Plan for the Fieldston Historic District.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-12787" name="T63C012_12-07"/>§ 12-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Implementation Rules for the District Master Plan for the Fieldston Historic District.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91210" number="109039" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Introduction.</CHARFORMAT> The implementation rules (&quot;Rules&quot;) for The District Master Plan for the Fieldston Historic District (&quot;District Master Plan&quot;) are promulgated to assist building owners in applying to the Landmarks Preservation Commission (&quot;LPC&quot;) for approval of applications to undertake various types of work on properties located within the Fieldston Historic District, including additions, outbuildings, window replacement, heating, venting and air conditioning, and work on or affecting significant landscape improvements. The Rules set forth herein permit the LPC staff to issue Certificates of No Effect (&quot;CNE&quot;) or Permits for Minor Work (&quot;PMW&quot;) for work that complies with the approved District Master Plan. Work that is not in accordance with the requirements of the District Master Plan will be reviewed by the Commission in accordance with its usual review procedures under the Landmarks Law. The provisions of the District Master Plan will take precedence over other rules that are not specifically tailored to the Fieldston Historic District. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-108782" number="109040" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>The objective of the District Master Plan is to provide owners and architects with design criteria which will allow timely review of proposed alterations while protecting the architecturally and historically significant features of the buildings, significant landscape improvements and the historic district&apos;s sense of place. The District Master Plan will cover all buildings in the Fieldston Historic District.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91211" number="109041" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in these Rules, the following terms shall have the following meanings:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91213" number="109042" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Commission.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Commission&quot; shall mean the appointed Commissioners, established by Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3020" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3020</LINK> of the Charter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91214" number="109043" version="1064">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>District Master Plan.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;District Master Plan&quot; shall mean the District Master Plan for the Fieldston Historic District approved by the Commission as a Certificate of Appropriateness. A copy of the District Master Plan may be reviewed at the Commission&apos;s offices by appointment or downloaded from the Commission&apos;s website: <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.nyc.gov/landmarks">www.nyc.gov/landmarks</LINK>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91215" number="109044" version="1891">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Landmarks Law.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Landmarks Law&quot; shall refer to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3020" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3020</LINK> of the Charter and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T25C003" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 3 of Title 25</LINK> of the Administrative Code of the City of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91216" number="109045" version="986">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Landscape Improvement.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Landscape Improvement&quot; shall mean a physical betterment of real property or any part thereof, consisting of natural or artificial landscape, including but not limited to grade, body of water, mature tree, walkway, road, plaza, wall, fence, step, fountain or sculpture.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91217" number="109046" version="986">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>LPC.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;LPC&quot; shall mean the Landmarks Preservation Commission acting in its agency capacity to implement the Landmarks Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91218" number="109047" version="986">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Rules.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Rules&quot; shall mean these implementation rules for the Fieldston Historic District.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-108783" number="109048" version="986">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Terms not otherwise defined in these rules or the District Master Plan shall have the meanings given them in the Landmarks Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91219" number="109049" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Eligible Buildings.</CHARFORMAT> All buildings in the Fieldston Historic District are subject to the District Master Plan.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91220" number="109050" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Permitted alterations.</CHARFORMAT> The LPC staff shall issue a CNE or PMW if the staff determines that: <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91221" number="109051" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The proposed work meets the criteria set forth in the District Master Plan; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91222" number="109052" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The proposed work will not adversely affect any significant architectural feature of the building or significant Landscape Improvement, not otherwise permitted by the District Master Plan or other LPC approval.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91223" number="109053" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application procedures.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91224" number="109054" version="1362">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Submission of application.</CHARFORMAT> See 63 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C002" destination-id="0-0-0-12623">Chapter 2</LINK>, Subchapter A (&quot;Application Procedure&quot;) and 63 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C012" destination-id="0-0-0-12773">Chapter 12</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91225" number="109055" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Application materials.</CHARFORMAT> The applicant shall submit adequate materials that clearly set forth the scope and details of the proposed work. At a minimum, the applicant shall submit detailed drawings that specifically show the proposed work and all other materials required by the LPC staff. Drawings shall be made to scale, and include all pertinent dimensions. LPC staff may require applicants to submit other materials, including but not limited to photographs of existing conditions, construction details, material samples, specifications, or maps as necessary to clearly explain the proposed work. LPC staff may also require mockups of proposed additions or outbuildings to determine the visibility of such additions or outbuildings, and probes or other investigations to determine existing conditions. Applications shall include a letter from the Fieldston Property Owners (&quot;FPOA&quot;) not objecting to the work or stating the work is not occurring on FPOA property, or a site survey demonstrating that the proposed work is not occurring on FPOA property. If the proposed work requires compliance with the Special Natural Area District (&quot;SNAD&quot;) rules, the applicant shall also provide a statement that s/he has met with the staff of the Department of City Planning (&quot;DCP&quot;) to discuss the proposal. If DCP staff has indicated that some aspect of the proposal is inconsistent with the SNAD rules and requires an Authorization or Special Permit, or other approval, the applicant shall indicate in the statement that s/he intends to seek the appropriate approvals from the DCP or City Planning Commission.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91226" number="109056" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Review procedures.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91227" number="109057" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The application will be deemed complete when the LPC staff determines that the materials submitted adequately and clearly set forth the scope and details of the proposed work.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91228" number="109058" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the application is complete, the LPC staff will review the application for conformity with these Rules. Upon determination that the criteria of the Rules have been met, a CNE or PMW will be issued pursuant to subdivision (f) of 63 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T63C012_12-01" destination-id="0-0-0-12775">12-01</LINK>. A determination that a CNE or PMW should be issued shall mean that the proposed work satisfies the criteria of the District Master Plan and that the work is appropriate to or will have no effect on protected architectural features of the specific building in question and is otherwise appropriate to the Fieldston Historic District. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91229" number="109059" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the LPC staff determines that the criteria set forth in these Rules have not been met, the LPC staff shall provide the applicant with a notice of the proposed denial of the application. The applicant may request a meeting with the Director of the Preservation Department, or, in the absence of the Director, with a Deputy Director, to discuss the determination.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-91230" number="109060" version="2548">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications for work that do not qualify for approval in accordance with these Rules shall be subject to the LPC&apos;s usual review procedure as set forth in the Landmarks Law. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-139657" number="109061" version="2544">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 7/20/2023, eff. 8/19/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-088]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>