<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-32756" number="38815" version="1960">
			<HEADING>Chapter 16: Advertisements on Private Property</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4369" name="T16C016"/>Chapter 16: Advertisements on Private Property</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-32757" number="38816" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 16-01 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4371" name="T16C016_16-01"/>§ 16-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32758" number="38817" version="748">
									<PARA>When used in this subchapter: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32759" number="38818" version="1085">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Advertisement.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Advertisement&quot; shall mean any paper, card, flyer, pamphlet, handbill, circular, or other written material advertising one or more businesses or soliciting business, which does not contain more than a de minimis amount of news, in that it does not contain any editorial content or information other than material concerning (a) the business or businesses, or (b) services or products offered by the business or businesses. If one or more documents are packaged together (for example, using a plastic bag or wrapper, rubber band, clip or similar device), each document shall be analyzed separately to determine whether it constitutes an &quot;advertisement&quot; under this definition. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32760" number="38819" version="1085">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Commissioner.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Commissioner&quot; shall mean Commissioner of Sanitation or his or her representative. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32761" number="38820" version="1085">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Multiple dwelling.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Multiple dwelling&quot; shall have the same meaning as defined in section four of the New York state multiple dwelling law, except that it shall not include a &quot;three family dwelling&quot; as defined in this section. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32762" number="38821" version="1085">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Person.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Person&quot; shall mean any individual, corporation, partnership, association, firm, trust, estate or any other legal entity whatsoever. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32763" number="38822" version="1085">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Three family dwelling.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Three family dwelling&quot; shall mean a multiple family dwelling that is owner-occupied and is designed for and occupied exclusively by no more than three families. A three family residence that does not satisfy the requirements of this definition shall be considered a &quot;multiple dwelling&quot; for the purposes of this chapter. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32764" number="38823" version="1085">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Two family dwelling.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Two family dwelling&quot; shall mean a multiple family dwelling that is designed for and occupied exclusively by no more than two families. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32765" number="38824" version="1085">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Unsolicited advertisement.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Unsolicited advertisement&quot; shall mean an advertisement placed on private property without being subscribed for, ordered by, or otherwise requested by the owner or a resident at the property.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-32766" number="38825" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 16-02 Issuance of Notice of Violation; Submission of Property Owner Complaint Form for One, Two or Three Family Dwellings.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4373" name="T16C016_16-02"/>§ 16-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Issuance of Notice of Violation; Submission of Property Owner Complaint Form for One, Two or Three Family Dwellings.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32767" number="38826" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section shall apply to one, two or three family dwellings. For the purposes of the section &quot;unauthorized placement of an unsolicited advertisement&quot; shall mean placement of one or more unsolicited advertisements on private property where the property-owner has posted, or caused to be posted, in a conspicuous location a sign which is not less than five inches by seven inches in size and which states in legible letters at least one inch in size: &quot;Do Not Place Unsolicited Advertising Materials On This Property&quot;.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32768" number="38827" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department may issue a notice of violation to any person it determines to be responsible for the unauthorized placement of an unsolicited advertisement at a one, two or three family dwelling based upon the submission of a property owner complaint form to the department by the owner of a one, two or three family dwelling. The property owner must complete the complaint form and, as set forth in the complaint form, certify that the information is truthful and accurate, and acknowledge that false statements in the complaint form are punishable under section 210.45 of the New York State Penal Law. The property owner must submit the signed and completed complaint form together with the unsolicited advertisement. If one or more advertisements are bundled and tied together by a rubber band, string, or otherwise, or are bundled and placed inside any outer wrapper, all of the materials must be submitted together with the complaint form.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32769" number="38828" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner of a one, two or three family dwelling may obtain a property owner complaint form through the department of sanitation website or by calling the city of New York 3-1-1 action center.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32770" number="38829" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner of a one, two or three family dwelling shall mail his or her signed complaint form together with the unsolicited advertisement to: Director of Enforcement c/o Lawn Litter, New York City Department of Sanitation, 1824 Shore Parkway, Brooklyn, New York 11214.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32771" number="38830" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner of a one, two or three family dwelling, who has submitted a property owner complaint form resulting in the department&apos;s issuance of a notice of violation, may be called upon to appear at an adjudicatory hearing by the environmental control board for the city of New York for the purpose of testifying in such adjudicatory matter. If the environmental control board determines that the appearance of the property owner is necessary, such property owner shall be contacted so that a date and time for the property owner&apos;s appearance can be arranged.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-32772" number="38831" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 16-03 Issuance of Notice of Violation; Submission of Property Owner Complaint Form for Multiple Dwellings.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4375" name="T16C016_16-03"/>§ 16-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Issuance of Notice of Violation; Submission of Property Owner Complaint Form for Multiple Dwellings.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32773" number="38832" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>This section shall apply to multiple dwellings. For the purposes of this section, &quot;unauthorized placement of an unsolicited advertisement at a multiple dwelling&quot; shall mean either of the following:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32774" number="38833" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>one or more unsolicited advertisements are placed on private property at a multiple dwelling where:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32775" number="38834" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>at least one unit owner or lessee of each separate dwelling unit within the building or on the property has agreed to prohibit unsolicited advertisements; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32776" number="38835" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the property-owner has posted or caused to be posted in a conspicuous location a sign which is not less than 5 inches by 7 inches in size and which states in legible letters at least one inch in size: &quot;Do Not Place Unsolicited Advertising Materials On This Property&quot;; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32777" number="38836" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>one or more unsolicited advertisements are placed on private property at a multiple dwelling in a location other than that specified on a sign at the multiple dwelling, or the number of unsolicited advertisements exceeds the number specified on the sign, where:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32778" number="38837" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the property-owner has posted or caused to be posted in a conspicuous location a sign which is not less than 5 inches by 7 inches in size and which states in legible letters at least one inch in size i) the number of unsolicited advertisements that may be left on the property and/or ii) a particular location or appropriate receptacle where the unsolicited advertisements may be placed; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32779" number="38838" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>if a number of permitted unsolicited advertisements is specified on the sign, the number represents at a minimum every separate dwelling unit in the building where the unit owners or lessees have not consented to prohibit unsolicited advertisements.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32780" number="38839" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The department may issue a notice of violation to any person it determines to be responsible for the unauthorized placement of an unsolicited advertisement at a multiple dwelling based upon the submission of a property owner complaint form to the department by the owner of a multiple dwelling, or the owner&apos;s designated agent. The property owner must complete the complaint form and, as set forth in the complaint form, certify that the information is truthful and accurate, and acknowledge that false statements in the complaint form are punishable under section 210.45 of the New York State Penal Law. The property owner must submit the signed and completed complaint form together with the unsolicited advertisement. If one or more advertisements are bundled and tied together by a rubber band, string, or otherwise, or are bundled and placed inside any outer wrapper, all of the materials must be submitted together with the complaint form.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32781" number="38840" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner of a multiple dwelling, or his or her designated agent, who has submitted a property owner complaint form resulting in the department&apos;s issuance of a notice of violation, may be called upon to furnish to the environmental control board for the city of New York a list of all current occupants of each apartment or unit within the multiple dwelling at the time the violation occurred, indicating whether the occupants residing therein at the time of such alleged violation consented to prohibiting the placement of unsolicited advertisements within such multiple dwelling, and how this information was obtained.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32782" number="38841" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner of any multiple dwelling, or his or her designated agent, may obtain a property owner complaint form through the department of sanitation website or by calling the city of New York 3-1-1 action center.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32783" number="38842" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner, or his or her designated agent, of any multiple dwelling shall mail his or her signed complaint form together with the unsolicited advertisement to: Director of Enforcement c/o Lawn Litter, New York City Department of Sanitation, 1824 Shore Parkway, Brooklyn, New York 11214.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32784" number="38843" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner of a multiple dwelling, or his or her designated agent, who has submitted a property owner complaint form resulting in the department&apos;s issuance of a notice of violation, may be called upon to appear at an adjudicatory hearing by the environmental control board for the city of New York for the purpose of testifying in such adjudicatory matter. If the environmental control board determines that the appearance of the property owner or designated agent is necessary, such property owner or designated agent shall be contacted so that a date and time for the property owner or designated agent&apos;s appearance can be arranged.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-32785" number="38844" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 16-04 Enforcement Agent Authority.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4377" name="T16C016_16-04"/>§ 16-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Enforcement Agent Authority.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-32786" number="38845" version="3">
									<PARA>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to preclude an enforcement agent from issuing a notice of violation based on his or her own observations, or in any other way to limit the authority of any enforcement agent.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>