<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-1072" number="835" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 24: Refuse Chutes and Refuse Rooms</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-650" name="T01C024"/>Chapter 24: Refuse Chutes and Refuse Rooms</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-1073" number="836" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 24-01 Construction and Maintenance of Refuse Chutes and Refuse Rooms.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-652" name="T01C024_24-01"/>§ 24-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Construction and Maintenance of Refuse Chutes and Refuse Rooms.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1074" number="837" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Refuse chute enclosures.</CHARFORMAT> Refuse chutes used for conveyance of garbage and rubbish from upper floors of a building to a cellar or other location shall be constructed with an enclosure of brick masonry at least eight inches in thickness or of reinforced concrete at least six inches in thickness, except as otherwise provided in this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1075" number="838" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Height and service openings. </CHARFORMAT>Refuse chutes shall extend from the refuse collection room to a height of at least six feet above the roof. A spark arrester shall be provided at the top of the chute above the roof. Service openings into the chute shall be equipped with approved self-closing hoppers so constructed that the chute is closed off while the hopper is being loaded and so that no part will project into the chute. The area of service opening shall not exceed one third the area of the chute. Hopper doors shall have a fire resistive rating of at least one hour, unless separated from the corridor by a fireproof, self-closing door in which case they shall be constructed of incombustible material.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1076" number="839" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Existing flues and refuse chutes. </CHARFORMAT>Flues for existing incinerators may be used for refuse chutes provided such flues are in good condition and provided the flues comply with the provisions of subdivisions (a) and (b) of this section. Existing refuse chutes may be continued in use provided they conform to the provisions of subdivisions (a) and (b) of this section, except that existing refuse chutes of other construction, which have been approved by the Department may be retained.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1077" number="840" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Refuse chutes in new construction. </CHARFORMAT>Where refuse compacting systems are required hereafter in new construction, refuse chutes shall be required for conveyance of garbage and rubbish to refuse collection rooms, except that refuse chutes will not be required in class A multiple dwellings which are four stories or less in height. Refuse chutes erected hereafter in new construction shall be of a type approved by the board or shall comply with the requirements of subdivisions (a) and (b) of this section. Chutes shall be constructed straight and plumb, without projections of any kind within the chute. Refuse chutes shall have an inside dimension of at least twenty-four inches for the full height of the chute. All chutes shall be supported on fireproof construction having at least a three hour resistive rating.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1078" number="841" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Refuse collection rooms. </CHARFORMAT>A refuse collection room shall be provided at the bottom of all chutes at the cellar or lowest story level to receive the refuse. Such rooms shall be enclosed with walls and roofs constructed of material having a minimum fire resistive rating of three hours, except that gypsum masonry may not be used for such enclosure walls. Openings to such rooms shall be provided with fireproof, self-closing doors having a minimum fire resistive rating of one and one-half hours. It shall be unlawful to keep such doors open. Refuse chutes shall extend to the underside of the roof of the refuse room or lower. Roofs shall be at least six inches away from combustible floor or wall construction. Refuse rooms shall be used only for receipt of refuse and for refuse compacting equipment. Refuse rooms shall be provided with sufficient sprinklers to sprinkle all parts of the room, with at least two sprinkler heads provided and with sprinklers so separated as to sprinkle a maximum area of the room when one of the sprinklers is blocked or not operating. A hose connection shall be provided within the refuse room. Existing refuse rooms and incinerator rooms that have been approved by the Department for such use may be retained as approved.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1079" number="842" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Collection room floors. </CHARFORMAT>The floor within the room for the collection of refuse shall be constructed of concrete and shall be sloped to a floor drain within the room connected to the house drain. The drain shall be provided with a protective screen to retain solid material. Floor drain traps shall be readily accessible for cleaning.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1080" number="843" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Use of existing combustion chambers. </CHARFORMAT>Existing incinerator combustion chambers may be used in whole or in part as refuse collecting rooms for collection of refuse and for compacting equipment provided the grates are removed and provided they comply with the provisions of subdivision (e) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1081" number="844" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Sprinkler operation and water supply. </CHARFORMAT>Sprinklers shall be designed to operate automatically at a temperature not exceeding one hundred sixty-five degrees Fahrenheit. They may be electrically controlled provided such sprinklers are approved by the Board of Standards and Appeals. Sprinklers may be connected to the cold water supply of the building at the point where such service enters the building or at the base of a water supply riser provided the piping of such service or riser is of adequate size. No connections, except those for sprinklers, shall be made to the sprinkler piping.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1082" number="845" version="2446">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hoppers, cut off doors and compactors. </CHARFORMAT>A hopper and cut off door shall be provided at the bottom of the refuse chute to regulate and guide the flow of refuse into containers. Where compactors are installed so that the refuse flows directly into the compacting equipment, the equipment may be used in place of the hopper and cut off door. Compacting equipment shall be arranged to operate automatically when the level of rubbish is not higher than three feet below the lowest door. Compactors shall be located entirely within the enclosure of the refuse room and former combustion chamber where the latter is retained, except that motors, pumps and controls may be installed in adjacent rooms. Where refuse is removed manually, the refuse shall be removed with sufficient frequency so that it will at no time extend less than three feet below the level of the lowest hopper door opening into the chute.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1083" number="846" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Number of sprinkler heads. </CHARFORMAT>Sufficient sprinklers shall be installed in the refuse room and former combustion chamber to provide sprinkler coverage for the entire area of each unit.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1084" number="847" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Adequate lighting shall be provided in refuse rooms.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1085" number="848" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Refuse chutes, refuse rooms, hoppers and all parts of the refuse collecting system shall be maintained in a clean and sanitary condition at all times, free of vermin, odors and defects, and shall be maintained in good operating condition. Fused sprinkler heads shall be replaced promptly.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1086" number="849" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner shall establish a program to ensure that the refuse chute and the refuse room and appurtenances will be treated as often as may be necessary to prevent infestation with insects or rodents. The owner shall maintain a record of such treatments which shall be available at all times for inspection by the Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1087" number="850" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>These rules shall apply only to refuse chutes in new construction and to refuse chutes resulting from the conversion of existing incinerator flues and to existing refuse chutes.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1088" number="851" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Collection and disposal of refuse within premises. </CHARFORMAT>The collection and disposal of refuse within any building or on any premises shall be performed as deemed necessary to provide for the safety, health and well being of the occupants of buildings and of the public. The construction, operation, maintenance, cleanliness and sanitation of refuse chutes and refuse rooms and extermination treatment for insects and rodents, and the keeping of records of such treatments for refuse chutes and refuse rooms shall be in accordance with regulations established by this Department in consultation with the Department of Health.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>