<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-1372" number="920" version="770">
			<HEADING>Chapter 29: Sprinkler Systems</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-674" name="T01C029"/>Chapter 29: Sprinkler Systems</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-1373" number="921" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 29-01 Installation of Automatic Sprinklers in Halls and Rooms in Class &quot;A&quot; Multiple Dwellings Used for Single-Room Occupancy Under the Provisions of Subdivision 7-A of § 4 and § 248 of the Multiple Dwelling Law.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-676" name="T01C029_29-01"/>§ 29-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Installation of Automatic Sprinklers in Halls and Rooms in Class &quot;A&quot; Multiple Dwellings Used for Single-Room Occupancy Under the Provisions of Subdivision 7-A of § 4 and § 248 of the Multiple Dwelling Law.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1374" number="922" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Before the installation of any sprinkler system in any single-room occupancy building is begun, an application, together with plans and specifications for such installation shall be filed with and approved by the Department of Buildings. Plans shall show accurately, both horizontally and vertically, the arrangement and dimensions of the private halls and rooms and the areas to be sprayed by each sprinkler head. Application and specification forms may be obtained at the borough office of the Department of Buildings. Applications shall be filed in the department office in the borough in which the premises are located. Applications and specifications shall be in triplicate. Preliminary plans may be on paper. Final plans shall be filed in triplicate on paper and microfilmed. When it is proposed to supply a sprinkler system by means of a direct connection to a public water supply main, the specifications shall be accompanied by a letter from the Department of Environmental Protection, establishing the fact that the water-supply conditions and pressures are suitable to meet the requirements of these rules for water supplies for sprinklers.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1375" number="923" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Sprinkler systems shall be of the automatic wet type.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1376" number="924" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Water supply from public water mains will be acceptable when such supply will provide a minimum static pressure at the highest sprinkler head or heads of not less than 15 pounds per square inch. Taps connecting to public water mains must be equal in size to the main pipe line, except that: A two-inch (2&quot;) tap connecting to the public water main and immediately increased to two-and-one-half inches (2 1/2&quot;) direct connection to the public water main and, A one-and-one-half inch (1 1/2&quot;) tap connecting to the public water main and immediately increased to two inches (2&quot;) in diameter, with piping of the same diameter extending into the building, shall be considered the same as a two-inch (2&quot;) direct connection to the public water main. The sprinkler system of each building shall have a separate and independent source of supply. When a sprinkler system is supplied direct from a public water main, it shall be separately and independently connected to the public water main. However, a house service water supply connection may be taken from the sprinkler water supply connection to the public main, on the house side of the main shut-off valve for the building, provided the diameter of the house service water supply connection does not exceed one-half of the diameter of the sprinkler water supply connection. Only one connection of the domestic water supply to the sprinkler water supply line shall be permitted and no shut-off valve shall be placed on the sprinkler supply line other than the main shut-off valve for the building on the street side of the house service water supply connection.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1377" number="925" version="1337">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A gravity tank upon the roof will be required when the normal minimum water pressure from the public mains is insufficient, or, in lieu of a gravity tank, a pressure tank may be installed in the basement or cellar in accordance with the requirements hereafter specified in these rules. The bottom of each gravity tank supplying the sprinkler system shall be elevated at least 20 feet above the roof. Each gravity tank shall be filled through a fixed water supply tank of at least one-and-one-half inch (1 1/2&quot;) diameter and independent of the sprinkler pipe system, by means of an automatically controlled pump of a discharge capacity of at least 65 gallons per minute against the total head, including friction at the discharge nozzle of the pump. The tank fill line shall be standard weight pipe, galvanized steel, or brass or copper pipe. A gravity tank, if used exclusively to supply the sprinkler system, shall have an effective capacity of not less than 1,500 gallons. Gravity tanks which serve both the house supply and the sprinkler system shall have a capacity of not less than 2,500 gallons. All exposed water supply piping connecting with roof gravity tanks shall be properly protected against frost action by four layers of one inch (1&quot;) high-grade hair felt, and each layer of hair felt shall be covered with a layer of heavy tar paper. Each wrapping must be securely fastened with heavy twine, and wrapping joints shall have a lap of not less than two inches (2&quot;), staggered with the laps of adjacent layers. All coverings shall be finally covered with heavy canvas, and painted with two coats of water-proof paint. In lieu of the foregoing, three inch thick fiberglass in a metal shield may be used.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1378" number="926" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pressure tanks when used shall be capable of supplying actual water volume as required in subdivision (j) of this section of these rules. The required water volume shall be two-thirds of the tank capacity and that air pressure one-third. For the pressure to be maintained, pressure tanks shall be constructed and tested in accordance with the requirements of the ANSI/NFiPA 22 of Reference Standard RS 17-10 of the Administrative (Building) Code. At the end of each pressure tank there shall be a glass water level gauge, and the pressure tank must also be provided with a pressure gauge and manhole for access to the tank. The filing pump for the pressure tank shall have a capacity of 65 gallons per minute with sufficient strength to pump water into the pressure tank against full air pressure. The air compressor for the pressure tank must be capable of delivering ten cubic feet of air per minute for the permanent maintenance of the required maximum air pressure in the tank. The filling pipe from pump to air compressor must be provided with a relief valve set at 15 pounds in excess of the maximum air pressure carried in the tank.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1379" number="927" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All tanks shall be supported in accordance with the provisions of the Administrative (Building) Code. All tanks shall be provided with emergency outlets in conformity with § P107.8(c) of Reference Standard RS-16 of the Administrative (Building) Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1380" number="928" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Standard one-half inch (1/2&quot;) spray type sprinkler heads. Each private hall and room within an apartment having single-room occupancy shall be sprinklered as hereinafter provided. In private halls within apartments, sprinkler heads shall be placed not more than fourteen feet (14&apos;) apart. No sprinkler head in a hallway shall be distant more than seven feet (7&apos;) from a wall, partition or end of the hall. No sprinkler protection will be required within any closet with a floor area of not more than 20 square feet provided such closet is within a room and the area of the closet is considered as part of the room area in computing the required number of heads.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1381" number="929" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;protected area&quot; shall be construed to mean that single-room occupancy apartment within the building requiring the greatest number of sprinkler heads. In computing the required number of heads within a &quot;protected area,&quot; the number of heads within the same apartment may be used on the condition that there is no connection to another apartment or private hall. Whenever there is a direct connection between two adjoining apartments, either or both of which are used for single-room occupancy, the combined connected apartments and private halls shall be considered as the &quot;protected area.&quot; In computing the required number of heads in a &quot;protected area&quot; of this type, the number of heads within the rooms in the connected apartments or the number of heads required in the private halls of such connected apartments, whichever is greater, shall be used.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1382" number="930" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The total number of heads in the &quot;protected area&quot; requiring the greatest number of heads shall determine the required size of the main supply, including service mains, main branch, tank, down feed and riser, but in no case shall the size of the main supply be less than two inches.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1383" number="931" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be sufficient actual water volume to supply 25 percent of the heads in the &quot;protected area&quot; requiring the greatest number of heads for a period of 20 minutes at 20 gallons per minute.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1384" number="932" version="897">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of sprinkler heads on a given size of piping shall not exceed the following:<LINEBRK/>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1385" number="933" version="1003">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="13" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="15" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">Size of pipe diameters</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">Maximum number or sprinkler heads allowed</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 inch</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">2 heads </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 1/4 inch</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">3 heads </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 1/2 inch</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">5 heads </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">2 inch</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">10 heads </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">2 1/2 inch</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">30 heads </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">3 inch</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">60 heads </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">3 1/2 inch</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">100 heads </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">4 inch</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">Unlimited heads </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(l)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The sprinkler main shall not be less in size than the sprinkler rise the check valve of equal diameter to the main and the riser shall be provided on the sprinkler main. For draining the sprinkler system, a 3/4&quot; plugged valve shall be provided on the sprinkler main just inside the aforesaid check valve. All sprinkler piping and fittings shall be so installed that they can be thoroughly drained. On the sprinkler main, an outside screw and yoke gate valve, readily accessible, must be provided near the front of the front of the building and located so as to control the water supply to all the interior sprinkler systems. The said outside screw and yoke gate valve must be sealed in an open position. If tank water supply is used for sprinklers, an outside screw and yoke gate valve shall be provided on the piping leading from the tank to the sprinkler system under conditions similar to those specified for such valves on sprinkler mains.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1386" number="934" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(m)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Sprinkler risers shall not be located close to windows and all sprinkler piping shall be properly supported.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1387" number="935" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(n)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Sprinkler systems shall be maintained for sprinkler use only, and connections to such sprinkler systems for any other purposes are prohibited.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1388" number="936" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(o)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All piping used in sprinkler systems shall be full weight standard steel threaded pipe, well reamed and screwed up tight into fittings without reducing the waterway. Fittings shall be standard cast iron. All fittings placed inside of tank shall be of brass or other non-corroding material.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1389" number="937" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(p)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Sprinkler risers shall be provided at the top for testing purposes, with a connection not less than one inch in diameter, with a valved outlet so located that same will be readily accessible at all times. When not in use, the valve shall be provided with an iron or brass plug screwed in tight.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1390" number="938" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(q)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Sprinkler systems when completed shall be subjected to a hydrostatic test at a pressure of not less than 30 pounds in excess of the normal pressure required for such sprinkler systems when in service, and shall remain uncovered in every part until they have successfully passed the test. The Department of Buildings, in the borough in which the test is to be conducted, shall be notified when such test is to take place. Tests shall be conducted by the contractor or the owner of the owner&apos;s representative, in the presence of a representative of the Building Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1391" number="939" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(r)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Sprinkler systems shall be inspected at least once in each month by a competent representative of the owner, to ascertain that all parts of the system are in perfect working order. A detailed record of each inspection shall be kept on the premises for examination by the Fire Department, the Department of Housing Preservation and Development, and the Department of Buildings.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1392" number="940" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(s)<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be kept available on the premises at all times a sufficient supply of extra sprinkler heads and also a sprinkler wrench for use to replace promptly any fused or damaged sprinkler heads. Any head which has opened or has been damaged shall be replaced immediately with a good sprinkler head. Sprinkler heads shall be of a type and manufacture approved by the Board of Standards and Appeals. The minimum operating temperature of all sprinkler heads shall be in the ordinary degree range. Appropriate higher degree operating temperatures shall be required in cooking spaces.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-1393" number="941" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 29-02 Installation of Automatic Wet-Pipe Sprinklers in Certain Class A and Class B Multiple Dwellings, Including Hotels, Under the Provisions of § 67, Multiple Dwelling Law.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-678" name="T01C029_29-02"/>§ 29-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Installation of Automatic Wet-Pipe Sprinklers in Certain Class A and Class B Multiple Dwellings, Including Hotels, Under the Provisions of § 67, Multiple Dwelling Law.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1394" number="942" version="1768">
									<PARA>Effective February 25, 1949, automatic wet-pipe sprinklers used in certain Class A and Class B multiple dwellings, including hotels, shall be installed in conformity with the provisions of the Administrative Code, Subchapter 17 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T27C001" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 1 of Title 27</LINK>, except as modified herein. These rules do not apply to sprinkler installations in converted dwellings, lodging houses or multiple dwellings used for single room occupancy.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1395" number="943" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In lieu of one of the four alternate automatic sources of water supply specified in § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-961" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-961</LINK>, of the Administrative (Building) Code, a connection may be made to the domestic water supply system on the condition that:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1396" number="944" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>It can be established from information obtainable from the Department of Environmental Protection that the pressure at the top of the highest riser will be 15 pounds per square inch (except as provided in 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-02" destination-id="0-0-0-678">29-02</LINK>(f).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1397" number="945" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the pressure from this source is insufficient to provide a pressure of 15 pounds at the highest line of sprinklers, but is sufficient to supply a pressure of 15 pounds or more at the highest line of sprinklers, an automatic booster pump is provided, the capacity of which shall be sufficient to supply 25 percent of the standard one-half inch (1/2&quot;) heads in the sprinkler area having the maximum number of heads, and in no event shall such supply be less than 250 gallons per minute at a pressure of at least 15 pounds at the highest sprinkler line.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1398" number="946" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A local approved type of water-flow alarm is provided, the gong so located that when it operates it may be heard by the occupants or employees, and the gong also plainly marked &quot;Sprinkler Alarm&quot;, in red letters one inch in height on a white background. <CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Exception: </CHARFORMAT>In a sprinkler area which does not contain more than 36 heads, no water-flow alarm shall be required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1399" number="947" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A sprinkler shut-off valve is provided conveniently accessible and its purpose clearly indicated by the words &quot;Automatic Sprinkler Shut-Off Valve&quot; on a sign affixed thereto.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1400" number="948" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The size of the domestic water supply line is at least equal to the size of the main sprinkler connection. <CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Note: </CHARFORMAT>The provisions of Paragraph c of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-964" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-964</LINK> shall not apply to sprinklers installed in conformity with the provisions of 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-02" destination-id="0-0-0-678">29-02</LINK>(a).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1401" number="949" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The capacity of gravity tanks for sprinklers shall be in conformity with the provisions of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-965" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-965</LINK> or such tank may be supplied by an automatic filing pump of at least 65 gallons per minute capacity, which shall be sufficient to supply 25 percent of the sprinkler heads in the largest sprinkler area for 20 minutes. The capacity of such tank shall be not less than 1,000 gallons. The bottom of the gravity tank or sprinkler supply pipe shall be not less than 20 feet above the highest supplied sprinkler line. When such elevation is not practicable, an automatic booster pump may be installed in the main sprinkler supply line in conformity with 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-02" destination-id="0-0-0-678">29-02</LINK>(a)(2).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1402" number="950" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In lieu of complying with the provisions of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-965" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-965</LINK>, a pressure tank located not more than one story below the highest supplied sprinkler line, filled by an automatic pump, and with a supply of water, all as described in 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-02" destination-id="0-0-0-678">29-02</LINK>(b) may be installed. In addition, a high-and-low air alarm shall be provided.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1403" number="951" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-963" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-963</LINK>(a) may be construed to permit the sprinkler connection to the street main to be the same size as main sprinkler riser, but in no instance shall it be less than two inches. A tap may be one pipe size less than the sprinkler main.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1404" number="952" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>§ <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-935" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-935</LINK> shall apply only when the number of heads in any sprinkler area as defined in these rules exceeds 36.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1405" number="953" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Standard 1/2-inch sprinkler heads.</CHARFORMAT> In lieu of applying the provisions of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-956" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-956</LINK>, sprinkler heads shall be so spaced that there shall be one head for approximately 168 square feet of floor area, and shall also be spaced not more than 14 feet on centers. The distance from a wall or partition to the first sprinkler head shall not exceed seven feet, measured at right angles to the wall or partition. In multiple dwellings that are presently equipped with sprinklers, the heads in the public halls may be spaced 14 feet on centers, with the first head not more than seven feet from any wall or partition. A 12 pound static pressure will be accepted at the topmost sprinkler line, provided the sprinkler heads are spaced to cover 100 square feet or less. Sprinkler heads may be installed in covered shafts in lieu of fire-retarding on the condition that:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1406" number="954" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such shafts are not exposed to freezing temperatures;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1407" number="955" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If ventilating louvres, windows or skylights are present in such shafts, the highest head is located a sufficient distance from such openings to prevent freezing;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1408" number="956" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>One head is centered at the top of such shaft at the level of the highest ceiling;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1409" number="957" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In shafts constructed in incombustible materials, excepting windows or doors opening thereon, sprinkler heads are placed at each floor level and are staggered at alternate levels;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1410" number="958" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In shafts constructed of combustible materials, and which exceed 60 square feet in cross-sectioned area, sprinkler heads are placed at each floor level and are staggered at alternate floor levels.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1411" number="959" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The protection afforded by sprinklers to stairs, halls, corridors, and other passageways shall also apply to their soffits and overlaps.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1412" number="960" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>These rules shall also apply to a store or other space used for business on any story where there are no sleeping rooms and which is not provided with sprinkler heads, unless such spaces are otherwise arranged in conformity with the provisions of § 61, Multiple Dwelling Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1413" number="961" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In lieu of complying with the provisions of § 3.9.1.1 of ANSI/NFiPA 13 of Reference Standard RS 17-2 of the Administrative (Building) Code, a 1 inch valved pipe may be extended from the top of the riser to the outside of the building, or inside the building to a deep sink for testing the system, pump and alarm under water-flow conditions.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1414" number="962" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Check valves, gate valves, and water meters shall be installed as and when directed by the Department of Environmental Protection.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1415" number="963" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;sprinkler area&quot; as used in these rules shall mean any floor space within a structure enclosed on all sides by exterior walls, fire walls, fire partitions, fire-retarded partitions, or fire-resistive partitions and doors acceptable to the Department of Housing and Buildings. The term &quot;fire-resistive partition&quot; as used in these rules shall mean a partition which is constructed of incombustible materials or wood studs covered on both sides with lath and plaster, plaster board, or other fire-resistive materials acceptable to the Department. Such partitions shall extend from the floor to the ceiling. All doors in such partitions shall be self closing.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1416" number="964" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(l)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The sprinkler control valve shall be inspected at least once weekly by a competent person, who is employed by the owner to see that such valves are sealed open, and who holds a certificate of fitness. A record of each inspection shall be kept for examination by a representative of the Department. The provisions of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-957" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-957</LINK>, in relation to alarm devices shall not apply to a sprinkler area which does not contain more than 36 heads in multiple dwellings, in which such weekly inspections are made.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1417" number="965" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(m)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Systems installed before July 1, 1928 shall be subject to inspection and if found adequate may be accepted by the Department of Buildings. However, in such cases, a copy of the plans approved by the Fire Department shall be filed with the Department of Buildings.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1418" number="966" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(n)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where there are practical difficulties in the way of carrying out these rules, the Superintendent may permit modifications, provided that the spirit of these rules are observed and safety secured.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-1419" number="967" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 29-03 Installation of Automatic Wet-Pipe Sprinkler Systems and Alarm Systems in Certain Class B Multiple Dwellings (Lodging Houses).</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-680" name="T01C029_29-03"/>§ 29-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Installation of Automatic Wet-Pipe Sprinkler Systems and Alarm Systems in Certain Class B Multiple Dwellings (Lodging Houses).</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1420" number="968" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notice is hereby given that, pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 713 of the Laws of 1929, and Section 4 of Chapter 553 of the Laws of 1944, effective April 5, 1944, automatic wet pipe sprinkler systems installed in &quot;lodging houses&quot;, shall be installed in conformity with the provisions of the Administrative Code of the city of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1421" number="969" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An automatic closed-circuit water-flow and valve-tamper alarm system, having at least one manual fire alarm station shall be provided in connection with the sprinkler system. This alarm system shall be connected to an approved central station which provided supervisory and maintenance service satisfactory to the fire commissioner. In connection therewith, there shall be an approved transmitter so arranged as to actuate all gongs of the interior fire alarm system whenever a water flow through the sprinkler system occurs. Interior fire alarm systems of the closed-circuit type previously installed under the rules then in force and approved by the fire commissioner may be accepted if, after inspection and test the systems are found to be adequate and in proper operating condition. Battery operated interior fire alarm systems of the open-circuit type shall be replaced with an approved closed-circuit system. In connection with these rules, the persons affected are advised to consult Article 5 of Subchapter 17 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T27C001" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 1 of Title 27</LINK> of the Administrative (Building) Code and §§ <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="15-126" destination-id="0-0-0-0">15-126</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="15-127" destination-id="0-0-0-0">15-127</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="15-214" destination-id="0-0-0-0">15-214</LINK>, of the Administrative (Fire Prevention) Code of the city of New York, concerning interior fire alarm system, watchmen&apos;s time detector system and telegraphic communication.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-1422" number="970" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 29-04 Installation of Automatic Wet-Pipe Sprinkler Systems and Alarm Systems in Certain Class B Multiple Dwellings (Lodging Houses).</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-682" name="T01C029_29-04"/>§ 29-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Installation of Automatic Wet-Pipe Sprinkler Systems and Alarm Systems in Certain Class B Multiple Dwellings (Lodging Houses).</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1423" number="971" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Automatic wet-pipe sprinkler systems installed in lodging houses in compliance with Subdivision 3, of § 66, of the Multiple Dwelling Law shall be in conformity with the provisions of the Administrative Code, Subchapter 17 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T27C001" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 1 of Title 27</LINK>, only to the extent that such article is not inconsistent with these amended rules.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1424" number="972" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Sprinkler systems shall be automatic wet-pipe with one automatic source of water supply.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1425" number="973" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Acceptable automatic sources of water supply shall be any one of the following:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1426" number="974" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Elevated gravity tank having a minimum capacity of 5,000 gallons and installed in accordance with § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-965" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-965</LINK> of the Administrative (Building) Code. Effective capacity shall be determined by the largest number of heads in any floor area multiplied by 75 gallons, and shall never be less than 5,000 gallons.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1427" number="975" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pressure tank having a minimum capacity of 2,500 gallons and installed in accordance with § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-965" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-965</LINK> of the Administrative (Building) Code. Effective water capacity shall be determined by the largest number of heads in any floor area multiplied by 37.5 gallons, and shall never be less than 2,500 gallons.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1428" number="976" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Automatic fire pump having a capacity of not less than 250 gallons per minute and installed in accordance with § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-964" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-964</LINK> of the Administrative (Building) Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1429" number="977" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A direct connection to the public water main, provided it is capable of maintaining a pressure of at least 15 pounds per square inch at the top of the highest sprinkler riser, with 250 gallons of water flowing per minute at a 2-1/2-inch outlet from a hydrant at the street level within 250 feet of the building. The hydrant test shall be made between the hours of 8 a.m. and 5 p.m. on a working day. If the public water main pressure is incapable of maintaining a minimum pressure of 15 pounds per square inch as specified herein, a booster pump may be installed in conformity with these rules; or, in lieu of such booster pump, the sprinkler spacing and pipe sizes for the area not having the required minimum water pressure of 15 pounds per square inch shall be in conformity with the provisions of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-956" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-956</LINK> of the Administrative (Building) Code, provided that in no event the minimum water pressure at the highest sprinkler riser be less than 2 pounds per square inch. Booster pumps, if required, shall have a capacity sufficient to supply 250 gallons per minute, at a pressure of at least 15 pounds at the top of the highest sprinkler riser. All shall be installed in accordance with § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-964" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-964</LINK> of the Administrative (Building) Code. A letter from the Department of Environmental Protection shall be filed with the application for the installation of a sprinkler system, stating the water pressure and supply conditions of the street main to which the sprinkler supply is to be connected.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1430" number="978" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>One common source of water supply shall be acceptable for any contiguous buildings under the same ownership or leasehold and under the same lodging-house management, provided that each such building is fully separated by fire walls with automatic fire doors on any connecting openings. Supply mains shall be at least the size of the largest main riser in any one building and shall be arranged to be centrally located and run as directly as possible from the source of water supply to the respective risers in each building. Each building shall be provided with a separate alarm valve in accordance with 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-04" destination-id="0-0-0-682">29-04</LINK>(a)(8). In all other respects, the installation in each building shall comply with these rules. Supply mains shall be increased in size as may be required for adequate water supply and pressure requirements in accordance with 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-04" destination-id="0-0-0-682">29-04</LINK>(a)(2).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1431" number="979" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Sprinkler spacing for standard 1/2-inch heads under sheathed or plaster ceilings shall not exceed 168 square feet of protection area, with the distance between lines and between sprinklers on lines not in excess of 14 feet.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1432" number="980" version="897">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The maximum permissible number of standard 1/2-inch sprinkler heads on a given pipe-size, in one fire area, on any one story shall be as follows:<LINEBRK/>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1433" number="981" version="897">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="11" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000">1 inch pipe</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000">2 sprinkler heads </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 1/4 inch pipe</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">3 sprinkler heads </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 1/2 inch pipe</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">5 sprinkler heads </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">2 inch pipe</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">10 sprinkler heads </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">3 inch pipe</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">30 sprinkler heads </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">4 inch pipe</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">60 No Limit </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>Branch lines should not exceed eight sprinkler heads on either side of a cross main. Areas within fire walls may be subdivided into separate fire areas by one-hour partitions. Openings in such partitions shall be protected with fireproof doors and assemblies, and such doors shall be self-closing. Areas within such subdivisions may be considered independent fire areas.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1434" number="982" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each riser shall be of sufficient size to supply all the sprinkler heads on that riser in any one fire area according to 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-04" destination-id="0-0-0-682">29-04</LINK>(a)(5). The supply main shall be at least the size of the riser it serves, except that no main shall be less than two inches and shall be installed in accordance with § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-956" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-956</LINK> of the Administrative (Building) Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1435" number="983" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Taps in the public water main may be one standard pipe-size smaller than the required supply main according to 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-04" destination-id="0-0-0-682">29-04</LINK>(a)(6), provided the supply main immediately increases at the tap to its full required size. All water main installations shall be subject to the approval of the Department of Environmental Protection.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1436" number="984" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Systems shall be equipped with an alarm valve so constructed that any flow of water in any part of the system, or the closure of any valve controlling water supply will automatically cause the interior fire alarm system and the central station alarm to operate.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1437" number="985" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Prior to the issuance of a letter of approval from the Department of Buildings as to the satisfactory installation of any system, a letter from the Department of Environmental Protection must be filed with the Department as to the size of tap and service main and its satisfactory installation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1438" number="986" version="1768">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An automatic closed-circuit water-flow and valve-tamper alarm system, having at least one manual fire alarm station shall be provided in connection with the sprinkler system. This alarm system shall be connected to an approved central station which provided supervisory and maintenance service satisfactory to the fire commissioner. In connection therewith, there shall be an approved transmitter so arranged as to actuate all gongs of the interior fire alarm system whenever a water flow through the sprinkler system occurs. Interior fire alarm systems of the closed-circuit type previously installed under the rules then in force and approved by the fire commissioner may be accepted, if, after inspection and test the systems are found to be adequate and in proper operating condition. Battery operated interior fire alarm systems of the open-circuit type shall be replaced with an approved closed-circuit system. In connection with these rules, the persons affected are advised to consult Article 5 of Subchapter 17 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T27C001" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 1 of Title 27</LINK> of the Administrative (Building) Code and §§ <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="15-126" destination-id="0-0-0-0">15-126</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="15-127" destination-id="0-0-0-0">15-127</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="15-214" destination-id="0-0-0-0">15-214</LINK> of the Administrative (Fire Prevention) Code of the city of New York, concerning interior fire alarm system, watchmen&apos;s time detector system and telegraphic communication.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-1439" number="987" version="2326">
								<HEADING>§ 29-05 Installation of Automatic Wet-Pipe Sprinklers in Fireproof Multiple Dwellings Converted to Business Use. [Repealed]</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-684" name="T01C029_29-05"/>§ 29-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Installation of Automatic Wet-Pipe Sprinklers in Fireproof Multiple Dwellings Converted to Business Use. [Repealed]</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1459" number="988" version="2326">
									<PARA>(Repealed City Record 11/7/2022, eff. 12/7/2022) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-080]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-135103" number="989" version="2326">
								<HEADING>§ 29-06 Installation of Automatic Sprinklers in the Public Halls of Multiple Dwellings Under the Provisions of § 187 (Converted Dwellings) and § 218, Subdivision 5 (Old-Law Tenements), of the Multiple Dwelling Law, and of the Sprinklers in Cooking Spaces in all Types of Multiple Dwellings Under the Provisions of § 33 of the Multiple Dwelling Law.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-686" name="T01C029_29-06"/>§ 29-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Installation of Automatic Sprinklers in the Public Halls of Multiple Dwellings Under the Provisions of § 187 (Converted Dwellings) and § 218, Subdivision 5 (Old-Law Tenements), of the Multiple Dwelling Law, and of the Sprinklers in Cooking Spaces in all Types of Multiple Dwellings Under the Provisions of § 33 of the Multiple Dwelling Law.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1460" number="990" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Certification from the Department of Environmental Protection. </CHARFORMAT>When it is proposed to supply a sprinkler system by means of a direct connection to a public water supply main, the specifications shall be accompanied by a letter or other approved certification from the Department of Environmental Protection, establishing the fact that the water supply conditions and pressure are such that will meet the requirements of these rules for water suppliers for sprinklers.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1461" number="991" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Type of system required. </CHARFORMAT>Sprinkler system shall be of the automatic wet type.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1462" number="992" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Connection to water main. </CHARFORMAT>The sprinkler system of each building shall have a separate and independent source of supply except as herein otherwise specifically provided. When a sprinkler system is supplied direct from a public water main, it shall be separately and independently connected to the public water main except that one street main supply will be accepted for not more than three contiguous buildings under one ownership where such buildings are separated by fire walls, provided that the supply is brought into the center building of a group of three, and provided further, that the supply shall be adequate for the total number of sprinklers in any two buildings, but not less than 50 percent of the total number of sprinklers in all the buildings in any case. In all other respects, the installation in each building shall comply with these rules. When one street supply serves more than one building, there shall be submitted to the department evidence that an easement has been created in favor of each building for the continued use of such supply for each building. A house service water supply connection may be taken from the sprinkler water supply connection to the city main, on the house side of the main shut-off valve for the building provided the diameter of the house service water supply connection does not exceed one-half of the diameter of the sprinkler water supply connection. Only one connection of the domestic water supply to the sprinkler water supply line shall be permitted and no shut-off valve shall be placed on the sprinkler supply line, other than the main shut-off valve for the building on the street side of the house service water supply connection. (1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-06" destination-id="0-0-0-686">29-06</LINK>(c) amended by resolution filed with City Clerk February 9, 1956.)</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1463" number="993" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Water pressure and supply. </CHARFORMAT>Water supply from public water mains will be acceptable when such supply will provide a minimum static pressure at the highest sprinkler of not less than 15 pounds per square inch. For computation of the required water pressure at the curb level to provide adequate pressure at the highest sprinkler, the following formula shall be used: Required water pressure in pounds per square inch = 0.434 H plus 15. Where H = height in feet from the curb level to the level of the highest sprinkler. When the minimum pressure in the water supply is insufficient to provide the required pressure, but is capable of providing a pressure of not less than five pounds per square inch at the highest sprinkler, an automatic centrifugal booster pump for the purpose of increasing the water pressure will be accepted under the following conditions:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1464" number="994" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The rated capacity of the pump shall be not less than 250 gallons per minute and shall be sufficient to supply at least 25 percent of the total number of sprinklers, or where there is insufficient pressure in the top story only, all the sprinklers on the top floor, at the rate of 20 gallons per minute per sprinkler. A 2 1/2-inch diameter test tee shall be attached to the discharge pipe from the pump for the purpose of testing its capacity.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1465" number="995" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be a pressure regulator attached to the pump which shall be set so that the pump will automatically start operating when the water pressure at the highest sprinkler falls below 20 pounds per square inch, and cease to operate when the said pressure reaches 30 pounds per square inch.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1466" number="996" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The pump shall be attached on bypass properly valved to the sprinkler main on the house side of the main control valve. The intake and discharge pipes to the pump shall be of sufficient size to deliver the required volume of water to the system at the stated minimum pressure.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1467" number="997" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Drain valves shall be installed on the main between the main (O.S.&amp;Y.) control valve and the intake connection to the pump and on the house side of the discharge connection to the pump. Such drain valves shall be closed by means of screw plugs.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1468" number="998" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A check valve shall be installed on the main on the inside service between the intake and discharge connections to the pump.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1469" number="999" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The intake and discharge pipes from the pump shall each be provided with an O.S.&amp;Y. valve.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1470" number="1000" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A variation of not more than two pounds per square inch, in the minimum pressure, in the street supply below the required pressure for the sprinkler system without the introduction of a booster pump or increased size in piping may be accepted by the Superintendent if in his opinion the supply is adequate. There shall be sufficient actual water volume to supply 25 percent of the heads for a period of 20 minutes at 20 gallons per minute.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1471" number="1001" version="2447">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Roof tanks. </CHARFORMAT>Except as otherwise specifically provided in 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-06" destination-id="0-0-0-686">29-06</LINK>(d), a gravity tank upon the roof will be required when the normal minimum water pressure from the public water main is insufficient. The bottom of each gravity tank supplying a sprinkler system shall be elevated at least 20 feet above the roof. Each gravity tank shall be filled through a fixed water supply pipe of at least one and one-half inch diameter and independent of the sprinkler pipe system, by means of an automatically controlled pump of a capacity at the discharge nozzle of the pump of at least 65 gallons per minute against the total head, including friction. The tank fill line shall be standard weight pipe, galvanized steel, brass or copper pipe. The pump shall be equipped with control apparatus which will automatically start operation when the effective capacity of the tank falls below the minimum reserve supply for the sprinkler system. A gravity tank, if used exclusively to supply the sprinkler system, shall have an effective capacity of not less than fifteen hundred (1,500) gallons. Gravity tanks which serve both the house supply and the sprinkler system shall have an effective capacity of not less than twenty-five hundred (2,500) gallons with a minimum of fifteen hundred (1,500) gallons reserved for the sprinkler system. All exposed water supply piping connecting with roof gravity tanks shall be properly protected against freezing by four layers of one inch high-grade hair felt, and each layer of hair felt shall be covered with a layer of heavy tar paper. Each wrapping shall be securely fastened with heavy twine, and wrapping joints shall have a lap of not less than two inches staggered into the laps of the adjacent layers. All coverings shall be finally covered with heavy canvas sewed at seams and painted with two coats of waterproof paint. In lieu of the foregoing, three inch thick fiberglass in a metal shield may be used. Exposed gravity tanks on the roof shall be protected against freezing by means of an approved enclosure, insulation, heating coil or other means acceptable to the Superintendent. Gravity tanks shall be supported in accordance with the provisions of § P107.8 of Reference Standard RS-16 of the Administrative (Building) Code. Gravity tanks shall be provided with emergency outlets in conformity with § P107.8 of Reference Standard RS-16 of the Administrative (Building) Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1472" number="1002" version="898">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Pressure tanks. </CHARFORMAT>Except as otherwise specifically provided in 1 RCNY §§ <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-06" destination-id="0-0-0-686">29-06</LINK>(d) and (e), a pressure tank will be required when the normal minimum water pressure from the public main is insufficient. Such pressure tank may be installed in the basement or cellar. Pressure tanks when used shall be capable of supplying actual water volume as required in 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-06" destination-id="0-0-0-686">29-06</LINK>(d) at a pressure of not less than 15 pounds per square inch. Pressure tanks shall be constructed and tested in accordance with the requirements of ANSI/NFiPA 22 of Reference Standard RS 17-10 of the Administrative (Building) Code. Pressure tanks shall be at least two-thirds filled with water and an air pressure by gauge shall be maintained in the tank of not less than 75 pounds plus the pressure caused by the column of water in the sprinkler system above the bottom of the tank. At the end of each pressure tank there shall be a glass water-level gauge, and the pressure tank shall also be provided with a pressure gauge and a manhole for access to the interior of the tank. The filling pump for the pressure tank shall have a capacity of not less than 65 gallons per minute against the total head including friction and air pressure of the tank. The compressor shall be powered by an electric motor which shall be equipped with control apparatus, which will automatically start the motor when the pressure in the tank drops to 75 pounds per square inch and will cut out the motor when the pressure in the tank reaches the total required pressure. The air compressor shall be capable of delivering not less than 10 cubic feet of air per minute. The filling pipe from the pump or air compressor shall be provided with a relief valve set to open at 15 pounds in excess of the maximum air pressure required in the tank.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1473" number="1003" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Sprinkler pressure, where required. </CHARFORMAT>Sprinklers shall be arranged to spray all parts of the public stairways, service stairways, their hallways, landings and soffits. Sprinkler protection shall be provided also in each closet opening on a public hall and in any permanent telephone booth placed in a public hall, but no sprinkler protection shall be required in any bathroom, water-closet compartment or shower room opening upon a public hall. There shall be two or more sprinklers installed under the soffit of each public stairs spaced not more than fourteen (14) feet apart. Sprinklers shall be provided over and under the stairway leading from the basement or cellar to the first floor, except that where the under part of the cellar stairway is completely enclosed with fireproof material, sprinklers will not be required under the soffit of such cellar stairway. Sprinkler protection shall be provided in spaces exceeding three (3) feet in height, above a public hall between the ceiling of the top story and the roof unless such spaces are properly cut off from the public hall by means of fire retarded partitions. Sprinkler protection shall be provided also on the underside of public stairhalls, stair landings and soffits which are not within stair enclosures except when such surfaces are fire-retarded. Sprinklers shall not be required in roof bulkheads or in unheated outside street vestibules. Sprinkler protection shall not be required in any auxiliary stairway extending from the lowest story to the next higher story above, on condition that such stairway is not located under any stairway leading to upper stories nor terminates in a public hall. Deflectors of sprinklers shall be placed not less than three inches nor more than ten inches below ceilings or soffits. Sprinklers shall not be located within 12 inches distance of any obstruction such as hanger, lighting fixture, etc.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1474" number="1004" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Tap sizes required. </CHARFORMAT>Taps connecting to public water mains shall be equal in size to the main pipe lines, except that: A two and one-half inch tap connecting to the public water main and immediately increased to three inches in diameter, with piping of the same diameter extending into the building, shall be considered the same as a three inch direct connection to the public water main. A two inch tap connecting to the public water main and immediately increased to two and one-half inches in diameter, with piping of the same diameter extending into the building, shall be considered the same as a two and one-half inch direct connection to the public water main. A one and one-half inch tap connecting to the public water main and immediately increased to two inches in diameter, with piping of the same diameter extending into the building, shall be considered the same as a two inch direct connection to the public water main.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1475" number="1005" version="898">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Pipe schedules. </CHARFORMAT>Except as otherwise provided in this section, the number of sprinklers on a given size of piping shall not exceed the following:<LINEBRK/>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1476" number="1006" version="1003">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="11" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="15" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">Diameter of Pipe</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">Maximum number of sprinklers allowed </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 inch</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">2 sprinklers </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 1/4 inch</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">3 sprinklers </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 1/2 inch</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">5 sprinklers </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">2 inch</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">10 sprinklers </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">2 1/2 inch</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">30 sprinklers </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">3 inch</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">60 sprinklers </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">3 1/2 inch</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">100 sprinklers </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">4 inch</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">Unlimited sprinklers </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>The sprinkler main shall not be less in size than the sprinkler riser and shall not be less in size than any branch it serves. Except as otherwise specifically provided in 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-06" destination-id="0-0-0-686">29-06</LINK>(h), the total number of sprinklers in a structure shall determine the required size of the tap, service main, risers and branches, but in no case shall the size of the main supply be less than two inches. The following sprinklers will not be counted in computing the size of the taps, mains and risers:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1477" number="1007" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>One sprinkler of the required sprinklers placed under the soffits of the stairs in each story when more than one sprinkler is provided.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1478" number="1008" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Sprinklers placed in any closet or telephone booth opening upon a public hall.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1479" number="1009" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Sprinklers placed (in lieu of fire retarding) on the underside of public stairhalls, stair landings and soffits not within the stair enclosure. The permissible number of heads may at the discretion of the Superintendent be increased by not more than 10 percent.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1480" number="1010" version="1769">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Siamese. </CHARFORMAT>A sprinkler system containing 55 or more sprinklers in one building or fire area, shall be provided with an approved Fire Department Siamese Connection installed in accordance with § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-940" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-940</LINK> of the Administrative (Building) Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1481" number="1011" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Sprinkler in existing cooking spaces. </CHARFORMAT>When a sprinkler is installed in the ceiling over an existing cooking space, pursuant to § 33 of the Multiple Dwelling Law, the sprinkler shall be connected with the domestic water supply of the building through a pipe of at least one inch diameter, at a point either side of the valve controlling the supply to the plumbing fixture in the cooking space. There shall be at least one sprinkler for every 49 square feet or fraction thereof of the floor area of the cooking space. Such sprinklers shall not be included in the computations for determining the size of the sprinkler piping or the necessity of a siamese as outlined in 1 RCNY §§ <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-06" destination-id="0-0-0-686">29-06</LINK>(i) and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-06" destination-id="0-0-0-686">29-06</LINK>(j). No sprinkler shall be installed in a cooking space without a written approval from the Department of Buildings. The Superintendent may, however, waive the requirement as to the filing of the plans when, in his opinion, the nature of the alteration may be fully explained in the application.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1482" number="1012" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(l)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Valves. </CHARFORMAT>Each valve controlling water supply and each valve controlling drainage of system or test flow, shall bear a metal plate securely attached to the valve and indicating clearly the purpose of each such valve. On the sprinkler main, an outside screw and yoke gate valve, readily accessible, shall be provided near the front wall of the building and located so as to control the water supply to all of the interior sprinkler system. The said outside screw and yoke gate valve shall be sealed in an open position. If a roof tank is used as a supply for sprinklers, an outside screw and yoke gate valve shall be provided in the piping leading from the tank to the sprinkler system, under conditions similar to those specified for such valves on sprinkler mains. A check valve of equal diameter to the main shall be installed in all sprinkler mains where a building is supplied by services connected to different street mains, or where a building is equipped with a siamese connection. Such check valve shall be placed within two feet of the outlet side of the main control valve. Where a sprinkler system is supplied with both a gravity tank and a street main, a check valve shall be placed in the independent supply pipe to the tank (on the tank side of the pump) and in the main at the outlet end of the main control valve. Such check valves shall be of equal diameter to the supply pipe and the main respectively. When the sprinkler system has an auxiliary supply in the form of a siamese connection, a check valve shall be placed in a horizontal position in the down feed from the gravity tank and immediately below the roof. When a building is supplied through a pressure tank in the cellar or basement, a check valve of equal diameter to the main shall be placed in the sprinkler main on the inside service between the intake and discharge connections to the pump feeding the pressure tank. Where a sprinkler system is equipped with a booster pump, valves shall be provided in accordance with 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-06" destination-id="0-0-0-686">29-06</LINK>(d). All control valves in supplies to the sprinkler system shall be sealed in an open position in an approved manner. Where an underground main is used, the main control valve shall be located where readily accessible.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1483" number="1013" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(m)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Drainage. </CHARFORMAT>All sprinkler pipe and fittings shall be so installed that the system can be thoroughly drained. Where practicable, all piping shall be arranged to drain to the main drain valve. Where this is impracticable, as in the case of sprinkler piping under stair soffits, a three-quarter inch screw plug shall be provided in the lower end of such piping to permit drainage. Except where otherwise provided in the previous paragraph, sprinkler pipes shall be pitched not less than one-quarter inch in the 10 feet. Pipe shall be straightened before installation to prevent pockets which would interfere with proper drainage. For draining the sprinkler system, a three-quarter inch tee branch with a three-quarter inch plugged valve shall be provided on the sprinkler main on the house side of the main (O.S.&amp;Y.) control valve. Where a sprinkler system is provided with check valves, the intermediate pipe between check valves shall be so arranged as to properly drain.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1484" number="1014" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(n)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Sprinkler specifications. </CHARFORMAT>Sprinklers shall be of a type and manufacture approved by the Board of Standards and Appeals and of current issue. The operating temperature of all sprinklers shall be in the ordinary degree range. Appropriate higher degree operating temperatures shall be required in cooking spaces. Any sprinkler which has opened or has been damaged shall be replaced immediately with a good sprinkler. There shall be kept available on the premises at all times at least three extra sprinklers and also a sprinkler wrench for use to replace any fused or damaged sprinklers.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1485" number="1015" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(o)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Pipe specifications – sleeves. </CHARFORMAT>All piping except underground piping used in sprinkler systems shall be full weight standard steel threaded pipe, well reamed and screwed up tight into fittings without reducing the waterway. Fittings shall be standard weight cast-iron. All fittings and pipes placed inside of tanks shall be of brass or other non-corroding material. Underground piping shall be of Extra Heavy Cast Iron Corporation pipe with bell and spriget or mechanical joints. Sprinkler piping passing through floors (other than floors in public halls) of concrete or waterproof construction, shall have properly designed substantial thimbles or sleeves projecting three to six inches above the floor to prevent possible floor leakage. The space between the pipe and sleeve should be caulked with oakum or equivalent material. If floors are of cinder concrete, thimbles or sleeves should extend all the way through to protect the piping against corrosion.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1486" number="1016" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(p)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hangers and support of piping. </CHARFORMAT>All branches shall be adequately supported. There shall be at least one hanger for each length of pipe between sprinklers, with one hanger within 30 inches of the end sprinkler and with hangers not over 12 feet apart. Vertical piping shall be securely supported at the base and at maximum intervals of every other floor, provided that such maximum intervals are 20 feet or less. The maximum spacing between hangers on horizontal mains and risers shall be 12 feet. Hangers shall be of a substantial metal type. Sprinkler risers shall not be located within 12 inches of a window or other exterior wall opening.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1487" number="1017" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(q)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Frost protection. </CHARFORMAT>When necessary for the protection of a sprinkler system against frost, the Superintendent shall require that the public halls be heated. Exposed water supply piping shall be protected against frost in accordance with 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-06" destination-id="0-0-0-686">29-06</LINK>(e).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1488" number="1018" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(r)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Tests. </CHARFORMAT>Sprinkler systems when completed shall be subjected to a hydrostatic test at a pressure of not less than 30 pounds per square inch, in excess of the normal pressure required for such sprinkler system when in service, except that where a siamese is required, the test pressure shall be not less than 200 pounds per square inch. All piping shall remain uncovered in every part until it has successfully passed the test. The Department of Buildings, in the borough in which the test is to be conducted, shall be notified when such test is to take place. Tests shall be conducted by the contractor or the owner or the owner&apos;s representative, in the presence of a representative of the Building Department. Sprinkler risers shall be provided at the top for testing purposes, with a connection not less than one inch in diameter, with a valve outlet so located that same will be readily accessible at all times. When not in use the valve shall be provided with an iron or brass plug screwed in tight.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1489" number="1019" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(s)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Maintenance. </CHARFORMAT>Each sprinkler system shall be maintained in good condition and in such manner that it will function effectively in the event of fire on the premises. The owner is responsible for the condition of his sprinkler system and shall use due diligence in keeping the system in good operating condition. Sprinkler systems shall be inspected at least once in each six months by the owner, to ascertain that all parts of the system are in perfect working order. A detailed record of each such inspection shall be kept on the premises for examination by the Department of Housing Preservation and Development, the Department of Buildings and the Fire Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1490" number="1020" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(t)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Painting. </CHARFORMAT>When the sprinkler system is given any kind of coating, such as whitewash or paint, care shall be exercised to see that no portion of the automatic sprinklers is covered.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1491" number="1021" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(u)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Alterations. </CHARFORMAT>No additional sprinklers shall be installed and no part of a sprinkler system shall be altered without a written approval from the Department of Buildings.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1492" number="1022" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Issuance of approval. </CHARFORMAT>Before the installation of a sprinkler system is approved and prior to the issuance of a letter of approval, there shall be filed with the Department of Buildings, in the borough in which the work has been installed, a letter from the Department of Environmental Protection indicating the size of the tap and service main and whether same has been installed in an approved manner.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-1493" number="1023" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 29-07 Installation of Wet-Pipe Sprinklers.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-688" name="T01C029_29-07"/>§ 29-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Installation of Wet-Pipe Sprinklers.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1494" number="1024" version="3">
									<PARA>Rules and Regulations for the Installation of Wet-Pipe Sprinklers under the provisions of § 248, Subdivision 4, Paragraph b, Multiple Dwelling Law, in Certain Fireproof Multiple Dwellings Erected before May 16, 1913, and Converted in Whole or in Part to Single Room Occupancy Prior to December 9, 1955.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1495" number="1025" version="748">
									<PARA>Extract from the Multiple Dwelling Law <LINEBRK/> Section 248, Subdivision 4, Paragraph b. &quot;There shall be access to a second means of egress within the apartment without passing through any public stair or public hall. On and after July first, nineteen hundred fifty-seven, every tenement used or occupied for single room occupancy in whole or part under the provisions of this section, and which does not have at least two means of egress accessible to each apartment, and extending from the ground story to the roof, shall be provided with at least two means of egress or, in lieu of such egress, every stair hall or public hall, and every hall or passage within an apartment, shall be equipped on each story with one or more automatic sprinkler heads approved by the department. Elevator shafts in such tenements shall be completely enclosed with fireproof or other incombustible material and the doors to such shafts shall be fireproof or shall be covered on all sides with incombustible material.&quot;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1496" number="1026" version="1770">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except as otherwise provided herein, automatic wet-pipe sprinklers installed under the provisions of § 248, Subdivision 4, Paragraph b, Multiple Dwelling Law, in certain fireproof dwellings erected before May 16, 1913, and converted in whole or in part to single room occupancy prior to December 9, 1955, shall be installed in conformity with Subchapter 17 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T27C001" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 1 of Title 27</LINK> of the Administrative Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1497" number="1027" version="1770">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In lieu of one of the four alternate automatic sources of water supply specified in § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-961" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-961</LINK>, Subdivision b, of the Administrative (Building) Code, a connection may be made to the domestic water supply system under the following conditions:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1498" number="1028" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>It can be established from the information obtainable from the Department of Environmental Protection that the minimum static pressure at the top of the highest riser will be at least 15 pounds per square inch, except as otherwise provided in 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-07" destination-id="0-0-0-688">29-07</LINK>(g).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1499" number="1029" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the pressure from this source is insufficient to provide a minimum static pressure of 15 pounds per square inch, at the highest line of sprinklers, but is sufficient to supply a pressure of 5 pounds per square inch or more at the highest line of sprinklers, an automatic booster pump shall be provided, the capacity of which shall be 250 gallons per minute at a pressure of at least 15 pounds per square inch at the highest sprinkler line.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1500" number="1030" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A sprinkler shut-off valve is provided conveniently accessible, and its purpose is clearly indicated by the words &quot;Automatic Sprinkler Shut-Off Valve&quot; on a sign affixed thereto, and that such valve is sealed open.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1501" number="1031" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The side of the domestic water supply line is at least equal to the size of the main sprinkler connection.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1502" number="1032" version="1770">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of Paragraph c of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-964" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-964</LINK> shall not apply to sprinklers installed in conformity with the provisions of this 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-07" destination-id="0-0-0-688">29-07</LINK>(b).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1503" number="1033" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where the length of pipe from the furthermost sprinkler to the riser exceeds 100 feet, the pipe beyond the 100 foot distance shall be increased in size one pipe size above the size of otherwise required, for each 100 feet of additional length or part thereof. This provision shall not require an increase in the size of the risers.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1504" number="1034" version="1770">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The capacity for gravity tanks for sprinklers shall be in conformity with provisions of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-965" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-965</LINK>, or such tank may be supplied by an automatic filling pump, capable of delivering at least 65 gallons per minute to the tank and shall have sufficient capacity to supply 25 percent of the sprinkler heads in the largest sprinkler area for 20 minutes, at 20 gallons per minute. The capacity of such tank shall not be less than 1,500 gallons. The bottom of the gravity tank or the sprinkler supply pipe shall not be less than 20 feet above the highest supplied sprinkler line. When such elevation is not practicable, an automatic booster pump may be installed in the main sprinkler supply line in conformity with 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-07" destination-id="0-0-0-688">29-07</LINK>(b)(2).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1505" number="1035" version="1770">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In lieu of complying with the provisions of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-965" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-965</LINK>, a pressure tank located not more than one story below the highest supplied sprinkler line, filled by an automatic pump, and with a supply of water, all as described in 1 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T01C029_29-07" destination-id="0-0-0-688">29-07</LINK>(c), may be installed. In addition, a high-and-low air-alarm shall be provided.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1506" number="1036" version="1770">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Subdivision b of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-963" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-963</LINK>(a) may be construed to permit the sprinkler connection to the street main to be the same size as the main sprinkler riser, but in no instance shall it be less than 2 inches. A tap may be one pipe-size less than the sprinkler main.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1507" number="1037" version="1770">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the number of sprinkler heads in any fire area as defined in these rules exceeds fifty-five (55), an approved Fire Department siamese connection shall be installed in accordance with the requirements of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-940" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-940</LINK> of the Administrative (Building) Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1508" number="1038" version="1770">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In lieu of applying the provisions of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-956" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-956</LINK>, sprinkler heads shall be so spaced that there shall be one head for approximately 144 square feet of floor area, and heads shall be spaced not more than 14 feet on centers. The distance from a wall or partition to the first sprinkler head shall not exceed 7 feet, measured at right angles to the wall or partition. A 12-pound minimum static pressure will be accepted at the topmost sprinkler line, provided the sprinkler heads are spaced to cover 100 square feet or less.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1509" number="1039" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In lieu of complying with the provisions of ANSI/NFPA 13 of Reference Standard RS 17-2 of the Administrative (Building) Code, a l-inch valve pipe may be extended from the top of the riser to the outside of the building, or inside the building to a deep sink for testing the system, pump and alarm under water-flow conditions.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1510" number="1040" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Check valves, gate valves, and water meters shall be installed as and when directed by the Department of Environmental Protection.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1511" number="1041" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definition.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1512" number="1042" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Sprinkler area.</CHARFORMAT> The term &quot;sprinkler area&quot; as used in these rules shall mean any floor space within a structure enclosed on all sides by exterior walls, fire walls, fire partitions, or fire-proof partitions and self-closing doors acceptable to the Department of Buildings.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1513" number="1043" version="1770">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The sprinkler control valves shall be inspected at least once weekly, by a competent person, who is employed by the owner and who holds a Certificate of Fitness to see that such valves are sealed open. A record of each inspection shall be kept for examination by a representative of the Department. The provisions of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-957" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-957</LINK>, in relation to alarm devices, shall not apply to those buildings having more than 36 heads in any sprinkler area.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1514" number="1044" version="1770">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(l)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In conformity with the provisions of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-957" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-957</LINK>, sprinkler alarm devices shall be required when more than 36 heads are installed in any fire area.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1515" number="1045" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(m)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where there are practical difficulties in the way of carrying out these rules, the Superintendent may permit modification, provided that the spirit of these rules are observed and safely secured.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-1516" number="1046" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 29-08 Installation of Sprinklers in Rooms of Class B Non-Fireproof Converted Dwellings and in Rooms Used for Class B Occupancy in Non-Fireproof Class A Converted Dwellings Under the Provisions of § 194 of the Multiple Dwelling Law.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-690" name="T01C029_29-08"/>§ 29-08 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Installation of Sprinklers in Rooms of Class B Non-Fireproof Converted Dwellings and in Rooms Used for Class B Occupancy in Non-Fireproof Class A Converted Dwellings Under the Provisions of § 194 of the Multiple Dwelling Law.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1517" number="1047" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Applicability. </CHARFORMAT>Sprinklers installed in rooms of class B non-fireproof converted dwellings, and in rooms used for class B occupancy in non-fireproof class A converted dwellings shall conform to the &quot;sprinkler rules governing the installation of automatic sprinklers in the public halls of multiple dwellings under the provisions of § 187 (Converted Dwellings) and § 218(7) (Old Law Tenements) of the Multiple Dwelling Law, and of sprinklers in cooking spaces in all types of multiple dwellings under the provisions of § 33 of the Multiple Dwelling Law,&quot; except as provided otherwise in these rules.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1518" number="1048" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Sprinkler protection – when required. </CHARFORMAT>In every room in a class B non-fireproof converted dwelling, and in every room used for class B occupancy in any non-fireproof class A converted dwelling, there shall be one or more sprinkler heads so arranged as to sprinkle all parts of such rooms. A sprinkler system in the public stairway or in the service stairway shall not be required by these rules, but sprinklers shall be provided for such stairways where required by the Multiple Dwelling Law or the provisions of other rules.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1519" number="1049" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Spray type sprinklers. </CHARFORMAT>Where approved spray type sprinkler heads are used, they shall conform to the requirements of the rules specified in subdivision (a) of this section, except that the protected area for approved 1/2 inch spray type sprinklers shall not exceed 168 square feet in area, and the distance between heads shall not exceed 14 feet and the maximum distance between such heads and a wall or partition shall not exceed 7 feet.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1520" number="1050" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Connection to existing sprinkler systems. </CHARFORMAT>Where a separate sprinkler system exists in a building and such sprinkler system was installed prior to December 15, 1956, and the sprinkler system was approved by the Department of Buildings and is in good operating condition, piping for the sprinklers in rooms may be taken from the existing sprinkler riser at each story, provided the riser has a diameter of not less than one inch. The size of the branch piping between the sprinklers and the riser shall be determined according to the number of sprinklers supplied but shall not be required to be greater in size than 1 1/4 inches in diameter, except that if the length of pipe exceeds 50 feet, the entire length of pipe shall be increased one pipe size for each 50 feet of length. Existing risers and mains of sprinkler systems shall not be required to be increased. The sprinkler heads installed in rooms shall not be counted in determining whether a siamese hose connection is required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1521" number="1051" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Installation where no sprinkler system exists. </CHARFORMAT>Where it is required that sprinklers be provided in rooms and there is no existing approved sprinkler system in the building, a system of sprinklers shall be provided which shall conform to the requirements of the rules specified in subdivision (a) of this section and to the requirements of these rules in the same manner as if such sprinklers were existing except that mains shall be not less than 1 1/4 inches in diameter and that a siamese hose connection shall not be required, and except as follows: Where the existing water supply piping is tested at any location within the dwelling and discharges at least 20 gallons of water per minute, at a flow pressure of not less than 10 pounds per square inch at the point of delivery, the existing house water supply main may be used provided the diameter of the main is not less than 3/4 inch, and provided a static pressure of at least 15 pounds per square inch is provided at the highest sprinkler. In such case, a riser for the sprinkler system shall be connected to the water main not more than 12 inches from the point where the main enters the building and on the house side of the main house control valve. No additional branch control valves shall be permitted. The size of the riser shall be determined by the number of sprinkler heads as required by the rules specified in subdivision (a) of this section, except that the riser shall not be required to be more than 1 1/4 inches in diameter regardless of the number of sprinkler heads provided. The size of branches shall be determined by the number of sprinkler heads, except that branches shall not be required larger than 1 1/4 inches in size. Risers and branches provided for the sprinkler system shall be used for no other purpose.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-1522" number="1052" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 29-09 Installation of Chlorinated Poly Vinyl Chloride (CPVC) Sprinkler Pipe and Fittings.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-692" name="T01C029_29-09"/>§ 29-09 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Installation of Chlorinated Poly Vinyl Chloride (CPVC) Sprinkler Pipe and Fittings.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1523" number="1053" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Storage and handling.</CHARFORMAT> CPVC piping shall be stored and carried in the original shipment containers whenever possible. Reasonable care should be exercised in handling the pipes. If improper handling results in splits, gouges or cuts and scratches that are not superficial in nature, the damaged section shall be cut out and discarded. Pipes must be covered with non-transparent material when stored outdoors without the original containers.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1524" number="1054" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Safety precautions.</CHARFORMAT> All solvent cements and primers for CPVC piping are flammable and shall not be used or stored near heat, spark or open flames. Cement shall be stored in closed containers at temperatures between 40°F (4.4°C) and 110°F (43°C). They shall be used only with adequate ventilation. Containers shall be kept tightly closed when not in use and covered as much as possible when in use.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1525" number="1055" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Certification.</CHARFORMAT> Individuals installing CPVC piping shall be trained and certified by the manufacturer. Documentation of such certification of the individual shall be on the job site at all times when installation work is performed.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1526" number="1056" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Installation.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1527" number="1057" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">General.</CHARFORMAT> Sprinkler piping systems shall be laid out so that the piping is not located adjacent to heat producing sources such as light fixtures and ballasts, steam lines, etc. which can produce an ambient temperature exceeding 150°F (66°C). CPVC pipes shall not be threaded, grooved or drilled.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1528" number="1058" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Concealed installation.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1529" number="1059" version="1968">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For concealed installation, the minimum protection shall consist of one layer of 3/8&quot; (10mm) gypsum wallboard or a suspended membrane ceiling with lay-in panels or tiles having a weight of not less than 0.35 pounds per square foot (1.71kg/m<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" point-size="8">
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" point-size="8" background-color-auto="1">
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" point-size="8" background-color-auto="1" baseline="-60">2</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" background-color-auto="1" baseline="-60">
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" baseline="-60">
										</CHARFORMAT>) when installed with metallic support grids, or 1/2&quot; (13mm) plywood pipe enclosure. Plywood used for pipe enclosure shall be fire-retardant treated when used in buildings of non-combustible construction.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1530" number="1060" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When pipes and fittings are installed in a plenum space, they shall not be positioned directly over open ventilation grills.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1531" number="1061" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>System risers shall not be installed exposed, and shall be provided with minimum protection for concealed installation as stated above.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1532" number="1062" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Exposed installation.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1533" number="1063" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Exposed sprinkler piping shall be installed below a smooth, flat, horizontal ceiling construction. Positioning of sprinkler heads relative to obstructions such as, but not limited to, beams, light fixtures or decorations shall be in accordance with Reference Standard RS 17-2, 17-2A and 17-2B.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1534" number="1064" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Only quick-response sprinkler heads shall be used on exposed piping.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1535" number="1065" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Deflectors of pendent sprinklers when installed shall be not more than 4&quot; (102mm) from the ceiling, and sidewall sprinklers not more than 6&quot; (152mm) from the ceiling and not more than 4&quot; (102mm) from the sidewall.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1536" number="1066" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upright quick-response sprinklers when installed on exposed piping shall meet the following conditions:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-104170" number="1067" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>The deflectors shall be not more than 4&quot; (102mm) from the ceiling.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-104171" number="1068" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>The maximum temperature rating shall be 155°F (68°C).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-104172" number="1069" version="1965">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>The maximum distance from the ceiling to the centerline of the main run of pipe shall be 7 1/2&quot; (191mm).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-104173" number="1070" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>The maximum distance from the centerline of a sprinkler head to a hanger shall be 3&quot; (76mm).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1537" number="1071" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hangers and supports.</CHARFORMAT> The pipe hangers shall comply with all the requirements of RS 17-2, 17-2A and 17-2B. The hanger shall not have rough or sharp edges which come in contact with the pipe. Hangers shall not bind the pipe from movement.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1538" number="1072" version="1003">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The support spacing shall be as shown on the following tables and diagram:<LINEBRK/>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1539" number="1073" version="1965">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="4">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="8" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="8" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="7" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="7" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELL cells-merged-right="3">
																<CELLFORMAT top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">
																	<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hangers and Supports</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</CELLFORMAT>
															</CELL>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELL cells-merged-right="1">Nominal Pipe Size </CELL>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELL cells-merged-right="1">Maximum Support Spacing </CELL>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">Inches </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">(millimeters) </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">Feet </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">(meters) </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 3/4 </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">(19) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">5 1/2</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">(1.675) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 3/4</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">(25) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">6 1/2</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">(1.830) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 1/4</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">(32) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">6 1/2</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">(1.980) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 1/2</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">(38) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">7 1/2</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">(2.135) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">2 1/2</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">(51) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">8 1/2</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">(2.440) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">2 1/2</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">(64) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">9 1/2</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">(2.745) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">3 1/2</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">(76) </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">10 1/2</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">(3.050) </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1540" number="1074" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Table A <LINEBRK/>Maximum Support Spacing Distance End Line Sprinkler Head Drop Elbow</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1541" number="1075" version="2498">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="3">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="11" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">Nominal Pipe Size (In)<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" baseline="-60">
																</CHARFORMAT>
															</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">Less than 100 psi (689 kPa)<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" baseline="-60">
																</CHARFORMAT>
															</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">More than 100 psi (689 kPa)<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" baseline="-60">
																</CHARFORMAT>
															</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">3/4&quot; (19 mm) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">9&quot; (229 mm) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">6&quot; (152 mm) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1&quot; (25 mm) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">12&quot; (305 mm) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">9&quot; (229 mm) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 1/4&quot; (32 mm) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">16&quot; (406 mm) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">12&quot; (305 mm) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">1 1/2&quot; - 3&quot; (38 - 76 mm) </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">24&quot; (610 mm) </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">12&quot; (305 mm) </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1542" number="1076" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Table B <LINEBRK/>Maximum Support Spacing Distance Inline Sprinkler Head Drop Tee</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1543" number="1077" version="2498">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="3">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="11" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="10" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">Nominal Pipe Size (In)<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" baseline="-60">
																</CHARFORMAT>
															</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">Less than 100 psi (689 kPa)<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" baseline="-60">
																</CHARFORMAT>
															</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT top-border-space="0" top-border-width="14" top-border-color="#000000" bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">More than 100 psi (689 kPa)<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" baseline="-60">
																</CHARFORMAT>
															</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">3/4&quot; (19 mm) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">4&apos; (1.220 m) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">3&apos; (0.915 m) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1&quot; (25 mm) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">5&apos; (1.525 m) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">4&apos; (1.220 m) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">1 1/4&quot; (32 mm) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">6&apos; (1.830 m) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">5&apos; (1.525 m) </PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">1 1/2&quot; - 3&quot; (38 - 76 mm)</CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">7&apos; (2.135 m) </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="center">
															<CELLFORMAT bottom-border-space="0" bottom-border-width="14" bottom-border-color="#000000">7&apos; (2.135 m) </CELLFORMAT>
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1544" number="1078" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<PICTURE id="0-0-0-50-img" object-class="Folio Objects" original-name="Obj:0ea7d6c2-e83c-43ee-bbb5-81474c4190f8" name="Obj_0ea7d6c2-e83c-43ee-bbb5-81474c4190f8-0-0-0-50" href="#!-- #EXECUTIVE:HOME_PATH --#/img/Obj_0ea7d6c2-e83c-43ee-bbb5-81474c4190f8-0-0-0-50" width="7581" height="3491" left-border-line-color="0" left-border-line-width="0" left-border-space="0" right-border-line-color="0" right-border-line-width="0" right-border-space="0" top-border-line-color="0" top-border-line-width="0" top-border-space="0" bottom-border-line-color="0" bottom-border-line-width="0" bottom-border-space="0"/>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1545" number="1079" version="3">
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1546" number="1080" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vertical pipes shall be supported at each floor level or at 10 feet (3.050m) intervals whichever is less.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1547" number="1081" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Other methods of pipe support shall be as recommended by the manufacturer.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1548" number="1082" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Pipe cutting.</CHARFORMAT> Pipes shall be cut with a wheel-type plastic-tubing cutter. If any indication of damage or cracking is evident cut off at least 2&quot; (51mm) beyond any visible crack. Burrs and filings can prevent contact between pipe and fittings during assembly, and must be removed from the outside and inside of the pipe. A slight bevel shall be placed at the end of the pipe to ease entry of the pipe into the socket.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1549" number="1083" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Pipe joints.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1550" number="1084" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Primer and cement application.</CHARFORMAT> The pipe and fittings shall be clean and free of any moisture and debris. Primer and cement shall be applied to the joining surfaces using an applicator. Puddling of cement or primer on or within fitting and pipe must be avoided. When cementing in temperatures below 40°F (4.4°C) make certain cement has not gelled. Gelled cement must be discarded. A bead of cement should be evident around the pipe and fitting juncture. If this bead is not continuous around the socket shoulder, it should be rejected and the joint must be cut out, discarded and begun again.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1551" number="1085" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Set and cure time.</CHARFORMAT> The assembly must be allowed to set, without any stress on the joint, in accordance with manufacturer&apos;s recommendations, which may vary from 1 to 5 minutes depending upon the pipe size and temperature. Refer to manufacturer&apos;s recommendation for minimum cure times prior to pressure testing.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1552" number="1086" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Sprinkler installation.</CHARFORMAT> Sprinklers shall be installed only after all pipes and fittings, including sprinkler head adopters, are solvent welded to the piping system and allowed to cure for a minimum of 30 minutes. Sprinkler head fittings should be visually inspected and probed with a wooden dowel to insure that the waterway and threads are clear of any excess cement. Only Teflon tape or equivalent approved by the Commissioner shall be used when installing the sprinkler heads. If a leak is detected on the sprinkler head drop when the system is pressure tested, the sprinkler head must be removed and the joint redone before reinstalling the head.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1553" number="1087" version="1770">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Firestopping.</CHARFORMAT> Pipe penetration through fire rated construction shall be firestopped as per § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-343" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-343</LINK> of the Building Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-1554" number="1088" version="1770">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hydrostatic pressure testing.</CHARFORMAT> After the installation is completed and cured, the system shall be pressure tested as per § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="27-967" destination-id="0-0-0-0">27-967</LINK> of the Building Code. Air or compressed gas must never be used for pressure testing.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>