<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-122400" number="101090" version="1565">
			<HEADING>Chapter 9: Public Funds Repayments</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-16395" name="T52C009"/>Chapter 9: Public Funds Repayments</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-122401" number="101091" version="3021">
								<HEADING>§ 9-01 Repayment of Public Funds.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-16539" name="T52C009_9-01"/>§ 9-01 Repayment of Public Funds.</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122402" number="101092" version="3021">
									<PARA>Candidates must promptly repay public funds upon a determination made by the Board that a repayment is required. Candidates returning public funds must make a check payable to the &quot;New York City Election Campaign Finance Fund.&quot; Candidates may not reclaim public funds they have returned. Public funds must be repaid to the Board separately from, and in addition to, any penalties owed by the candidate. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-118]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122403" number="101093" version="3021">
									<PARA>(Added City Record 8/16/2019, eff. 9/15/2019; amended City Record 1/23/2026, eff. 2/22/2026) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-118]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-122404" number="101094" version="1567">
								<HEADING>§ 9-02 Reasons for Repayment.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-16541" name="T52C009_9-02"/>§ 9-02 Reasons for Repayment.</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122405" number="101095" version="1565">
									<PARA>The Board shall determine whether a candidate or such candidate&apos;s principal committee is required to repay public funds previously received as follows:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122406" number="101096" version="1886">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Overpayment of public funds.</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0"> Pursuant to § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3-710" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3-710</LINK>(2)(a) of the Code, the candidate&apos;s principal committee is required to pay to the Board an amount equivalent to the amount of public funds received in excess of the amount which the candidate is eligible to receive.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122407" number="101097" version="1886">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Qualified expenditure deficit.</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0"> Pursuant to § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3-710" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3-710</LINK>(2)(b) of the Code, the candidate&apos;s principal committee is required to pay to the Board an amount equivalent to the amount of public funds paid to the candidate that were not spent on qualified expenditures.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122408" number="101098" version="1565">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Determination of personal liability.</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0"> A candidate may be personally liable for paying to the Board the amount of public funds not spent on qualified expenditures, or a portion of that amount. In considering whether and to what extent a participating candidate shall be personally liable for repayment of public funds, the Board shall act in accordance with the following:</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122409" number="101099" version="1565">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>where credible documentation supporting each qualified expenditure exists but is incomplete, the Board shall not impose such liability for such expenditure;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122410" number="101100" version="1565">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>where there is an absence of credible documentation for each qualified expenditure, the Board may impose such liability upon a showing that such absence of credible documentation for such expenditure arose from a lack of adequate controls including, but not limited to, trained staff, internal procedures for following Board guidelines and internal procedures for employing standard financial controls.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122411" number="101101" version="1929">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Final bank balance.</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0"> Pursuant to § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3-710" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3-710</LINK>(2)(c) of the Code, the candidate and the principal committee are required to pay to the Board an amount equivalent to the campaign funds remaining in such candidate&apos;s principal committee account. The candidate must promptly pay to the Board such remaining funds; provided, however, that all remaining funds for a candidate shall be immediately due and payable to the Board upon a determination by the Board that the candidate has delayed the post-election audit process. The candidate must promptly pay to the Board any additional remaining campaign funds based upon a determination made by the Board at a subsequent date. The amount of remaining campaign funds shall be presumed to be equal to the candidate&apos;s authorized committee bank account balance on January 11 in the year following the election, or for special elections, on the last day of the reporting period for the later of the 27 day post-election disclosure statement or the first semi-annual disclosure statement the candidate is required to file with the Board following the date of such election, less any permissible documented post-election expenditures pursuant to paragraph (i) of this subdivision. The Board may also consider information revealed in the course of an audit or investigation in making a remaining funds determination, including, but not limited to, the fact that campaign expenditures were made in violation of law, that expenditures were made for any purpose other than the furtherance of the candidate&apos;s nomination or election, or that the candidate has not maintained or provided requested documentation. If a candidate repays to the Fund all funds remaining in such candidate&apos;s authorized committee bank account on or before December 31 in the year of the election, or, for special elections, on or before the last day of the month following the month in which the election took place, such candidate shall be presumed not to owe additional remaining funds, provided that any contributions received and expenditures made after such funds are repaid must be raised and spent in compliance with the Act and these rules.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-058]<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											</CHARFORMAT>
										</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122412" number="101102" version="2012">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Before repaying campaign funds remaining in the committee bank account, a candidate may make post-election expenditures only for routine activities involving nominal cost associated with winding down a campaign and responding to the post-election audit. Such expenditures may include: payment of utility bills and rent; reasonable staff salaries and consultancy fees for responding to a post-election audit; reasonable staff salaries and legal fees incurred prior to the date of the issuance of the candidate&apos;s final audit report and associated with defending against a claim that public funds must be repaid; a post-election event for staff, volunteers, or supporters held within 30 days of the election; reasonable moving expenses related to closing the campaign office; a holiday card mailing to contributors, campaign volunteers, and staff; thank you notes to contributors, campaign volunteers, and staff; payment of taxes and other reasonable expenses for compliance with applicable tax laws; and interest expense. Routine post-election expenditures that may be paid for with remaining campaign funds do not include such items as post-election mailings other than as specifically provided for in this paragraph; making contributions; or making bonus payments or gifts to staff or volunteers. Campaign funds remaining in the committee account may not be used for transition and inauguration activities. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122413" number="101103" version="1565">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the restriction on the use of receipts provided in subdivision (c)(i), a candidate who has outstanding liabilities from the election, including a candidate who owes public funds or penalties to the Board, may make post-election expenditures for the purpose of raising funds to repay such debt, provided, however, that such expenditures and any contributions received shall be included in the calculation of the candidate&apos;s remaining funds, unless such expenditures and contributions are incurred or received after the date of the issuance of the candidate&apos;s final audit report.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122414" number="101104" version="1565">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Notwithstanding the prohibition on post-election bonus payments provided in subdivision (c)(i), a bonus payment to an employee may be considered a permissible pre-election expenditure, even if paid after the election, provided that:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122415" number="101105" version="1565">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the bonus is paid pursuant to a contract executed before the services that serve as the basis for the bonus are performed;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122416" number="101106" version="1565">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>such contract states in detail the amount of the bonus and the criteria that must be satisfied in order for the bonus to be paid;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122417" number="101107" version="1565">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>such criteria are quantifiable, merit-based, and related to services provided prior to the election;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122418" number="101108" version="1565">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(D)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the bonus is not conditioned, either in existence or amount, on the result of the election, the amount of funds remaining in the committee account, or whether the candidate received public funds; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122419" number="101109" version="1565">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(E)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the bonus does not constitute more than 10% of the total amount paid to the employee.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122421" number="101110" version="1929">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Breach of certification.</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0"> A candidate found to have breached such candidate&apos;s certification pursuant to 52 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T52C003_3-01" destination-id="0-0-0-16439">3-01</LINK>(e) may be deemed ineligible to receive public funds and may be required to return all public funds previously received.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122428" number="101111" version="1929">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Ballot disqualification.</CHARFORMAT> Pursuant to § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3-709" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3-709</LINK>(7) of the Code, a candidate who has been finally disqualified or whose designating or nominating petitions have been finally declared invalid by the Board of Elections or a court, or whose only remaining opponent has been finally disqualified or whose designating or nominating petitions have been finally declared invalid by the Board of Elections or a court, may not spend public funds for any purpose other than the payment of previous liabilities incurred in qualified campaign expenditures, except as provided in 52 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T52C009_9-02" destination-id="0-0-0-16541">9-02</LINK>(i)(iii). All public funds in excess of those liabilities previously incurred shall be promptly repaid to the Board. The amount to be repaid will be determined in accordance with § <CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3-710" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3-710</LINK>
										</CHARFORMAT>(2)(b) of the Code and subdivision (b) of this section. A repayment made pursuant to § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3-709" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3-709</LINK>(7) does not prevent the Board from determining that an additional repayment is required. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-126408" number="101112" version="1929">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Ballot fraud.</CHARFORMAT> Pursuant to § <CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3-710" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3-710</LINK>
										</CHARFORMAT>(3)(a) of the Code, a candidate who has been disqualified by a court on the grounds that the candidate committed fraudulent acts in order to obtain a place on the ballot must pay to the Board an amount equal to the total public funds paid to the candidate. Repayments pursuant to this subdivision must be made promptly upon the court&apos;s determination of disqualification. No repayment is required if the decision is reversed. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-126407" number="101113" version="1929">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Failure to actively campaign.</CHARFORMAT> Pursuant to § <CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3-710" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3-710</LINK>
										</CHARFORMAT>(3)(b) of the Code, a candidate who fails to actively campaign for a covered office may be required to repay an amount equal to the total public funds received. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-126406" number="101114" version="1929">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Ceasing to campaign. </CHARFORMAT>Pursuant to § <CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3-710" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3-710</LINK>
										</CHARFORMAT>(3)(c) of the Code, a candidate who ceases to actively campaign for a covered office may be required to repay an amount equivalent to the amount of public funds paid to the candidate that were not spent on qualified expenditures. Only expenditures incurred prior to the date on which the candidate ceased actively campaigning may be considered qualified expenditures. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-126405" number="101115" version="1929">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>O<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">ther reasons for repayment.</CHARFORMAT> The Board may require a candidate to repay public funds because: <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-126404" number="101116" version="1929">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the candidate failed to maintain copies of checks or contribution cards that document matchable contributions; <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-126403" number="101117" version="1929">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the public funds paid were based on contributions that were returned or contribution checks that have not been paid; <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-126402" number="101118" version="1929">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the candidate has failed to demonstrate eligibility for the public funds paid or compliance with Program requirements, including the requirements to appear on the ballot and to be opposed by at least one other candidate on the ballot. The Board may seek immediate repayment of the difference between the amount of public funds received by a candidate and the total amount spent by the candidate as of the date on which the candidate ceases to be on the ballot or ceases to be opposed on the ballot; provided, however, that the candidate may retain public funds previously received for that anticipated election to be used in furtherance of a different election (other than a special election to fill a vacancy) held later in the same calendar year in which the candidate seeks election for the same office, unless the candidate is seeking election exclusively as a write-in candidate in such later election; and further provided that the amount of such public funds retained for a later election will be deducted from the total amount of public funds the candidate is eligible to receive for such later election; or <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-126401" number="101119" version="2306">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a determination pursuant to § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="3-705" destination-id="0-0-0-0">3-705</LINK>(6) or (7) of the Code is reversed following reconsideration pursuant to 52 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T52C007_7-10" destination-id="0-0-0-16527">7-10</LINK>(b)(vii). <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-058]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-122429" number="101120" version="1929">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Repayment is largest amount.</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0"> Where more than one grounds for repayment exists as provided in this section, the amount to be paid to the Board shall be the largest of the amounts.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;<HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-058]<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											</CHARFORMAT>
										</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-127487" number="101121" version="2012">
									<PARA>(Added City Record 8/16/2019, eff. 9/15/2019; amended City Record 5/22/2020, eff. 6/21/2020; amended City Record 1/19/2021, eff. 2/18/2021; amended City Record 6/10/2021, eff. 7/10/2021) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-063]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>