<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Title" style-name-escaped="Title" style-id="0-0-0-474" level-depth="1" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-80949" number="93406" version="1248">
			<HEADING>Title 43: Mayor</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-15538" name="Title 43"/>Title 43: Mayor</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-80950" number="93407" version="3">
				<HEADING>Chapter 1: Uniform Rules and Regulations for All City Agencies Pertaining to the Administration of the Freedom of Information Law</HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10781" name="T43C001"/>Chapter 1: Uniform Rules and Regulations for All City Agencies Pertaining to the Administration of the Freedom of Information Law</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
							<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80951" number="93408" version="3">
									<HEADING>§ 1-01 Scope.</HEADING>
									<PARA>
										<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10783" name="T43C001_1-01"/>§ 1-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Scope.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80952" number="93409" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>These Rules and Regulations shall govern the procedures by which records made available for public inspection pursuant to the Freedom of Information Law (Public Officers Law, Art. 6) may be obtained from a city agency.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80953" number="93410" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Agency personnel shall furnish to the public the information and records required to be made available by the Freedom of Information Law, as well as records otherwise available by law. Any conflicts among laws governing public access to records shall be construed in favor of the widest possible availability of public records.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
							<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80954" number="93411" version="3">
									<HEADING>§ 1-02 Designation of Records Access Officer.</HEADING>
									<PARA>
										<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10785" name="T43C001_1-02"/>§ 1-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Designation of Records Access Officer.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80955" number="93412" version="3">
										<PARA>The head or governing body of each agency shall be responsible for insuring compliance with these Rules and Regulations and shall designate one or more persons as records access officer or officers to coordinate the agency&apos;s response to public requests for inspection and copying of records. The designation shall include the name, specific job title, telephone number and business address of such access officer. The designation of a records access officer or officers shall not be construed to prohibit other agency officers and employees who have been authorized previously to make records or information available to the public from continuing to do so.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
							<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80956" number="93413" version="3">
									<HEADING>§ 1-03 Responsibilities of Records Access Officer.</HEADING>
									<PARA>
										<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10787" name="T43C001_1-03"/>§ 1-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Responsibilities of Records Access Officer.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80957" number="93414" version="3">
										<PARA>Each agency&apos;s records access officer shall have the following responsibilities:</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80958" number="93415" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>He shall maintain a reasonably detailed current subject matter list of all records in the possession of the agency, whether or not such records are available for inspection and copying pursuant to the Freedom of Information Law. The list shall be of sufficient detail to permit identification by the public of categories of records. The subject matter list shall be updated not less than twice per year and the date of the most recent revision of the list shall appear on its first page.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80959" number="93416" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>He shall assist members of the public in identifying requested records.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80960" number="93417" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When requested records are located, he shall either make such records available for inspection or deny access to such records in whole or in part, with a written statement of the grounds for denial of access.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80961" number="93418" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon request for copies of records, he shall either arrange to make copies available on payment of or offer to pay the established fee or shall permit the requesting party to copy the records using photocopying equipment on agency premises.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80962" number="93419" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>He shall, upon request, certify that a copy of a record is a true copy.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80963" number="93420" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon failure to locate records, he shall state in writing that the agency is not the custodian of such records or that the records cannot be found after diligent search.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80964" number="93421" version="1406">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>He shall maintain the records required to be maintained by subdivisions (b) and (f) of 43 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T43C001_1-05" destination-id="0-0-0-10791">1-05</LINK>.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
							<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80965" number="93422" version="3">
									<HEADING>§ 1-04 Hours and Location.</HEADING>
									<PARA>
										<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10789" name="T43C001_1-04"/>§ 1-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hours and Location.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80966" number="93423" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each agency shall designate a location or locations where records shall be available for public inspection and copying.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80967" number="93424" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each agency shall accept requests for public access to records and shall produce records during the agency&apos;s regular business hours. If an agency does not have regular business hours, it shall establish a written procedure by which a member of the public may arrange an appointment to inspect and copy records. The procedure shall specify the name, job title, telephone number and business address of the person to be contacted for the purpose of making such appointments.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
							<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80968" number="93425" version="3">
									<HEADING>§ 1-05 Procedure for Making Requests; Responses to Requests.</HEADING>
									<PARA>
										<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10791" name="T43C001_1-05"/>§ 1-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Procedure for Making Requests; Responses to Requests.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80969" number="93426" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any request to inspect or copy records shall be made in writing and addressed to the records access officer of the appropriate agency. The request shall reasonably describe the record or records sought and shall, whenever possible, supply information regarding dates, file designations or other information which will enable the records access officer to identify the records sought.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80970" number="93427" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon receipt of a request, the records access officer shall forward the request to the division of the agency having custody of the records requested. The records access officer shall retain a file copy of each request received by him and shall maintain or cause to be maintained a record showing the date on which the request was received, the division to which it was forwarded and the date of forwarding.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80971" number="93428" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within five business days of receipt of a request, the records access officer shall respond to the request:</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80972" number="93429" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the agency determines that the request should be granted, the records access officer shall so notify the requesting party in a writing which states the time and place at which the requested records may be inspected and the procedures and fees for copying of records.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80973" number="93430" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the agency determines that the requested records are exempt from disclosure under the terms of the Freedom of Information Law and that the request should be denied, the records access officer shall so notify the requesting party in a writing which states the grounds for the denial.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80974" number="93431" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If a request does not adequately describe the records sought, the records access officer shall notify the requesting party in writing that his request has been denied, stating the reasons why the request does not meet the requirements of this section and extending to the requesting party an opportunity to confer with the records access officer in order to attempt to reformulate the request in a manner that will enable the agency to identify the records sought.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80975" number="93432" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If a requested record does not exist, has been destroyed or otherwise disposed of, or is in the possession, custody or control of another agency, the records access officer shall so notify the requesting party in writing. In the case of records which the records access officer believes to be in the possession, custody or control of another agency, he shall state in the writing the agency to which the request should be addressed.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80976" number="93433" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the agency determines that a request should be granted in part and denied in part, the records access officer shall so notify the requesting party in a writing which sets forth the information required by subparagraphs (1), (2), (3) and (4) of this subdivision (c), as applicable.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80977" number="93434" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each writing denying a request in whole or in part shall inform the requesting party of his right to appeal the determination of the agency within thirty days and shall state the name of the person or body designated in the agency to hear such appeals. Such person or body shall be identified by name, title, business address and telephone number.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80978" number="93435" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If, because of unusual circumstances, an agency is unable to determine within five business days whether to grant, deny or otherwise respond to a request for inspection and copying, the records access officer shall, within such five day period, acknowledge receipt of the request in writing to the requesting party, stating the approximate date, not to exceed ten business days from the date of the acknowledgement, by which a determination with respect to the request will be made. If the agency does not make a determination with respect to the request within ten business days from the date of such acknowledgement, the request may be deemed denied and an appeal may be taken to the person or body designated in the agency to hear appeals. As used in this subdivision (d), &quot;unusual circumstances&quot; means:</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80979" number="93436" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The need to search for and collect the requested records from facilities or offices that are separate from the office processing the request; or</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80980" number="93437" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The need to search for, collect, examine and evaluate a voluminous amount of separate and distinct records which are demanded in a single request; or</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80981" number="93438" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The need for consultation, which shall be conducted with all practicable speed, with another agency having a substantial interest in the determination of the request or between two or more divisions or departments of an agency having a substantial subject matter interest therein; or</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80982" number="93439" version="1954">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any other circumstances in which the agency is unable, by the exercise of due diligence, and acting in good faith, to comply with the time limits set forth in this subdivision.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80983" number="93440" version="748">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>To prevent unwarranted invasions of personal privacy, an agency, in making records available for inspection and copying, may delete identifying details or may withhold records otherwise available, if deletion of identifying details is impracticable or will not, in fact, prevent an unwarranted invasion of the privacy of the person to whom the record refers. An unwarranted invasion of privacy includes, but is not limited to:</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80984" number="93441" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Disclosure of employment, medical or credit histories or personal references of applicants for employment; or</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80985" number="93442" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Disclosure of items involving the medical or personal records of a client or patient in a medical facility; or</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80986" number="93443" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Sale or release of lists of names and addresses if such lists would be used for commercial or fund-raising purposes; or</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80987" number="93444" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Disclosure of information of a personal nature when disclosure would result in economic or personal hardship to the subject party and such information is not relevant to the work of the agency requesting or maintaining it; or</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80988" number="93445" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Disclosure of information of a personal nature reported in confidence to an agency requesting or maintaining it and which is not relevant to the ordinary work of such agency.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80989" number="93446" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The records access officer shall retain a file copy of each writing granting, denying or acknowledging a request pursuant to subdivision (d) of this section and shall promptly forward to the Law Department a copy of each denial.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
							<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80990" number="93447" version="3">
									<HEADING>§ 1-06 Procedures for Appeals.</HEADING>
									<PARA>
										<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10793" name="T43C001_1-06"/>§ 1-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Procedures for Appeals.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80991" number="93448" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The head or governing body of each agency shall hear appeals or shall designate a person or body to hear appeals (an &quot;appeals officer&quot;) from denials of requests by a records access officer. No records access officer shall also serve as an appeals officer.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80992" number="93449" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When a request for inspection has been denied in writing in whole, or in part by a records access officer, the requesting party shall have thirty days after receipt of the denial within which to appeal. An appeal shall be in writing, addressed to the denying agency&apos;s appeals officer, and shall include the name of the records access officer who denied the request, the date of the request, the date of the denial, the records which were the subject of the request and the name and address of the appellant.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80993" number="93450" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each appeals officer shall transmit to the Law Department and the Committee on Open Government, Department of State, 162 Washington Avenue, Albany, N.Y. 12231, copies of all appeals upon their receipt.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80994" number="93451" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Within ten business days from the date of actual receipt of an appeal, the appeals officer shall make a written determination either affirming or reversing the denial and shall transmit copies of his or its determination to the appellant, the Law Department and the Committee on Open Government. Determinations affirming denials shall state the grounds for withholding of the requested records and that judicial review of the denial may be obtained in a proceeding under Article 78 of the Civil Practice Law and Rules commenced within four months after determination of the appeal.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
							<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-80995" number="93452" version="3">
									<HEADING>§ 1-07 Fees.</HEADING>
									<PARA>
										<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10795" name="T43C001_1-07"/>§ 1-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Fees.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80996" number="93453" version="3">
										<PARA>Except when a different fee is otherwise prescribed by law:</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80997" number="93454" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each agency shall charge a fee for copying of records equal to the actual reproduction cost, which is the average unit cost for copying of records, excluding fixed costs of the agency, such as operators&apos; salaries; provided that, in no case shall the fee charged for copying exceed 25 cents per page for photocopies not exceeding 9 by 14 inches in size.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80998" number="93455" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No fee shall be charged for the search for records, the inspection of records or for any certification made pursuant to these Rules and Regulations.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-80999" number="93456" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If an agency does not have operational photocopying equipment, the agency may either arrange for the production of photocopies outside the agency or prepare a transcript of requested records upon request. A transcript prepared by the agency may be either typed or handwritten and the persons requesting the records may be charged for the clerical time involved in making the transcript. Photocopies obtained by agencies which do not have operational photocopying equipment shall be charged to the requesting party at the same rate as that paid by the agency to the person or firm which made the photocopies.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-81000" number="93457" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Payment for copying shall be made by check or money order payable to the City of New York and shall be made upon delivery of the copies to the person requesting them. Where the anticipated fee chargeable under this section exceeds $25, an advance deposit of 25 percent of the anticipated fee or $25, whichever is greater, may be required. Where a requesting party has previously failed to pay a fee under this section, payment of any past-due fees and an advance deposit of the full amount of the anticipated fee may be required.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
							<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-81001" number="93458" version="3">
									<HEADING>§ 1-08 Public Notice; Promulgation of Rules and Regulations by City Agencies.</HEADING>
									<PARA>
										<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10797" name="T43C001_1-08"/>§ 1-08 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Public Notice; Promulgation of Rules and Regulations by City Agencies.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-81002" number="93459" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each agency shall publicize by posting in a conspicuous location:</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-81003" number="93460" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the location or locations where records shall be made available for inspection and copying;</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-81004" number="93461" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the hours during which records may be inspected and copied or the procedures for requesting an appointment to inspect and copy;</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-81005" number="93462" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the procedures for requesting and inspecting records and the procedures and fees for copying;</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-81006" number="93463" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the name, title, business address and telephone number of the designated records access officer or officers; and</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-81007" number="93464" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the procedures for appeals and the name, title and business address of the agency&apos;s appeals officer.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-81008" number="93465" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each agency shall forthwith submit for publication in the City Record notice of the hours when records are available for inspection and copying, the location or locations where records may be inspected and copied, the fees for copying, and the name, title, business address and telephone number of the person(s) designated to serve as records access officer(s) and of the person or body designated to serve as appeals officer. Notice of any change in the above information shall be published as soon as practicable in the City Record.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-81009" number="93466" version="3">
										<PARA>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to the matters required to be published pursuant to subdivision (b) of this section, each agency may, after consultation with the Law Department, promulgate such additional rules and regulations as may be necessary to effectuate the purpose of these Rules and Regulations; provided that any such agency rules and regulations must be consistent with the Freedom of Information Law, the applicable Rules and Regulations of the Committee on Open Government and the Rules and Regulations set forth herein. Such additional rules and regulations may provide where appropriate for the safeguarding of records during inspection and copying.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
							<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-81010" number="93467" version="3">
									<HEADING>§ 1-09 Removal of Records.</HEADING>
									<PARA>
										<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10799" name="T43C001_1-09"/>§ 1-09 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Removal of Records.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-81011" number="93468" version="3">
										<PARA>In no case shall an agency permit removal of agency records from agency premises by a requesting party.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
							<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-81012" number="93469" version="3">
									<HEADING>§ 1-10 Severability.</HEADING>
									<PARA>
										<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-10801" name="T43C001_1-10"/>§ 1-10 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Severability.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
									<RECORD id="0-0-0-81013" number="93470" version="3">
										<PARA>If any provision of these Rules and Regulations or the application thereof to any person or circumstances is adjudged invalid by a court of competent jurisdiction, such determination shall not affect or impair the validity of the other provisions of these Rules and Regulations or the application thereof to other persons and circumstances.</PARA>
									</RECORD>
								</LEVEL>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>