<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-24914" number="28845" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 12: Perchloroethylene Dry Cleaning Facilities</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3417" name="T15C012"/>Chapter 12: Perchloroethylene Dry Cleaning Facilities</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-24915" number="28846" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-01 Applicability.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3419" name="T15C012_12-01"/>§ 12-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Applicability.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24916" number="28847" version="3">
									<PARA>This Rule applies to all new and existing dry cleaning facilities in the City of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-24917" number="28848" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-02 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3421" name="T15C012_12-02"/>§ 12-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24918" number="28849" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the purpose of this Rule, the definitions of the New York City Air Pollution Control Code apply.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24919" number="28850" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For the purpose of this Rule, the following definitions also apply:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24920" number="28851" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Adsorptive cartridge filter.</CHARFORMAT> A replaceable cartridge filter that contains diatomaceous earth or activated clay as the filter medium.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24921" number="28852" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Ancillary equipment.</CHARFORMAT> The equipment used with a dry cleaning machine in a dry cleaning system including, but not limited to, emission control devices, pumps, filters, muck cookers, stills, solvent tanks, solvent containers, water separators, exhaust dampers, diverter valves, interconnecting piping, hoses and ducts.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24922" number="28853" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Articles.</CHARFORMAT> Clothing, garments, textiles, fabrics, leather goods, and the like, that are dry cleaned.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24923" number="28854" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Azeotropic control device.</CHARFORMAT> A dry cleaning control system where the vapor stream from the dry cleaning machine drum is first cooled and condensed to reduce the concentration of perc in the vapor stream, and is then treated with water to further enhance the displacement of perc from the articles when the vapor stream is returned to the machine drum. There is no exhaust to the atmosphere during the drying cycle.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24924" number="28855" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Carbon adsorber.</CHARFORMAT> An air cleaning device that consists of an inlet for exhaust gases from a dry cleaning machine; activated carbon in the form of a fixed bed, cartridge, or canister, as an adsorbent; an outlet for exhaust gases; and a system to regenerate, or reclaim saturated adsorbent.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24925" number="28856" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cartridge filter.</CHARFORMAT> A replaceable cartridge filter that contains one of the following as the filter medium: paper, activated carbon, or paper and activated carbon. A cartridge filter contains no diatomaceous earth or activated clay. Cartridge filters include, but are not limited to: standard filters, split filters, &quot;jumbo&quot; filters, and all carbon polishing filters.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24926" number="28857" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Closed-loop machine.</CHARFORMAT> Dry cleaning equipment in which washing, extraction, and drying are all performed in the same single unit (also known as a dry-to-dry unit) and which recirculates perc-laden vapor through a primary control system (e.g., refrigerated condenser) with no exhaust to the atmosphere during the drying cycle. A closed-loop machine may allow for venting to the ambient air through a local exhaust ventilation system, such as a door fan, after the drying cycle is complete and only while the machine door is open.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24927" number="28858" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Co-located.</CHARFORMAT> Sharing a common wall, floor, or ceiling with a residence or business.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24928" number="28859" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Colorimetric detector tube.</CHARFORMAT> A glass tube (sealed prior to use), containing material impregnated with a chemical that is sensitive to perc and is designed to measure the concentration of perc in air.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24929" number="28860" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(10)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commercial building.</CHARFORMAT> Any building where only commercial business is conducted, such as an office building or strip mall.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24930" number="28861" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(11)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Condenser.</CHARFORMAT> An air cleaning device that removes condensable vapors by a reduction in the temperature of the exhaust gases or, in the case of a surface condenser, by contact of the exhaust gases with structures that are cooled by a circulating cooling fluid.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24931" number="28862" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(12)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Converted machine.</CHARFORMAT> An existing vented machine that has been modified to be a closed-loop machine by eliminating the aeration step, installing a primary control system, and providing for recirculation of the perc-laden vapor with no exhaust to the atmosphere or workroom during the drying cycle. A converted machine may allow for venting to the ambient air through a local exhaust ventilation system, such as a door fan, after the drying cycle is complete and only while the machine door is open.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24932" number="28863" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(13)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cool-down.</CHARFORMAT> The portion of the drying cycle that begins when the heating mechanism deactivates and the refrigerated condenser continues to reduce the temperature of the air recirculating through the drum to reduce the concentration of perc in the drum.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24933" number="28864" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(14)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department.</CHARFORMAT> The New York City Department of Environmental Protection.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24934" number="28865" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(15)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Desorption.</CHARFORMAT> Regeneration or stripping of an activated carbon bed, or any other type of vapor adsorber by removal of the adsorbed solvent using hot air, steam, or other means.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24935" number="28866" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(16)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dip tank.</CHARFORMAT> A separate tank that contains perc and is used for purposes other than dry cleaning (e.g., waterproofing).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24936" number="28867" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(17)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Diverter valve.</CHARFORMAT> A flow control device that prevents room air from passing through a refrigerated condenser when the door of a dry cleaning machine is open.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24937" number="28868" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(18)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Door fan.</CHARFORMAT> A local exhaust ventilation system designed to provide for a minimum 100 fpm inward air velocity into the effective door open area of a dry cleaning machine whenever the door is opened, and where the perc emissions are controlled by a carbon adsorber or equivalent control prior to venting to the outer air.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24938" number="28869" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(19)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Drum.</CHARFORMAT> The rotating cylinder or wheel of the dry cleaning machine that holds the articles being cleaned.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24939" number="28870" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(20)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dry cleaning.</CHARFORMAT> The process used to remove soil, greases, paints and other unwanted substances from articles with the use of perc or non perc.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24940" number="28871" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(21)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dry cleaning control system.</CHARFORMAT> Equipment (e.g., carbon adsorber, refrigerated condenser, azeotropic unit, etc.) or an air cleaning device used to reduce the amount of air pollutant(s) in an air stream prior to discharge to the atmosphere.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24941" number="28872" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(22)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dry cleaning equipment.</CHARFORMAT> Any machine, device, or apparatus used to dry clean articles.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24942" number="28873" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(23)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dry cleaning facility.</CHARFORMAT> A facility with one or more dry cleaning systems.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24943" number="28874" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(24)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dry cleaning system.</CHARFORMAT> All of the following equipment, devices, or apparatus associated with the perc dry cleaning operations, including, but not limited to: dry cleaning equipment; filter or purification systems; waste holding, treatment, or disposal systems; perc supply systems; dip tanks; pumps; gaskets; piping, ducting, fittings, valves, or flanges that convey perc-contaminated air; and dry cleaning control systems.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24944" number="28875" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(25)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Drying cabinet.</CHARFORMAT> A housing in which materials that have been previously dry cleaned in perc are dried instead of being dried by tumbling in a dry cleaning machine.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24945" number="28876" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(26)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Drying cycle.</CHARFORMAT> The operation used to actively remove the perc remaining in the materials after washing and extraction. For closed-loop machines, the heated portion of the cycle is followed by cool-down and may be extended beyond cool-down by the activation of a control system. The drying cycle begins when heating coils are activated and ends when the machine ceases rotation of the drum.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24946" number="28877" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(27)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Drying sensor.</CHARFORMAT> A device that senses when articles being cleaned are relatively dry and automatically controls the drying cycle. Drying sensors include but are not limited to: infrared analyzers, float switches, and resistance probes. The device detects the concentration of synthetic solvents in the drying air or that the liquid solvent recovery rate is at a minimal rate. The drying sensor extends the drying cycle for a minimum time beyond the activation point to ensure dry articles.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24947" number="28878" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(28)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dry-to-dry machine.</CHARFORMAT> A one-machine dry cleaning operation in which drying and washing are performed in the same machine.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24948" number="28879" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(29)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dry-to-dry vented machine.</CHARFORMAT> Dry cleaning equipment in which washing, extraction, and drying are all performed in the same single unit and in which fresh air is introduced into the drum in the last step of the drying cycle and exhausted to the outdoor atmosphere, either directly or through a control device (2nd generation equipment).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24949" number="28880" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(30)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Environmental Training Program.</CHARFORMAT> An initial course or a refresher course of the Environmental Training Program, described in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-14" destination-id="0-0-0-3445">12-14</LINK> and § 232.14 of Title 6 of the Codes, Rules, and Regulations of the State of New York for owners and operators of perc dry cleaning operations that has been authorized by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation or the Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24950" number="28881" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(31)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Equivalent closed-loop vapor recovery system.</CHARFORMAT> A device or combination of devices that achieves, in practice, a perc recovery performance equal to or exceeding that of refrigerated condensers.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24951" number="28882" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(32)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Existing facility.</CHARFORMAT> Any facility at which dry cleaning equipment was installed or operated prior to May 15, 1997.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24952" number="28883" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(33)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Facility.</CHARFORMAT> All emission sources located at one or more adjacent or contiguous properties owned or operated by the same person or persons under common control.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24953" number="28884" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(34)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Filter muck.</CHARFORMAT> The residue from a filter using loose diatomaceous earth, which must be replaced periodically.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24954" number="28885" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(35)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">First generation equipment.</CHARFORMAT> Transfer machines where cleaning and drying (reclaiming) take place in separate machines with the manual transfer of articles from one machine to another.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24955" number="28886" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(36)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Fourth generation equipment.</CHARFORMAT> A primary closed-loop refrigerated dry cleaning machine that has a &quot;secondary control system&quot; (e.g., closed-loop refrigerated condenser with a drying sensor and an integral carbon adsorber).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24956" number="28887" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(37)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Fugitive emissions.</CHARFORMAT> Emissions of air contaminants which could not reasonably pass through a stack, vent, chimney, or other functionally equivalent opening.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24957" number="28888" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(38)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">fpm.</CHARFORMAT> Feet per minute.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24958" number="28889" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(39)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Full-size carbon unit.</CHARFORMAT> A carbon unit that is used to adsorb perc from a dry cleaning machine when the vapors are recirculating or venting from the drum during the drying cycle. (Normally used on first and second generation equipment.)</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24959" number="28890" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(40)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">General exhaust ventilation system.</CHARFORMAT> A mechanical exhaust ventilation system consisting of fresh air makeup inlets and one or more exhaust fans in a dry cleaning facility. This type of system would commonly be used to exhaust a dry cleaning workroom or a room enclosure. This system shall be completely separate from the ventilation system(s) for the remainder of the building.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24960" number="28891" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(41)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Halogenated-hydrocarbon detector.</CHARFORMAT> A portable device capable of detecting vapor concentrations of perc and indicating an increasing concentration by emitting an audible signal or visual indicator that varies as the concentration changes.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24961" number="28892" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(42)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Liquid leak.</CHARFORMAT> A leak of liquid containing perc of more than one drop every three minutes.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24962" number="28893" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(43)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Local exhaust ventilation system.</CHARFORMAT> A mechanical exhaust ventilation system connected directly to a dry cleaning machine or other related dry cleaning equipment. For example, the exhaust system on a door fan for a third generation machine constitutes a local exhaust ventilation system.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24963" number="28894" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(44)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Major source.</CHARFORMAT> A dry cleaning facility that emits or has the potential to emit more than 9.1 megagrams per year (10 tons per year) of perc to the atmosphere. In lieu of measuring a facility&apos;s potential to emit perc or determining a facility&apos;s potential to emit perc, a dry cleaning facility is a major source if: (1) it includes only dry-to-dry machine(s) and has a total yearly perc consumption greater than 8,000 liters (2,100 gallons) as determined according to 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-12" destination-id="0-0-0-3441">12-12</LINK>, subdivision (b); or, (2) it includes only transfer machine system(s) or both dry-to-dry machine(s) and transfer machine system(s) and has a total yearly perc consumption greater than 6,800 liters (1,800 gallons) as determined according to 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-12" destination-id="0-0-0-3441">12-12</LINK>, subdivision (b).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24964" number="28895" version="2297">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(44-a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Material safety data sheet.</CHARFORMAT> The material safety data sheet as defined in § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-702" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-702</LINK> of the Administrative Code of the City of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24965" number="28896" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(45)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Mixed-use facility.</CHARFORMAT> A facility that is co-located.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24966" number="28897" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(46)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Muck cooker.</CHARFORMAT> A device for heating filter muck to drive off perc vapors for reclaiming.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24967" number="28898" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(47)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">New facility.</CHARFORMAT> A facility that was not used for the operation of any dry cleaning equipment prior to May 15, 1997.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24968" number="28899" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(47-a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Non perc.</CHARFORMAT> Any chemical substance used in the dry cleaning process other than perc.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24969" number="28900" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(48)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Occupancy.</CHARFORMAT> Any building or part of a building, excluding the dry cleaning facility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24970" number="28901" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(49)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Openings.</CHARFORMAT> Any window, door or air intake.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24971" number="28902" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(50)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Perceptible leak.</CHARFORMAT> Any perc vapor or liquid leaks that are obvious from the odor of perc, pools or droplets of perc or the detection of gas flow by passing a finger over the surface of the equipment, or as detected by an appropriate portable monitoring instrument.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24972" number="28903" version="1812">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(51)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Perc.</CHARFORMAT> A colorless volatile chlorinated hydrocarbon. Perc is also known as perchloroethylene, tetrachloroethylene, tetrachloroethene, and PCE. The chemical formula for perc is C1<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" point-size="8">
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" point-size="8" baseline="60">2</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" baseline="60">
										</CHARFORMAT>C:CC1<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" point-size="8">
										</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" point-size="8" baseline="60">2</CHARFORMAT>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0" baseline="60">
										</CHARFORMAT>. The CAS registry number for perc is 00127-18-4.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24973" number="28904" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(52)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Perc-contaminated wastewater evaporator.</CHARFORMAT> A device that vaporizes wastewater through physical action or the addition of thermal energy.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24974" number="28905" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(53)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">ppb.</CHARFORMAT> Parts per billion by volume in air or by weight in water.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24975" number="28906" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(54)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">ppm.</CHARFORMAT> Parts per million by volume in air or by weight in water.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24976" number="28907" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(54-a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Primary chemical.</CHARFORMAT> The chemical that is used in the greatest concentration in the dry cleaning process.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24977" number="28908" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(55)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Primary control system.</CHARFORMAT> A refrigerated condenser or equivalent closed-loop vapor recovery system approved by the Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24978" number="28909" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(56)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Process ventilation emission.</CHARFORMAT> An emission from any dry cleaning machine normally vented to the outer air that occurs both during the aeration cycle and when the machine door is open, excluding any emissions from door fans on azeotropic control devices and third generation equipment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24979" number="28910" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(57)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Refrigerated condenser.</CHARFORMAT> A closed-loop vapor recovery system into which perc vapors are condensed by cooling below the dew point of the perc using a mechanical refrigerated system.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24980" number="28911" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(58)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Residential building.</CHARFORMAT> Any dwelling or housing that is owned, rented, or occupied by the same person for a period of 180 days or more in a year, excluding short-term housing such as a motel or hotel room rented and occupied by the same person for a period of less than 180 days.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24981" number="28912" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(59)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Room enclosure.</CHARFORMAT> A room that encloses the dry cleaning machine or equipment. It is constructed of material that is impermeable to perc and designed and operated to maintain negative pressure at all times that the equipment is operating and is used with a general exhaust ventilation system.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24982" number="28913" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(60)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Second generation equipment.</CHARFORMAT> A dry-to-dry vented-dry cleaning machine which is not vented to a refrigerated condenser. Typically these machines are properly vented to a control device which may, for example, consist of a carbon adsorber or azeotropic control device plus a small carbon adsorber.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24983" number="28914" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(61)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Secondary control system.</CHARFORMAT> A device or apparatus that reduces the concentration of perc in the recirculating air at the end of the drying cycle beyond the level achievable with a refrigerated condenser alone. For example, an integral carbon adsorber used in fourth generation equipment constitutes a secondary control system.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24984" number="28915" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An &quot;integral&quot; secondary control system is designed and offered as an integral part of a production package with a single make and model of dry cleaning machine and primary control system.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24985" number="28916" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An &quot;add-on&quot; secondary control system is designed or offered as a separate retrofit system for use on multiple machine makes and models.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24986" number="28917" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(62)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Self-service dry cleaning machine.</CHARFORMAT> A perc dry cleaning machine that is loaded, activated, or unloaded by the customer.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24987" number="28918" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(63)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Small carbon adsorbers.</CHARFORMAT> A carbon unit that is used to adsorb perc from the machine drum when the machine door is opened to remove clothes at the end of the drying cycle. For example, the adsorbers used to control emissions from supplemental door fans or azeotropic control devices would constitute small carbon adsorbers.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24988" number="28919" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(64)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Solvent mileage.</CHARFORMAT> The average weight of articles cleaned per volume of perc used.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24989" number="28920" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(65)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Solvent tank.</CHARFORMAT> Any container that is used to store perc prior to use in the dry cleaning operation and from which the perc is introduced into the drum of the machine at the start of the cleaning cycle.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24990" number="28921" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(66)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Stand-alone facility.</CHARFORMAT> A facility that is not co-located.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24991" number="28922" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(67)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Still.</CHARFORMAT> Distillation equipment used to volatilize and recover perc from contaminated solvent removed from the cleaned materials.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24992" number="28923" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(68)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Third generation equipment.</CHARFORMAT> A closed-loop dry cleaning machine equipped with a refrigerated condenser or other equivalent primary control system.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24993" number="28924" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(69)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Trained operator.</CHARFORMAT> A person who holds a certificate of completion for the initial course of an environmental training program and maintains her/his status by successfully completing refresher courses as required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24994" number="28925" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(70)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Transfer machine.</CHARFORMAT> Perc dry cleaning equipment in which washing and extraction are performed in one unit and drying is performed in a separate unit. (First generation equipment.)</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24995" number="28926" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(71)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Vapor adsorber.</CHARFORMAT> A bed of activated carbon or other adsorbent into which vapors are introduced and trapped for subsequent desorption.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24996" number="28927" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(72)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Vapor barrier.</CHARFORMAT> A material surface or coating that is impermeable to perc.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24997" number="28928" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(73)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Vapor leak.</CHARFORMAT> A fugitive emission of perc vapor from unintended openings in the dry cleaning system. A vapor leak can be indicated by a rapid audible signal or visual signal from a halogenated-hydrocarbon detector or other approved instrument.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-24998" number="28929" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(74)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Water separator.</CHARFORMAT> A vessel that uses gravity to physically separate liquid perc from liquid water.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-24999" number="28930" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-03 Variances.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3423" name="T15C012_12-03"/>§ 12-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Variances.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25000" number="28931" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Unless otherwise precluded by federal or state statute or regulation, or subdivision (d) of this section, the Department may, upon written application from any person who is subject to this Rule, grant a variance from one or more specific provisions of this Rule consistent with § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-110" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-110</LINK> of the Administrative Code of the City of New York and under the conditions set forth in this subchapter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25001" number="28932" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every application for a variance must:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25002" number="28933" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>identify the specific provisions of this Rule from which a variance is sought;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25003" number="28934" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>demonstrate that compliance with the identified provisions would, on the basis of conditions unique to the person&apos;s particular situation in contrast to the rest of the industry or any segment thereof, impose unreasonable hardship;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25004" number="28935" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>demonstrate that the proposed activity will have no significant adverse impact on the public health, safety, or welfare, the environment or natural resources and will be consistent with the provisions of the New York City Air Pollution Control Code and the performance expected from an activity permitted under the provisions of this Rule; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25005" number="28936" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>include a copy of any variance granted by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation. If no variance has been granted by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation then the application to the Department shall state that no variance has been granted by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25006" number="28937" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In granting any variance under this subchapter, the Department may impose specific conditions necessary to assure that the subject activity will have no significant adverse impact on the public health, safety, or welfare, the environment, or natural resources.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25007" number="28938" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Phase-out dates for dry cleaning equipment cannot be extended by a variance.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25008" number="28939" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-04 Prohibitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3425" name="T15C012_12-04"/>§ 12-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Prohibitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25009" number="28940" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Perc dry cleaning machines may not be installed in residential buildings after July 13, 2006.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25010" number="28941" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Perc dry cleaning machines that were installed in residential buildings between December 21, 2005 and July 13, 2006 must eliminate perc use by July 13, 2009. In the interim, all perc dry cleaning facilities must continue to comply with the requirements of 6 NYCRR Part 232.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25011" number="28942" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Perc dry cleaning machines that were installed in residential buildings before December 21, 2005, must eliminate perc use by December 21, 2020.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25012" number="28943" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The use of any dry-to-dry vented or non-vented equipment as a transfer machine is prohibited.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25013" number="28944" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The installation of any self-service dry cleaning machine(s) after May 15, 1997 is prohibited.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25014" number="28945" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The use or offering for use of any self-service dry cleaning machine(s) after May 15, 1997 is prohibited.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25015" number="28946" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The use of immersion heaters to evaporate solvent from the untreated water effluent of solvent water separators is prohibited.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25016" number="28947" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except as provided in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-05" destination-id="0-0-0-3427">12-05</LINK>, the installation, construction, alteration, modification, or operation of a perc dry cleaning facility without first obtaining an installation or alteration permit or an operating certificate issued by the Department in accordance with the requirements of 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-15" destination-id="0-0-0-3447">12-15</LINK> is prohibited.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25017" number="28948" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Venting of perc emissions from dry cleaning equipment or emission control devices into the workroom or facility is prohibited.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25018" number="28949" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-05 Pre-Permitting Requirements for Existing Facilities.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3427" name="T15C012_12-05"/>§ 12-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Pre-Permitting Requirements for Existing Facilities.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25019" number="28950" version="1063">
									<PARA>Existing facilities with a valid operating certificate(s) issued by the Department must comply with the following requirements in accordance with the timeframes established in this section in advance of applying for and obtaining an operating certificate amendment(s) required under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-15" destination-id="0-0-0-3447">12-15</LINK>. Prior approvals from the Department are not needed for construction of room enclosures, vapor barriers, general exhaust ventilation systems, or changes in vent stack locations. New facilities must comply with all the applicable requirements contained in this section at the time of installation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25020" number="28951" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Room enclosures, vapor barriers, and general exhaust ventilation.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25021" number="28952" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Stand-alone dry cleaning facilities that are designated as major sources, pursuant to the National Perchloroethylene Air Emission Standards for Dry Cleaning Facilities under Title 40, Part 63 of the Code of Federal Regulations, Subpart M and that have transfer type machines should have contained all such machines inside room enclosures by September 23, 1996. Each room enclosure must be:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25022" number="28953" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Constructed of materials impermeable to perc; and,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25023" number="28954" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Designed and operated to maintain a negative pressure at each opening at all times that the machine is operating.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25024" number="28955" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Co-located dry cleaning facilities must be equipped with a vapor barrier or room enclosure(s) and general exhaust ventilation that meets the design and performance requirements established in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-06" destination-id="0-0-0-3429">12-06</LINK>, subdivision (a), by the following dates:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25025" number="28956" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>transfer machines – immediately upon the effective date of this Rule.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25026" number="28957" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>dry-to-dry vented machines – by no later than August 15, 1998.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25027" number="28958" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>3rd generation dry-to-dry machines – by no later than November 15, 1998.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25028" number="28959" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>4th generation dry-to-dry machines – by no later than May 15, 1999.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25029" number="28960" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The facility owner shall notify the Department by mail no later than 30 days after the installation of the required vapor barrier and general exhaust ventilation system and certify that it meets all regulatory requirements. Such notification shall be sent by certified mail to the Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25030" number="28961" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Relocation of emission points.</CHARFORMAT> The relocation of process ventilation emission point(s) to the outdoor atmosphere must comply with the retrofitting requirements and be completed by the deadlines established under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-06" destination-id="0-0-0-3429">12-06</LINK>(b)(3) and (b)(6).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25031" number="28962" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Public information notice.</CHARFORMAT> The facility owner must post a copy of the notice required under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-18" destination-id="0-0-0-3453">12-18</LINK> immediately.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25032" number="28963" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Leak inspection.</CHARFORMAT> The facility owner must initiate the leak inspection requirements established in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-07" destination-id="0-0-0-3431">12-07</LINK> immediately upon the effective date of this Rule.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25033" number="28964" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Operation and maintenance.</CHARFORMAT> The facility owner must initiate all operation and maintenance requirements which apply to dry cleaning machines and existing emission control systems established in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-08" destination-id="0-0-0-3433">12-08</LINK> immediately upon the effective date of this Rule. However, all requirements established under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-08" destination-id="0-0-0-3433">12-08</LINK> that are already in effect pursuant to the National Perchloroethylene Air Emission Standards for Dry Cleaning Facilities in Title 40, Part 63, Subpart M of the Code of Federal Regulations continue to be in effect.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25034" number="28965" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Compliance inspections.</CHARFORMAT> The compliance inspection requirements under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-16" destination-id="0-0-0-3449">12-16</LINK> are effective immediately upon the effective date of this Rule. Facility owners must initiate the first compliance inspection at their facility immediately upon the effective date of this Rule.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25035" number="28966" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Recordkeeping.</CHARFORMAT> The facility owner must initiate all applicable recordkeeping required under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-12" destination-id="0-0-0-3441">12-12</LINK> immediately upon the effective date of this Rule. Such recordkeeping must cover all requirements established under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-12" destination-id="0-0-0-3441">12-12</LINK> for dry cleaning systems and facilities in general and must also comply with requirements for specific dry cleaning machine types and emission control systems. However, all requirements established under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-12" destination-id="0-0-0-3441">12-12</LINK> that are already in effect pursuant to the National Perchloroethylene Air Emission Standards for Dry Cleaning Facilities in Title 40, Part 63, Subpart M of the Code of Federal Regulations, continue to be in effect.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25036" number="28967" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Perc-contaminated wastewater management.</CHARFORMAT> Facilities must comply with the perc-contaminated wastewater management requirements under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-09" destination-id="0-0-0-3435">12-09</LINK> and under 15 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C019" destination-id="0-0-0-3685">Chapter 19</LINK> governing the use of the public sewer system by no later than May 15, 1998.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25037" number="28968" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hazardous waste management and emergency response.</CHARFORMAT> The hazardous waste management requirements under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-10" destination-id="0-0-0-3437">12-10</LINK> and the emergency response requirements under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-11" destination-id="0-0-0-3439">12-11</LINK> are effective immediately upon the effective date of this Rule.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25038" number="28969" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-06 Equipment Standards and Specifications.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3429" name="T15C012_12-06"/>§ 12-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Equipment Standards and Specifications.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25039" number="28970" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Specific equipment standards and emission control specifications:</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25040" number="28971" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Vapor barriers.</CHARFORMAT> Vapor barriers must, at a minimum, enclose the dry cleaning equipment. Vapor barriers can be constructed of polyvinyl chloride, PVC sheet 22 mil thick (0.022 in.), sheet metal, metal foil face composite board, or other equivalent materials that are impermeable to perc vapors. Vapor barriers must be constructed so that all joints and seams are sealed except for inlet makeup air and exhaust openings and entry doors. Entry doors may only be open when a person is entering or exiting the room enclosure.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25041" number="28972" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">General exhaust ventilation system.</CHARFORMAT> Dry cleaning facilities which are co-located must be equipped with a vapor barrier and with a general exhaust ventilation system that is completely separate from the ventilation system(s) serving other areas of the building. The general exhaust ventilation system must be located near the dry cleaning machinery or connected to a separate room enclosure with a vapor barrier exhausting emissions to the outer air. The system shall be designed and operated to maintain a negative pressure in the room enclosure whenever the dry cleaning machine(s) is operating. This dry cleaning general exhaust ventilation system must be operated at all times when the dry cleaning machine(s) is in operation, and during maintenance operations and must be capable of at least one air change per five minutes.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25042" number="28973" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Door fan/local exhaust ventilation systems.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25043" number="28974" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All first, second and third generation dry cleaning equipment must be equipped with a door fan/local exhaust ventilation system. This system must include a mechanical exhaust fan that is activated when the loading door is open, drawing air from the machine drum causing fresh air to be drawn in through the loading door. A minimum inward air velocity of 100 fpm, must be maintained through the effective door opening area of the loading door of the machine.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25044" number="28975" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Door fan/local exhaust ventilation systems must not recirculate vapors into the workroom and must be properly vented to the outer air.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25045" number="28976" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Door fan/local exhaust ventilation emissions must be controlled to a design emission standard of five ppm perc with an in-use maximum compliance standard of 20 ppm.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25046" number="28977" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Process Ventilation Emissions – Interim Standards.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25047" number="28978" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Process ventilation emission points on first and second generation machines that exhaust during the aeration cycle and when the machine door is open must be vented to the outer air above the roof and more than 25 feet from all openings in nearby occupancies.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25048" number="28979" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Process ventilation emissions from existing first and second generation vented machines having emission controls as part of the original equipment or retrofitted to comply with the 100 ppm perc emission standard effective May 10, 1981 under the repealed version of Title 6, Part 232 of Codes, Rules, and Regulations of the State of New York must continue to meet this standard until such time as retrofitting, replacement, or shutdown is required under this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25049" number="28980" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Process ventilation emissions from existing second generation machines that are retrofitted with control equipment to comply with interim standards established under (b)(3) or (b)(6) in this section must be designed to achieve a perc concentration of five ppm or less in the exhaust and achieve an in-use compliance standard of less than 20 ppm perc in the exhaust.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25050" number="28981" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The exhaust damper of a vented first or second generation machine must be completely closed when the machine is not being vented, and must not leak vapors into the workroom or the outer air.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25051" number="28982" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Primary emission control systems.</CHARFORMAT> Refrigerated condensers or equivalent closed-loop vapor recovery systems must meet the following requirements:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25052" number="28983" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Refrigerated condensers must be capable of achieving an outlet vapor temperature downstream of any by-pass of the condenser less than or equal to 45°F (7.2°C) during the final cool down cycle, and achieve a concentration of 8600 ppm or less perc in the drum upon completion of the drying cycle.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25053" number="28984" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Refrigerated condensers must have a graduated thermometer, thermocouple or equivalent instrument with a minimum range from 0°F (-18°C) to 150°F (66°C), that measures the temperature of the outlet vapor stream downstream of any by-pass of the condenser, and is easily visible to the operator.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25054" number="28985" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>New third and fourth generation equipment with refrigerated condenser control systems must be equipped with a drying sensor/controller that extends the drying time at least four minutes beyond the point that the solvent recovery rate is less than 40 ml/min or solvent vapor concentration in the drum is less than 8600 ppm perc.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25055" number="28986" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The refrigerated condenser must be operated with a diverter valve.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25056" number="28987" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Equivalent closed-loop vapor recovery systems or other control device must use a technology that has been demonstrated, pursuant to the requirements of 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-17" destination-id="0-0-0-3451">12-17</LINK>, to achieve at least 90 percent by weight emission reduction based upon the amount of perc entering and leaving the control device.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25057" number="28988" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A secondary control system must:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25058" number="28989" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>be designed to function with a primary control system complying with all requirements for third generation equipment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25059" number="28990" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>be capable of reducing the perc concentration in the drum from 8600 ppm or greater to 300 ppm.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25060" number="28991" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any integral carbon adsorber used as a secondary control system must be sized correctly for the machine and be capable of reducing the perc concentration in the drum from 8,600 ppm or greater to 300 ppm or less.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25061" number="28992" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The integral carbon adsorber must be designed for non-contact steam or hot air stripping operation, and must be stripped or desorbed in accordance with manufacturer&apos;s instructions or at least weekly, whichever is more stringent.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25062" number="28993" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Spill containment.</CHARFORMAT> All new third and fourth generation, or used, reinstalled dry cleaning equipment must be equipped with a spill containment system capable of containing 125 percent of the capacity of the largest dry cleaning perc tank or vessel associated with the dry cleaning machine.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25063" number="28994" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>To determine which standards will apply to a particular dry cleaning facility, first determine whether the facility is new or existing. Then determine whether the facility is a stand-alone or is co-located. If co-located, determine whether it is in a commercial or residential building. Finally, for each piece of equipment there are two primary issues addressed by this Rule – the type of emissions control and the location of any process ventilation emission points. Process ventilation emissions apply only to transfer and dry-to-dry vented equipment, not to door fans, general or other ventilation. In all, there are six different categories for which equipment standards are provided as follows: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25064" number="28995" version="2499">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>New stand-alone facilities – Equipment requirements </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25065" number="28996" version="2499">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Existing stand-alone facilities – Replacement or addition of equipment </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25066" number="28997" version="2499">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Existing stand-alone facilities – Retrofitting of equipment </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25067" number="28998" version="2499">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>New mixed-use facilities – New equipment </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25068" number="28999" version="2499">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Existing mixed-use facilities – Replacement or addition of equipment </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25069" number="29000" version="2499">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Existing mixed-use facilities – Retrofitting of equipment</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25070" number="29001" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">New stand-alone facilities – equipment requirements.</CHARFORMAT> The following types of new and/or used equipment are allowed in new stand-alone facilities.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25071" number="29002" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">New equipment – Fourth generation.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25072" number="29003" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vapor barrier – Not Required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25073" number="29004" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Spill containment – Required as specified in paragraph (a)(7) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25074" number="29005" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>General exhaust ventilation system – Optional.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25075" number="29006" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(D)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Primary and secondary control systems, and drying sensor – Required as specified in paragraphs (a)(5) and (6) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25076" number="29007" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(E)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Fugitive perc emissions from any part of the dry cleaning system must not exceed 50 ppm at any time.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25077" number="29008" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">New equipment – Third generation.</CHARFORMAT> The installation of this type of equipment is prohibited after December 31, 1999.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25078" number="29009" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vapor barrier – Not Required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25079" number="29010" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Spill containment – Required as specified in paragraph (a)(7) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25080" number="29011" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>General exhaust ventilation system – Optional.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25081" number="29012" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(D)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Primary control system, drying sensor, and door fan – Required as specified in paragraph (a)(3) and (5) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25082" number="29013" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(E)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Fugitive perc emissions from any part of the dry cleaning system must not exceed 50 ppm at any time.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25083" number="29014" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(F)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An additional option would be to convert to a fourth generation machine with less than or equal to 300 ppm in drum. Under this option a door fan would not be required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25084" number="29015" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Used equipment – Third generation.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25085" number="29016" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vapor barrier – Not Required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25086" number="29017" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Spill containment – Required as specified in paragraph (a)(7) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25087" number="29018" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>General exhaust ventilation system – Optional.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25088" number="29019" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(D)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Primary control system and door fan – Required as specified in paragraphs (a)(3) and (5) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25089" number="29020" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(E)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Fugitive perc emissions from any part of the dry cleaning system must not exceed 50 ppm perc at any time.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25090" number="29021" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(F)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An additional option would be to convert to a fourth generation machine with less than or equal to 300 ppm perc in the drum. Under this option a door fan would not be required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25091" number="29022" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Existing stand-alone facilities – replacement or addition of equipment.</CHARFORMAT> The equipment standards for new stand-alone facilities must be followed. However, transfer machines may be replaced with upgraded dry-to-dry vented equipment in accordance with the retrofitting requirements.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25092" number="29023" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Existing stand-alone facilities – retrofitting of equipment.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25093" number="29024" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Transfer machines – no retrofitting is allowed.</CHARFORMAT> All transfer machines must be removed from service on the following schedule.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25094" number="29025" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the process ventilation emission point is located above the roof and more than 25 feet from all openings in nearby occupancies, and if previously retrofitted to meet the less than 100 ppm perc vented emission level (see subparagraph (a)(4)(ii) of this section) and is operating in compliance with that emission level, the equipment must be replaced with third or fourth generation equipment by January 1, 2000.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25095" number="29026" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the process ventilation emission point is located below the roof or less than 25 feet from any opening in a nearby occupancy, or if process ventilation emissions do not meet the 100 ppm perc emission level, the equipment must be replaced with third or fourth generation equipment immediately upon the effective date of this Rule.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25096" number="29027" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vapor barrier – not required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25097" number="29028" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(D)<TAB tab-count="1"/>General exhaust ventilation system – Optional.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25098" number="29029" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dry-to-dry vented – Second generation.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25099" number="29030" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vapor barrier – Not required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25100" number="29031" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>General exhaust ventilation system – Optional.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25101" number="29032" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Process ventilation emission point location – </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25102" number="29033" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>If the process ventilation emission point is above the roof and more than 25 feet from all openings in nearby occupancies, the relocation of the process ventilation emission point is not required. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25103" number="29034" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>If the process ventilation emission point is below the roof or less than 25 feet from any opening in a nearby occupancy, the process ventilation emission point must be changed to be over the roof and more than 25 feet from all openings in nearby occupancies immediately upon the effective date of this Rule. Alternatively, the equipment may be replaced with third or fourth generation equipment within the same time limit.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25104" number="29035" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(D)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Emission controls.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25105" number="29036" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Controlled.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25106" number="29037" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>If the machine has been controlled with either an azeotropic control device plus small carbon adsorber or converted to a closed-loop third generation machine having an integral or external primary refrigerated condenser (the water cooled condensing system having been eliminated) and has a door fan, meeting the requirements of paragraph (a)(3) of this section, no additional control is required. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25107" number="29038" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>If the machine is equipped with either a full sized carbon adsorber or a refrigerated condenser with a water cooled condensing system, it must be retrofitted with either an azeotropic control device plus small carbon adsorber (provided EPA publishes a determination that an azeotropic control device is equivalent to a refrigerated condenser), or converted to a closed-loop third generation machine by adding an integral or external primary refrigerated condenser (eliminating the water cooled condensing system) and a door fan with a small carbon adsorber by December 31, 1999. Alternatively, the equipment may be replaced with a third generation machine with a door fan by December 31, 1999, or with a fourth generation by January 1, 2001. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25108" number="29039" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Uncontrolled.</CHARFORMAT> Equipment must be retrofitted with either an azeotropic control device plus small carbon adsorber (provided EPA publishes a determination that an azeotropic control device is equivalent to a refrigerated condenser), or converted to closed-loop third generation by adding an integral or external primary refrigerated condenser (eliminating the water cooled condensing system) and a door fan with a small carbon adsorber immediately upon the effective date of this Rule. Alternatively, equipment may be replaced with third or fourth generation equipment within the same time limit.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25109" number="29040" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(E)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Fugitive perc emissions from any part of the dry cleaning system must not exceed 50 ppm at any time.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25110" number="29041" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dry-to-dry non-vented. Third generation.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25111" number="29042" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vapor barrier – Not Required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25112" number="29043" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>General exhaust ventilation system – Optional.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25113" number="29044" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Equipment must be retrofitted with a door fan meeting the requirement of paragraph (a)(3) of this section by no later than May 15, 2001; or,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25114" number="29045" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(D)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An additional option would be to convert this type of equipment to a fourth generation machine that achieves a perc concentration of less than or equal to 300 ppm in the drum by no later than May 15, 2001. Under this option a door fan would not be required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25115" number="29046" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(E)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Fugitive perc emissions from any part of the dry cleaning system must not exceed 50 ppm at any time.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25116" number="29047" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dry-to-dry non-vented. Fourth generation.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25117" number="29048" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vapor barrier – Not Required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25118" number="29049" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>General exhaust ventilation system – Optional.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25119" number="29050" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Primary and secondary control system and drying sensors must meet requirements specified in paragraphs (a)(5) and (6) of this section. However, for non-major facilities that purchased machines prior to May 15, 1997 the following provision applies: If the owner/manager or operator can demonstrate that the machine is operating in the best possible working condition, no action is required if the measured perc concentration in the drum is less than 500 ppm. If the level exceeds 500 ppm, a door fan that meets the requirements of paragraph (a)(3) of this section must be installed by January 1, 2000.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25120" number="29051" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(D)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Fugitive perc emissions from any part of the dry cleaning system must not exceed 50 ppm at any time.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25121" number="29052" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">New mixed-use facilities – new equipment.</CHARFORMAT> Only new dry-to-dry fourth generation equipment is allowed in new mixed-use facilities. No used or retrofitted equipment is allowed.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25122" number="29053" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Vapor barrier and general exhaust ventilation system.</CHARFORMAT> Required as specified in paragraphs (a)(1) and (2) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25123" number="29054" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Spill containment.</CHARFORMAT> Required as specified in paragraph (a)(7) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25124" number="29055" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Primary and secondary control systems and drying sensor.</CHARFORMAT> Required as specified in paragraphs (a)(5) and (6) of this section. Note: Any machine not meeting the 300 ppm requirement, and, where the owner/manager or operator can demonstrate that the machine is operating in the best possible working condition must have a door fan installed that meets the requirements of paragraph (a)(3) of this section within six months of an inspection indicating high ppm levels.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25125" number="29056" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Fugitive perc emissions from any part of the dry cleaning system must not exceed 50 ppm at any time.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25126" number="29057" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Existing mixed-use facilities – replacement or addition of equipment.</CHARFORMAT> The equipment standards for new mixed-use facilities must be followed.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25127" number="29058" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Existing mixed-use facilities – retrofitting of equipment.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25128" number="29059" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Transfer machines.</CHARFORMAT> No emission control retrofitting is allowed. All transfer machines must be removed from service on the following schedule.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25129" number="29060" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the process ventilation emission point is located above the roof and more than 25 feet from all openings in nearby occupancies, and if the equipment has been previously retrofitted to comply with the less than 100 ppm perc vented emission level (see subparagraph (a)(4)(ii) of this section) and is operating in compliance with that emission level, the equipment must be removed from service by September 22, 1998.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25130" number="29061" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the process ventilation emission point is located at or below the roof or is 25 feet or less from all openings in nearby occupancies, or if the equipment has not previously been retrofitted or is not in compliance with the less than 100 ppm perc emission level (see subparagraph (a)(4)(ii) of this section), the equipment must be removed from service immediately upon the effective date of this Rule.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25131" number="29062" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A vapor barrier and general exhaust ventilation system are required immediately upon the effective date of this Rule as specified in paragraphs (a)(1) and (2) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25132" number="29063" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dry-to-dry vented. Second generation.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25133" number="29064" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vapor barrier and general exhaust ventilation system. Required immediately upon the effective date of this Rule as specified in paragraphs (a)(1) and (2) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25134" number="29065" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Process vent emission location. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25135" number="29066" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>If the process ventilation emission point is above the roof and more than 25 feet from all openings in nearby occupancies, the relocation of the process ventilation emission point is not required. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25136" number="29067" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>If the process ventilation emission point is at or below the roof or 25 feet or less from any opening in a nearby occupancy, the process ventilation emission point must be changed to be over the roof and more than 25 feet from all openings in nearby occupancies immediately upon the effective date of this Rule. Alternatively, equipment may be replaced with fourth generation equipment within the same time limit.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25137" number="29068" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Emission Controls. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25138" number="29069" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Mixed-use – commercial – uncontrolled.</CHARFORMAT> Equipment must be retrofitted with either an azeotropic control device plus a small carbon adsorber (provided EPA publishes a determination that an azeotropic control device is equivalent to a refrigerated condenser), or converted to a closed-loop third generation machine by adding an integral or external primary refrigerated condenser (eliminating the water cooled condensing system) and a door fan as specified in paragraph (a)(3) of this section immediately upon the effective date of this Rule. Alternatively, equipment may be replaced with fourth generation equipment within the same time limit. The retrofit of this equipment is only an interim measure, and all retrofitted equipment of this type must be removed from service by January 1, 2005. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25139" number="29070" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Mixed-use – commercial – controlled. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25140" number="29071" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>If the machine has been controlled with either an azeotropic control device plus small carbon adsorber or converted to a third generation machine having an integral or external primary refrigerated condenser (the water cooled condensing system having been eliminated) and has a door fan as specified in paragraph (a)(3) of this section, no interim retrofitting action is required. This equipment must be removed from service and replaced with fourth generation equipment by January 1, 2005. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25141" number="29072" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>If the machine is equipped with either a full-sized carbon adsorber or a refrigerated condenser with a water cooled condensing system, it must be retrofitted with either an azeotropic control device plus small carbon adsorber (provided EPA publishes a determination that an azeotropic control device is equivalent to a refrigerated condenser), or converted to a third generation machine by adding an integral or external primary refrigerated condenser (eliminating the water cooled condensing system) and a door fan as specified in paragraph (a)(3) of this section by January 1, 2001. Alternatively, equipment may be replaced with fourth generation equipment by January 1, 2001. The retrofit of this equipment is an interim measure only and all retrofitted equipment must be replaced with fourth generation equipment by January 1, 2005. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25142" number="29073" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Mixed-use – residential – uncontrolled.</CHARFORMAT> Equipment must be retrofitted with either an azeotropic control device plus small carbon adsorber (provided EPA publishes a determination that an azeotropic control device is equivalent to a refrigerated condenser), or converted to third generation equipment by adding an integral or external primary refrigerated condenser (eliminating the water cooled condensing system) and a door fan as specified in paragraph (b)(3) of this section immediately upon the effective date of this Rule. Alternatively, the equipment must be replaced with fourth generation equipment within the same time limit. The retrofit of this equipment is only an interim measure and all retrofitted equipment of this type must be removed from service by January 1, 2000. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25143" number="29074" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Mixed-use – residential – controlled. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25144" number="29075" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>If the machine has been controlled with either an azeotropic control device plus a small carbon adsorber or has been converted to a third generation machine having an integral or external primary refrigerated condenser (the water cooled system having been eliminated) and has a door fan as specified in paragraph (b)(3) of this section, no additional retrofitting is required. However, all equipment of this type must be replaced with fourth generation equipment by January 1, 2000. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25145" number="29076" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>If the machine is equipped with a full-sized carbon adsorber with a water cooled condensing system, it must be operated in compliance with the 100 ppm standards of the previous version of Part 232 of Title 6 of the Codes, Rules, and Regulations of the State of New York and must be replaced with fourth generation equipment by January 1, 2000.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25146" number="29077" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(D)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Fugitive perc emissions from any part of the dry cleaning system must not exceed 50 ppm at any time.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25147" number="29078" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dry-to-dry non-vented. Third generation.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25148" number="29079" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vapor barrier and general exhaust ventilation system. Required by no later than November 15, 1998 as specified in paragraphs (a)(1) and (2) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25149" number="29080" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Equipment must be retrofitted with a door fan meeting the requirements of paragraph (a)(3) of this section by no later than May 15, 2001; or,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25150" number="29081" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An additional option is to convert this piece of equipment to a fourth generation machine that achieves a perc concentration of less than or equal to 300 ppm in the machine drum by no later than May 15, 2001. Under this option a door fan would not be required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25151" number="29082" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(D)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Fugitive perc emissions from any part of the dry cleaning system must not exceed 50 ppm at any time.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25152" number="29083" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Dry-to-dry non-vented. Fourth generation.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25153" number="29084" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vapor barrier and general exhaust ventilation system. Required by no later than May 15, 1999 as specified in paragraphs (a)(1) and (2) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25154" number="29085" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Primary and secondary controls and drying sensor. Required as specified in paragraphs (a)(5) and (6) of this section. However, for non-major facilities that purchased machines prior to May 15, 1997 the following provision applies: If the owner/manager or operator can demonstrate that the machine is operating in the best possible working condition, no action is required if the measured perc concentration in the drum is less than 500 ppm. If the level exceeds 500 ppm, a door fan as specified in paragraph (a)(3) of this section is required.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25155" number="29086" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Fugitive perc emissions from any part of the dry cleaning system must not exceed 50 ppm at any time.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25156" number="29087" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-07 Leak Inspections and Self Monitoring Requirements.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3431" name="T15C012_12-07"/>§ 12-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Leak Inspections and Self Monitoring Requirements.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25157" number="29088" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Leak check requirements.</CHARFORMAT> The trained operator, must inspect the dry cleaning system for perceptible liquid and vapor leaks and other fugitive emissions. The trained operator, or a designee, must record the status of each component on a checklist supplied by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation. Completed checklists must be kept for at least five years from the date of the inspection.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25158" number="29089" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The dry cleaning system must be thoroughly inspected, at least weekly, for vapor leaks using one of the following devices or methods for detecting vapor leaks:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25159" number="29090" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a halogenated-hydrocarbon detector;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25160" number="29091" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a portable gas analyzer;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25161" number="29092" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>an air sampling pump and colorimetric tube; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25162" number="29093" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>an alternative method approved by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25163" number="29094" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>all equipment referenced in paragraph (a)(1) of this section must be properly calibrated.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25164" number="29095" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The following components of the dry cleaning system must be inspected weekly for perceptible liquid and vapor leaks and for proper operation as required by 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-08" destination-id="0-0-0-3433">12-08</LINK> (operation and maintenance requirements) while the dry cleaning system is operating:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25165" number="29096" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>hose and pipe connections, fittings, couplings and valves;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25166" number="29097" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>door gaskets and seatings;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25167" number="29098" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>filter gaskets and seatings;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25168" number="29099" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>pumps;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25169" number="29100" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>solvent (including spent solvent) tanks and containers;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25170" number="29101" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>water separators;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25171" number="29102" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>muck cookers;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25172" number="29103" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>stills;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25173" number="29104" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9)<TAB tab-count="1"/>exhaust dampers;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25174" number="29105" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(10)<TAB tab-count="1"/>diverter valves; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25175" number="29106" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(11)<TAB tab-count="1"/>cartridge filter housings.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25176" number="29107" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Carbon adsorber vents must be tested weekly using colorimetric detector tubes or portable halogen detectors and the test results must be noted on the checklist.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25177" number="29108" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The temperature of the vapor stream on the inlet and outlet side of a refrigerated condenser must be measured weekly and recorded on the checklist.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25178" number="29109" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Preparedness and prevention equipment and conditions as required in paragraph (d)(7) of 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-08" destination-id="0-0-0-3433">12-08</LINK> must be inspected weekly to ensure proper operation and maintenance. A notation must be made on the checklist at the time of inspection.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25179" number="29110" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The inward air velocity for a loading door fan must be checked weekly with a portable velometer or equivalent measurement instrument. A notation of the instrument reading must be made on the checklist.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25180" number="29111" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any liquid leak, vapor leak, or malfunction that has been detected by the operator must be noted on the checklist and, if at all possible, repaired immediately. If the leak cannot be repaired at the time of detection, the leaking component must be physically marked or tagged in a manner that is readily observable by an inspector and must be repaired within 24 hours of detection, unless repair parts are unavailable.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25181" number="29112" version="2455">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If repair parts are not available at the facility, the parts must be ordered within two working days of detecting such a leak. Such repair parts must be installed within five working days after receipt. Equipment with a leak that has been repaired by the end of the 15th working day after detection must not be operated until the leak is repaired, unless the facility owner or operator receives a leak-repair extension from the Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25182" number="29113" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Department may grant a leak-repair extension to a facility owner for a single period of thirty days or less. Any person applying to the Department for a leak-repair extension shall include a copy of a leak-repair extension granted by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation. If no leak-repair extension has been granted by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation, then the application to the Department shall state that no leak-repair extension has been granted by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation. A leak-repair extension may be granted only if the Department makes the following findings:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25183" number="29114" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the delay in repairing the leak could not have been avoided by action on the part of the facility owner or operator;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25184" number="29115" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the facility owner and operator used reasonable preventive measures and acted promptly to initiate the repair;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25185" number="29116" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the leak will not significantly increase perc exposure near the facility; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25186" number="29117" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the facility is in compliance with all other requirements of this section and has a history of compliance.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25187" number="29118" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Once a repair is completed, the completion date must be recorded on the checklist.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25188" number="29119" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where a hazard is imminent or has already occurred, remedial action must be taken immediately.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25189" number="29120" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All uncontainable releases, fires or explosions must be reported to the Department and appropriate emergency response agencies immediately.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25190" number="29121" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A fugitive emission concentration of 50 ppm of perc emanating from any part of the dry cleaning system is a violation; except for short-term maintenance operations involving the opening of dry cleaning system components for inspection or repair.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25191" number="29122" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any exceedance of the leak inspection requirements of this Rule that has been detected by the operator must be noted on the checklist and repaired/adjusted immediately.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25192" number="29123" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-08 Operation and Maintenance Requirements.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3433" name="T15C012_12-08"/>§ 12-08 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Operation and Maintenance Requirements.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25193" number="29124" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Dry cleaning facilities must be maintained and operated to minimize the release of perc to the environment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25194" number="29125" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The operator must operate and maintain all components of the dry cleaning system in accordance with the requirements of this Rule and the conditions specified in a facility&apos;s operating permit. For operations not specifically addressed, the components must be operated and maintained in accordance with the manufacturer&apos;s recommendations. The facility operator must retain, on-site, a copy of the design specifications and the operating manuals for each dry cleaning system and each emission control device located at the dry cleaning facility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25195" number="29126" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each operation and maintenance function and the date performed must be recorded on a checklist supplied by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation. Completed checklists must be maintained on-site for at least five years from the date of the checklist.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25196" number="29127" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Operators must comply with the following operation and maintenance requirements, as applicable:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25197" number="29128" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Fourth generation machines.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25198" number="29129" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Refrigerated condensers must be operated in accordance with manufacturer&apos;s specifications.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25199" number="29130" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Integral refrigerated condensers must be operated to ensure that exhaust gases are recirculated until the air-vapor stream temperature is 45°F or less at the outlet. The difference between the temperature of the air-perc gas vapor stream entering and exiting the refrigerated condenser must be greater than or equal to 20°F (11.1°C). The temperature differential must be determined at least weekly with a thermometer with a temperature range of from 32°F (0°C) to 120°F (48.9°C) to an accuracy of ±2°F (1.1°C) (see 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-07" destination-id="0-0-0-3431">12-07</LINK>).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25200" number="29131" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vapor adsorbers used with a primary control system or secondary control system must be operated to ensure that exhaust gases are recirculated at the temperature specified for optimum adsorption.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25201" number="29132" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Cartridge filters and adsorptive cartridge filters must be handled using one of the following methods:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25202" number="29133" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Drained in the filter housing, before disposal, for no less than 24 hours for cartridge filters and 48 hours for adsorptive cartridge filters. If the filters are then transferred to a separate device to further reduce the volume of perc, this treatment must be done in a system that routes any vapor to a primary closed-loop control system, with no exhaust to the atmosphere. In performing such a transfer the filter housing must be closed as soon as possible to minimize vapor leaks. The general exhaust ventilation system must be operated during this activity.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25203" number="29134" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Dried, stripped, sparged, or otherwise treated, within the sealed filter housing, to reduce the volume of perc contained in the filter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25204" number="29135" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All steam and condensing coils must be maintained to be free of lint and hard lint build-up on interior surfaces.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25205" number="29136" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vi)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For dry cleaning equipment equipped with a door fan the operator must use a portable velometer or equivalent measurement instrument to verify that the required 100 fpm inward air velocity is maintained through the effective door opening when the loading door is open. The inward air velocity must be checked on a weekly basis.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25206" number="29137" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Test carbon absorber exhaust vents daily using colorimetric detector tubes or portable gas detectors. These absorbers shall be stripped periodically and maintained so that the perc concentration in the exhaust air does not exceed 20 ppm.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25207" number="29138" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Third Generation Machines.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25208" number="29139" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Refrigerated condensers must be operated in accordance with manufacturer&apos;s specifications.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25209" number="29140" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Integral and external refrigerated condensers must be operated to ensure that exhaust gases are recirculated until the air-vapor stream temperature is 45°F or less at the outlet. The difference between the temperature of the air-perc gas vapor stream entering and exiting the refrigerated condenser must be greater than or equal to 20°F (11.1°C). The temperature differential must be determined at least weekly with a thermometer with a temperature range of from 32°F (0°C) to 120°F (48.9°C) to an accuracy of ±2°F (1.1°C) (see 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-07" destination-id="0-0-0-3431">12-07</LINK>).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25210" number="29141" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Vapor adsorbers used when the machine has been retrofitted as a fourth generation machine must be operated to ensure that exhaust gases are recirculated at the temperature specified by the manufacturer for optimum adsorption.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25211" number="29142" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Cartridge filters and adsorptive cartridge filters must be handled using one of the following methods:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25212" number="29143" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Drained in the filter housing, before disposal, for no less than: 24 hours for cartridge filters and 48 hours for adsorptive cartridge filters. If the filters are then transferred to a separate device to further reduce the volume of perc, this treatment must be done in a system that routes any vapor to a primary closed-loop control system, with no exhaust to the atmosphere. In performing such a transfer the filter housing must be closed as soon as possible to minimize vapor leaks. The general exhaust ventilation system must be operated during this activity.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25213" number="29144" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Dried, stripped, sparged, or otherwise treated, within the sealed filter housing, to reduce the volume of perc contained in the filter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25214" number="29145" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All steam and condensing coils must be maintained to be free of lint and hard lint build-up on interior surfaces.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25215" number="29146" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vi)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For dry cleaning equipment equipped with a door fan, the operator must use a portable velometer or equivalent measurement instrument to verify that the required 100 fpm inward air velocity is maintained through the effective door opening when the loading door is open. The inward air velocity must be checked on a weekly basis.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25216" number="29147" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Test carbon absorber exhaust vents daily using colorimetric detector tubes or portable gas detectors. These absorbers shall be stripped periodically and maintained so that the perc concentration in the exhaust air does not exceed 20 ppm.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25217" number="29148" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Second Generation Machines.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25218" number="29149" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A vented machine operated with full-sized carbon adsorbers (dry-to-dry vented) that function during the drying cycle must meet the following requirements:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25219" number="29150" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Desorption must be performed at the frequency specified by the manufacturer or as specified by this clause, whichever is more stringent. The minimum frequency for desorption of full-size carbon units is as follows, each time all dry cleaning equipment exhausted to the device has cleaned a total of three pounds of articles for each pound of activated carbon. Desorption must be performed with the minimum steam pressure and air flow capacity specified by the manufacturer.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25220" number="29151" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Once desorption is complete, the carbon bed must be fully dried according to the manufacturer&apos;s instructions.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25221" number="29152" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No perc vapors may bypass the carbon adsorber to the outdoor atmosphere at any time, nor be recirculated into the facility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25222" number="29153" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(D)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The filter located in front of the carbon adsorber must be checked and cleaned weekly.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25223" number="29154" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(E)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For dry cleaning equipment in mixed-use settings, the carbon adsorber vent must be tested weekly using colorimetric detector tubes. Test results must be recorded on the checklist. Test results of five ppm or greater of perc will require an immediate stripping of the carbon adsorber.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25224" number="29155" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Small external carbon adsorbers used for azeotropic control systems, must be stripped at least weekly when in use. If not in continuous daily use, adsorbers must be stripped after they have been used for ten days.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25225" number="29156" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Small external carbon adsorbers must be vented to outside the building and must not recirculate vapor into the facility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25226" number="29157" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Small external carbon adsorbers used in mixed-use settings must be tested weekly using colorimetric detector tubes or equivalent measuring devices. Test results must be recorded on the inspection checklist. A test result of five ppm or greater of perc will require an immediate stripping of the carbon adsorber.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25227" number="29158" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The exhaust damper of a vented machine must be completely closed when the machine is not being vented and must be repaired or replaced within five working days if malfunctioning.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25228" number="29159" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Cartridge filters and adsorptive cartridge filters must be handled using one of the following methods:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25229" number="29160" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Drained in the filter housing, before disposal, for no less than 24 hours for cartridge filters and 48 hours for adsorptive cartridge filters. If the filters are then transferred to a separate device to further reduce the volume of perc, this treatment must be done in a system that routes any vapor to a primary closed-loop control system, with no exhaust to the atmosphere. In performing such a transfer the filter housing must be closed as soon as possible to minimize vapor leaks. The general exhaust ventilation system must be operated during this activity.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25230" number="29161" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Dried, stripped, sparged, or otherwise treated, within the sealed filter housing, to reduce the volume of perc contained in the filter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25231" number="29162" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All water-cooled condensers must include temperature gauges installed in the inlet and outlet water lines of the condensing coil on the dryer. The temperature difference must be maintained according to manufacturer&apos;s specifications.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25232" number="29163" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vi)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Azeotropic control devices must be maintained and operated in accordance with manufacturer&apos;s instructions and specifications.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25233" number="29164" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Test carbon absorber exhaust vents daily using colorimetric detector tubes or portable gas detectors. These absorbers shall be stripped periodically and maintained so that the perc concentration in the exhaust air does not exceed 20 ppm.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25234" number="29165" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">First generation machines.</CHARFORMAT> An existing facility with a transfer machine operating a full-sized carbon adsorber or azeotropic control device, and cartridge filters must meet the applicable requirements of paragraph (d)(3) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25235" number="29166" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Ancillary Equipment.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25236" number="29167" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All filter muck must be treated in a still or muck cooker, which routes perc-contaminated vapors to a condenser or other control device and recycles condenser vapors into the machine. Still or muck cooker emissions must not be vented into the facility. Any still or muck cooker must not be operated in a manner that exceeds 75 percent of its capacity or other alternate value recommended by the manufacturer. Any still or muck cooker must be cooled to 100°F (38°C) or less before being emptied or cleaned.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25237" number="29168" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Button and lint traps must be cleaned each working day and the lint must be placed in a tightly sealed container. Whenever possible such operations must be performed so that the opening of such traps is done quickly with the local or general exhaust ventilation system operating to minimize perc emissions.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25238" number="29169" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Perc-contaminated wastewater treatment units.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25239" number="29170" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Carbon filtration units – carbon cartridges must be replaced according to a schedule as specified by the manufacturer to assure an effluent quality that does not exceed 20 ppb perc.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25240" number="29171" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Evaporators – perc contaminated wastewater evaporators must be operated to ensure that no liquid perc or visible emulsion is allowed to vaporize.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25241" number="29172" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Dip tanks and drying cabinets must be exhausted to maintain an inward air flow, and be maintained under negative pressure, to ensure that fugitive emissions will be no greater than 50 ppm. Vented emissions from dip tanks and drying cabinets must not exceed 20 ppm.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25242" number="29173" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner or operator of a dry cleaning system must maintain the following equipment as recommended by manufacturer&apos;s specifications:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25243" number="29174" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>hose and pipe connections, fittings, couplings, and valves;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25244" number="29175" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>door gaskets and seatings;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25245" number="29176" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>filter gaskets and seatings;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25246" number="29177" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>pumps;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25247" number="29178" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>water separators;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25248" number="29179" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vi)<TAB tab-count="1"/>muck cookers;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25249" number="29180" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(vii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>stills;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25250" number="29181" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(viii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>exhaust dampers;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25251" number="29182" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ix)<TAB tab-count="1"/>diverter valves;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25252" number="29183" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(x)<TAB tab-count="1"/>cartridge filter housings;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25253" number="29184" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(xi)<TAB tab-count="1"/>drying sensors;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25254" number="29185" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Preparedness and prevention.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25255" number="29186" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All dry cleaning operations must be equipped with the following:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25256" number="29187" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>adequate spill control equipment including sorbent materials, or alternative method for absorbing spills,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25257" number="29188" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>vapor-proof containers for storing spill-contaminated material, and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25258" number="29189" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>fire control equipment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25259" number="29190" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The facility owner must maintain aisle space to allow proper inspection of the dry cleaning equipment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25260" number="29191" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A reasonable supply of spare parts for repairing dry cleaning equipment must be available at the dry cleaning facility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25261" number="29192" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All parts of the dry cleaning system including solvent containers where perc may be emitted to the atmosphere must be kept closed at all times except when access is required for proper operation and maintenance.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25262" number="29193" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-09 Perc-Contaminated Wastewater Management.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3435" name="T15C012_12-09"/>§ 12-09 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Perc-Contaminated Wastewater Management.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25263" number="29194" version="3">
									<PARA>Perc-contaminated wastewater generated by all new and existing facilities subject to this Rule must be managed as follows:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25264" number="29195" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Perc-contaminated wastewater discharges.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25265" number="29196" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Perc-contaminated wastewater that is discharged to the public sewer system must be treated by physical separation (water separator) and double carbon filtration, or an equivalent control which has been approved by the Department, which has been properly designed to assure an effluent quality that:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25266" number="29197" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>is less than or equal to 20 ppb perc without perc evaporation; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25267" number="29198" version="1894">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>complies in all other respects to the requirements of 15 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C019" destination-id="0-0-0-3685">Chapter 19</LINK> regulating the use of the public sewer system.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25268" number="29199" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except as provided for by subparagraph (a)(1)(i) of this section, no person may discharge into the public sewer system any perc-contaminated wastewater or wastes resulting from dry cleaning processes including, but not limited to, still bottom or sludge residues, dirt, lint, soils, or any other deposits or residues extracted as a result of dry cleaning processes. The discharge into the public sewer system of filters or other filter media used in dry cleaning processes is prohibited.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25269" number="29200" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No person may discharge perc-contaminated wastewater to the surface or groundwaters within New York City except in compliance with the terms and conditions of a valid State Pollution Discharge Elimination Permit.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25270" number="29201" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Evaporation of perc-contaminated wastewater.</CHARFORMAT> Perc-contaminated wastewater that is evaporated must be treated by physical separation (water separator) and double carbon filtration prior to evaporation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25271" number="29202" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-10 Hazardous Waste Management.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3437" name="T15C012_12-10"/>§ 12-10 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Hazardous Waste Management.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25272" number="29203" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any perc-contaminated wastes generated must be managed in accordance with Parts 370 through 376 of Title 6 of the Codes, Rules, and Regulations of the State of New York. Perc-contaminated wastewater must be handled as provided in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-09" destination-id="0-0-0-3435">12-09</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25273" number="29204" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All perc-contaminated wastes (including spent cartridge filters, spent carbon, still bottoms, and lint) must be stored in tightly sealed containers, which are impermeable to the solvent, so that no perc is emitted to the atmosphere.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25274" number="29205" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Containers must be appropriately labeled and stored in a designated area.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25275" number="29206" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Containers must be in good condition and must be kept closed except when necessary to add or remove waste.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25276" number="29207" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Receipts or records showing the date and volume of any perc-contaminated hazardous waste shipments must be retained for five years.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25277" number="29208" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-11 Emergency Response.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3439" name="T15C012_12-11"/>§ 12-11 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Emergency Response.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25278" number="29209" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Dry cleaning systems must be operated and maintained to ensure that perc releases are contained and do not migrate to sewer systems or groundwater.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25279" number="29210" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For existing dry cleaning equipment:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25280" number="29211" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>floor drains and flooring in the vicinity of the equipment must be sealed so as to be impermeable to spills, or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25281" number="29212" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>temporary dikes, berms and containment devices must be placed in areas where spills are most likely to occur and procedures for preventing spill migration must be established and followed.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25282" number="29213" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For new dry cleaning equipment, a spill containment system must be installed under the equipment as specified in paragraph (a)(7) of 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-06" destination-id="0-0-0-3429">12-06</LINK>. This spill tank shall be capable of holding 125% of the capacity of the largest perc tank or vessel that is part of the dry cleaning machine.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25283" number="29214" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the event of a perc release, the owner, operator or a designee must take all reasonable measures to ensure the release is contained. These measures must include, where applicable, stopping processes and operations, increasing room exhaust ventilation, collecting and containing released perc and removing and maintaining containers.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25284" number="29215" version="1894">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the facility owner and/or operator knows or has reason to know of any release of one (1) pound or more of perc (1 pound of perc is equivalent to 0.0740 gallons of perc), a fire, or an explosion, then the facility owner and/or operator shall report the perc release, fire, or explosion to the Department immediately and shall also comply with all other reporting requirements of 15 RCNY <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C011" destination-id="0-0-0-3405">Chapter 11</LINK> governing Hazardous Substances Emergency Response.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25285" number="29216" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any emergency response action must be recorded as specified in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-12" destination-id="0-0-0-3441">12-12</LINK>. This record must include, at a minimum:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25286" number="29217" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The date, duration and nature of any malfunction, spill or incident of the dry cleaning system;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25287" number="29218" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The notification procedures; and,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25288" number="29219" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The corrective actions taken.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25289" number="29220" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-12 Reporting and Recordkeeping.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3441" name="T15C012_12-12"/>§ 12-12 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Reporting and Recordkeeping.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25290" number="29221" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Operators of all dry cleaning facilities or their designees must record the following:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25291" number="29222" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The date, duration and nature of any malfunction, spill, incident, or emergency response at the facility as outlined in paragraph (d) of 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-11" destination-id="0-0-0-3439">12-11</LINK>;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25292" number="29223" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The date of maintenance on any air cleaning component or exhaust system (such as the regeneration and/or replacement of the carbon in a carbon adsorber);</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25293" number="29224" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The number of loads between regenerations, cleaning and replacement of lint filters and carbon adsorber pre-filters, repair or replacement of exhaust fans;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25294" number="29225" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The amount of activated carbon in carbon adsorbers (dry weight in pounds);</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25295" number="29226" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The date of maintenance of drying sensors;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25296" number="29227" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The date and volume of any perc-contaminated hazardous waste shipments; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25297" number="29228" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The dates of perc-contaminated wastewater treatment unit carbon cartridge replacement.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25298" number="29229" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each owner or operator of a dry cleaning facility must keep receipts of perc purchases, a log of the following information, maintain such information on-site and provide it upon request for a period of five years:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25299" number="29230" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The volume of perc purchased each month by the dry cleaning facility as recorded from perc purchases; if no perc is purchased during a given month then the owner or operator would enter zero gallons into the log;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25300" number="29231" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner or operator must perform the following calculation on the first day of every month:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25301" number="29232" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Sum the volume of all perc purchases made in each of the previous twelve months, as recorded in the log described in paragraph (1) above.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25302" number="29233" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If no perc purchases were made in a given month, then the perc consumption for that month is zero gallons.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25303" number="29234" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The total sum calculated is the yearly perc consumption at the facility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25304" number="29235" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each owner or operator of a dry cleaning facility must record the following information on an inspection checklist as described in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-07" destination-id="0-0-0-3431">12-07</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25305" number="29236" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The dates when the dry cleaning system components are inspected for perceptible leaks as specified under the inspection and testing requirements, and the name or location of dry cleaning system components where perceptible leaks are detected;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25306" number="29237" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The date, time and colorimetric detector tube monitoring results as specified in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-07" destination-id="0-0-0-3431">12-07</LINK>, if a carbon adsorber is used for primary or secondary emission control;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25307" number="29238" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The date, time and temperature sensor monitoring results for refrigerated condensers, as specified in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-07" destination-id="0-0-0-3431">12-07</LINK>; and,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25308" number="29239" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The dates of repair and records of written or verbal orders for repair parts to demonstrate compliance with the inspection and testing requirements in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-07" destination-id="0-0-0-3431">12-07</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25309" number="29240" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each owner or operator of a dry cleaning facility must retain on-site copies of the operation and maintenance checklists required under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-08" destination-id="0-0-0-3433">12-08</LINK> and compliance inspection reporting forms required under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-16" destination-id="0-0-0-3449">12-16</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25310" number="29241" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each owner or operator of a dry cleaning facility must retain on-site a copy of the design specifications and the operating manuals for each dry cleaning system and each emission control device located at the dry cleaning facility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25311" number="29242" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All records must be maintained on-site for at least five years and must be made available to the Department upon written or verbal request.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25312" number="29243" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to the permitting requirements of 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-15" destination-id="0-0-0-3447">12-15</LINK>, new facilities, or facilities installing new equipment, must submit to the Department a copy of the compliance report submitted to the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation within 30 days of commencing operation to certify compliance with the federal National Emission Standard for Hazardous Air Pollutants requirements. This statement must include:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25313" number="29244" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name and address of the owner or operator;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25314" number="29245" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The address (that is, physical location) of the dry cleaning facility;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25315" number="29246" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An estimation of the annual perc consumption;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25316" number="29247" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A description of the machines&apos; control devices;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25317" number="29248" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A statement verifying compliance with each applicable requirement under Title 40 of the Code of Federal Regulations subchapters 63.322, 63.323, and 63.324; and,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25318" number="29249" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A statement certifying that all information contained in the statement is accurate and true.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25319" number="29250" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to the permitting requirements of 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-15" destination-id="0-0-0-3447">12-15</LINK>, facilities exceeding the consumption thresholds identified in Title 40 of the Code of Federal Regulations subchapter 63.620(d), (e), or (g) must submit to the Department a copy of the compliance report submitted to the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation within 30 days of the compliance deadline of 180 days certifying compliance with any additional federal requirements. This statement must include:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25320" number="29251" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name and address of the owner or operator;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25321" number="29252" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The address (that is, physical location) of the dry cleaning facility;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25322" number="29253" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An estimation of the annual perc consumption;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25323" number="29254" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A description of the machines&apos; control devices;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25324" number="29255" version="1175">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A statement verifying compliance with each applicable requirement under 40 C.F.R. Subchapters 63.322, 63.323, and 63.324; and,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25325" number="29256" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A statement certifying that all information contained in the statement is accurate and true.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25326" number="29257" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-13 Equipment Testing and Certification.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3443" name="T15C012_12-13"/>§ 12-13 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Equipment Testing and Certification.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25327" number="29258" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Prohibitions and requirements.</CHARFORMAT> The provisions of this section will be effective 60 days after the date that the first qualifying testing program is approved by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation or its agent.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25328" number="29259" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Only the following kinds of dry cleaning equipment are permitted to be installed in perc dry cleaning facilities subject to this Rule: new closed-loop dry cleaning machines; converted dry cleaning machines; door fan systems; or, add-on secondary control systems which meet the design and performance standards in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-06" destination-id="0-0-0-3429">12-06</LINK> and testing requirements of this section. Unless otherwise specified in this Rule, the dry cleaning equipment as manufactured and installed must comply in all respects with the unit upon which certification by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation or its agent was based.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25329" number="29260" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any manufacturer or vendor of any new closed-loop dry cleaning equipment that is to be installed in and used by a dry cleaning facility in New York City must apply for and receive certification from the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation or its agent that the equipment to be installed and operated complies in all respects with the performance standards and the testing requirements of Part 232 of Title 6 of the Codes, Rules, and Regulations of the State of New York. Such certification must include the operating parameters under which the equipment was tested to receive certification.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25330" number="29261" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>It is unlawful for any person to sell, offer for sale, cause to be offered for sale, lease or represent new closed-loop dry cleaning equipment or any other machine or system described in paragraph (a)(1) of this section as one which can be used by a dry cleaning facility in New York City unless it has been certified by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation or its agent.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25331" number="29262" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The contract of sale, lease, or use between the manufacturer or vendor and dry cleaning equipment user must contain, at a minimum, a provision stating that the manufacturer or vendor must, upon request, provide the user with a copy of the certification of the equipment by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation or its agent, as required by § 232.13 of Title 6 of the Codes, Rules, and Regulations of the State of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25332" number="29263" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The manufacturer or vendor must provide immediate notification to the Department of any generic design or functional defect discovered in the equipment. Such notice must include a detailed plan of the manufacturer&apos;s or vendor&apos;s remedy.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25333" number="29264" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>After the certified dry cleaning equipment has been installed at the user&apos;s facility, the manufacturer or manufacturer&apos;s representative must supply at least a two-day training session to the purchaser or lessee. The training must include instruction on how to maintain and operate the dry cleaning machine. This requirement does not apply to add-on door fan systems designed to capture drum vapors when the door is open.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25334" number="29265" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Equipment testing.</CHARFORMAT> All persons conducting equipment testing must comply with the equipment testing requirements, protocols, methods, and procedures of § 232.13(b) of Title 6 of the Codes, Rules, and Regulations of the State of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25335" number="29266" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-14 Owner/Manager Operator and Inspector Training and Certification.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3445" name="T15C012_12-14"/>§ 12-14 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Owner/Manager Operator and Inspector Training and Certification.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25336" number="29267" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except for the conditions established in subdivision (b) and the effective date provisions of subdivision (f) of this subchapter, it is unlawful for any person to operate a dry cleaning facility subject to this Rule unless:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25337" number="29268" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the facility manager and/or owner has a current and valid Dry Cleaning Owner/Manager Certification; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25338" number="29269" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the person operating the dry cleaning machine has a current and valid Dry Cleaning Operator Certification.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25339" number="29270" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the event that an unforeseen/unpredictable situation prevents a dry cleaning facility from having a certified operator operating the dry cleaning equipment, the owner/manager will be allowed to continue operation of the dry cleaning machine with a non-certified operator for a period not to exceed three days per occurrence. Under no circumstances may an uncertified operator operate dry cleaning equipment at any facility for a total of more than ten days in any calendar year. If the use of an uncertified operator would cause nonperformance of required maintenance and leak detection, the facility must suspend dry cleaning operations until a certified operator is available. The purpose of this provision is to accommodate emergencies or unforeseen extenuating circumstances and must not be used to cover routine situations such as vacations or other scheduled absences.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25340" number="29271" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A Dry Cleaning Owner/Manager Certification may be issued by any organization that offers a training program (including refresher courses) approved by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation in accordance with the requirements of § 232.14(c) of Title 6 of the Codes, Rules, and Regulations of the State of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25341" number="29272" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A Dry Cleaning Operator Certification may be issued by any organization that offers a training and testing program (including refresher courses) approved by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation in accordance with the requirements of § 232.14(d) of Title 6 of the Codes, Rules, and Regulations of the State of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25342" number="29273" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Individuals that inspect dry cleaning facilities, either as a registered inspector or under the supervision of a registered inspector, must obtain a Dry Cleaner Owner/Manager Certification.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25343" number="29274" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Effective date for Dry Cleaning Owner/Manager and Dry Cleaning Operator Certification.</CHARFORMAT> After the date of the first qualifying training program approved by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation, the requirements of this subdivision will take effect and the first training and certification will be mandatory according to the following schedule:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25344" number="29275" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>upon start up for all operators of new dry cleaning facilities unless the facility Owner/Manager can demonstrate that compliance with this requirement poses an unreasonable burden because of the unavailability of scheduled training courses or testing facilities;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25345" number="29276" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>three months for operators of all existing dry cleaning facilities that are in mixed-use locations and that contain transfer machines;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25346" number="29277" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>six months for operators of all existing dry cleaning facilities in mixed-use locations that contain dry-to-dry vented machines but do not contain transfer machines;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25347" number="29278" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>nine months for operators of all the rest of the existing dry cleaning facilities in mixed-use locations;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25348" number="29279" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>twelve months for operators of all existing dry cleaning facilities in stand-alone locations that contain transfer machines;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25349" number="29280" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>fifteen months for operators of existing dry cleaning facilities in stand-alone locations that contain dry-to-dry vented machines but do not contain transfer machines; and,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25350" number="29281" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>eighteen months for operators of all the rest of existing dry cleaning facilities in stand-alone locations.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25351" number="29282" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A Dry Cleaning Operator Certification will be valid for a three year period and may be renewed upon completion of a refresher course.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25352" number="29283" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Persons or organizations authorized to offer operator training and certification courses may not require membership in an association or purchase of a product as a prerequisite to enrollment or successful completion of the course.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25353" number="29284" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An authorization to offer operator training and certification courses is valid for a maximum of five years. The authorization may be renewed by filing an application provided by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation. Such ap- plication must be filed at least six months prior to the expiration of the current authorization.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25354" number="29285" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation fails to approve and implement the training programs set forth in § 232.14 of Title 6 of the Codes, Rules, and Regulations of the State of New York in a timely manner then the Department may elect, in its sole discretion, to implement such training programs consistent with this subchapter and § 232.14 of Title 6 of the Codes, Rules, and Regulations of the State of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25355" number="29286" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Dry cleaning owners and/or managers and all machine operators shall attend a 16-hour training course, successfully pass a DEC Certification test and hold current, valid DEC Owner/Manager and/or Operator Certificates. Every shop owner shall have at least one person with an Owner/Manager Certification and one person with an Operator Certification.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25356" number="29287" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-15 Permits and Certificates.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3447" name="T15C012_12-15"/>§ 12-15 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Permits and Certificates.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25357" number="29288" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Alterations or Modifications to Existing Certificated Dry Cleaning Facilities Required by 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-05" destination-id="0-0-0-3427">12-05</LINK>.</CHARFORMAT> Any person who owns or operates an existing perc dry cleaning facility which has a valid operating certificate and who is required to perform alterations or modifications in order to comply with the requirements of 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-05" destination-id="0-0-0-3427">12-05</LINK> shall submit to the Department by means of certified mail a copy of the same notice submitted to the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation in accordance with the requirements of § 232.5(a)(3) of Title 6 of the Official Compilation of Codes, Rules, and Regulations of the State of New York.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25358" number="29289" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">New Installations that are Not Major Sources of Perc and Alterations or Modifications to Existing Certificated Dry Cleaning Facilities.</CHARFORMAT> No person may install or construct a new perc dry cleaning facility or undertake alterations or modifications to an existing certificated perc dry cleaning facility, except for alterations or modifications required by 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-05" destination-id="0-0-0-3427">12-05</LINK>, without first submitting an application on a form to be supplied by the Department and obtaining an installation or alteration permit. All installation and alteration permit applications shall reference any process application number(s) previously assigned to the facility by the Department and shall also include a copy of the facility&apos;s New York State Department of Environmental Conservation air permit or registration. Except as provided for by subdivision (c) of this section, the Department shall issue an installation or alteration permit or an operating certificate to any new or existing perc dry cleaning facility that the Department determines is in full compliance with all the provisions, requirements, and standards of this Rule.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25359" number="29290" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">New Installations that are Major Sources of Perc.</CHARFORMAT> The Department may grant an installation permit to a new dry cleaning facility that will be a major source of perc only after the Department has determined that the proposed dry cleaning facility is in full compliance with the provisions, requirements, and standards of this Rule and that the proposed dry cleaning facility will not cause detriment to the health, safety, welfare or comfort of any person. The Department may impose such additional permit and/or certificate terms and conditions as it determines may be necessary to protect the health, safety, welfare, or comfort of any person. In addition to the requirements of this section, any new perc dry cleaning facility which is a major source of perc must comply with all requirements under federal and state law including, but not limited to, the National Emission Standard for Hazardous Air Pollutants for Perchloroethylene Dry Cleaning Facilities and shall also obtain a Title V permit as required by the Federal Clean Air Act.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25360" number="29291" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-16 Compliance Inspections.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3449" name="T15C012_12-16"/>§ 12-16 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Compliance Inspections.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25361" number="29292" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Stand-alone dry cleaning facilities must be inspected at least annually, and mixed-use facilities must be inspected according to the following schedule:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25362" number="29293" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>At least twice annually where any transfer or dry-to-dry vented equipment is operated; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25363" number="29294" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>At least annually where only non-vented equipment is operated.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25364" number="29295" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such inspections must be performed by an inspector registered with the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation or by an individual working under the supervision of a registered inspector.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25365" number="29296" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All registered inspectors must meet the requirements of paragraphs (1), (2) and (3) of this subdivision. All individuals working under the supervision of a registered inspector must meet the requirements of paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subdivision.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25366" number="29297" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The inspector must be one of the following:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25367" number="29298" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a licensed professional engineer;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25368" number="29299" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a registered architect; or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25369" number="29300" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>a certified industrial hygienist.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25370" number="29301" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Must possess a Dry Cleaner Owner/Manager certification in accordance with 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-14" destination-id="0-0-0-3445">12-14</LINK> and complete other appropriate training as specified by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation on topics related to inspections.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25371" number="29302" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Must not be engaged in the sales or marketing of dry cleaning equipment. Must not be engaged in providing services to the dry cleaning industry. Employees of trade associations may not conduct inspections, but trade associations may solicit bids for performing inspections on behalf of their members.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25372" number="29303" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Inspections must be conducted in accordance with protocols specified by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation, using an inspection reporting form supplied by the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25373" number="29304" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Analysis of air samples collected by passive sampling devices or the equivalent must be conducted by a laboratory certified by the Environmental Laboratory Approval Program (ELAP) of the New York State Department of Health.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25374" number="29305" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The inspection will verify that the NOTICE required by 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-18" destination-id="0-0-0-3453">12-18</LINK> is posted in a conspicuous location in the facility.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25375" number="29306" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>After the inspection is completed, the registered inspector must provide a completed inspection reporting form to the Department and to the facility owner within 45 days of the inspection.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25376" number="29307" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Failure of the registered inspector to comply with the above requirements may result in the removal of the registered inspector from the Department&apos;s list of registered inspectors.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25377" number="29308" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner/manager or operator must:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25378" number="29309" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Make available upon request the most recent completed inspection reporting form to interested individuals for review on premises during normal business hours.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25379" number="29310" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the inspection reveals a leak or malfunction, the facility must be repaired within the timeframes established in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-07" destination-id="0-0-0-3431">12-07</LINK> and reinspected within one month.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25380" number="29311" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-17 Equivalency.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3451" name="T15C012_12-17"/>§ 12-17 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Equivalency.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25381" number="29312" version="1063">
									<PARA>Any person requesting that use of alternative equipment or procedures be considered as equivalent to the requirements under 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C012_12-06" destination-id="0-0-0-3429">12-06</LINK> shall make an application to the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation in accordance with the requirements of § 232.17 of Title 6 of the Codes, Rules, and Regulations of the State of New York and shall submit a copy of the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation&apos;s equivalency determination to the Department.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25382" number="29313" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-18 Posting Notice.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3453" name="T15C012_12-18"/>§ 12-18 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Posting Notice.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25383" number="29314" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The facility owner must post the notice required by § 232.18 of Title 6 of the Official Compilation of Codes, Rules, and Regulations of the State of New York in a conspicuous location in the dry cleaning facility to inform building tenants and/or customers of the substances (perc) used in the dry cleaning system and potential health effects associated with exposure to them.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25384" number="29315" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In addition to the notice required by subdivision (a), the owner of a dry cleaning facility that uses perc in the cleaning process must post in a conspicuous location in the facility a notice, on a form to be provided by the Department and with dimensions of 8 1/2 × 11 inches, that contains the following statements:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25385" number="29316" version="1064">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Information about the hazardous chemical substance (perc) used at this dry cleaning facility can be found on the Material Safety Data Sheet, which may be read at <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.nyc.gov/dep/drycleanermsds">www.nyc.gov/dep/drycleanermsds</LINK>.&quot;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25386" number="29317" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;This facility is inspected and permitted by the Department of Environmental Protection. The Department of Environmental Protection permit number is ____________. The RTK ID # is ____________.&quot;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25387" number="29318" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner of a dry cleaning facility that uses non-perc in the cleaning process must post in a conspicuous location in the facility a notice, on a form to be provided by the Department and with dimensions of 8 1/2 × 11 inches, that contains the following statements:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25388" number="29319" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;The primary non-perc chemical substance used at this dry cleaning facility is ______________.&quot;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25389" number="29320" version="1063">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Detailed information about the primary non-perc chemical substance can be found on the Material Safety Data Sheet, which may be read at <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="www.nyc.gov/dep/drycleanermsds">www.nyc.gov/dep/drycleanermsds</LINK>.&quot;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25390" number="29321" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;This facility is inspected and permitted by the Department of Environmental Protection. The Department of Environmental Protection permit number is ____________. The RTK ID # where applicable is __________.&quot;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25391" number="29322" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The owner of a dry cleaning facility that uses both perc and non-perc in the cleaning process must post the notice required by subdivision (c) of this section, in addition to the notices required by subdivisions (a) and (b) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25392" number="29323" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-19 Enforcement.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3455" name="T15C012_12-19"/>§ 12-19 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Enforcement.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25393" number="29324" version="3">
									<PARA>Any person who is in violation of or fails to comply with any provision, standard, or requirement of this Rule or the terms and conditions of any permit issued pursuant to this Rule shall be subject to the issuance of notice(s) of violation and other enforcement action(s) pursuant to the provisions of the Administrative Code of the City of New York including, but not limited to, the payment of civil penalties and compliance with orders of the Environmental Control Board.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-25394" number="29325" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 12-20 Severability.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3457" name="T15C012_12-20"/>§ 12-20 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Severability.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-25395" number="29326" version="3">
									<PARA>If any provision of this Rule or its application to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the remainder of this Rule, and the application of those provisions to persons other than those to which it is held invalid, will not be affected thereby.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>