<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-85029" number="100043" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 4: Domestic Partner Registration</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11697" name="T51C004"/>Chapter 4: Domestic Partner Registration</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-85030" number="100044" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-01 Domestic Partner Affidavit Form.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11699" name="T51C004_4-01"/>§ 4-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Domestic Partner Affidavit Form.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85031" number="100045" version="1423">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Both parties must be present at the time of submitting their affidavit to register as domestic partners at the City Clerk&apos;s office. Parties must provide acceptable identification as specified in 51 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T51C004_4-03" destination-id="0-0-0-11703">4-03</LINK>, and register during regular business hours.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85032" number="100046" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Both partners must sign the affidavit in the presence of a Notary Public or Commissioner of Deeds who will then sign and notarize the document before the affidavit is submitted for registration in the City Clerk&apos;s office.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85033" number="100047" version="1423">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The foregoing do not apply to cases where City Clerk personnel are processing a domestic partnership registration in a prison or a hospital, pursuant to 51 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T51C004_4-02" destination-id="0-0-0-11701">4-02</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-85034" number="100048" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-02 Accepting Registration Outside of the Office.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11701" name="T51C004_4-02"/>§ 4-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Accepting Registration Outside of the Office.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85035" number="100049" version="3">
									<PARA>Domestic partners may register at the office of the City Clerk during regular business hours. Exceptions to this provision will be made only in those cases where an individual is confined to a hospital and in cases where an individual is confined in prison. The acceptance of prison or hospital registration is a courtesy, and is therefore entirely subject to the availability of personnel and the schedule in the office,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85036" number="100050" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In a hospital case, the following requirements must be satisfied before registration will occur:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85037" number="100051" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The parties must present a statement from the doctor or hospital indicating that the sick party is seriously ill, that the party will be confined to the hospital for a very long period of time, that there is a possibility that the sick person will not survive the illness, and that the sick person is mentally competent to apply for registration of a domestic partnership;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85038" number="100052" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The parties must call ahead of time or make arrangements for the registration application to be completed; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85039" number="100053" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The parties must be willing to furnish City Clerk personnel with transportation to and from the hospital and must arrange on their own for someone to return to the City Clerk office to pick up the domestic partner registration certificate and pay any registration filing fee.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85040" number="100054" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In a prison case, the requirements are as follows:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85041" number="100055" version="2491">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The parties must present a written statement from the social worker, warden or other authorized person granting consent for the processing of the domestic partner registration in the prison; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85042" number="100056" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The parties must contract the City Clerk&apos;s office ahead of time to request that a domestic partner affidavit be registered and to make all necessary preparations.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-85043" number="100057" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-03 Identification to Register.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11703" name="T51C004_4-03"/>§ 4-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Identification to Register.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85044" number="100058" version="2501">
									<PARA>1.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Acceptable forms of identification.</CHARFORMAT> At the time of submitting an application to register a domestic partnership, each party must present identification. Identification documents acceptable for registration purposes are:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85045" number="100059" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>valid drivers license, learner&apos;s permit or identification card issued by the department of motor vehicles of a state or territory of the United States;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85046" number="100060" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>original birth certificate;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85047" number="100061" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>valid passport;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85048" number="100062" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>school records;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85049" number="100063" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>immigration card;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85050" number="100064" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>employee identification card; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85051" number="100065" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>such form of identification deemed acceptable by the City Clerk. All documents that are not written in English must be translated into English with an affidavit attesting to the accuracy of the translation. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-101041" number="100066" version="2501">
									<PARA>2.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Production of witnesses or notarized affidavits to establish identity for persons who do not possess forms of identification pursuant to subdivision 1 above.</CHARFORMAT> If in the opinion of the issuing clerk there appears to be some question as to the identity of one or both of the parties to the prospective domestic partnership, the City Clerk may compel the production of witnesses, certified official records or notarized affidavits to establish the identity of the parties. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-101042" number="100067" version="2501">
									<PARA>3.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Request for review of City Clerk&apos;s preliminary denial of domestic partnership.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85052" number="100068" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applicants who have been preliminarily denied a domestic partnership by the City Clerk may request a review of such determination by paying a $25 fee and filing a request for a review on such form as may be provided by the City Clerk no later than 30 days after such preliminary denial. The City Clerk may waive this fee upon a showing of financial hardship.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85053" number="100069" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Duty of the City Clerk.</CHARFORMAT> Within fifteen days of receipt of a request for review the City Clerk shall forward to the Office of Administrative Trials and Hearings (OATH) such request for review, a written statement outlining the reason for the preliminary denial of the domestic partnership and the documentary evidence supporting the preliminary denial all of which documentation with the exception of the request for review shall constitute the petition. A copy of the petition shall be mailed contemporaneously to the applicant via certified mail return receipt requested.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85054" number="100070" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Notice to domestic partner or spouse of record.</CHARFORMAT> Where the domestic partnership registration was denied because of the existence in the records of the City Clerk of a prior non-terminated domestic partnership registration or marriage, the City Clerk shall exert its best efforts to notify the domestic partner or spouse of record of the impending action. The domestic partner or spouse of record shall be given twenty-one days from the date of mailing to respond to such notification. In such response, the domestic partner or spouse of record may request an opportunity to be heard on the issue, either in writing or at the hearing, if OATH decides a hearing is warranted. Upon request contained in such response, the City Clerk shall forward to the domestic partner or spouse of record all documentation exchanged among OATH, the City Clerk and the applicant.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85055" number="100071" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Applicant&apos;s duty to respond.</CHARFORMAT> Applicant shall, no later than thirty days after he or she receives the petition, submit in duplicate an answer to the City Clerk including therein any documentary evidence or other proof which may include notarized affidavits in support of his or her claim. Upon written request of the applicant stating the specific reason for such request submitted no later than five days prior to the due date for such answer, the City Clerk may for good cause grant an extension of time for applicant to submit the same. Upon receipt of the answer the City Clerk shall forward a copy thereof to OATH. Applicant&apos;s failure to respond by the deadline set forth herein, including any extension granted by the City Clerk pursuant to this paragraph, shall be deemed a withdrawal of the applicant&apos;s challenge to the City Clerk&apos;s preliminary decision and such preliminary decision shall thereafter be deemed final.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85056" number="100072" version="1747">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Designation of OATH.</CHARFORMAT> Pursuant to Section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="1813066185-672468487-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Charter.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="1048" destination-id="0-0-0-0">1048</LINK> of the Charter, the City Clerk designates OATH to conduct on its behalf all the reviews and hearings referred to herein.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85057" number="100073" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">The reviewing officer.</CHARFORMAT> An ALJ employed by OATH shall review the petition and the answer no later than fifteen days after the date of receipt of both the petition and the answer as well as any documentation presented by the domestic partner or spouse of record, if any. If upon such review the ALJ shall conclude that such evidence is sufficient to form a conclusion then the ALJ shall prepare no later than thirty days after receipt of all of the documents referred to in the first sentence of this paragraph a report summarizing the evidence presented, an analysis of the legal and factual issues, recommended findings of fact and recommended disposition. Such report shall be sent to the City Clerk for a final determination of the facts and a final disposition. Alternatively, if the ALJ shall conclude that the evidence presented is insufficient to form a conclusion, the ALJ shall convene a hearing at a date to be determined in such ALJ&apos;s sole discretion but no later than sixty days from the date of such initial review. Upon notification thereof by such ALJ, which notification may be electronic, the City Clerk, not later than five days after the date of such notification, shall notify the applicant as well as his or her attorney or other representative, if any, and the domestic partner or spouse of record, if any, of the date of the hearing by certified mail return receipt requested. Such notification shall be post-marked no later than thirty days prior to the date of such hearing.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85058" number="100074" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Use of expert witness.</CHARFORMAT> It shall be the obligation of any party intending to present the testimony of expert witness or witnesses at the hearing to notify the ALJ and the opposing parties of such intention no later than fifteen days prior to the date of the hearing and to submit to both the ALJ and the opposing parties no later than seven days prior to the date of the hearing copies of any reports, filings or any other documentation produced by such expert witness or witnesses which such party intends to use at the hearing. The ALJ may grant an extension of time to the parties.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85059" number="100075" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">The hearing.</CHARFORMAT> The ALJ shall preside over the hearing, make all procedural rulings, and make a statement on the record describing the nature of the proceedings, the issues, and the manner in which the hearing will be conducted. The ALJ shall have all the requisite powers conferred by law to administer oaths, issue subpoenas, require the attendance of witnesses and production of records, rule upon requests for adjournment, rule upon evidentiary matters and to otherwise regulate the hearing, observe the requirements of due process and effectuate the purposes and provisions of applicable law. All testimony shall be given under oath or affirmation administered by the ALJ. The City Clerk shall have the burden of demonstrating by a preponderance of the evidence that the applicant should not be granted a domestic partnership.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85060" number="100076" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The applicant and the domestic partner or spouse of record, if any, may be represented by an attorney or other representative of his or her choice.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85061" number="100077" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(j)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The applicant as well as the City Clerk and the domestic partner or spouse of record, if any, may have witnesses, may give testimony and may otherwise present relevant and material evidence on his or her behalf, may cross-examine witnesses and may examine any document or other item offered into evidence.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85062" number="100078" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(k)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A recorded copy of the record of the hearing shall be prepared by OATH; upon request a compact disc audio recording of the hearing, at no cost, or a transcript of the hearing, at a cost to be determined by OATH, may be provided.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85063" number="100079" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(l)<TAB tab-count="1"/>At the discretion of the ALJ, the hearing may be adjourned for good cause upon the request of any of the parties or upon the ALJ&apos;s own motion and with notice to the parties.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85064" number="100080" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(m)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The hearing shall be conducted in conformity with procedural requirements of applicable law and the rules of procedure adopted by OATH which are not inconsistent with these rules. In the event of any conflict of laws, the rules of this section shall be determinative and controlling.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85065" number="100081" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(n)<TAB tab-count="1"/>After the conclusion of the hearing, the ALJ shall prepare a report summarizing the evidence presented, an analysis of the legal and factual issues, recommended findings of fact and a recommended disposition. Such report shall be sent to the City Clerk for a final determination of the facts and a final disposition.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85066" number="100082" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(o)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Final decision.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85067" number="100083" version="493">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The City Clerk&apos;s final decision shall be in writing and shall state reasons for the determinations and, when appropriate, direct specific action. Notwithstanding the foregoing, such final decision need not be a separate formal document and a report submitted to the City Clerk pursuant to paragraph 3(f) or 3(n) hereof together with a letter from the City Clerk concurring with the recommended findings of fact and recommended disposition shall constitute a final decision. In reaching such final decision, the City Clerk may review the petition and answer and memoranda of law of the parties, if any, and any record of the hearing. The City Clerk shall not be bound by the ALJ&apos;s recommendation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85068" number="100084" version="493">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A copy of such final decision shall be mailed by the City Clerk to the applicant and his or her attorney or representative, if any, and the domestic partner or spouse of record, if any.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85069" number="100085" version="493">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any of the aggrieved parties have the right to judicial review in accordance with the provisions of Article 78 of the Civil Practice Law and Rules.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-85070" number="100086" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-04 Domestic Partner Registration Certificate.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11705" name="T51C004_4-04"/>§ 4-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Domestic Partner Registration Certificate.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85071" number="100087" version="3">
									<PARA>Upon completion of the application process, the City Clerk will issue a domestic partnership registration certificate to the registered partners.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-85072" number="100088" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-05 Release of Domestic Partners Registration Records.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11707" name="T51C004_4-05"/>§ 4-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Release of Domestic Partners Registration Records.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85073" number="100089" version="3">
									<PARA>Domestic Partner Registration information and documents shall not be subject to public inspection or disclosure. In the ordinary course of business, domestic partner records shall only be released to either of the parties to the registration in person, after proper identification has been submitted to the City Clerk staff. No requests shall be accepted via telephone. Further, domestic partnership information released pursuant to written authorization from one of the parties to the domestic partnership shall only be released if such written authorization is notarized.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-85074" number="100090" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-06 Modification of Domestic Partner Registration.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11709" name="T51C004_4-06"/>§ 4-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Modification of Domestic Partner Registration.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85075" number="100091" version="3">
									<PARA>After a domestic partnership has been registered by the City Clerk, such record will only be modified or amended upon the filing of a written request for amendment form and offering adequate evidence to justify the proposed change of the record.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-85076" number="100092" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-07 Termination of Domestic Partnership.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11711" name="T51C004_4-07"/>§ 4-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Termination of Domestic Partnership.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85077" number="100093" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Either or both of the parties to a registered domestic partnership, may file a termination statement with the City Clerk.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85078" number="100094" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the termination statement is not signed by both, then the party who has not signed the termination must be given notice of such termination by registered mail, return receipt requested.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85079" number="100095" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The City Clerk will provide written notice of the filing of a termination to both parties of the registered partnership.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85080" number="100096" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The termination statement must be filed in person except that in circumstances where in-person filing is impossible or such filing would create a hardship, the City Clerk may permit such filing by certified mail.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-85081" number="100097" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 4-08 Registration Fees.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11713" name="T51C004_4-08"/>§ 4-08 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Registration Fees.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85082" number="100098" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The registration fee for filing a domestic partnership is thirty-five dollars.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85083" number="100099" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The fee for filing a termination of a domestic partnership is twenty-seven dollars.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85084" number="100100" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The fee for obtaining a second or subsequent certificate for a registered domestic partnership is nine dollars per certificate.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85085" number="100101" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The fee for amending a domestic partnership registration is twenty-seven dollars</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85086" number="100102" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The fee for a domestic partnership ceremony is twenty-five dollars.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85087" number="100103" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All fees required under this section are to be only paid in cash or by such other means as deemed acceptable in the sole discretion of the City Clerk.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-85088" number="100104" version="1564">
								<HEADING>§ 4-09 Domestic Partnership Ceremony.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-11715" name="T51C004_4-09"/>§ 4-09 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Domestic Partnership Ceremony.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85089" number="100105" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Upon receipt of the applicable fee and subsequent to the registration of the domestic partnership, the City Clerk or an employee of the City Clerk designated for such purpose shall, upon request, conduct a ceremony in the City Clerk chapel to recognize the formation of a domestic partnership.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-85090" number="100106" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No ceremony is required to formalize a domestic partnership.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>