<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-36489" number="43450" version="1604">
			<HEADING>Chapter 10: Financial Corporations</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4971" name="T19C010"/>Chapter 10: Financial Corporations</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-36490" number="43451" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 10-01 Bad Debts.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4973" name="T19C010_10-01"/>§ 10-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Bad Debts.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36491" number="43452" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Consolidated returns. </CHARFORMAT>Requests to the Commissioner of Finance for permission to file banking corporation tax returns on a consolidated basis (or to include corporations not previously included, or to exclude corporations previously included, in a consolidated return) must be filed not later than thirty days after the close of the taxable period for which permission is requested. In no event will a request be considered which is not filed on or before such thirtieth day.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36492" number="43453" version="1834">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Bad debts may be treated in either of two ways: by a deduction from income as to debts ascertained to be worthless in whole or in part, or by a deduction from income of an addition to a reserve for bad debts. A corporation or association filing its first return of income, pursuant to Part 1 or 2 of Subchapter 3 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C006" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 6, Title 11</LINK>, New York City Administrative Code, may select either of the two methods, subject to approval by the Commissioner of Finance upon examination of the return, provided however that a corporation or association electing the reserve method must use particular reserve method it uses for New York State franchise tax purposes. The method originally adopted on such first return must be used in filing returns for all subsequent years unless the Commissioner of Finance consents to a change. Application for permission to change the method of treating bad debts shall be made at least 30 days prior to the close of the year the income of which is to measure the tax to be paid under the changed method.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36493" number="43454" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rules governing actual charge-off method.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36494" number="43455" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where all surrounding and attending circumstances indicate that debt is worthless, either wholly or in part, the amount which is worthless and charged off within the year on the books of the corporation or association shall be allowed as a deduction in computing net income. Where a debt is ascertained to be worthless, in whole or in part, and the amount so ascertained is credited to a specific reserve account for such debt, having the effect of removing the debt from the assets of the taxpayer, such credit is considered a charge-off. Before a corporation or association may charge off and deduct a debt in part, it must ascertain and be able to demonstrate, with a reasonable degree of certainty, the amount thereof which is uncollectible.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36495" number="43456" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In determining whether a debt is worthless in whole or in part, the Commissioner of Finance will consider all pertinent evidence including the value of the collateral, if any, securing the debt and the financial condition of the debtor. Partial deductions will be allowed with respect to specific debts only. Where the surrounding circumstances indicate that a debt is worthless and uncollectible and that legal action to enforce payment would in all probability not result in the satisfaction of execution on a judgment, a showing of these facts will be sufficient evidence of the worthlessness of the debt for the purpose of deduction. Bankruptcy is generally an indication of the worthlessness of at least a part of an unsecured and unpreferred debt. Actual determination of worthlessness in bankruptcy cases is sometimes possible before, and at other times only when, a settlement in bankruptcy shall have been made. If a corporation or association computes its income upon the basis of valuing its notes or accounts receivable at their fair market value when received, which may be less than their face value, the amount deductible for bad debts in any case is limited to such original valuation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36496" number="43457" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where a taxpayer which is subject to supervision by Federal or by State authorities charges off debts in whole or in part pursuant to the order, suggestion or policy of such authority, or in keeping with the classification of the debts by such authority, such debts shall, in the absence of affirmative evidence clearly establishing the contrary, be presumed, for the purpose of measuring this tax, as of the date of the charge-off by the taxpayer, to be worthless or recoverable only in part, as the case may be. The provisions of this paragraph, however, shall not be construed as limiting the validity of charge-offs for bad debts not directed or approved by the supervising authority.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36497" number="43458" version="1093">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All recoveries on charged-off loans, allocable to offices or branches located within New York City, including the release of specific reserves or valuation allowances therefor, must be included in gross income unless excludable under the provisions of 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C010_10-01" destination-id="0-0-0-4973">10-01</LINK>(b)(6) below.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36498" number="43459" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A corporation or association doing business or carrying on business through offices or branches both within and without New York City shall charge off only those worthless debts allocated and determined on the basis of separate accounting to the offices or branches located in New York City. Deductions for charge-off of loans administered by an office or branch must be allocated to that office or branch. If loans are administered and serviced centrally, the deduction for charge-off of such loans must be apportioned in a manner consistent with the apportionment of income derived therefrom.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36499" number="43460" version="1896">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Recoveries on loans allocated within New York City (exclusive of those evidenced by bonds or other securities) may be excluded from gross income to the extent that such write-off did not serve to reduce the amount of tax computable upon net income in the year made. Where such debts when charged off did serve to reduce the tax computable on net income, recoveries thereon may be excluded until they equal in the aggregate the sum of the charge-offs not accomplishing a reduction in tax liability. Recoveries on loans charged off during a year in which the taxpayer was not subject to tax under Part 1 or 2 of Subchapter 3 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C006" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 6 of Title 11</LINK>, may not be excluded from gross income in whole or in part.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36500" number="43461" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Rules governing use of reserve method.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36501" number="43462" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Taxpayers which have established the reserve method (other than specific reserves) of treating bad debts and maintain proper reserve accounts for bad debts, and which in accordance with subdivision (b) of this section adopt the reserve method of treating bad debts, may deduct from gross income a reasonable addition to a reserve for bad debts in lieu of a deduction for specific bad debt items.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36502" number="43463" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>What constitutes a reasonable addition to a reserve for bad debts must be determined in the light of the facts and will vary with conditions of business prosperity. It will depend primarily upon the total amount of debts outstanding as of the close of the taxable year, those arising currently as well as those arising in prior taxable years, and the total amount of the existing reserve. In case subsequent realizations upon outstanding debts prove to be more or less than estimated at the time of the creation of the existing reserve, the amount of the excess or inadequacy in the existing reserve must be reflected in the determination of the reasonable addition necessary for the taxable year. A taxpayer using the reserve method must show, in a statement made part of its return, the total amount of loans receivable at the beginning and close of the taxable year, the percentage of the reserve to the total loans outstanding at the close of the year, and the amount of the debts which have become wholly or partially worthless and have been charged off against the reserve account.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36503" number="43464" version="1093">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A corporation or association doing business or carrying on business through offices or branches both within and without New York City must determine what constitutes a reasonable addition to a reserve for bad debts on the basis of the total amount of debts and total amount of existing reserves of the New York City offices or branches. The statement required in 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C010_10-01" destination-id="0-0-0-4973">10-01</LINK>(d)(2) above should show the total loans receivable at the beginning and close of the taxable year, the percentage of the reserve to the loans outstanding at the end of the year and the amount of the bad debts which have become totally or partially worthless and have been charged against the reserve account of the New York City offices or branches allocated or determined on the basis of separate accounting. Loans administered by an office or branch must be allocated to that office or branch. Loans administered and serviced centrally must be apportioned in a manner consistent with the apportionment of income derived therefrom. The existing reserve of New York City offices or branches, as of January 1, 1966, is that amount which bears the same ratio to the total amount of the existing reserve for New York State franchise tax purposes, as of January 1, 1966, that the amount of outstanding New York City loans, as of January 1, 1966, bears to the total outstanding loans, as of January 1, 1966.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36504" number="43465" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>As an alternative, a taxpayer may adopt the moving-average method of computing reserves. Deductions in such cases will be allowed for additions to reserves for bad debts in accordance with the principles and rules adopted by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue on December 8, 1947 (Mim. 6209) and the rules interpretative thereof, issued by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue under dates of December 29, 1947, January 21, 1948, January 29, 1948, March 16, 1948 (Mim. 6247), March 1948, March 31, 1948, June 14, 1948, under GCM 25,605 and under I.T. 3936, except as otherwise expressly provided below.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36505" number="43466" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of a corporation or association using the moving-average method of determining the addition to the reserve for bad debts for New York State franchise tax purposes and electing the same method for New York City Financial Corporation Tax purposes, which is not doing business or carrying on business through offices or branches outside New York City, the initial balance of the New York City reserve for bad debts shall be the existing reserve for bad debts as determined for New York State franchise tax purposes under Article 9-B or 9-C of the Tax Law, as of the close of the calendar year preceding the year for which the election to use the moving-average method becomes effective. Accordingly, the addition to the reserve for bad debts for New York City Financial Corporation Tax purposes for such a corporation or association shall be an amount equal to, and shall be computed in the same manner as, the deduction reported for New York State franchise tax purposes under Article 9-B or 9-C of the Tax Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36506" number="43467" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A corporation or association using the moving-average method of determining the addition to the reserve for bad debts for New York State franchise tax purposes and electing the same method for New York City Financial Corporation Tax purposes, which is doing business or carrying on business through offices or branches both within and without New York City, must compute the addition to the reserve for bad debts in the manner provided under Mim. 6209 as interpreted, except that:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36507" number="43468" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The moving average shall be the moving average for twenty years, including the taxable year for which the report is made, as determined for New York State franchise tax purposes; provided, however, that a taxpayer may apply to the Commissioner of Finance for permission to substitute the experience of New York City offices or branches for twenty consecutive years, including the taxable year for which the report is made, as determined by separate accounting.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36508" number="43469" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Outstanding loans of New York City offices or branches of the taxpayer are those allocated or determined on the basis of separate accounting to the offices and branches located in New York City. Loans directly administered by a New York City office or branch are allocable to New York City. Loans administered and serviced centrally must be apportioned in a manner consistent with the apportionment of income derived therefrom.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36509" number="43470" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The initial balance of the New York City reserve for bad debts shall be that amount which bears the same ratio to the New York State reserve for bad debts, as determined for New York State franchise tax purposes under Article 9-B or 9-C of the Tax Law as of the close of the calendar year preceding the year for which the election to use the moving-average method becomes effective, as the amount of outstanding loans of New York City offices and branches, as of the close of such preceding calendar year, bears to outstanding loans of all offices and branches, as of the close of such preceding calendar year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36510" number="43471" version="1093">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(D)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In determining net charge-offs, outstanding loans ascertained to be worthless and charged off, and any recoveries of loans previously charged against the reserve allocable and apportioned under 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C010_10-01" destination-id="0-0-0-4973">10-01</LINK>(d)(4)(ii)(B)(D) to offices and branches situated outside New York City, must be excluded. All other recoveries, including loans charged off prior to January 1, 1966, must be included.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36511" number="43472" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A corporation or association may deduct (in addition to any allowable deduction computed under Mim. 6209 as provided in subparagraph (i) or (ii) of this paragraph, if any) an amount equal to the difference between</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36512" number="43473" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the product of the current moving average percentage times the amount by which the outstanding loans of New York City offices and branches at the close of the taxable year for which the report is made exceeds the outstanding loans of New York City offices and branches at the close of the preceding calendar year, and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36513" number="43474" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the deduction computed in accordance with Mim. 6209 and subparagraph (i) or (ii) of this paragraph; provided, however, that the total deduction allowable under this subparagraph for all taxable years shall not exceed the initial balance of the New York City reserve for bad debts as determined in subparagraph (i) or subparagraph (ii)(c) of this paragraph. A corporation or association claiming such additional deduction must attach a schedule to the return for the taxable year showing the computation of such deduction, the total of such deductions taken for all years (including that taken on the return), and the initial balance of the New York City reserve for bad debts as defined hereunder.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-36514" number="43475" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 10-02 Allocation of Income.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-4975" name="T19C010_10-02"/>§ 10-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Allocation of Income.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36515" number="43476" version="1834">
									<PARA>(Administrative Code §§ <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-620" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-620</LINK>(2), <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-621" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-621</LINK>(7), <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-628" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-628</LINK>(2) and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-629" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-629</LINK>(1)(g))</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36516" number="43477" version="1859">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The New York City Financial Corporation Tax, Subchapter 3 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C006" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 6 of Title 11</LINK>, New York City Administrative Code, is imposed upon that proportion of net income which is derived from business carried on within New York City. A corporation or association which maintains an office or place of business within the City, and not elsewhere, is taxable on all of its net income. A corporation or association which is doing business or carries on its business through offices or branches maintained both within the City and without the City must allocate its net income as provided in these regulations.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36517" number="43478" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>&#160;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36518" number="43479" version="1093">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;Doing Business&quot; and &quot;Business Carried On.&quot;</CHARFORMAT> A corporation or association is regarded as &quot;doing business&quot; or &quot;carrying on business&quot; within or without the City when it occupies, has or maintains an office, agency or branch where its functions are systematically and regularly carried on. In order to require an allocation of the income from business carried on within or without New York City, it is not necessary that the branch or agency maintained within or without the City conduct all functions of the banking business of the corporation or association. It is sufficient if the branch or office conducts some of the functions which the corporation or association is authorized to exercise regularly and with a fair measure of permanency and continuity.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36519" number="43480" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Allocation where business is carried on both within and without the City.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36520" number="43481" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A corporation or association doing business or carrying on business both within and without the City which keeps accounts of the gross income and deductions of each office or branch, which, in the opinion of the Commissioner of Finance, accurately reflect the income from business carried on within the City of each office or branch, may report as its net income subject to tax the net income derived from the offices or branches maintained within the City. In all cases, however, the taxpayer must report the gross and net income of the corporation or association from all business carried on within and without New York City.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36521" number="43482" version="1834">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where the corporation or association (other than an alien banking corporation or association) does not keep accounts of the gross income and deductions of each branch or agency so as to reflect accurately the net income from business carried on within the City, or the corporation or association elects to allocate and determine gross income and deductions under rules and regulations prescribed by the Commissioner of Finance (See: §§ <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-620" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-620</LINK>(2), <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-628" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-628</LINK>(2), <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-621" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-621</LINK>(7) and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-629" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-629</LINK>(i)(g) of the Administrative Code), an allocation of gross income and deductions shall be made by a net income allocation formula as determined under subdivision (d) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36522" number="43483" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A corporation or association which elects to allocate income and deductions by such net income allocation formula must use the formula in filing returns for all subsequent years to the year of adoption of the formula, unless the Commissioner of Finance consents to a change from the formula. Application for permission to change from use of the allocation formula shall be made at least 30 days prior to the close of the year the income of which is to measure the tax to be paid under the changed method.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36523" number="43484" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If it shall appear to the Commissioner of Finance that the net income from New York City is not fairly and equitably reflected under the provisions of paragraphs (1) or (2), the Commissioner of Finance, in his discretion, may approve some other method which will more accurately reflect income within New York City. Application for permission to use an alternative method must be made, as provided in paragraph (3) above.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36524" number="43485" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An alien banking corporation or association not reporting on the basis of separate accounting must allocate income and deductions in the same manner as for New York State franchise tax purposes, or by such other method approved by the Commissioner of Finance.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36525" number="43486" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Computation of net income allocation percentage. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36526" number="43487" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If a corporation or association (other than an alien banking corporation or association) has a branch, office or agency outside New York City during the period covered by the report and its books and records do not accurately reflect the net income from business carried on within the City, or it does not elect to determine the proportion of its net income derived from business carried on within the City on the basis of accounts of income and deductions of each office or branch within the City, its net income from business carried on within the City shall be determined by multiplying net income by an allocation percentage. The net income allocation percentage, composed of four factors having different weights, is computed on the basis of the corporation&apos;s or association&apos;s:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36527" number="43488" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>payrolls within and without New York City,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36528" number="43489" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>operating receipts within and without New York City,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36529" number="43490" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>real and tangible personal property (including real property rented to it) within and without New York City, and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36530" number="43491" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>deposits within and without New York City.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36531" number="43492" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The net income allocation percentage is computed by adding together</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36532" number="43493" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the percentage of the corporation&apos;s or association&apos;s payroll factor, multiplied by two;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36533" number="43494" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the percentage of the corporation&apos;s or association&apos;s operating receipts factor, multiplied by two;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36534" number="43495" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the percentage of the corporation&apos;s or association&apos;s real and tangible personal property factor; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36535" number="43496" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>the percentage of the corporation&apos;s or association&apos;s deposits factor within New York City during the period covered by the report and dividing the total of such percentages by six.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36536" number="43497" version="1834">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of this paragraph, net income is gross income from all sources as defined in § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-620" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-620</LINK> of the Administrative Code for corporations or associations taxable under Part 1 of Subchapter 3 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C006" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 6 of Title 11</LINK> and § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-628" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-628</LINK> for corporations taxable under Part 2 of Subchapter 3, less the deductions provided in § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-621" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-621</LINK> and § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-629" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-629</LINK>, respectively; subject to the adjustment provided in § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-614" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-614</LINK>(2) and § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-625" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-625</LINK>(2), respectively, provided, however:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36537" number="43498" version="1834">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In determining net income subject to allocation, no deduction for depreciation shall be allowed with respect to property for which a deduction was claimed under § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-621" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-621</LINK>(12) or § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-629" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-629</LINK>(1)(j), respectively, and that gain or loss from the sale or other disposition thereof shall be excluded. Any amount claimed under § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-621" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-621</LINK>(12) or § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="11-629" destination-id="0-0-0-0">11-629</LINK>(1)(j) and gain or loss from the sale or other disposition of such property, computed by adjusting the basis of such property to reflect the deductions so allowed, shall be added to, or deducted from, the portion of net income allocated to New York City hereunder.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36538" number="43499" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The deduction for debts ascertained to be worthless and charged off within the year or a reasonable addition to a reserve for bad debts shall be the amount determined for New York State franchise tax purposes under 9-B or 9-C of the Tax Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36539" number="43500" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Computation of the payroll factor. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36540" number="43501" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The percentage of the taxpayer&apos;s payroll allocable to New York City is determined by dividing the wages, salaries and other personal service compensation of the taxpayer&apos;s employees (except general executive officers) within New York City during the preceding calendar year by the total amount of compensation of all the taxpayer&apos;s employees (except general executive officers) during the preceding calendar year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36541" number="43502" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Employees within New York City shall be all employees (including, but not limited to, bookkeeping, auditing, accounting, legal and personnel involved in the administration of all securities or loans) regularly connected with or working out of an office or place of business of the corporation or association within New York City, irrespective of where the services of such employees were employed.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36542" number="43503" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>General executive officers include the chairman, vice-chairman, president, vice-president, secretary, assistant-secretary, treasurer, assistant-treasurer, comptroller and all other officers charged with and performing general executive duties of the corporation or association. An executive officer whose duties or services are substantially restricted to one or more specific offices or branches, either within or without the City, or whose activities involve the administration of securities and loans, is not a general executive officer.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36543" number="43504" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Computation of the property factor. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36544" number="43505" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The percentage of the taxpayer&apos;s real and tangible personal property within New York City is determined by dividing the average fair market value of such property within New York City (without deduction of any encumbrances) by the average fair market value of all such property within and without New York City for the preceding calendar year. In determining such percentage, real property rented to the corporation or association, as well as real and tangible personal property owned by it, must be considered.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36545" number="43506" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The average fair market value of real and tangible personal property owned by the corporation or association, both within and without New York City, is the price at which a willing seller not compelled to sell, will sell, and a willing buyer not compelled to buy, will buy, computed on a quarterly or more frequent basis. The fair market value of real property, both within and without New York City, which is rented to the taxpayer, is determined by multiplying the gross rent payable during the preceding calendar year by eight. The same methods of valuation must be used consistently with respect to property within and without the City. Any method of valuation adopted by the taxpayer on any report and accepted by the Commissioner of Finance may not be changed on any subsequent report without the prior approval of the Commissioner, and subject to such conditions and limitations which may be then imposed by the Commissioner.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36546" number="43507" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;tangible personal property&quot; means corporeal personal property, used in the conduct of the corporation&apos;s or association&apos;s business, such as business machines and furniture and fixtures, and does not include such intangibles as U.S. Government and Government Agency obligations; State, municipal and public securities; cash on hand, bonds, notes, mortgages and other evidences of indebtedness; or personal property acquired by foreclosure or in satisfaction of outstanding indebtedness.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36547" number="43508" version="2470">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;real property&quot; means real estate and all improvements thereon, other than real estate acquired by foreclosure or transfers in satisfaction of outstanding indebtedness.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36548" number="43509" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Computation of the operating receipts factor. </CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36549" number="43510" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The percentage of a corporation&apos;s or association&apos;s receipts within New York City is determined by ascertaining the taxpayer&apos;s operating receipts within the City during the period covered by the report and dividing the sum of the receipts by the taxpayer&apos;s total operating receipts within and without New York City during such period. The following operating receipts are allocable to New York City:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36550" number="43511" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Interest from loans directly administered by, or allocable on, the books and records of the corporation or association to New York City offices or branches.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36551" number="43512" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Rentals from safe deposit boxes serviced by New York City offices or branches.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36552" number="43513" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Rentals from property situated in New York City.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36553" number="43514" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Service charges directly allocable to the New York City office or branch handling the account.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36554" number="43515" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Fees and commissions for services performed in New York City or by New York City offices or branches, or allocable to New York City offices or branches.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36555" number="43516" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Receipts factor – interest from loans.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36556" number="43517" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where loans are directly administered from and by an office or branch, the interest from such loans is receipts allocable to New York City if the office or branch is situated in the City.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36557" number="43518" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If such loans are centrally administered and serviced, but the net income derived therefrom is regularly and properly allocated on the books and records of the corporation or association to an office or branch, the receipts from such loans may be apportioned in the same manner and are allocable to New York City if the office or branch is situated in the City.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36558" number="43519" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any such loans are treated on the books and records of the corporation or association as an investment of the corporation or association, or are not properly allocable in the books and records of the corporation or association to an office or branch, the interest derived therefrom shall be excluded in computing the receipts factor.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36559" number="43520" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Receipts factor – safe deposit box rentals.</CHARFORMAT> Rentals from safe deposit boxes are allocable to the branch that services the boxes.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36560" number="43521" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Receipts factor – rents.</CHARFORMAT> Receipts from rentals or real and personal property situated in New York City are allocable to the City. Receipts from rentals include all amounts received by the taxpayer from the use or occupation of property, whether or not such property is owned by the corporation or association.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36561" number="43522" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Receipts factor – service charges.</CHARFORMAT> Service charges are allocable to the office or branch that handles the account.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36562" number="43523" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Receipts factor – fees and commissions.</CHARFORMAT> Fees and commissions are allocable to the office or branch that produced the income.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36563" number="43524" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(h)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Computation of the deposits factor.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36564" number="43525" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In determining the percentage of a corporation&apos;s or association&apos;s deposits within New York City, due allowance must be made for variations in the amount of deposits held by the taxpayers during the preceding calendar year, both within and without New York City, by computing deposits on a quarterly basis.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36565" number="43526" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The term &quot;deposits&quot; means demand deposits, savings accounts, Savings Certificates and any form of time deposits, no matter how termed, less total reserves in respect to such deposits.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36566" number="43527" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A deposit is within New York City if, and so long as, in the case of a time deposit or demand account, it is domiciled at a New York City office or branch of the taxpayer; or, in the case of a Savings Certificate, if such certificate is issued by a New York City office or branch. A time deposit or saving deposit account is considered to be domiciled at a New York City office or branch if such account was opened at, or transferred to, a New York City office or branch of the taxpayer, no matter where subsequent deposits or withdrawals may be made, and so long as such account is maintained as an account of a New York City office or branch on the books of the taxpayer.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36567" number="43528" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Allocation of issued capital stock.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36568" number="43529" version="1834">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A corporation or association taxable under Part 1, of Subchapter 3 of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T11C006" destination-id="0-0-0-0">Chapter 6 of Title 11</LINK>, New York City Administrative Code, which is doing business or carrying on business through offices or branches maintained both within and without the City, must pay a minimum tax of not less than 1 mill except that for the years nineteen hundred seventy-one and those following such minimum tax shall be not less than one and one-quarter mills upon each dollar of that proportion of its issued capital stock on the last day of the calendar year preceding that in which such tax becomes due which its gross income from sources within New York City during such calendar year bears to its gross income derived from all business, both within and without the City, during said year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-36569" number="43530" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In computing the minimum tax on its issued capital stock in the case of a corporation or association not reporting income and deductions on the basis of separate accounting, the part of its issued capital stock allocable to New York City shall be determined by multiplying its issued capital stock by the net income allocation percentage determined as provided in subdivision (d) of this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>