<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-38676" number="45664" version="3">
			<HEADING>Chapter 25: Retail Licensees of the State Liquor Authority</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5353" name="T19C025"/>Chapter 25: Retail Licensees of the State Liquor Authority</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="false">
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38677" number="45665" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-01 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5355" name="T19C025_25-01"/>§ 25-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38678" number="45666" version="748">
									<PARA>When used in these regulations the following terms shall mean or include: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38679" number="45667" version="1109">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>City.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;City&quot; shall mean the City of New York. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38680" number="45668" version="1109">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Commissioner.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Commissioner&quot; shall mean the Commissioner of Finance of the City of New York. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38681" number="45669" version="1109">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>License.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;License&quot; shall mean a license issued pursuant to the Alcoholic Beverage Control Law. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38682" number="45670" version="1109">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>License fees payable.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Licenses fees payable&quot; shall mean:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38683" number="45671" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The annual license fees payable under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law, including the fees payable under § 122 of such law relating to the continuance of business by a receiver or representative, whether or not a lesser sum is paid thereunder.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38684" number="45672" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of summer and winter licenses issued under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law, the license fees payable for the period of time for which a summer or winter license may be issued under such law, whether or not a lesser sum is paid thereunder.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38685" number="45673" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>&quot;License fees payable&quot; do not include:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38686" number="45674" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Amounts paid as filing fees on an initial or renewal application under § 56-a of the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38687" number="45675" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Amounts paid to defray administrative expenses under section 101-bbb of the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law relating to the prohibition against retail sales at less than cost; and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38688" number="45676" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Amounts paid to defray administrative expenses under section 101-bbb of the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law relating to the enforcement of minimum consumer resale prices of wine. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38689" number="45677" version="1109">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Person</CHARFORMAT>. &quot;Person&quot; shall mean an individual, partnership, society, association, joint stock company, corporation, estate, receiver, lessee, trustee, assignee, referee, or any other person acting in a fiduciary or representative capacity, whether appointed by a court or otherwise, and any combination of individuals. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38690" number="45678" version="1109">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Retail licensee</CHARFORMAT>. &quot;Retail licensee&quot; shall mean any person to whom a license has been issued by the State Liquor Authority under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law who sells at retail in the City, for on or off premises consumption, any liquor, wine or beer for the sale of which such license is required. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38691" number="45679" version="1109">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Return</CHARFORMAT>. &quot;Return&quot; shall mean any return required to be filed as herein provided. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38692" number="45680" version="1109">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>State</CHARFORMAT>. &quot;State&quot; shall mean the state of New York. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38693" number="45681" version="1109">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Tax year</CHARFORMAT>. &quot;Tax year&quot; shall mean June first of any calendar year through May thirty-first of the following calendar year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38694" number="45682" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-02 Imposition of the Tax.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5357" name="T19C025_25-02"/>§ 25-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Imposition of the Tax.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38695" number="45683" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The law imposes a tax for the privilege of selling liquor, wine or beer at retail, for on or off premises consumption, within the City of New York, to be paid annually for each tax year, commencing with the tax year beginning on June 1, 1980, by each retail licensee in an amount equal to 25% of the annual license fees payable under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law by such retail licensee for the license year in effect at the commencement of the tax year under the law. A retail licensee who obtains a license subsequent to the commencement of a tax year is required to pay the tax based upon the fees payable under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law by such licensee for the license year in effect at the time such license is issued. The tax imposed is in addition to any and all other taxes paid by such retail licensee.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38696" number="45684" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The tax is required to be paid for each tax year, commencing with the tax year beginning on June 1, 1980, even though the retail licensee may not be engaged in the sale of liquor, wine or beer for the entire tax year. Thus, a retail licensee at the beginning of the tax year who ceases to do business before the expiration of such tax year, or who becomes a retail licensee after the commencement of a tax year, whether or not he ceases to do business at expiration of such tax year, is liable for the tax. Provision for refund of any tax paid is made herein in cases where a retail licensee ceases to do business during the course of a tax year under circumstances which result in, or would entitle him to, a refund of the license fee by the New York State Liquor Authority (See: 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C025_25-08" destination-id="0-0-0-5369">25-08</LINK>).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38697" number="45685" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The amount of the tax required to be paid is determined by applying the tax rate, viz: 25% of the annual license fees, or summer or winter license fees, as the case may be, payable under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law by such retail licensee for the license year in effect at the commencement of the tax year under the law. Where a retail licensee obtains a license subsequent to the commencement of a tax year, the amount of tax required to be paid to the City by such licensee shall be determined by taking that portion of 25% of the annual license fee payable under such law which the remaining number of days in the tax year bears to the total number of days in said tax year, but in no event shall the tax be less than the amount determined by applying such percentage to 25% of the annual license fee payable under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law, as the minimum license fee payable thereunder bears to the annual license fee payable thereunder for such license; and, in the case of summer or winter licenses issued under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law, by taking that portion of 25% of the summer or winter license fee payable under said law which the number of days in the remaining calendar months of the tax year for which summer or winter license is issued bears to the number of days in the total calendar months of the tax year for which summer or winter licenses may be issued, but in no event shall the tax be less than the amount determined by applying such percentage to 25% of the summer or winter license fee payable under said law as the minimum license fee payable thereunder bears to the maximum license fee payable thereunder for such license. In the case of licenses issued under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law for periods of more than one year, the tax required to be paid shall be determined by the license fee payable on a yearly basis. The following will illustrate the above: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38698" number="45686" version="1337">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Illustration 1:</CHARFORMAT> A retail licensee obtains a license on March 1, 1980, for the license year commencing March 1, 1980, and expiring February 28, 1981, and pays the annual license fee of $1,200, the amount payable under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law. He continues in business as a retail licensee to or beyond June 1, 1980. Since the license fee payable for the license year in effect on June 1, 1980 (the date of the commencement of the tax year) is $1,200, the tax payable to the City is 25% thereof, or $300.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109599" number="45687" version="1337">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Illustration 2:</CHARFORMAT> Assume that the amount of the annual license fee payable under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law by the retail licensee for the license year in effect at the time such license is issued is $1,200, and the retail licensee obtains the license on April 1, 1981. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38699" number="45688" version="1337">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>$1,200 × 25% = $300. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38700" number="45689" version="1337">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where:<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>$1,200 = annual license fee payable under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38701" number="45690" version="2500">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="1" strike-out="0" hidden="0">61</CHARFORMAT> × $300 = $50.14 <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>365 </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38702" number="45691" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where:<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>61 = remaining number of days in tax year-April 1st to May 31st, 1981.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38703" number="45692" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>365 = total number of days in tax year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38705" number="45693" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>1/2* of $300 = $150.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109598" number="45694" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Since the tax of $50.14 in item (ii) is less than one-half of $300, the tax required to be paid to the City is $150.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-109597" number="45695" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Illustration 3:</CHARFORMAT> Assume the same facts as in illustration (2) above except that the retail license was obtained August 1, 1981. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38706" number="45696" version="1337">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>$1,200 × 25% = $300.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38707" number="45697" version="1337">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where:<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>$1,200 = annual license fee payable under the New York State Beverage Control Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38708" number="45698" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="1" strike-out="0" hidden="0">304</CHARFORMAT> × $300 = $249.86 <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>365 </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38709" number="45699" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where:<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>304 = remaining number of days in tax year-August 1, 1981 to May 31, 1982.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38710" number="45700" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>365 = total number of days in tax year</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38711" number="45701" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>1/2* of $300 = $150. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38712" number="45702" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Since the tax in item (ii) $249.86 is more than $150, the tax required to be paid to the City is $249.86.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38713" number="45703" version="2471">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Illustration 4:</CHARFORMAT> X obtains a summer liquor license under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law on April 1, 1980 covering the period April 1, 1980 to October 31, 1980 for which he is required to pay $700, although the annual license fee for a yearly liquor license is $1,200. Since the license fee payable for a summer liquor licensee for the license year in effect on June, 1, 1980 (the date of the commencement of the tax year) is $700, the tax payable to the City for such tax year is 25% thereof, or $175. In this illustration it is assumed that the retail licensee intends to and actually obtains another license in 1981 for the period from April 1, 1981 to October 31, 1981. If such retail licensee does not obtain a license for the months of April and May, 1981, he will be deemed to have ceased doing business as a retail licensee not later than October 31, 1980. In such event, he may avail himself of the provisions for refund of the tax paid as prescribed in 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C025_25-08" destination-id="0-0-0-5369">25-08</LINK>. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38714" number="45704" version="1337">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Illustration 5:</CHARFORMAT> A obtains a summer liquor license under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law on April 1, 1981 covering the period April 1, 1981 to October 31, 1981 for which he is required to pay $700, although the annual license fee for a yearly liquor license is $1,200. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38715" number="45705" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>$700 × 25% = $175. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38716" number="45706" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where:<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>$700 = the summer liquor license fee payable under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38717" number="45707" version="2500">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="1" strike-out="0" hidden="0">61</CHARFORMAT> × $175 = $49.88 <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>214 </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38718" number="45708" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where:<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>61 = remaining number of days in remaining calendar months of tax year – April 1, 1981 to May 31, 1981.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38719" number="45709" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>214 = number of days in total calendar months of tax year for which summer license may be issued – June 1, 1980 to October 31, 1980 and April 1, 1981 to May 31, 1981.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38720" number="45710" version="2500">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="0" underline="1" strike-out="0" hidden="0">$600</CHARFORMAT>&#160;<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">or half of</CHARFORMAT> $175 = $87.50 <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>$1,200 </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38721" number="45711" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>
											<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where:<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										</CHARFORMAT>$600 = minimum license fee payable under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38722" number="45712" version="1337">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>$1,200 = the maximum license fee payable under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38723" number="45713" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Since the tax of $49.88 in item (ii) is less than one-half of $175, the minimum tax required to be paid for the tax year ending May 31, 1981 is $87.50 (item (iii)). For the tax year commencing June 1, 1981, A is required to pay a tax of $175 (25% of $700, i.e., the license fee payable for a summer liquor license for the license year in effect on June 1, 1981); provided, however, if A does not obtain another summer liquor license for the months of April and May, 1982 he will be deemed to have ceased doing business as a retail licensee not later than October 31, 1981, in which event he may avail himself of the provisions for refund of the tax so paid as prescribed in 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C025_25-08" destination-id="0-0-0-5369">25-08</LINK> as amended. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38724" number="45714" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-03 Exemptions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5359" name="T19C025_25-03"/>§ 25-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Exemptions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38725" number="45715" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The tax does not apply to:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38726" number="45716" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The State of New York, or any of its agencies, instrumentalities, public corporations (including a public corporation created pursuant to agreement or compact with another State or Canada) or political subdivisions;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38727" number="45717" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The United States of America, and any of its agencies and instrumentalities insofar as it is immune from taxation;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38728" number="45718" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The United Nations or other international organizations of which the United States of America is a member;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38729" number="45719" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any corporation, or trust, or community chest, fund, or foundation organized and operated exclusively for religious, charitable, or educational purposes, or for the prevention of cruelty to children or animals, no part of the net earnings of which inures to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual and no substantial part of the activities of which is carrying on propaganda, or otherwise attempting to influence legislation, provided, however, that nothing in this paragraph shall include an organization operated for the primary purpose of carrying on a trade or business for profit, whether or not all of its profits are payable to one or more organizations described in this paragraph.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38730" number="45720" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person claiming exemption under paragraph (4) of subdivision (a) hereof must make application for such exemption to the Commissioner of Finance and is required to submit to the Commissioner of Finance such information as will enable the Commissioner to rule upon the applicant&apos;s status. The Commissioner, if satisfied that the applicant is entitled to the exemption, will issue a letter of exemption to the applicant. A corporation or unincorporated entity organized and operated for nonprofit purposes claiming exemption is required to submit an affidavit which shall set forth the following.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38731" number="45721" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The type of organization,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38732" number="45722" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The purpose for which it is organized,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38733" number="45723" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Its actual activities,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38734" number="45724" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The source and disposition of its income,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38735" number="45725" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whether or not any of its income is credited to surplus or may inure to any private stockholder or individual, and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38736" number="45726" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Such other facts which may affect its right to exemption. The affidavit must be supplemented by a copy of the articles of incorporation, or articles of association, as the case may be, a copy of the by-laws of the organization, a financial statement showing its assets and liabilities for the most recent year, a statement of its receipts and disbursements for the most recent year, and a photostatic copy of the letter, if any, from the United States Treasury Department granting the organization exemption from Federal income taxation.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38737" number="45727" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-04 Returns.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5361" name="T19C025_25-04"/>§ 25-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Returns.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38738" number="45728" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Every person subject to the tax for the tax year beginning June 1, 1980 must file a return on or before August 25th, 1980 and annually thereafter on or before the 25th day of June of each year for each tax year during which such person is a retail licensee. Thus, a retail licensee who is in business on or before June 1, 1980 is required to file a return on or before August 25, 1980, and on or before June 25th of each tax year thereafter during which such person is a retail licensee.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38739" number="45729" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A retail licensee who obtains a license subsequent to the commencement of a tax year must file a return for such tax year on or before the 25th day of the month following the month in which such license was obtained, and annually thereafter on or before the 25th day of June, if such person is a retail licensee during the tax years then in effect. Thus, a retail licensee who obtains a license from the New York State Liquor Authority on September 1, 1980, must file a return on or before October 25, 1980, and if he shall be a retail licensee on June 1, 1981, he must also file a return on or before June 25, 1981 and annually thereafter on or before the 25th day of June of each year, if he shall be a retail licensee during each such tax year.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38740" number="45730" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The return required to be filed hereunder shall be filed with the Commissioner of Finance on a form prescribed by the Commissioner. The return shall state the amount of license fees paid to the State under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law and the date when a license under such law was issued to the retail licensee, and shall contain any other information which the Commissioner of Finance may deem necessary. The Commissioner of Finance may require amended returns to be filed within twenty days after notice and to contain the information specified in such notice. If a return required by law is not filed or if a return when filed is incorrect or insufficient on its face, the Commissioner of Finance will take the necessary steps to enforce the filing of such a return or of a corrected return. A return filed by a partnership must be signed by a partner or duly authorized agent having knowledge of the facts; a return of a corporation or other organization must be signed by an officer, agent or member thereof duly authorized to sign the same and having knowledge of the facts contained therein. A change of business organization from individual proprietorship to partnership or corporation, or otherwise, constitutes a change of taxable entity and a separate return must be filed and tax paid by each such separate entity. A termination of business, or removal from the premises, or change of name, should be reported promptly to the Commissioner of Finance. All returns must be filed with the Bureau of Tax Operations of the Department of Finance at the address designated on the return form.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38741" number="45731" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For cause shown, the Commissioner may grant an extension of time not exceeding thirty days within which to file any return under the law. An application for such extension must be made in writing prior to the due date of a return. A return must be filed on or before the date of expiration of the period of time granted. The balance of the tax due, plus interest thereon at the rate prescribed by law, computed from the original due date of the return, must be paid at the time of filing the return.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38742" number="45732" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Electronic filing.</CHARFORMAT> Pursuant to 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C017_17-03" destination-id="0-0-0-5235">17-03</LINK>, the Commissioner may authorize the electronic filing of returns and reports required by this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38743" number="45733" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-05 Identifying Numbers.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5363" name="T19C025_25-05"/>§ 25-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Identifying Numbers.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38744" number="45734" version="3">
									<PARA>Every person required to file a tax return, information return, certificate or other document pursuant to the law or these regulations shall include thereon identifying numbers in the form of his federal employer identification number or, if no such number has been assigned, his social security account number, and his New York State Liquor Authority license serial number, for purposes of proper identification.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38745" number="45735" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-06 Payment of Tax.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5365" name="T19C025_25-06"/>§ 25-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Payment of Tax.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38746" number="45736" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each person subject to the tax imposed by the law is required to pay the tax to the Commissioner of Finance at the time of the filing of a return. The tax is due and payable on the last day on which such return is required to be filed, regardless of whether a return is filed or whether the return which is filed correctly indicates the amount of tax due. The tax may be paid by check, post office money order, express company money order, bank draft, or cash. Postage stamps will not be accepted in payment of the tax. If payment is made by check, money order or draft and a receipt is requested, a duplicate copy of the return must also be submitted, accompanied by return postage. The duplicate copy will be receipted, indicating that payment has been made, and returned to the taxpayer. Cash payments will be accepted only at the Bureau of Tax Operations, 151 West Broadway, New York, N.Y. 10013, by a cashier, before 3 p.m., Monday through Friday. Under no circumstances should cash be sent by mail. Where a cash payment is made at the Bureau of Tax Operations, a duplicate copy of the return in addition to the original thereof must be submitted and the duplicate copy will be receipted by the cashier indicating that payment has been made.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38747" number="45737" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Electronic payment.</CHARFORMAT> Pursuant to 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C017_17-03" destination-id="0-0-0-5235">17-03</LINK>, the Commissioner may authorize the electronic payment of any tax required to be paid by this section.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38748" number="45738" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-07 Determination of Tax.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5367" name="T19C025_25-07"/>§ 25-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Determination of Tax.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38749" number="45739" version="748">
									<PARA>If a return required by the law is not filed, or if a return when filed is incorrect or insufficient, the Commissioner of Finance will determine the amount of tax due from such information as may be obtainable and, if necessary, may estimate the tax on the basis of external indices. Notice of such determination will be given to the person liable for the payment of the tax. Such determination will finally and irrevocably fix the tax unless the person against whom it is assessed, within thirty days after the giving of notice of such determination, shall apply in writing to the Commissioner of Finance for a hearing or unless the Commissioner of Finance of his own motion shall redetermine the tax. After such hearing the Commissioner will give notice of his determination to the person against whom the tax is assessed. The determination of the Commissioner of Finance shall be reviewable for error, illegality or unconstitutionality or any other reason whatsoever by a proceeding under Article 78 of the Civil Practice Law and Rules if application therefor is made to the Supreme Court within thirty days after the giving of the notice of such final determination. A proceeding under Article 78 of the Civil Practice Law and Rules shall not be instituted unless (a) the amount of any tax sought to be reviewed, with interest and penalties thereon, if any, shall be first deposited and there is filed an undertaking with the Commissioner of Finance issued by a surety company authorized to transact business in this State and approved by the Superintendent of Insurance of this State as to solvency and responsibility in such amount as a Justice of the Supreme Court shall approve to the effect that if such proceeding be dismissed or the tax confirmed the petitioner will pay all costs and charges which may accrue in the prosecution of the proceeding or (b) at the option of the petitioner such undertaking must be filed with the Commissioner of Finance in a sum sufficient to cover the taxes, penalties and interest stated in such determination plus the costs and charges which may accrue against it in the prosecution of the proceeding, in which event the petitioner shall not be required to pay such taxes, interest or penalties as a condition precedent to the application.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38750" number="45740" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-08 Refunds.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5369" name="T19C025_25-08"/>§ 25-08 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Refunds.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38751" number="45741" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Commissioner of Finance shall refund or credit, without interest, any tax, penalty or interest erroneously, illegally or unconstitutionally collected or paid, provided:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38752" number="45742" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A written application for refund or credit was made to the Commissioner of Finance within one year from the payment of the tax, penalty or interest, and</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38753" number="45743" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The application is made by the retail licensee or other person who actually paid the tax.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38754" number="45744" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>No specific form has been prescribed for refund applications. An application for refund, however, shall be in writing and shall comply with the following requirements: (1) It must contain a verified statement setting forth the applicant&apos;s reasons for such requested refund.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38755" number="45745" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>It must be signed by the applicant or his duly authorized agent. If signed by an agent, the application must be accompanied by a power of attorney acceptable to the Commissioner of Finance.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38756" number="45746" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>It must demonstrate that the refund provisions of the law have been complied with.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38757" number="45747" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>It must be accompanied by the cancelled check or a photostatic copy thereof, showing both the front and back of the check; or, if paid by cash or money order, by evidence of such payment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38758" number="45748" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where a retail licensee ceases to do business during the course of the tax year under circumstances which result in, or would entitle him to, a refund of a license fee by the New York State Liquor Authority, a refund, without interest, of an appropriate portion of the tax paid under the law will be granted, if, at the time the retail licensee ceases to do business as a retail licensee, at least one month of the tax year remains to run. Such refund shall be computed for the unexpired term of the tax year, for full months commencing with the first day of the month succeeding the one in which such retail licensee ceases to do business as a retail licensee, except that where such cessation of business occurs on the first day of the month that month shall be included in the computation; provided, however, where a refund of the tax or any portion thereof paid under the law is granted to the holder of a summer or winter license, such refund shall be computed for the unexpired months of the tax year for which summer or winter licenses may be issued under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law, for full months commencing with the first day of the month succeeding the one in which such summer or winter retail licensee ceases to do business as a retail licensee, except that where such cessation of business occurs on the first day of the month that month shall be included in the computation. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38759" number="45749" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">For example:</CHARFORMAT> A summer (liquor) retail licensee who obtained a license for the period from April 1, 1981 to October 31,1981 and paid the tax to the City as provided by the law and regulations, and who did not obtain a new license for the period from April 1, 1982 to October 31, 1982, and who meets the requirements of the refund provisions of the law and regulations, would be entitled to a refund on the basis of two-sevenths of the tax paid to the City, said fraction being the ratio that the unexpired term of the tax year (the two months of April and May 1982) bears to the seven months of the tax year (June 1, 1981 to October 31, 1981 and April 1, 1982 to May 31, 1982) for which summer licenses may be issued. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38760" number="45750" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In the case of an application for refund by a retail licensee who ceases to do business during the course of the tax year, under circumstances which result in, or would entitle him to, a refund of the license fee by the New York State Liquor Authority, the applicant shall submit a photostatic copy of the surrender receipt or refund check, executed and delivered to him by such liquor authority, with the application, or at any time thereafter but before the Commissioner of Finance makes any determination with respect to such application, together with such other information as the Commissioner may require. In the event that action on an applicant&apos;s right to a refund by the New York State Liquor Authority is pending before such authority but not concluded at the time the application for refund is filed with the Commissioner of Finance as herein provided, the applicant shall further state the status of his claim or right to refund before such authority, and thereupon, the Commissioner may hold in abeyance any action on such application until the said authority has finally acted thereon, provided, however, that in no event will a refund be granted where the applicant has failed to make written application therefor to the Commissioner within one year from the payment of the tax, penalty or interest. However, where a retail licensee is not entitled to a refund by the New York State Liquor Authority, merely because his license has expired or because he has ceased to do business less than one month before the expiration date of the license issued to him by the New York State Liquor Authority, the provisions of this subdivision (d) and of subdivision (c) shall not apply.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38761" number="45751" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever a taxpayer files a claim for refund, such application shall constitute an application for revision of the tax, penalty or interest complained of. The Commissioner of Finance may audit the taxpayer&apos;s books and records or may grant the refund subject to future audit. The Commissioner of Finance may determine without resorting to an audit that, based upon the evidence presented, the claim is without merit and, therefore, deny it. The Commissioner of Finance will notify the taxpayer in writing of his determination. Such determination shall become final and irrevocable unless the person to whom it is addressed shall, within 30 days after the date thereof, apply to the Commissioner of Finance for a hearing.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38762" number="45752" version="2471">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(f)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the Commissioner of Finance approves the application for refund, he will make such refund or, in lieu thereof, allow credit therefor on payments due from the applicant.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38763" number="45753" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(g)<TAB tab-count="1"/>A taxpayer shall not be entitled to a refund or credit if he has had a hearing or an opportunity for a hearing in connection with a deficiency assessment as provided by law and by 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C025_25-07" destination-id="0-0-0-5367">25-07</LINK>, or has failed to avail himself of the remedies provided thereby, if such refund or credit application is for taxes included in the same period covered by such deficiency assessment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38764" number="45754" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-09 Proceedings to Recover Tax.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5371" name="T19C025_25-09"/>§ 25-09 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Proceedings to Recover Tax.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38765" number="45755" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever any person shall fail to pay any tax or penalty or interest imposed by the law as therein provided, the Corporation Counsel shall, upon request of the Commissioner of Finance, bring or cause to be brought an action to enforce payment of the same against the person liable for the same on behalf of the City of New York in any court of the State of New York or of any other state or of the United States. If, however, the Commissioner of Finance in his discretion believes that a taxpayer subject to the law is about to cease business, leave the state, or remove or dissipate the assets out of which tax or penalties might be satisfied, and that any such tax or penalty will not be paid when due, he may declare such tax or penalty to be immediately due and payable and may issue a warrant immediately.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38766" number="45756" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>As an additional or alternate remedy, the Commissioner of Finance may issue a warrant, directed to the City Sheriff commanding him to levy upon and sell the real and personal property of such person which may be found within the City, for payment of the amount thereof, with any penalties and interest, and the cost of executing the warrant, and to return such warrant to the Commissioner of Finance and to pay to him the money collected by virtue thereof within sixty days after the receipt of such warrant. The City Sheriff shall, within five days after the receipt of the warrant, file with the County Clerk a copy thereof, and thereupon such clerk shall enter in the judgment docket the name of the person mentioned in the warrant and the amount of the tax, penalties, and interest for which the warrant is issued and the date when such copy is filed. Thereupon the amount of such warrant so docketed shall become a lien upon the title to and interest in real and personal property of the person against whom the warrant is issued. The City Sheriff shall then proceed upon the warrant in the same manner and with like effect as that provided by law in respect to executions issued against property upon judgments of a court of record, and for services in executing the warrant he shall be entitled to the same fees which he may collect in the same manner. In the discretion of the Commissioner of Finance, a warrant of like terms, force and effect may be issued and directed to any officer or employee of the Department of Finance, and in the execution thereof such officer or employee shall have all the powers conferred by law upon sheriffs, but he shall be entitled to no fee or compensation in excess of the actual expenses paid in the performance of such duty. If a warrant is returned not satisfied in full, the Commissioner of Finance may from time to time issue new warrants and shall also have the same remedies to enforce the amount due thereunder as if the City has recovered judgment therefor and execution thereon has been returned unsatisfied.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38767" number="45757" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-10 Bulk Sales; Liability of Purchaser.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5373" name="T19C025_25-10"/>§ 25-10 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Bulk Sales; Liability of Purchaser.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38768" number="45758" version="748">
									<PARA>The law provides that whenever there is made a sale, transfer or assignment in bulk of any part or the whole stock of merchandising or of fixtures, or merchandise and of fixtures pertaining to the conducting of the business of the seller, transferor or assignor, otherwise than in the ordinary course of trade and in the regular prosecution of said business, the purchaser, transferee or assignee shall at least ten days before taking possession of such merchandise, fixtures or merchandise and fixtures, or paying therefor, notify the Commissioner of Finance by registered mail of the proposed sale and of the price, terms and conditions thereof whether or not the seller, transferor or assignor, has represented to, or informed the purchaser, transferee or assignee that it owes any tax pursuant to said law and whether or not the purchaser, transferee or assignee has knowledge that such taxes are owing, and whether any such taxes are in fact owing. Whenever the purchaser, transferee or assignee shall fail to give notice to the Commissioner of Finance as required by the preceding paragraph, or whenever the Commissioner of Finance shall inform the purchaser, transferee or assignee that a possible claim for such tax or taxes exists, any sums of money, property or choses in action, or other consideration, which the purchaser, transferee or assignee is required to transfer over to the seller, transferor or assignor shall be subject to a first priority right and lien for any such taxes therefore or thereafter determined to be due from the seller, transferor or assignor to the City, and the purchaser, transferee or assignee is forbidden to transfer to the seller, transferor or assignor any such sums of money, property or choses in action to the extent of the amount of the City&apos;s claim. For failure to comply with the provisions of this subdivision, the purchaser, transferee or assignee, in addition to being subject to the liabilities and remedies imposed under the provisions of Article 6 of the Uniform Commercial Code, shall be personally liable for the payment to the City of any such taxes theretofore or thereafter determined to be due to the City from the seller, transferor or assignor, and such liability may be assessed and enforced in the same manner as the liability for tax under said law.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38769" number="45759" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-11 Records.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5375" name="T19C025_25-11"/>§ 25-11 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Records.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38770" number="45760" version="748">
									<PARA>Every retail licensee must keep records of the date he commenced doing business as a retail licensee, the date of the issuance of a license to him by the State Liquor Authority under the New York State Alcoholic Beverage Control Law, the amount of license fees paid and/or payable for each license, and the period for which such license was issued. Every such retail licensee is also required to keep records of the date, if any, when he discontinued doing business, and of any refund received from the State Liquor Authority, together with the amount thereof and the date received. The Commissioner of Finance may require every retail licensee to keep such other records of his business and in such form as the Commissioner of Finance may from time to time require. Such records shall be offered for inspection and examination at any time upon demand by the Commissioner of Finance or his duly authorized agent or employee, and shall be preserved for a period of three years, except that the Commissioner of Finance may consent to their destruction within that period or may require that they may be kept longer.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38771" number="45761" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-12 Returns to be Secret.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5377" name="T19C025_25-12"/>§ 25-12 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Returns to be Secret.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38772" number="45762" version="748">
									<PARA>Except in accordance with judicial order or as otherwise provided by law, it is unlawful for the Commissioner of Finance or any officer or employee of the Department of Finance to divulge or make known in any manner any information relating to the business of a taxpayer contained in any return required under the law. The officers charged with the custody of such returns are not required to produce any of them or evidence of anything contained in them in any action or proceeding in any court, except on behalf of the Commissioner of Finance in an action or proceeding under the provisions of the law, or on behalf of any party to any action or proceeding under the provisions of the law when the returns or facts shown thereby are directly involved in such action or proceeding, in either of which events the court may require the production of and may admit in evidence so much of the returns or of the facts shown thereby as are pertinent to the action or proceeding and no more. A taxpayer may obtain a certified copy of any return filed in connection with his tax upon application in writing to the Commissioner. Where a representative of a taxpayer applies for a certified copy of such return, he must file a power of attorney with the application. The Corporation Counsel or other legal representatives of the City or the District Attorney of any county within the City may be permitted to inspect the return of any taxpayer who shall bring action to set aside or review the tax based thereon, or against whom an action or proceeding under this title may be instituted. Nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit the publication of statistics so classified as to prevent the identification of particular returns or items thereof.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38773" number="45763" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-13 Interest.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5379" name="T19C025_25-13"/>§ 25-13 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Interest.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38774" number="45764" version="3">
									<PARA>If any amount of tax is not paid on or before the last date prescribed for payment (without regard to any extension of time granted for payment), interest on such amount at the rate prescribed by the law and regulations of the Commissioner of Finance shall be paid for the period from such last date to the date of payment. In computing the amount of interest to be paid with respect to taxes which remain or become due on or after July 16, 1985, such interest shall be compounded daily. No interest shall be paid if the amount thereof is less than one dollar.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38775" number="45765" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-14 Penalties.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5381" name="T19C025_25-14"/>§ 25-14 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Penalties.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38776" number="45766" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Civil penalties. </CHARFORMAT>Any person failing to file a return or to pay over any tax due prior to February 24, 1983, within the time required by law shall be subject to a penalty of five per cent of the amount due. If the Commissioner of Finance is satisfied that the delay was excusable he may remit all or any part of such penalty. With respect to returns or payments which become due on or after February 24, 1983, the following penalties apply:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38777" number="45767" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Failure to file return.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38778" number="45768" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>In case of failure to file a return on or before the prescribed date (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause (see: paragraph (5) of this subdivision (a)) and not due to willful neglect, there is to be added to the amount required to be shown as tax on such return five percent (5%) of the amount of such tax for each month or fraction thereof during which such failure continues, not exceeding twenty-five percent (25%) in the aggregate.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38779" number="45769" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to returns required to be filed on or after July 16, 1985, in the case of a failure to file a return of tax within 60 days of the date prescribed for filing of such return (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not due to willful neglect, the addition to tax under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall not be less than the lesser of one hundred dollars ($100.) or one hundred percent (100%) of the amount required to be shown as tax on such return.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38780" number="45770" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of subparagraphs (i) and (ii) of this paragraph (1), the amount of tax required to be shown on the return shall be reduced by the amount of any part of the tax which is paid on or before the date prescribed for payment of the tax and by the amount of any credit against the tax which may be claimed on the return.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38781" number="45771" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Failure to pay tax shown on return.</CHARFORMAT> In case of failure to pay the amount shown as tax on a return to be filed on or before the prescribed date (determined with regard to any extension of time for payment), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause (see: paragraph (5) of this subdivision (a)) and not due to willful neglect, there shall be added to the amount shown as tax on such return one-half of one percent (1/2%) of the amount of such tax for each month or fraction thereof during which such failure continues, not exceeding twenty-five percent (25%) in the aggregate. For the purpose of computing the addition for any month the amount of tax shown on the return shall be reduced by the amount of any part of the tax which is paid on or before the beginning of such month and by the amount of any credit against the tax which may be claimed on the return. If the amount of tax required to be shown on a return is less than the amount shown as tax on such return, this paragraph shall be applied by substituting such lower amount.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38782" number="45772" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Failure to pay tax required to be shown on return.</CHARFORMAT> In case of failure to pay any amount in respect of any tax required to be shown on a return required to be filed which is not so shown (including a determination made pursuant to 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C025_25-07" destination-id="0-0-0-5367">25-07</LINK>), within ten (10) days of the date of notice and demand, unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause (see: paragraph (5) of this subdivision (a)) and not due to willful neglect, there shall be added to the amount of tax stated in such notice and demand one-half of one percent (1/2%) of such tax for each month or fraction thereof during which such failure continues, not exceeding twenty-five percent (25%) in the aggregate. For the purpose of computing the addition for any month, the amount of tax stated in the notice and demand shall be reduced by the amount of any part of the tax which is paid before the beginning of such month.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38783" number="45773" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Limitations on additions.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38784" number="45774" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to any return the amount of the addition to tax is limited to the following</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38785" number="45775" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>At no time will the addition for one (1) month be more than five percent (5%).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38786" number="45776" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subdivision (a) are both applicable, the addition under paragraph (1) is reduced by the addition under paragraph (2). Thus, the addition to tax will be four and one-half percent (4 1/2%) under paragraph (1) and one-half of one percent (1/2%) under paragraph (2) for each month up to and including the first five (5) months. After the first five (5) months, the addition of one-half of one percent (l/2%) per month pursuant to paragraph (2) will apply for the next forty-five (45) months for a maximum aggregate of forty-seven and one-half percent (47 1/2%) addition to tax. However, in any case described in subparagraph (ii) of paragraph (1) of this subdivision (relating to returns filed after 60 days of the due date) the amount of the addition to tax under such paragraph (1) shall not be reduced below the amount provided in such subparagraph (i.e. the lesser of $100 or 100% of the tax due).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38787" number="45777" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If paragraphs (1) and (3) of this subdivision are both applicable, the maximum amount of the addition to tax may not exceed twenty-five percent (25%) in the aggregate. The maximum amount of the addition to tax pursuant to paragraph (3) of this subdivision shall be reduced by the amount of the addition to tax pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subdivision (determined without regard to subparagraph (ii) of such paragraph (1)) which is attributable to the tax for which the notice and demand is made and which is not paid within ten (10) days of such notice and demand.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38788" number="45778" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of this paragraph may be illustrated by the following examples: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38789" number="45779" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example A(a):</CHARFORMAT> Assume the taxpayer filed his tax return for the tax year beginning June 1, 1983 (due June 25, 1983) on September 30, 1983, and the failure to file on or before the prescribed date is not due to reasonable cause. The tax shown on the return is $800 and a deficiency of $200 is subsequently assessed, making the tax required to be shown on the return, $1,000. The amount shown due on the return of $800 is paid on October 31, 1983. The failure to pay on or before the prescribed date is not due to reasonable cause. There will be imposed, in addition to interest, an additional amount under paragraph (2), of $20.00, which is 2.5 percent (2% for the 4 months from June 26 through October 25, and 0.5% for the fractional part of the month from October 26 through October 31) of the amount shown due on the return of $800. There will also be imposed an additional amount under paragraph (1) of $184, determined as follows: <LINEBRK/>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38790" number="45780" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="26" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="6" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>20 percent (5% per month for the 3 months from June 26 through September 25 and 5% for the fractional part of the month from September 26 through September 30) of the amount due of $1,000 required to be shown on the return</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="right"> $200</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Reduced by the amount of the addition imposed under paragraph (2) for those months</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="right">$16</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Addition to tax under paragraph (1)</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="right"> $184</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38791" number="45781" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example A(b):</CHARFORMAT> A notice and demand for the $200 deficiency is issued on January 8, 1984, but the taxpayer does not pay the deficiency until December 23, 1984. In addition to interest there will be imposed an additional amount under paragraph (3) of $10, determined as follows: <LINEBRK/>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38792" number="45782" version="2497">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="26" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="6" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Addition computed without regard to limitation: 6 percent (5 1/2% for the 11 months from January 19, 1984, through December 18, 1984, and 0.5% for the fractional part of the month from December 19 through December 23)of the amount stated in the notice and demand ($200)</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="right">$12</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Limitation on addition:<LINEBRK/>25 percent of the amount stated in the notice and demand ($200)</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="right">$50</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Reduced by the part of the addition under paragraph (1) for failure to file attributable to the $200 deficiency (20% of $200)</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="right">$40</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Maximum amount of the addition under paragraph (3)</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="right">$10</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38793" number="45783" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Example B:</CHARFORMAT> A taxpayer files his tax return for the tax year beginning June 1, 1983, on February 14, 1984, and such delinquency is not due to reasonable cause. The balance due, as shown on the return, of $500 is paid when the return is filed on February 14, 1984. In addition to interest and the addition for failure to pay under paragraph (2) of $20 (8 months at 0.5% per month, 4%), there will also be imposed an additional amount under paragraph (1) of $112.50, determined as follows: <LINEBRK/>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38794" number="45784" version="2497">
									<PARA>
										<TABLE>
											<TABLEFORMAT number-of-widths="2">
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="26" percentage="yes"/>
												<COLUMNFORMAT column-width="6" percentage="yes"/>
											</TABLEFORMAT>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Penalty at 5% for maximum of 5 months, 25% of $500</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="right"> $125.00</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Less reduction for the amount of the addition under paragraph (2): </PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="right">
														</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Amount imposed under paragraph (2) for failure to pay for the months in which there is also an addition for failure to file – 2 1/2 percent for the 5 months June 26 through November 29 of the net amount due ($500)</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="right">$12.50</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
											<ROW>
												<COL>
													<PARA>Addition to tax under paragraph (1)</PARA>
												</COL>
												<COL>
													<PARA>
														<PARAFORMAT justify="right"> $112.50</PARAFORMAT>
													</PARA>
												</COL>
											</ROW>
										</TABLE>
									</PARA>
									<PARA>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38795" number="45785" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Reasonable cause as used in paragraphs (1), (2) and (3) must be affirmatively shown in a written statement. The taxpayer&apos;s previous compliance record may be taken into account. Grounds for reasonable cause, where clearly established, may include the following:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38796" number="45786" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>death or serious illness of the responsible officer or employee of the taxpayer, or his unavoidable absence from his usual place of business;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38797" number="45787" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>destruction of the taxpayer&apos;s place of business or business records by fire or other casualty;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38798" number="45788" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>timely prepared reports misplaced by a responsible employee and discovered after the due date;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38799" number="45789" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iv)<TAB tab-count="1"/>inability to obtain and assemble essential information required for the preparation of a complete return despite reasonable efforts;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38800" number="45790" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(v)<TAB tab-count="1"/>any other cause or delinquency which appears to a person of ordinary prudence and intelligence as a reasonable cause for delay in filing a return and which clearly indicates an absence of gross negligence or willful intent to disobey the taxing statutes. Past performance should be taken into account. Ignorance of the law, however, will not be considered reasonable cause.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38801" number="45791" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Underpayment due to negligence.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38802" number="45792" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any part of an underpayment is due to negligence or intentional disregard of the law or rules or regulations thereunder (but without intent to defraud), there shall be added to the tax a penalty in an amount equal to five percent (5%) of the underpayment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38803" number="45793" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to taxes required to be paid on or after July 16, 1985, there shall be added to the tax (in addition to the amount determined under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph) an amount equal to fifty percent of the interest payable under 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C025_25-13" destination-id="0-0-0-5379">25-13</LINK> with respect to the portion of the underpayment described in such subparagraph (i) which is attributable to the negligence or intentional disregard referred to in such subparagraph (i), for the period beginning on the last date prescribed by law for payment of such underpayment (determined without regard to any extension) and ending on the date of the assessment of the tax (or, if earlier, the date of the payment of the tax).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38804" number="45794" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Underpayment due to fraud.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38805" number="45795" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If any part of an underpayment is due to fraud, there shall be added to the tax a penalty in an amount equal to fifty percent (50%) of the underpayment.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38806" number="45796" version="1110">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>With respect to taxes required to be paid on or after July 16, 1985, there shall be added to the tax (in addition to the penalty determined under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph) an amount equal to fifty percent of the interest payable under 19 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T19C025_25-13" destination-id="0-0-0-5379">25-13</LINK> with respect to the portion of the underpayment described in such subparagraph (i) which is attributable to fraud, for the period beginning on the last day prescribed by law for payment of such underpayment (determined without regard to any extension) and ending on the date of the assessment of the tax (or, if earlier, the date of the payment of the tax).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38807" number="45797" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The penalty under this paragraph (paragraph 7) shall be in lieu of the maximum twenty-five percent (25%) penalty due to willful neglect for failure to file a return, (paragraph (1)), the additional one-half of one percent (1/2%) per month for failure to pay tax shown on a return (paragraph (2)), the additional one-half of one percent (1/2%) per month for failure to pay tax required to be shown on a return (paragraph (3)), and the five percent (5%) penalty due to negligence (paragraph (6)).</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38808" number="45798" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(8)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who fails to pay tax, or to make, render, sign or certify any return, or to supply any information within the required time, with fraudulent intent, shall be liable for a penalty of not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000), in addition to any other amounts required under the law to be imposed, assessed and collected by the Commissioner of Finance. The Commissioner of Finance has the power, in his discretion, to waive, reduce or compromise any penalty under this paragraph.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38809" number="45799" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(9)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The additions to tax and penalties provided by this subdivision shall be paid and enforced in the same manner as taxes.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38810" number="45800" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(10)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Whenever a penalty is assessed for failure to pay the tax when due, an application for the remission thereof may be made to the Commissioner of Finance. Such application must be made by the person against whom the penalty is assessed, and must set forth the grounds upon which the remission is requested.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38811" number="45801" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Criminal penalties.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38812" number="45802" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Failure to obey subpoena; false testimony.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38813" number="45803" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who, being duly subpoenaed in connection with a matter arising under the law, to attend as a witness or to produce books, accounts, records, memoranda, documents or other papers,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38814" number="45804" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(A)<TAB tab-count="1"/>fails or refuses to attend without lawful excuse,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38815" number="45805" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(B)<TAB tab-count="1"/>refuses to be sworn,</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38816" number="45806" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(C)<TAB tab-count="1"/>refuses to answer any material and proper question, or</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38817" number="45807" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(D)<TAB tab-count="1"/>refuses, after reasonable notice, to produce books, papers and documents in his possession or under his control which constitute material and proper evidence shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38818" number="45808" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who shall testify falsely in any material matter pending before the Commissioner of Finance shall be guilty of and punishable for perjury.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38819" number="45809" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Willful failure to file a return or report or pay tax.</CHARFORMAT> Any person required to pay any tax or make any return or report, who willfully fails to pay such tax or make such return or report, at the time or times so required, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38820" number="45810" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Fraudulent returns, reports, statements or other documents.</CHARFORMAT>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38821" number="45811" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(i)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who willfully makes and subscribes any return, report, statement or other document which is required to be filed with or furnished to the Commissioner of Finance or to any person, pursuant to the provisions of the law, which he does not believe to be true and correct as to every material matter shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38822" number="45812" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(ii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any person who willfully delivers or discloses to the Commissioner of Finance or to any person, pursuant to the provisions of the law, any list, return, report, account, statement or other document known by him to be fraudulent or to be false as to any material matter shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38823" number="45813" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(iii)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For purposes of this paragraph, the omission by any person of any material matter with intent to deceive shall constitute the delivery or disclosure of a document known by him to be fraudulent or to be false as to any material matter.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38824" number="45814" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Failure to keep records.</CHARFORMAT> Any person who willfully fails to keep or retain any records required to be kept or retained by the law shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38825" number="45815" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commissioner&apos;s Certificate.</CHARFORMAT> The certificate of the Commissioner of Finance to the effect that a tax has not been paid, that a return has not been filed, that information has not been supplied or that records have not been retained shall be prima facie evidence thereof.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-38826" number="45816" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 25-15 Notices, Limitations of Time, Mailing Rules.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-5383" name="T19C025_25-15"/>§ 25-15 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Notices, Limitations of Time, Mailing Rules.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38827" number="45817" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any notice authorized or required under the provisions of the law may be given by mailing the same to the person for whom it is intended in a postpaid envelope addressed to such person at the address given in the last return filed by him pursuant to the provisions of the law or in any application made by him, or if no return has been filed or application made, then to such address as may be obtainable. The mailing of such notice shall be presumptive evidence of the receipt of the same by the person to whom addressed. Any period of time which is determined according to the provisions of the law by the giving of notice shall commence to run from the date of mailing of such notice.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38828" number="45818" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of the Civil Practice Law and Rules or any other law relative to limitations of time for the enforcement of a civil remedy shall not apply to any proceeding or action taken by the City to levy, appraise, assess, determine or enforce the collection of any tax, penalty or interest provided by the law. However, except in the case of a willfully false or fraudulent return with intent to evade the tax, no assessment of additional tax shall be made after the expiration of more than three years from the date of the filing of the return; provided, however, that where no return has been filed as provided by law, the tax may be assessed at any time.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38829" number="45819" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Where, before the expiration of the period prescribed herein for the assessment of an additional tax, a taxpayer has consented in writing that such period be extended, the amount of such additional tax due may be determined at any time within such extended period. The period so extended may be further extended by subsequent consents in writing made before the expiration of the extended period.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38830" number="45820" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The provisions of the regulations of the Commissioner relating to the mailing rules for New York City income and excise tax apply with respect to retail licensee tax returns and payments. Generally, those regulations provide that if a tax return or payment properly addressed with sufficient postage prepaid is delivered to the Department of Finance by U.S. mail after the due date, the date of the U.S. Postal Service postmark stamped on the envelope will be deemed the date of delivery, provided the postmark date falls on or before the due date. Non-U.S. Postal Service postmarks will also be recognized, provided delivery to the Department of Finance occurs within five days of the postmark date. If the five-day limit is exceeded, the taxpayer must establish that the item was actually deposited in the mail by the due date, that the delay in receipt was due to a delay in the transmission of the mail, and the cause of the delay.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-38831" number="45821" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>When the last day prescribed in these regulations for filing a return or paying a tax (including the last day covered by an extension of time) falls on Saturday, Sunday or a legal holiday in the State of New York, the filing of such return or paying of such tax will be considered timely if it is filed or paid on the next succeeding date which is not a Saturday, Sunday or legal holiday.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>