<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Rules" content-collection-id="NYCrules" source-infobase-title="The Rules of the City of New York" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\NYCrules.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCrules_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCrules\output\HUCCVLERTKEUARDR\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCrules_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-477" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-28906" number="33296" version="1960">
			<HEADING>Chapter 26: Rules Concerning the Use of Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel and Emissions Control Technology on Vehicles That Transport Children to and from School</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3837" name="T15C026"/>Chapter 26: Rules Concerning the Use of Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel and Emissions Control Technology on Vehicles That Transport Children to and from School</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-28907" number="33297" version="3">
				<HEADING>Subchapter A: General Provisions</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter A: General Provisions</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28908" number="33298" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 26-01 Definitions.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3839" name="T15C026_26-01"/>§ 26-01 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28909" number="33299" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Best available retrofit technology.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Best available retrofit technology&quot; shall mean a technology, verified by the United States environmental protection agency or the California air resources board, for reducing the emission of pollutants that achieves reductions in particulate matter emissions at the highest classification level for diesel emission control strategies, as set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C026_26-04" destination-id="0-0-0-3845">26-04</LINK>, that is applicable to the particular engine and application. Such technology shall also, at a reasonable cost, achieve the greatest reduction in emissions of nitrogen oxides at such particulate matter reduction level and shall in no event result in a net increase in the emissions of either particulate matter or nitrogen oxides. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28910" number="33300" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commissioner.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Commissioner&quot; shall mean the Commissioner of the New York City Department of Environmental Protection or his or her designee. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28911" number="33301" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Department of education.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Department of education&quot; shall mean the New York city department of education, formerly known as the New York city board of education, and any successor agency or entity thereto, the expenses of which are paid in whole or in part from the city treasury. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28912" number="33302" version="748">
									<PARA>&#160;<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Person.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Person&quot; shall mean any natural person, partnership, firm, company, association, joint stock association, corporation or other legal entity. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28913" number="33303" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Reasonable cost.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Reasonable cost&quot; shall mean that such technology does not cost greater than thirty percent more than other technology applicable to the particular engine and application that falls within the same classification level for diesel emission control strategies, as set forth in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C026_26-04" destination-id="0-0-0-3845">26-04</LINK>, when considering the cost of the strategies, themselves, and the cost of installation. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28914" number="33304" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">School bus.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;School bus&quot; means any vehicle operated pursuant to a school bus contract, designed to transport ten or more children at one time, of the designation &quot;Type C bus&quot; or &quot;Type D bus&quot; as set forth in 17 NYCRR §§ 720.1(Z) and (AA), and used to transport children to or from any school located in the city of New York, and excluding any vehicle utilized primarily to transport children with special educational needs who do not travel to and from school in vehicles used to transport general education students. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28915" number="33305" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">School bus contract.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;School bus contract&quot; shall mean any agreement between any person and the department of education to transport children on a school bus. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28916" number="33306" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Ultra low sulfur diesel fuel.</CHARFORMAT> &quot;Ultra low sulfur diesel fuel&quot; shall mean diesel fuel that has a sulfur content of no more than fifteen parts per million.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-28917" number="33307" version="3">
				<HEADING>Subchapter B: Use of Best Available Retrofit Technology and Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter B: Use of Best Available Retrofit Technology and Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28918" number="33308" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 26-02 Best Available Retrofit Technology Determination.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3841" name="T15C026_26-02"/>§ 26-02 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Best Available Retrofit Technology Determination.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28919" number="33309" version="1813">
									<PARA>Pursuant to § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-163.7" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-163.7</LINK> of the Code, any diesel fuel-powered school bus used to transport children to and from school located in the City of New York shall utilize the Best Available Retrofit Technology (&quot;BART&quot;), as defined in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C026_26-01" destination-id="0-0-0-3839">26-01</LINK>. In making their selections, persons fulfilling school bus contracts are directed to consult the EPA and CARB verified lists at <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="http://www.epa.gov/otaq/retrofit/retroverifiedlist.htm">http://www.epa.gov/otaq/retrofit/retroverifiedlist.htm</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-32" type="Web" url="http://www.arb.ca.gov/diesel/verdev/background.htm">http://www.arb.ca.gov/diesel/verdev/background.htm</LINK>. The persons fulfilling school bus contracts shall select BART for their diesel fuel-powered school buses in accordance with 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C026_26-05" destination-id="0-0-0-3847">26-05</LINK>. Such persons shall notify the Department of their selections, and the Department shall make a determination as to whether the BART selected may be utilized for the vehicle, engine and application for which it was selected. The Department shall notify these persons of its determination.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28920" number="33310" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 26-03 School Buses That Are Not Subject to BART.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3843" name="T15C026_26-03"/>§ 26-03 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">School Buses That Are Not Subject to BART.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28921" number="33311" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any diesel fuel-powered school bus that is equipped with an engine certified to the applicable 2007 United States Environmental Protection Agency standard for particulate matter as set forth in § 86.007-11 of title 40 of the Code of Federal Regulations or to any subsequent United States environmental protection agency standard for such pollutant that is at least as stringent, shall not be required to utilize the BART as defined in 15 RCNY § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Jump" destination-name="T15C026_26-01" destination-id="0-0-0-3839">26-01</LINK>.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28922" number="33312" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any best available retrofit technology, or substantially similar technology, purchased or installed in whole or in part with funds provided by the state of New York or the federal government pursuant to a specific diesel emissions reduction program in effect upon the date of enactment of this section, shall constitute the best available retrofit technology for a period of not less than three years from the date on which such equipment was installed.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28923" number="33313" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 26-04 Classification Levels.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3845" name="T15C026_26-04"/>§ 26-04 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Classification Levels.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28924" number="33314" version="748">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Level IV</CHARFORMAT> A Closed Crankcase Filtration System in combination with any Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF) or other technology verified for a specific application from either the CARB or EPA verified lists that reduces particulate matter emissions by 85 percent or greater, or reduces engine emissions to less than or equal to 0.01 grams diesel particulate matter per brake horsepower-hour. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28925" number="33315" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Level III</CHARFORMAT> A Closed Crankcase Filtration System in combination with any DPF or Flow Through Filter or combination of technologies verified for a specific application from either the CARB or EPA verified lists that reduces diesel particulate matter emissions by between 50 and 84 percent. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28926" number="33316" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Level II</CHARFORMAT> A Closed Crankcase Filtration System in combination with any DOC or Flow Through Filter or other technology verified for a specific application from either the CARB or EPA verified lists that reduces diesel particulate matter emissions by between 25 and 49 percent. </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28927" number="33317" version="1071">
									<PARA>
										<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Level I</CHARFORMAT> A Closed Crankcase Filtration System in combination with any DOC or emulsified diesel fuel or Flow Through Filter or other technology verified for a specific application from either the CARB or EPA verified lists that reduces diesel particulate matter emissions by between 20 and 24 percent.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28928" number="33318" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 26-05 Selection Process.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3847" name="T15C026_26-05"/>§ 26-05 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Selection Process.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28929" number="33319" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>For each type of school bus subject to the BART requirement, the person fulfilling a school bus contract must identify, in list form, all types of pollution control technology devices verified for such type of school bus at classification Level IV.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28930" number="33320" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>All types of pollution control technology devices identified by such person as classification Level IV devices that are not technologically feasible for use with respect to the particular vehicle, engine or application are to be eliminated from such list. The engine model year should be considered for BART selection among different DPFs as an active filter is necessary for pre-1994 engine model years. To eliminate all types of pollution control technology devices identified by such person at classification Level IV, or a specific type of pollution control technology, or a particular pollution control technology device, such person must demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Commissioner that operational constraints or physical, chemical or engineering principles preclude the successful and effective use of the school bus when used with such types of technology devices, or type of technology, or particular pollution control technology device.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28931" number="33321" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If, after the elimination process, no pollution control technology devices remain in classification Level IV from which such person can select a BART, the same identification and elimination process must be done for classification Level III. If, after the elimination process, no pollution control technology devices remain in classification Level III from which such person can select a BART, the same identification and elimination process must be done for classification Level II. If, after the elimination process, no pollution control technology devices remain in classification Level II from which such person can select a BART, the same identification and elimination process must be done for classification Level I.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28932" number="33322" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Once a level is selected as provided for in subdivisions (a), (b), and (c) of this section, an economic impact analysis is to be performed on the remaining technologies where the technology reduces both PM and nitrogen oxide (NOx). Such person shall select the technology achieving, at a reasonable cost, the greatest reduction in NOx emissions. If the NOx emission does not meet the reasonable cost test, the technology that achieves the greatest PM reduction from the other remaining technologies must be selected.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28933" number="33323" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 26-06 Best Available Retrofit Technology Selection Applicability.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3849" name="T15C026_26-06"/>§ 26-06 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Best Available Retrofit Technology Selection Applicability.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28934" number="33324" version="3">
									<PARA>No person fulfilling a school bus contract shall be required to replace a selected BART within three years of having first utilized such technology. Furthermore, no person fulfilling a school bus contract shall be required to replace Level IV technology until it has reached the end of its useful life.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28935" number="33325" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 26-07 Use of Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3851" name="T15C026_26-07"/>§ 26-07 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Use of Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28936" number="33326" version="1813">
									<PARA>All diesel fuel-powered school buses used to transport children to or from any school located in the City of New York must be powered by ultra low sulfur diesel fuel unless the Commissioner has issued a waiver pursuant to subdivision (g) of § <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-31" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="24-163.7" destination-id="0-0-0-0">24-163.7</LINK> of the Code.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Subchapter" style-name-escaped="Subchapter" style-id="0-0-0-480" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-28937" number="33327" version="3">
				<HEADING>Subchapter C: Waiver Procedures</HEADING>
				<PARA>Subchapter C: Waiver Procedures</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Subtitle" style-name-escaped="Subtitle" style-id="0-0-0-15301" level-depth="4" toc-section="false">
				<LEVEL style-name="Part" style-name-escaped="Part" style-id="0-0-0-483" level-depth="5" toc-section="false">
					<LEVEL style-name="Subpart" style-name-escaped="Subpart" style-id="0-0-0-15960" level-depth="6" toc-section="false">
						<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-486" level-depth="7" toc-section="true">
							<RECORD id="0-0-0-28938" number="33328" version="3">
								<HEADING>§ 26-08 Waiver for the Use of BART Based on Written Finding of Unavailability by Department of Education.</HEADING>
								<PARA>
									<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-3853" name="T15C026_26-08"/>§ 26-08 <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Waiver for the Use of BART Based on Written Finding of Unavailability by Department of Education.</CHARFORMAT>
								</PARA>
							</RECORD>
							<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28939" number="33329" version="2512">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(a)<TAB tab-count="1"/>If the BART required for a school bus in unavailable, a person fulfilling a school bus contract may apply for a waiver for the use of BART. Such application must be based on a Written Finding of Unavailability by the Department of Education indicating that the BART for the subject school bus is unavailable for purchase. Such application shall also contain the following:</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28940" number="33330" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name of the person fulfilling the school bus contract who is applying for approval of the Written Finding of Unavailability;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28941" number="33331" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name and identification number of the subject contract, if applicable;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28942" number="33332" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification of the school bus that is the subject of the Written Finding of Unavailability;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28943" number="33333" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification of the required BART;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28944" number="33334" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>An explanation as to why the required BART is unavailable. Such explanation must include all documentation generated in the BART selection process described in this chapter;</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28945" number="33335" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Identification of a technology for reducing the emission of pollutants, if any, that is available and appropriate for such vehicle, which may include a technology that does not appear on the EPA or CARB verified lists, and that, if available and appropriate, will be used instead of the BART.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28946" number="33336" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(7)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The name and contact number of the applicant.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28947" number="33337" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(b)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Applications should be sent to: </PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28948" number="33338" version="33">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Director of the Division of Air and Noise Programs, Enforcement and Policy <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Bureau of Environmental Compliance<LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>New York City Department of Environmental Protection <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>59-17 Junction Blvd. <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>Flushing, NY 11373 <LINEBRK/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>or by email to bartwaivers@dep.nyc.gov <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-012]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28949" number="33339" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(c)<TAB tab-count="1"/>The Commissioner will make a determination whether to approve the Written Finding of Unavailability no later than thirty days after receipt of the application.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28950" number="33340" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(d)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Waivers are effective for three years. Any application for renewal shall be submitted no later than thirty days prior to the expiration date of the waiver.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-28951" number="33341" version="3">
									<PARA>
										<TAB tab-count="1"/>(e)<TAB tab-count="1"/>Contractors shall maintain records that include the installation date of the BART as well as the engine model year and engine manufacturer.</PARA>
								</RECORD>
								<RECORD id="0-0-0-96904" number="33342" version="33">
									<PARA>(Amended City Record 3/15/2017, eff. 4/14/2017) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-33">[ALP S-012]</HIGHLIGHTER>
									</PARA>
								</RECORD>
							</LEVEL>
						</LEVEL>
					</LEVEL>
				</LEVEL>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>