<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Charter" content-collection-id="NYCcharter" source-infobase-title="New York City Charter" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCcharter\output\XIIBFNTGOGPHNCEJ\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCcharter\output\XIIBFNTGOGPHNCEJ\NYCcharter.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCcharter_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCcharter\output\XIIBFNTGOGPHNCEJ\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCcharter_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-35" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-1262" number="2202" version="458">
			<HEADING>Chapter 11: Independent Budget Office</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-411" name="Chapter 11"/>Chapter 11: Independent Budget Office</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-1263" number="2203" version="3">
				<HEADING>Section 259. Independent budget office. </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-413" name="259"/>Section 259. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Independent budget office. </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-1264" number="2204" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be an independent budget office to be headed by a director who shall be appointed upon the recommendation of the independent budget office advisory board, by a special committee convened for this purpose. Such committee shall consist of the comptroller, the public advocate, a borough president chosen by the borough presidents, and a council member chosen by the council, and shall act by majority vote. The director shall be appointed without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties assigned by this chapter. The term of office of the director first appointed shall expire on August first, two thousand, and the terms of office of directors subsequently appointed shall expire on such date in each fourth year thereafter. Any individual appointed to fill a vacancy prior to the expiration of a term shall serve only for the unexpired portion of the term. An individual serving as director at the expiration of a term may continue to serve until a successor is appointed.</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-1265" number="2205" version="768">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The appropriations available to pay for the expenses of the independent budget office during each fiscal year shall not be less than ten per centum of the appropriations available to pay for the expenses of the office of management and budget during such fiscal year. The director shall appoint such personnel and procure the services of such experts and consultants, within the appropriations available therefor, as may be necessary for the director to carry out the duties and functions assigned herein. Such personnel and experts shall perform such duties as may be assigned to them by the director. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-1266" number="2206" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The director shall be authorized to secure such information, data, estimates and statistics from the agencies of the city as the director determines to be necessary for the performance of the functions and duties of the office, and such agencies shall provide such information, to the extent that it is available, in a timely fashion. The director shall not be entitled to obtain records which are protected by the privileges for attorney-client communications, attorney work product, and material prepared for litigation. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-1267" number="2207" version="48">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be an independent budget office advisory committee consisting of ten members appointed jointly by the comptroller and the public advocate for five year staggered terms. Of the members originally appointed, two shall serve until the thirty-first day of March, nineteen hundred ninety-nine, two shall serve until the thirty-first day of March, two thousand, two shall serve until the thirty-first day of March, two thousand one, two shall serve until the thirty-first day of March, two thousand two and two shall serve until the thirty-first day of March, two thousand three. The members shall all be individuals with extensive experience and knowledge in the fields of finance, economics, accounting, public administration and public policy analysis, including at least one former director of the New York city office of management and budget or of a comparable office in another local government jurisdiction in the United States; one nationally recognized expert in the fields of budget theory and the budgetary process; one former director of the New York state division of the budget or of a comparable legislative or executive office in another state government; one dean or director or former dean or director of a graduate school of business administration located in New York city; one dean or director or former dean or director of a graduate school of public administration or public affairs or public policy located in New York city; one chair or former chair of a graduate economics department of a college or university located in New York city; one officer or former officer of, or economic advisor of, a labor union; one officer or former officer of, or economic advisor to, a business corporation; one officer or former officer of a civic or public interest advocacy organization involved in budgetary matters; and one officer or former officer of a human services advocacy organization involved in budget matters. No member may be reappointed to consecutive terms. Vacancies occurring because of the expiration of terms shall be filled promptly on the recommendation of the members of the committee whose terms are not expiring. Vacancies occurring otherwise shall be filled promptly on the recommendation of the remaining members of the committee. The members of the committee shall receive no compensation but shall be reimbursed for their necessary expenses. The committee shall at its first meeting in every even numbered year elect, from among its members, a chair and vice-chair who shall serve until the thirty-first day of March of the next even numbered year. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-1268" number="2208" version="3">
				<HEADING>Section 260. Powers and duties. </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-415" name="260"/>Section 260. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Powers and duties. </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-1269" number="2209" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>It shall be the duty of the office to provide to the comptroller, the president of the council, the members and committees of the council, the borough presidents, and the community boards information which will assist such officials and bodies in the discharge of their responsibilities which are related to the budgetary process, including:</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-1270" number="2210" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>information with respect to the budget, appropriations bills and proposed local laws with fiscal implications; </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-1271" number="2211" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>information with respect to estimated revenues and receipts and changing revenue conditions; and </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-1272" number="2212" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>to the extent practicable, such other information or analyses as may be requested by such officials and bodies. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-1273" number="2213" version="87">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The director, upon the request of a borough president or the president of the council for a proposed local law introduced by such official, or the chair or ranking minority member of a committee of the council for a proposed local law being considered by such committee, shall complete a fiscal impact statement of such proposed local law consistent with the requirements of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Jump" destination-name="33" destination-id="0-0-0-125">thirty-three</LINK>. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-1274" number="2214" version="84">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The director shall from time to time publish such reports as may be appropriate to enhance official and public understanding of the budgetary process and of the budget documents published in accordance with the provisions of <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Jump" destination-name="Chapter 6" destination-id="0-0-0-197">chapters six</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Jump" destination-name="Chapter 9" destination-id="0-0-0-301">nine</LINK> and <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Jump" destination-name="Chapter 10" destination-id="0-0-0-341">ten</LINK>. The director shall from time to time publish such reports as may be necessary or appropriate to provide such information, data, and analysis as will enhance official and public understanding of matters relating to city revenues, expenditures, financial management practices and related matters. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-1275" number="2215" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The director may procure, for the office, up-to-date computer equipment, obtain the services of experts and consultants in computer technology, and develop techniques for the evaluation of revenue projections and budgetary requirements. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-1276" number="2216" version="80">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The director shall make all information, data, estimates, and statistics obtained under subdivision c of section ninety-eight, and all studies and reports prepared by the office, available for public inspection and copying during normal business hours and shall, to the extent practicable, furnish a copy of any such information or report to any person upon request at a reasonable cost. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>