<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="#!-- #STYLESHEETS:ALP.xsl --#"?>

<DOCUMENT source-infobase-name="Charter" content-collection-id="NYCcharter" source-infobase-title="New York City Charter" base-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCcharter\output\XIIBFNTGOGPHNCEJ\" default-split-level="Chapter" makefile-filename="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCcharter\output\XIIBFNTGOGPHNCEJ\NYCcharter.mak" css-stylesheet-href="#!-- #ID=NYCcharter_css_id --#" xml-output-dir="D:\process\NFOProcess\codes\ny\newyorkcity\NYCcharter\output\XIIBFNTGOGPHNCEJ\XML\" css-stylesheet-name="NYCcharter_css" makefile-document-depth="2">
	<LEVEL style-name="Chapter" style-name-escaped="Chapter" style-id="0-0-0-35" level-depth="2" toc-section="false">
		<RECORD id="0-0-0-6170" number="4725" version="528">
			<HEADING>Chapter 47: Public Access to Meetings and Information</HEADING>
			<PARA>
				<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1059" name="Chapter 47"/>Chapter 47: Public Access to Meetings and Information</PARA>
		</RECORD>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-3080" number="4726" version="3">
				<HEADING>Section 1058. Heads of departments to furnish copies of papers on demand. </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1061" name="1058"/>Section 1058. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Heads of departments to furnish copies of papers on demand. </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3081" number="4727" version="617">
					<PARA>The heads of all administrations and departments, except the police and law departments, and the chiefs of each and every division or bureau thereof, and all borough presidents shall, with reasonable promptness, furnish to any taxpayer desiring the same, a true and certified copy of any book, account or paper kept by such administration, department, bureau or office, or such part thereof as may be demanded, upon payment in advance of ten cents for every hundred words thereof by the person demanding the same. The provisions of this section shall not apply to any papers prepared by or for the comptroller for use in any proceeding to adjust or pay a claim against the city or any agency, or by or for counsel for use in actions or proceedings to which the city or any agency is a party, or for use in any investigation authorized by this charter. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-3082" number="4728" version="3">
				<HEADING>Section 1059. Inspection by taxpayers of books and papers. </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1063" name="1059"/>Section 1059. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Inspection by taxpayers of books and papers. </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3083" number="4729" version="617">
					<PARA>All books, accounts and papers in the office of any borough president or any division or bureau thereof, or in any city administration or department or any division or bureau thereof, except the police and law departments, shall at all times be open to the inspection of any taxpayer, subject to such reasonable rules and regulations in regard to the time and manner of such inspection as the borough president, administration, department, office, division or bureau may make; in case such inspection shall be refused, such taxpayer, on his sworn petition, describing the particular book, account or paper that he desires to inspect, may, upon notice of not less than one day, apply to any justice of the supreme court for an order that he be allowed to make such inspection as such justice shall by his order authorize. The provisions of this section shall not apply to any papers prepared by or for the comptroller for use in any proceedings to adjust or pay a claim against the city or any agency, or by or for counsel for use in actions or proceedings to which the city or any agency is a party, or for use in any investigation authorized by this charter. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-3084" number="4730" version="3">
				<HEADING>Section 1060. Public attendance at executive sessions. </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1065" name="1060"/>Section 1060. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Public attendance at executive sessions. </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3085" number="4731" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Except as otherwise provided pursuant to subdivision b of this section, the public may attend all sessions or meetings of the following agencies whenever items on the calendar of such agency are to be considered and acted upon in a preliminary or final manner; art commission, conciliation and appeals board, environmental control board, board of health, landmarks preservation commission, city planning commission, board of standards and appeals, tax commission, youth board, and the council and its committees.</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3086" number="4732" version="48">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Any agency specified pursuant to subdivision a of this section may convene an executive session closed to the public by a three-fourths vote of all of its members, but shall not take final action at any such meeting. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-3087" number="4733" version="3">
				<HEADING>Section 1061. Commission on public information and communication. </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1067" name="1061"/>Section 1061. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Commission on public information and communication. </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3088" number="4734" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be a commission on public information and communication which shall consist of the public advocate, as chair, the corporation counsel or the delegate of such officer, the director of operations or the delegate of such officer, the commissioner of the department of records and information services or the delegate of such officer, the commissioner of information technology and telecommunications or the delegate of such officer, the president of the WNYC communications group or the delegate of such officer, and one council member elected by the council, all of whom shall serve on the board without compensation. In addition, there shall be four other members, each appointed for a four-year term, who shall not hold or seek public or political party office or be public employees in any jurisdiction, except the representative of the community board as set forth herein, to be appointed as follows: two by the mayor, one of whom is or has been a representative of the news media and one of whom shall be a member of a community board; one by the public advocate; and one by the borough presidents acting as a group. Such members shall receive a per diem compensation for each calendar day they perform the work of the commission. No such members shall serve for more than two consecutive four-year terms. All initial appointments shall be made by the first day of March, nineteen hundred ninety.</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3089" number="4735" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Members may be removed by the mayor for cause after notice and opportunity to be heard. Members shall serve until their successors have been appointed. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3090" number="4736" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commission shall appoint an executive director, a general counsel and such other officers, employees, and consultants as are necessary to fulfill its duties, within appropriations available therefor. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3091" number="4737" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commission shall: </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3092" number="4738" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>(1)<TAB tab-count="1"/>undertake, by itself, or in cooperation with other entities, activities to educate the public about the availability and potential usefulness of city produced or maintained information and assist the public in obtaining access to such information; </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3093" number="4739" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>(2)<TAB tab-count="1"/>review (i) all city information policies, including but not limited to, policies regarding public access to city produced or maintained information, particularly, computerized information; (ii) the quality, structure, and costs to the public of such information; (iii) agency compliance with the various notice, comment, and hearing provisions of the charter and other laws applicable to city agencies; and (iv) the usefulness and availability of city documents, reports, and publications; </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3094" number="4740" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>(3)<TAB tab-count="1"/>assist city agencies in facilitating public access to their meetings, transcripts, records, and other information, and monitor agency compliance with the provisions of the charter, and other laws which require such public access; </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3095" number="4741" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>(4)<TAB tab-count="1"/>hold at least one public hearing each year on city information policies and issue at least one report each year with such recommendations as the commission deems advisable; </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3096" number="4742" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>(5)<TAB tab-count="1"/>on the request of any member of the public, elected official, or city agency, render advisory opinions regarding the application of those provisions of the charter or other laws which require public access to meetings, transcripts, records and other information. Such advisory opinions shall be indexed by subject matter and maintained on a cumulative basis; </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3097" number="4743" version="48">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>(6)<TAB tab-count="1"/>make recommendations regarding: (i) the application of new communications technology to improve public access to city produced or maintained information; (ii) the distribution of information to the public about the purposes and locations of the city&apos;s service delivery facilities; and (iii) programming for the municipal cable channels and broadcasting system. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3098" number="4744" version="723">
					<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-19">
						<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Administrative Code Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="L.L. 1994/024" destination-id="0-0-0-0">L.L. 1994/024</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-6800" number="4745" version="723">
				<HEADING>Section 1062. Public data directory. </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1069" name="1062"/>Section 1062. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Public data directory. </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3099" number="4746" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commission shall publish annually a directory of the computerized information produced or maintained by city agencies which is required by law to be publicly accessible. Such directory shall include specific descriptions of the contents, format and methods of accessing such information, and the name, title, office address, and office telephone number of the official in each agency responsible for receiving inquiries about such information.</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3100" number="4747" version="48">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The mayor shall transmit to the commission such information as the commission requires to compile and update the public data directory. The mayor shall also ensure that all agencies provide the commission with such assistance and information as the commission requires. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-3101" number="4748" version="3">
				<HEADING>Section 1063. Cablecasting and broadcasting the public proceedings of city government. </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1071" name="1063"/>Section 1063. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Cablecasting and broadcasting the public proceedings of city government. </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-6856" number="4749" version="787">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All future cable franchises and franchise renewals shall require (i) that channels be designated for governmental use and (ii) that the franchisee provide the interconnections necessary to allow the cablecasting of the public proceedings of the council and its committees and the city planning commission.</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3103" number="4750" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The council and its committees and the city planning commission shall make their public meetings and hearings available for cablecasting and broadcasting. The council, on the recommendation of the commission on public information and communication, may by local law require that other agencies of city government be subject to the requirements of this subdivision. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3104" number="4751" version="787">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Reserved. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-086]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3105" number="4752" version="787">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each city agency, committee, commission and task force and the council shall record or cause to be recorded in digital video format its meetings and hearings, or portions thereof, that are required to be public pursuant to article seven of the public officers law, provided that this section shall not apply to community boards or local school boards. Such recordings shall be webcast live, where practicable, and shall be archived and made available to the public on the city&apos;s website or on the website of such agency, committee, commission, task force, or council, not more than seventy-two hours after adjournment of the meeting or hearing recorded.</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3106" number="4753" version="787">
					<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2023/069, 5/29/2023, eff. 6/28/2023) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-086]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-6872" number="4754" version="787">
				<HEADING>Section 1064. Centralized contract and contractor information. </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1073" name="1064"/>Section 1064. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Centralized contract and contractor information. </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-4507" number="4755" version="236">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The mayor shall maintain, in a central place which is accessible to the public, standard information regarding each city contract and contractor. Such information shall include: (1) a copy of the contract; (2) information regarding the method by which the contract was let; (3) such standard documents as the contractor is required to submit, which documents shall be updated regularly in accordance with rules of the procurement policy board; (4) information regarding the contractor&apos;s qualifications and performance; (5) any evaluations of the contractor and any contractor responses to such evaluations; (6) any audits of the contract and any contractor responses to such audits; and (7) any decisions regarding the suspension or debarment of the contractor.</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3108" number="4756" version="133">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The procurement policy board shall regularly review the scope and form of all information maintained pursuant to this section and shall promulgate rules regarding its contents, organization and management. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3109" number="4757" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The mayor shall ensure adequate public access to the information on contracts and contractors, which shall be maintained in a manner to facilitate public review, with due consideration for the need to protect, where appropriate, the confidentiality of any such information. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3110" number="4758" version="772">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The information on contracts and contractors shall be computerized to the extent feasible. The computerized information shall be stored in a manner which allows for meaningful read-only access to such information by the agency name, contractor name, contract category, and contract number included in prior notices published in the City Record pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Jump" destination-name="325" destination-id="0-0-0-497">three hundred twenty-five</LINK>. At least one computer terminal shall be available for such access in the central place established by the mayor pursuant to subdivision a of this section, and such access shall also be provided to the public through the City&apos;s website. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-032]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-5202" number="4759" version="236">
					<PARA> (Am. L.L. 2017/076, 5/10/2017, eff. 1/1/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-032]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-3111" number="4760" version="3">
				<HEADING>Section 1065. Budget documents. </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1075" name="1065"/>Section 1065. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Budget documents. </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3112" number="4761" version="617">
					<PARA>Each budget document required by <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Jump" destination-name="Chapter 10" destination-id="0-0-0-341">chapters ten</LINK>, <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Jump" destination-name="Chapter 6" destination-id="0-0-0-197">six</LINK>, or <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Jump" destination-name="Chapter 9" destination-id="0-0-0-301">nine</LINK> of the charter shall be a public document. The official or agency responsible for preparing each such document shall file a copy in the municipal reference and research center, in the principal branch library of each borough and, for the various geographic based budget documents, in the relevant branch library. Copies of each such required budget document shall also be made available for reasonable public inspection in the office of the official or agency responsible for preparing it. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-3113" number="4762" version="3">
				<HEADING>Section 1066. City Record. </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1077" name="1066"/>Section 1066. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">City Record. </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3114" number="4763" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be published daily, except Saturdays, Sundays and legal holidays, under contract or by the department of citywide administrative services, a paper to be known as the City Record.</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3115" number="4764" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>There shall be inserted in the City Record nothing aside from such official matters as are expressly authorized. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3116" number="4765" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All advertising required to be done for the city, except as otherwise provided by law, shall be inserted at the public expense in the City Record and a publication therein shall be sufficient compliance with any law requiring publication of such matters or notices. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3117" number="4766" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Nothing herein contained shall prevent the publication elsewhere of any advertisement required by law to be so published. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3118" number="4767" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of citywide administrative services shall cause a continuous series of the City Record to be bound as completed quarterly and to be deposited with his or her certificate thereon in the office of the city register, in the county clerk&apos;s office of each county and in the office of the city clerk; and copies of the contents of any part of the same, certified by such register, county clerk or city clerk, shall be received in judicial proceedings as prima facie evidence of the truth of the contents thereof. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3119" number="4768" version="85">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>f.<TAB tab-count="1"/>The commissioner of citywide administrative services shall provide copies of each issue of the City Record to the municipal reference and research center where they shall be available without charge to any member of the public requesting a copy on the publication date or within a reasonable period of time thereafter, to be determined by the commissioner of records and information services. The commissioner shall also provide free subscriptions to the City Record to each borough president, council member, community board, and branch of the public library and to the news media as defined in paragraph three of subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Jump" destination-name="1043" destination-id="0-0-0-1011">one thousand forty-three</LINK> of the charter. The commissioner of citywide administrative services, each borough president, council member and community board shall, upon receipt, make copies of each issue of the City Record available in their respective offices for reasonable public inspection without charge.</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-4570" number="4769" version="409">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>g.<TAB tab-count="1"/>All information published in the City Record after the effective date of the local law that created this subdivision shall be available as soon as possible, but no later than 24 hours of publishing, at no charge on a website maintained by or on behalf of the city of New York as well as on a single web portal that is linked to <LINK style-name="Web" style-name-escaped="Web" style-id="0-0-0-23" type="Web" url="nyc.gov">nyc.gov</LINK> or any successor website maintained by, or on behalf of, the city of New York created pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="23-502" destination-id="0-0-0-0">23-502</LINK> of the administrative code. Such information shall be available in both a non-proprietary, machine-readable format and a human-readable format and shall be capable of being downloaded in bulk. Such information shall be searchable by, at minimum, date of publication, relevant agency, keyword, and category, such as public hearings, procurement notices, and changes in personnel. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-014]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3120" number="4770" version="711">
					<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-19">
						<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Administrative Code Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="L.L. 1996/059" destination-id="0-0-0-0">L.L. 1996/059</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-085]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-6759" number="4771" version="711">
				<HEADING>Section 1067. Organization of the agency; notice. </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1079" name="1067"/>Section 1067. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Organization of the agency; notice. </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3121" number="4772" version="617">
					<PARA>In January, nineteen hundred ninety and every year thereafter, in accordance with the notice procedures of subdivision b of section<LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Jump" destination-name="1043" destination-id="0-0-0-1011"> one thousand forty-three</LINK> of this charter, the head of each agency shall cause to be published in the City Record and shall give notice of a written plan or chart describing the organization of the agency. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-3122" number="4773" version="3">
				<HEADING>Section 1068. [Resolutions amending or extending charter.] </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1081" name="1068"/>Section 1068. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">[Resolutions amending or extending charter.] </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3123" number="4774" version="617">
					<PARA>The text of each resolution or similar action provided for by this charter which has the force of law or which amends or extends the charter shall appear as part of the administrative code or of the compilation of city rules required by section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Jump" destination-name="1045" destination-id="0-0-0-1015">one thousand forty-five</LINK>, as the mayor deems appropriate. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-3124" number="4775" version="3">
				<HEADING>Section 1069. Access to public insurance coverage information. </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1083" name="1069"/>Section 1069. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Access to public insurance coverage information. </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3125" number="4776" version="409">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Pursuant to the provisions of this section, each agency designated as a participating agency under the provisions of this section shall implement and administer a program of distribution of the public health insurance program options pamphlet published by the department of health and mental hygiene pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="17-183" destination-id="0-0-0-0">17-183</LINK> of the administrative code of the city of New York. The following offices are hereby designated as participating agencies: the administration for children&apos;s services, the board of education, the city clerk, the commission on human rights, the department for the aging, the department of correction, the department of employment, the department of homeless services, the department of housing preservation and development, the department of juvenile justice, the department of health and mental hygiene, the department of probation, the department of social services/human resources administration, the taxi and limousine commission, the department of youth and community development, the office to end domestic and gender-based violence, and the office of immigrant affairs; provided, however, that the department of health and mental hygiene, as it deems appropriate, may designate additional agencies to be participating agencies. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-034]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3126" number="4777" version="410">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Participating agencies shall be required to: (i) distribute such public health insurance program options pamphlet to all persons requesting a written application for services, renewal or recertification of services or request for a change of address relating to the provision of services by such agency; provided, however, that this section shall not apply to services that must be provided to prevent actual or potential danger to the life, health or safety of any individual or to the public (ii) include a public health insurance program options pamphlet with any agency communication sent through the United States mail for the purpose of supplying an individual with a written application for services, renewal or recertification of services or with a request for a change of address form relating to the provision of services by such agency; and (iii) provide an opportunity for an individual requesting a written application for services, renewal or recertification for services or change of address form relating to the provision of services by such agency via the Internet to request a public health insurance program options pamphlet, and provide such pamphlet, by United States mail or an Internet address where such pamphlet may be viewed or downloaded, to any person who indicates via the Internet that they wish to be sent a public health insurance program options pamphlet; provided, however, that the taxi and limousine commission shall only be required to distribute to public health insurance program options pamphlet to those persons applying for or renewing a driver&apos;s license or vehicle license as those terms are defined in section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="19-502" destination-id="0-0-0-0">19-502</LINK> of this code; and provided further, that the board of education shall be required only to ensure that the public health insurance program options pamphlet is distributed to those individuals who appear in person to register a child in the public school system. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3127" number="4778" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>c.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Participating agencies shall ensure that the employees of such agency do not make any statement to an applicant for services or client or take any action the purpose or effect of which is to lead the applicant or client to believe that a decision to request public health insurance or a public health insurance program options pamphlet has any bearing on their eligibility to receive or the availability of services or benefits provided by such agency. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3128" number="4779" version="3">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>d.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each participating agency shall request that any contractor of such agency operating pursuant to a contract which (i) is in excess of two hundred and fifty thousand dollars and (ii) requires such contractor to supply individuals with a written application for, or written renewal or recertification of services, or request for change of address form in the daily administration of their contractual obligation to such participating agency, fulfill the obligations of participating agencies under this section. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3129" number="4780" version="249">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>e.<TAB tab-count="1"/>Each participating agency may establish procedures as they deem necessary to implement the local law that added this section. The commissioner or head of a participating agency, with the concurrence of the commissioner of the department of health and mental hygiene, may exclude a program in whole or in part from the requirements of this section upon determining that the inclusion of such a program would not substantially further the purpose of the local law that added this section. The commissioner or head of each participating agency that administers programs receiving funds under the workforce investment act of 1998, as codified at 29 U.S.C. § 2801 et seq., shall, with the concurrence of the commissioner of the department of health and mental hygiene, determine which workforce investment act offices providing workforce development services, including core and intensive services or substantive training funded in whole or in part by the city&apos;s share of funds provided under such workforce investment act, shall be required to fulfill the obligations of participating agencies under this section; such determination shall be based upon whether the inclusion of such offices would substantially further the purpose of the local law that added this section. A copy of each determination made pursuant to this subdivision shall be forwarded to the council and the mayor within thirty days of such determination.</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-5228" number="4781" version="412">
					<PARA>(Am. L.L. 2019/038, 2/24/2019, eff. 2/24/2019) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-034]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3130" number="4782" version="691">
					<PARA style-name="EdNoteSm" style-name-escaped="EdNoteSm" style-id="0-0-0-19">
						<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Editor&apos;s note:</CHARFORMAT> For related unconsolidated provisions, see Administrative Code Appendix A at <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="L.L. 2002/001" destination-id="0-0-0-0">L.L. 2002/001</LINK>. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-084]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-6590" number="4783" version="691">
				<HEADING>Section 1069.1. Distribution of pamphlet on public health insurance program options in day care centers. </HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1083" name="1069"/>Section 1069.1. <CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Distribution of pamphlet on public health insurance program options in day care centers. </CHARFORMAT>
				</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-3131" number="4784" version="617">
					<PARA>Each day care center shall be required to distribute the pamphlet on public health insurance program options provided to it by the department of health and mental hygiene pursuant to subdivision b of section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="671734137-329684122-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Admin.nfo" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="17-183" destination-id="0-0-0-0">17-183</LINK> of the administrative code of the city of New York to those individuals who appear in person to register a child in such day care center. Day care centers shall also be required to ensure that pamphlets on public health insurance program options are made available to parents and/or guardians on the premises of such centers throughout the year. For the purposes of this section, &quot;day care center&quot; shall mean any child day care facility operating in New York city that is required to obtain a license from, or to register with, the department of health and mental hygiene pursuant to section <LINK style-name="Jump" style-name-escaped="Jump" style-id="0-0-0-21" type="Inter Infobase Jump" destination-infobase-id="381572687-333571626-0-0" destination-infobase-uil="L:\NY\New York City\Folio\Working\Rules.NFO" destination-infobase-name="" destination-infobase-title="" destination-name="T24HC_47.05" destination-id="0-0-0-0">47.05</LINK> of the New York city health code and/or the New York state department of social services pursuant to section 390 of the New York state social services law. </PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
		<LEVEL style-name="Section" style-name-escaped="Section" style-id="0-0-0-38" level-depth="3" toc-section="true">
			<RECORD id="0-0-0-3132" number="4785" version="983">
				<HEADING>Section 1069.2. By-laws of advisory bodies.</HEADING>
				<PARA>
					<DESTINATION id="0-0-0-1833" name="1069.2"/>Section 1069.2. By-laws of advisory bodies.</PARA>
			</RECORD>
			<LEVEL style-name="Normal Level" style-name-escaped="Normal-Level" style-id="0-0-0-0" level-depth="0" toc-section="false">
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-7584" number="4786" version="983">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>a.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Definitions.</CHARFORMAT> As used in this section the following terms have the following meanings: <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-116]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-7583" number="4787" version="983">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Advisory body.</CHARFORMAT> The term “advisory body” means an entity: (i) established by local law or executive order to advise, study, or report on a subject; (ii) the body of which includes at least one member of the public; (iii) which holds one or more public meetings; and (iv) that is neither a community board nor a borough board. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-116]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-7582" number="4788" version="983">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<CHARFORMAT bold="1" italic="0" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">By-laws.</CHARFORMAT> The term “by-laws” means the code or codes of rules adopted for the regulation or management of the affairs of an advisory body regardless of the name or names by which such rules are designated. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-116]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-7581" number="4789" version="983">
					<PARA>
						<TAB tab-count="1"/>b.<TAB tab-count="1"/>
						<CHARFORMAT bold="0" italic="1" underline="0" strike-out="0" hidden="0">Publication of by-laws.</CHARFORMAT> Any advisory body that adopts by-laws shall publish such by-laws to its website, or to the city’s website, in a searchable, non-proprietary, and machine-readable format. Any advisory body that updates its by-laws shall publish updated by-laws no later than 2 weeks after the date on which such advisory body adopts revisions to such by-laws. An advisory body that has completed its functions pursuant to local law or executive order shall no longer be required to post or update its by-laws pursuant to this paragraph. <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-116]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
				<RECORD id="0-0-0-7579" number="4790" version="994">
					<PARA>(L.L. 2025/182, 12/12/2025, eff. 12/12/2025) <HIGHLIGHTER style="highlighter-ALP" original-style-name="ALP" style-name-escaped="highlighter-ALP" name="ALP" id="0-0-0-24">[ALP S-116]</HIGHLIGHTER>
					</PARA>
				</RECORD>
			</LEVEL>
		</LEVEL>
	</LEVEL>
</DOCUMENT>